- [Narrator] So in order to switch to Vue,
I will mark all that code,
and comment it out.
Which you can do by selecting this all
and then going to Edit,
and then toggle line or block comment.
I used line comment here.
So now this code will not
have any effect anymore.
I'm not deleting it
so that we can still
see it and compare it.
Because now I wanna use Vue.
For that we first of all need to add Vue.
We need to import Vue.
We can
do this from vuejs.org and on this page,
there is this "Install" link
on which you can click,
which takes you
to the official documentation
where you find instructions
on how to create a Vue project.
By the way, in general,
the official documentation is really good.
So in addition to taking this course,
I can only recommend that you also dive
into the official documentation
after going through this course
to dove deeper
or refresh certain concepts.
But when it comes to setting up a project
and getting started,
we're here in the quick start section
and you find different ways
of creating a Vue project.
We will learn about different ways
throughout this course,
but the easiest way is not to install
packages, as it's mentioned up here.
We will do this later,
but instead the easiest way to get started
is by simply adding
an import to the Vue package
from a CDN to your page.
And for this,
we can grab this script tag here,
which you find in the
without built tools section and copy that.
And then with this
copied
we add this into our index.html file,
and you should make sure
that the link here
- this import link - ends with vue@3
or vue@next,
which also gives you version 3.
So let's grab that,
go to index HTML and add
that before your script here.
So before we execute app.js,
add this script with the Vue
CDN above your own script.
That will your script allow to use Vue.
So now let's save this file.
In app.js we can use Vue.
And now what does use Vue mean?
With Vue, we can solve the same problem,
if you wanna call it like this,
in a totally different way.
In regular Java script,
which we used before,
we used a so-called imperative approach.
Which means we define every single step,
step by step,
which should be executed by the browser.
Get access to the button,
get access to the input element,
get access to the list element,
create a function,
add a click event handler to the button
and execute this function
of a click occurs.
And in that function,
get access to the entered value,
create a list item element,
add the text content,
append this list item,
clear the value.
You see a pattern?
We define every single step.
With Vue, we have a
totally different approach.
There, we define the desired end result,
and the data we will need in our Vue app,
and we will leave it
up to Vue to figure out
what needs to be created or
added or changed in the Dom
at which point of time.
And for that, we need
to create a view app,
which takes control over our HTML code.
And we do this by calling Vue,
which is a global object
that is available,
thanks to our view CDN import,
Vue.createApp.
So this global Vue object,
we can call createApp.
CreateApp takes an object,
a JavaScript object,
where we configure this Vue app.
And when I say configure,
I mean things like setting
up which kind of data
we will use in our Vue app.
For example, in this demo,
I plan on working with a list of goals.
So one piece of data which we'll
need is that list of goals.
Another piece of data which we'll need
is what the user entered here.
And we define that data
by adding a data property
to this object we pass to createApp,
and this has to be called data.
It actually holds a function as a value
and therefore in modern JavaScript,
we can also write it like this,
which is the exact same.
A property named data,
which has a function as a value.
This function must return an object.
And in this object,
we can then define the data
our Vue app should be aware of.
As a side note,
if this is a bit too fast for you,
no worries.
We'll walk through all the
basics in greater depth
in the next module.
This year is just a quick overview,
which is why I'm not diving super deep
into all these concepts at the moment.
We'll definitely do that
in the next section though.
So we need to return an object here.
And in here, we can simply
add the data we wanna manage in this app.
This would be a goals array,
which initially is empty
as a key value pair,
and the entered value,
which initially is an empty string.
And now these two pieces of data
are pieces of data Vue is aware of.
And that will become important later.
Now we can connect this entered value
with this input
by adding a special so-called
directive on the input,
a special HTML attribute.
And that would be the V-model attribute.
That's not a default attribute,
which is supported by HTML.
This will only be understood by Vue.
And as a value,
we repeat the name of this property,
entered value.
This will establish a connection
between this input and the
value being entered there,
and this data property.
And Vue will manage this for us.
It will automatically listen
to what the user enters
and it will automatically
update this input
whenever we change entered
value in code, for example.
And that's of course way more convenient,
than manually reaching out to the input
and managing all of that.
But this is just the first step.
Now upon a button,
we wanna make sure that we
get what's currently
stored in entered value
and add this to goals.
For this we can add another key value pair
to this object we're passing to createApp,
and that's the methods key,
which now holds an object.
In here we can define methods,
functions,
that should be callable
from inside the HTML code.
So for example, here we
can add an addGoal method,
and in there,
then reach out to Goals and
add to currently entered value.
We can do this with this Goals
and then push,
since Goals is an array,
this entered value.
In case you're wondering why
this refers to this object
Vue will establish the
connection behind the scenes.
It does some magic for us here,
though throughout the course,
we are going to explore and
also understand that magic.
Now addGoal should be triggered
whenever this button is clicked.
And instead of manually reaching
out to the button element
and adding a click listener,
as we did it before,
with just JavaScript,
with Vue,
we can simply add
another special attribute
to the button element,
the V-on attribute.
Then we add a colon,
and then the name of the event
to which we wanna listen,
in this case, click.
And then as a value,
we specify the name of the
method that should be triggered
when the item
on which we added to this
special attribute is clicked.
So in our case,
addGoal, just like this.
With that, Vue will
make sure that addGoal,
this method,
gets executed whenever
this button is clicked
and it will then automatically
give us the currently entered value,
and add it as a new value to Goals.
And now there's only
one thing that remains.
We wanna output our Goals
here in this unordered list.
And for that we wanna
create list items here.
One for every goal.
And with Vue, as I mentioned,
we define the desired end result,
not how we get there.
So again, we wanna have
a list item at the end,
that's our desired result.
But of course not just one.
And Vue get the V-for attribute,
which we can add on an element
to replicate this element multiple times.
And here between the double quotes,
we then need to write "goal in goals"
to in the end loop through
all our goals here,
and create one list item per a goal.
And we get access to that goal,
for which we're currently creating one,
in this goal variable.
Now we can output this goal
with another special
syntax understood by Vue.
And that's double curly braces,
opening and closing,
and between them,
goal.
So this name here.
And that will now replicate
list item as often as needed,
and then put one goal per goal entry
we have in this goals array.
And if we now saved it all and reload,
you'll see absolutely nothing.
Instead, you just see
that curly brace thing,
which I'd just entered.
The reason for that is that
this Vue code will be correct,
but Vue doesn't know where that
code should have an effect,
where it should be applied.
That's why on this created app,
here, after the closing parentheses,
we need to call mount,
and let Vue know which part of the page
should be controlled by that Vue app.
And conveniently, I got a div here,
with the ID app,
which contains all the markup
that uses the Vue features
I explained over the last minutes,
where I use all the special
attributes, for example.
This diff with the ID app
contains all that code.
So it's this diff that should
be controlled by this Vue app.
And therefore to mount,
we pass a string with a CSS selector,
selecting one element in the Dom.
And since we have the
ID app on that dev here,
we can use the ID selector
for the ID app like this.
With hash and then app.
And if we save this now and reload again,
now, it just looks differently.
And if I finished a course, that's added,
if I learn Vue, that's being added.
And if I wanna reset the input,
I can simply set this entered
value to an empty string
and Vue will automatically
reach out to the Dom
and make the required updates.
So again,
learn Vue, and it's clear.
Finish the course, and it's cleared.
And now this is Vue taking over.