In the last module,
we had a look under the hood of Vue.
Maybe you skipped this module.
That's fine as well, but if you skipped it,
be aware that in that module,
I also talked about using multiple Vue apps
and I highlighted that those apps
would then not be connected, so that every Vue app you have,
which controls its part of the HTML page,
is totally independent from other apps.
Now, we're going to take this concept
of multiple apps one step further
and we're going to explore Vue components,
another core feature built into Vue,
which indeed builds up on all the other pieces
you learned about thus far.
So this is an important next step, because as you will see,
components will now be there
throughout the entire rest of the course,
and components are a super important concept in Vue,
but also in other alternative frameworks,
like Angular or React,
just in case you ever want to explore those as well.
In this module, we will therefore see
what exactly components are
and why we have this concept and how we use it of course.
And we'll start working with some components,
so that we get a first idea of what a component is
and what we can do with it.