Now, again, attached to find a starting project,
which gives you this page essentially,
it's a little dummy application
where you can keep a list of your friends around
and store the phone number and email address
of your friends.
It's just a dummy application,
but it will allow us to explore the concept of components.
Now, if we inspect the code for this,
we get an index HTML file with some markup,
to be precise with an unordered list
that holds the two friend list items.
So one list item per friend
and then we have a nested list in every friend
with the phone and email number.
We got the name, we got a button
which currently does nothing
and important, we also got an empty app.js file.
So no view app at all
and now it would not be totally unrealistic
that this should be managed as one app
and we may be don't want to hard to code this friend data
into the HTML code.
But instead we wanna keep that friend data around
in our view code, in our view application
and we don't want to hard code those list items
into the HTML code, but we want to render
those list items dynamically with view.js
and it turns out that with the knowledge we gained thus far,
that is possible,
but actually has some tricky elements to it.
But let's try implementing this
with what we learned thus far.
So in the app.js file, I'm going to create a new view app
with view create app
and of course, we're going to mount this
to control a part off the Dom with it
and here I wanna control this section,
which has an idea of app.
So let's target this with this ID selector here
and now let's say we wanna implement this
by adding some data here
and actually in here, we have our friend's property,
which should be an array full of data about our friends
and each friend could be represented by an object
where we, for example, have an ID manual, for example,
then a name field Manuel Lorenz for my friend Manuel here,
a phone field with that imaginary phone number
you can try calling it.
Maybe you get someone there, but I just made that number up
and the email address, which of course also is fictionally
so let's store that as well
and with that we would have an entry for Manuel.
Now let's add a second one for Julie,
so here we have Julie Jones,
we can grab her imaginary phone number
and store that here
and also grab her imaginary email address
and store it at here
and now we have that data managed in Java script
and as before in the course, data is a scenario
you will typically have.
That could be data, which you fetched from a database,
it could be data which the user entered.
You will rarely have websites where you hard code
data like this into the HTML code.
That's why this approach, which we had here initially
is not very realistic
and why we instead might want to use vue.
Also to for example make this button work
and ensure that we only show our details here
with the phone number and the email,
if the button is pressed.
So therefore now we have that data
with that data, we can delete one of the two list items
and then use the for here as we learned it
to go through all the friends
in this friends' data property.
So in this data property, which holds this array,
so we're looping through this two array elements now,
and therefore now inside of this list item
inside of we-for we can now interpolate friend.name
for example, here for the phone number
we can output with double curly braces, friend.phone
and instead of the email address, we can output friend.email
and we can also assign a key here
and bind it dynamically to friend.id
because we have that ID field on every friend entry
and with that, if we save all that and reload,
we get the same as before,
but now with less HTML code leveraging view.
But the show details button is not working
and that's the part where it gets tricky.
Of course we could add methods here
and then add a method which we could call toggle details,
which should be connected to the button
and we wanna show the details
if they're not currently visible
and hide them if they were visible.
So we could add a second data property
details are visible, which initially let's say is false
to initially not show them
and then here in toggle details,
we set details are visible to what they're currently not
to basically invert the value
as we also did it many times before
and with that, we can go back to the HTML code
and connect that button.
Upon a click, I want to trigger toggle details
so I wanna execute this newly added method here
and then we get that detailed are visible property,
which we can use with the v-if on this unordered list
to control whether that list should be shown.
So whether it should be added to the Dom or not,
we can then even replace this label
on the button dynamically
by checking if details are visible
and if they are the button should say hide details
and only otherwise say show details
and of course, we could also use a computed property here,
but I wanna keep this simple and to the point
so I will not do it here.
If we now reload, we get the button,
but the problem is no matter
on which friend we press the button,
we always showed a details
or hide the details of all friends
and it should be obvious why that happens
with v-for we output multiple list items here,
one for every friend,
but the button always points at the same method.
So every button for every friend
gets the same event handler it points at the same method.
So no matter which button on which friend we press,
we always call the same method
and we just have details are visible here,
which is just one property that controls
the visibility of the details in both contacts.
Now there would be work arounds we could pass the ID here
to toggle details.
We could forward the friend ID to toggle details
and then inside of toggle details, we could expect that ID
and now manage two properties.
Details are visible A, details are visible B
and we could try to make it work with properties like that,
but still it would be very cumbersome,
I'm not sure how we would make it work with v-if
to find out on which friend we are here.
So ultimately this is not what we wanna do,
I also don't even wanna get started
with having a ABC and whatever a here
because this list may grow dynamically.
It doesn't in this application because it's a simple one
but if you allow users to add new friends,
you can't anticipate how many properties you will need
to toggle the visibility of the details.
So this will lead nowhere
and therefore I'll reverts this here,
this is not how I wanna solve that.
Instead, that's exactly the kind of problem
we can solve with components.
So let's see what components are,
how we create them and how we work with them.