Components are a great,
if you have certain pieces of HTML.
Certain HTML blocks like here,
which you reuse in different parts of your page,
like here, where we create multiple list items.
Where you then have a certain functionality
that should be enclosed in that HTML block.
And that should be specific to this HTML block.
Components can also be great
to splitting your big application
into multiple smaller chunks,
but that's something we'll explore later automatically
once we work more and more with components.
So, since components seem to be very helpful,
how can we create such a component?
How does it work?
A component is the official feature Vue.js knows,
and we can create one on an app.
So on an app we create it with create app,
by using that app which in my case here
is stored in that app constant
and calling the component method on it.
This tells Vue that we want to create a new component.
Now this component method needs two things.
The first thing is an identifier
because a component and that's important,
you have to memorize this.
A component is basically like a custom HTML element.
So here you define your own HTML tag
and that could for example,
be user dash contact
or friend dash contact, something like this.
You should always use an identifier that contains a dash.
So you should always have component names,
custom HTML tags therefor which contained a dash,
so which are made up of two words.
The reason for that is simple,
this avoids that you potentially clash
with official built in HTML elements.
For example, if it would name my component h2,
well, there already is h2 element,
and that would therefore clash.
Therefore, a simple rule is that you should use
multi word component names, so custom HTML tags,
because all built in HTML elements
are a single word elements.
So that's now my own HTML element name
which we will later be able to use.
This is the identifier of our components so to say.
The second argument you pass to this component method,
is a conflict object just as you pass it to create app
because, and that's another important
piece of information to keep in mind.
A Vue component is essentially just another Vue app,
just an app that belongs to another app.
So this which we're creating here is a new Vue app,
but, and that's the important thing,
an app which will be connected to our main app.
So components are like mini apps you could say.
So therefore they can also have data,
they can have methods and therefore a here,
our component can have its own data,
where we, for example, have a detailsAreVisible property
which initially is false.
We can also add methods to our component
and add our toggle details method
here to the methods of my own component.
So that we then toggle this component specific data
with this component specific method.
And we can remove methods from the main app now,
and also get rid of details are visible there.
We could also keep it here,
we wouldn't have a clash because this component
is essentially encapsulated.
It does not communicate with the parent app
so with the app it belongs to,
but we can still remove this property
because we don't need it in the main app anymore.
So now we got our component, friend contact
and how do we now use this component?
And how does it work?
Well, this component misses one important thing
before we can use it.
And that's a template since this is a new app,
it needs its own template.
Our main app has a template, this whole section,
which we mounted the app to,
but our component now is a mini app
and it needs its own template.
Now, here we don't mount this component,
we don't call mount on it,
so that's not how we will connect it to HTML.
Instead here for the moment,
we'll add this template option,
which I also showed in the deep dive
in the behind the scenes module.
In case you skipped that,
yes there is a template option
which you can add to your view apps also to the main app
to define the template of that app.
So to define the HTML code of that app
and you need to do that for this component.
Now I will already say that later in the course
in the next modules,
we will learn about a much nicer way
of defining those templates.
But for the moment, I'll just create a multiline string here
with backticks.
So these are not single quotes, these are backticks,
which is a different character on the keyboard.
And I will now grab this list item here,
so these entire code and cut it from my HTML file
and instead added here in this backticked string.
And I'm using backticks because they allow me to write
a multiline string like this.
But in the end, that's just a JavaScript string now.
With all those view features in it though,
now, I will remove that v4 code on the list item
and to make sure the interpolations work
for the moment I will add a friend property
to the data off that component
so not friends, but friend.
And I will just copy one friend which I defined here.
Let's take manual and store him in this friend key.
This is just temporary,
we'll soon make it work with our list again,
but to get started, we'll just use friend like that
And now if I save that,
we can finally start using our own component
and therefore our own HTML element.
Because now we can go to index HTML
and instead of our main apps template,
we can now use friend contact as if it would be
an official HTML element.
And it's not, I really want to emphasize it.
This is not an HTML element which the browser would know.
If you try to use that outside
of the Vue app controlled part, this will do nothing
the browser will ignore it.
But inside of our main app Vue will understand this,
it will understand this component
because we registered this component to our main app
with the component method,
by giving it that exact identifier
which I'm now using as an HTML tag in my template.
And that's why we should use
a non-default HTML tag name here,
because if we would have named our component h2,
Vue would not recognize it as a custom component of course.
But since we have such a name with a dash in it,
a two word name, which is this identifier we used here,
Vue detects that here in the end,
we wanna render this mini app with its template
and all the dynamic pieces in the template.
So now if we save this again and reload,
we see Manual Lorenz on the screen
and we can click show details and hide details
and this just works.
And now we can repeat that
and simply add a number of component.
And if I reload, we have Manuel Lorenz twice
and the important thing is every Manual Lorenz,
works, stand-alone, totally detached from the other one.
Now, of course we have the same data twice now,
that's something we're going to fix soon,
but this shows you how components allow you
to easily replicate and encapsulated piece of HTML code
with, and that's the important part
with attached data and logic.
So components are reusable pieces of HTML
with connected data and logic.
And that is very, very powerful
especially as you will soon see
how we can also reuse one and the same component
with different data that we pass into the component.
That will be the next step,
which will then really make components a powerful tool.
But you can hopefully already see
how a component helps us encapsulate structure,
content and logic into small reusable pieces.
And you can really add as many of these components
here as you want, and they will all be rendered
and they all work, stand-alone.
So now we've got a bunch of Vue mini apps
in the same main app.
And these apps will then also be able to communicate
with each other to share information
and hence we'll have the best of both roles.
Encapsulated, isolated pieces of code,
which also makes it easier to work on that code
in case you have bigger projects.
And at the same time,
we can combine all those isolated pieces
to build a bigger app from them.
Now that's our components
and they will be super important
and we're going to use them
throughout the rest of the course.
But at the same time,
we're now already reaching a part
where this setup we used thus far has certain limitations.
We'll have more and more code in the same file
and writing templates like this in such a string form,
that will not be very nice to do.
In addition we of course also need
to learn more about components
so that we can really make this component reusable
and also work with different data
so that the component acts like a shell
to which we can pass different data.
We'll take care of all of that in the next modules.