Now in the module,
we're just getting started with components,
and we don't really see their full potential yet.
This will change.
Over the next modules, you will learn all about components
and you will learn how you can build applications
like this one where the entire user interface
is built by combining components.
And where we use components
to encapsulate different templates and logic
tied to that templates into reusable building blocks,
you will see how that makes it easier to structure
the code phase of complex apps and keep it manageable
by splitting your code, your logic,
and all of your templates and what's on the screen
into smaller reusable pieces.
Now this is all code you won't understand at this point
but we'll get there, and we'll get there
starting in the next module.