In this module here,
we're going to pick up on this component concept
and we're going to take it to the next level.
You will learn how to build really reusable components
and how to communicate between components.
This will be super-important
because only with the knowledge you gain in this module,
only with that, you'll be able to build
a rich user interfaces in Vue applications with components,
and you will see why components are such a powerful thing,
such a powerful concept,
and why modern Vue applications in the end
are all about components.
Now for that, we'll get there step-by-step.
We'll start building a user interface with components
to get an understanding for how we combine
these different building blocks.
And we'll then also explore how those components
can communicate with each other,
which basically means
how you can pass data between components.
Because as you'll see,
and as you actually already saw a bit
in the component introduction module,
passing data to components, and between components
will be an important concept.
Now, last but not least,
you will also see that there are different ways
of communication and you will learn which approaches exist
and when you use which approach.
So therefore, let's not waste any time.
And let's get started with working with components
and with letting them talk to each other.