Now as I emphasized in the last lecture,
props are super important.
We use them for something which is also called
parent child communication.
So the parent component or app in this case,
our main app, communicates
to its child HTML element
to its child component.
In this case to the friend contact component.
The friend contact component, is a child of this app
because we use it in the template of the app.
On the other hand, for friend contact,
the app would be the parent,
because well, friend contact
gets used in the template of app.
So these are just terms you can keep in mind,
parent and child.
And we use props to communicate
from the parent to the child.
So to pass data from the parent to the child component
from app to friend contact, in our case.
Now here's one important thing you have to know about props
and which you should keep in mind.
Props typically should not be mutated.
And what do I mean by that?
Let's add a new prop.
Let's say here in App.vue,
we have is favorite prop,
which we passed to friend contact.
And the value I pass here,
is one for a true or a zero for false.
So here I pass isFavorite.
And here let's say I set this to zero.
Now that's a new prop, which we do for should add
here in friend contact isFavorite written like this.
Now we've got, this isFavorite prop.
Now let's say we wanna use that to output
some extra information after the name.
Here with interpolation,
I'm checking if isFavorite is equal to one
and if that's the case,
I'll put some extra text here,
otherwise I won't.
And the extra text is a pair of parentheses where I say
Favorite.
If I now save that and reload,
you see Favorite after Manuel Lawrence,
because that is where I added isFavorite.
And after Julie Jones, we don't see that because there,
I set isFavorite to zero.
Now, why am I doing that?
Well, let's also see we have another button here,
which allows us to change the favorite status.
I'll say Toggle Favorite on the button.
And I'll add a new method.
toggleFavorite could be the name
to which I wanna point here
with the click listener on that button.
And now we add this method here
in the methods, toggleFavorite.
And in here, I'll check if this isFavorite is equal to one.
So if we were a favorite,
in which case I'll set it to zero
and otherwise, if isFavorite was zero I'll set it to one.
we could do it as to change the favorite status
with help of the button.
If we saved it, we get an error here.
The error is unexpected mutation of isFavorite prop.
As I mentioned, that's not something you should do.
Now, why should you not do that?
Because Vue uses a concept which is called
unidirectional data flow.
Now that's again a fancy term,
but it means one simple thing.
Data passed from app to friend contact
should only be changed in app, not in friend contact.
We just pass data down to friend contact.
And once the data is passed down,
friend contact cannot change the data we manage an app view,
at least not by simply changing the received data.
So if we change data inside of friend contact like here,
when I tried to change isFavorite,
this is not allowed by Vue,
because we violate this pattern
of having a unidirectional data flow.
Now, if we want to change this,
there are two ways of doing that.
The first way of doing it, is that we let the parent know
that we'd like to change this.
Then the parent can go ahead and change the data in itself
and pass the updated data back to friend contact.
That's a pattern we'll explore later.
It's an important pattern
and will therefore have a detailed look at it soon.
The other approach is that we simply take the received data
as the initial data, inside of friend contact,
and then we changed that data instead of friend contact,
but we are aware of the fact that we only change it there
and that this won't affect the data in App.vue.
To implement this pattern,
all we need to do is we need to add a new data property
in our component,
for example, friendisFavorite.
So using a different name than I used here
and now we'll set this equal to this isFavorite.
So set it equal to the received prop value.
Then we use the received prop value just as an initial value
for friendisFavorite.
And now friend is Favorite can be used here,
friendisFavorite,
in the template,
but also in the rest of the code.
And if we now change that friendisFavorite property,
that will be okay,
because that's now our regular data property,
where the prop we received
is just used to set an initial value.
So now that works and I can toggle this favorite status.
I'm emphasizing this and talking about this
because this unidirectional data flow
is an important concept.
Now of course you will have scenarios
where you want to be able
to change the original data
you got from the App.vue file.
So where just using it as initial data
and then changing it internally is not enough.
Therefore, we'll also very soon
have a look at how you can implement that,
for the moment be aware that you should not mutate props,
but if you need to do it,
you can just take a prop as an initial value
and then change the component exclusive property and stat.