So props are important as you can tell,
and thus far we're specifying props like this,
as an array of the props we expect to get
where every prop is just added as a string.
I mentioned that this would be
the bare minimum configuration.
With that view will let you know about the props
you expect to get,
but you don't provide any other information to view.
This is okay, especially for simple apps
or simple components,
but for more complex components,
and especially when working in a team for example,
you might want to share more information
about your props.
Simply, so that view can let you know
if you pass incorrect data to a component
or if you forgot some required prop.
And for that, you can replace this array of props,
actually I'll copy it and comment it out
so that you'll still have it for reference,
you can replace it with an object.
And in that object, you now have your props
as JavaScript property names,
and then certain values for them.
And here the most basic extra information
you could provide is the type of data you expect to get.
For example, string.
To make it clear that the value of the main prop
should be a string.
And if instead a number would be provided,
we would get an error.
Side note, I'm speaking of a number type being provided.
Not text that contains a number.
That would of course be okay,
since it would be a string.
So we can do that instead,
and now make it clear that all our data,
at the moment, at least,
is getting a string like this.
So now we're saying that this component
will get a name, a phone number, an email address,
and the isFavorite prop,
and every prop should get a value of type string.
Enhance does of course works
but now we provide more information.
But you can be even more detailed than that.
Instead of just providing that type here,
you can provide an object as a value
for the prop you're expecting to get.
And in this object,
you now can add a type, property, which holds the type
of the prop you wanna get,
but you can also add more properties.
Now not any properties of your choice,
instead specific properties view will look for,
for example type, but also required.
To indicate whether this prop, the name prop here
should be required or not.
And this should be true or false.
So here we could make it clear
that this component, the friend contact component,
needs a name prop, this is required.
And we can do the same, of course, for the other props.
Type string, and the phone number is also required.
And also for the email address.
We want to get a string and this required.
Now let's say the isFavorite prop is also a type string
but it's not required.
In that case, if you have a non-required prop,
you can add a default key,
where you provide a default value,
which will be used if the prop should be missing.
So here for example, zero, so that by default,
this component is not a favorite.
Default can also be a function by the way,
where you could have a more complex code snippet
that executes to derive the default.
But here I'll just set this to zero as a string.
You can also add a validator
which holds a function,
which should return true or false.
This validator function will get
the value provided for the prop
and then you can have any validation object of your choice
to find out whether that's a valid value or not.
So here for isFavorite for example
we could check if value is equal to one,
or if value is equal to zero,
and that will be able for a yield true
if either of the two is correct,
or false, if we get a totally different value.
So with that we could make sure that really only
the values one and zero are allowed here.
And what's the whole idea behind that?
Well, with that more detailed configuration here,
we can go to the place where we use our component,
and for example omit isFavorite, let's say,
on the second component here, on Julie.
With that, the app still works,
because we made this prop isFavorite non-required,
it's optional, we have a default fallback value.
On the other hand, if I remove the name here and save that,
we don't get an error here,
but if we open up the developer tools
and the JavaScript consol here,
we get a warning by view,
that we got a missing required prop name.
And that helps us as a developer
to spot such mistake quicker during development.
And we don't have to guess why the component
now is not working anymore.
Instead, we get a clear warning.
So that's very useful.
And let's bring back that name.
If I provide an invalid value for isFavorite, for example,
we got the invalid prop warning,
because our custom validator check failed.
We didn't provide one or zero,
but instead 100, which is simply not valid,
as specified here.
So you can have more complex prop definitions
to make sure that your component really gets used correctly.
Now ultimately, of course, it's your component,
so it's up to you how detailed you wanna be.
If you have an entire project on which you work on your own,
you might not need those more detailed configurations,
because you know all your components
and all your props anyways.
But if you're sharing your component with other people,
as a third-party package
or because you're working in a team,
you might want to provide
such more detailed prop definitions
so that everyone who's using your component
is quickly able to see how that component works,
which state it needs,
and when a prop is valid or not valid.
Getting such extra warnings here
can then really be helpful
and make your life as a developer
much-much easier.
And that's the idea behind more complex
prop definitions and prop validations,
which I've showed you here.
Now for the majority of the course,
I will use the simpler types of definitions,
either this array or just defining the value type
but I want you to be aware of that
so that if you are working on a bigger project,
you do know how to be more explicit regarding your props
and how they should look like.