Now of course,
props cannot just be set to string values.
And of course, just like other HTML elements,
you can bind them to dynamic values.
For example, is favorite currently works with one or zero.
Now, since we have exactly two values,
it would make much more sense, that we want a Boolean here.
So that we make it clear,
that this should be of type Boolean.
Then we can also get rid of that validator,
because a Boolean can only be true or false.
There are no other values.
The default value then could be false here.
So that is favorite is false by default.
But now to pass false,
we can't just set this to true or false here.
This is not how it works,
because this will always be some text here.
Instead to use the true value type,
we need to bind this with v-bind,
and that is something we can do.
We can bind our own props,
just as we can bind any other HTML attribute.
And if we got a prop that needs a JavaScript value,
other than a string, then we need to use v-bind,
or the shorthand of course, to pass in that value,
You can, of course, still also execute
any JavaScript expression here,
call a method or whatever you wanna do,
but you can also use that to pass non string values.
But being able to bind props dynamically,
is not just useful for that.
It's not just useful to pass non-string values,
even though that is useful.
But it's also useful to make those components,
a bit more dynamic.
Maybe you forgot about it already,
but we have our friends here in NRA,
inside of our App.vue file.
Now wouldn't it be nice if we could use v-for again,
but now repeat our own component,
and then pass in the different data for each loop iteration?
Well, turns out you can do that.
You can use v-for, and also v-if by the way,
on your own components,
just as you can use it on default HTML elements.
So here, I can loop through my friends like this,
and now there's just one important rule.
You always need to add a key here.
I talked about the key before.
Keys are important, when you deal with v-for.
When you use v-for on a custom component,
adding a key is mandatory.
So, make sure you add the key prop here.
You don't need to specify it in your component.
Vue automatically knows what to do with it.
Make sure you use it when you use v-for,
on a custom component.
And then here we can bind key dynamically,
to friend.id for example.
And now we can not just find key dynamically,
but also all the other fields like name.
Here, we can set this equal to friend.name.
Phone number, we can set this equal to friend.phone,
because that is the field we have here,
where we store our dummy phone number.
And the same, of course, although for email address,
bind it's dynamically to friend.email.
And for the moment I'll leave is favorite as it is,
we'll work on that again later.
Now we can remove that second usage
of friend contact, because now v-for,
will create multiple friend-contact elements on this page.
One for every friend in France.
And we're binding all prop values dynamically,
to pass in the different data we have for every friend.
This of course also means, that we now can get rid,
of that dummy friend,
we're defining in friend contact.view.
We don't need that anymore, because we already are receiving
all the prop data we need from outside.
And we can also change toggle favorite.
Since is favorite is now a Boolean by default,
we no longer should check if it's one or zero,
we can simplify this and set this friend is favorite,
equal to what it's currently not, to toggle it like this,
and set it to true if it was false,
and false if it was true.
And with all of that, if we now go back,
you now see your different data still,
but now in two components, that are created with v-for.
Now, toggle favorite is not working here,
let's see why that is the case.
Yeah, because this check of course is wrong.
Since it's a Boolean, we should check
if it's true or false like this.
So, for now adjust this.
That now looks better.
Now at the moment, both are favorites,
because I set is favorite to true,
here on the friend-contact component in general.
So, for every iteration we create a new friend-contact,
but it always has is favorite set to true.
But that is something we'll take care about later.
The key takeaway here, is that we can use v-for,
that we can bind those props to dynamic values,
and that now, we got a even more reusable component.
Hopefully making it clearer and clearer,
why components are that amazing.