So that's it for props for the moment.
We're using props to pass data from the app.vue file
into our FriendContact component.
Now what about communication from the component
to the parent?
A good example would be toggle favorite.
At the moment, this is kind of a dummy thing.
I'm setting it to true for every generated friend.
And we're not really managing it on a friend specific level.
Yes, I can toggle it for an individual friend,
but that only changes inside of the component.
In reality, just like the name, the phone number,
the email address.
is-favorite should not be set to true like this.
Instead, we should probably have a isFavorite property
on our friend object so that this data is really stored
on the input data, where we have the rest
of our friends data as well.
So we could have isFavorite here and also here.
That's what we typically would want to do
because the information,
whether a friend is a favorite of us or not
is just as important and friend specific
as its phone number and email address.
And it's not just something which we want to change here
inside of a component.
It should be part of our core friends data,
which could be coming from a database or anything like that.
Now we got isFavorite managed here,
and of course we can pass that down to our component,
but there, again, it just acts as an initial prop value,
which means if I click toggle favorite here,
that changes it inside of the FriendContact component,
but not inside of our core friends data.
Here of course, that is just some dummy data,
but if this would be coming from a database,
we probably would want to send it back
to that database as well.
So just changing it inside of that component is not enough.
We would also want to change it here in app.vue file
in our friends data, in our friends array.
So therefore, we now need communication
from the FriendContact component back to app.vue.
So basically the opposite of props.
Props allowed us to pass data from app.vue
to FriendContact.
Now we need a way of letting FriendContact tell app.vue
that the favorite status changed
and how could that work?
How could we implement that?
Well, how does it work for regular HTML elements?
If we click a button,
the button in the end wants to let us know
that it was clicked.
So the button emits a click event to which we can listen.
And it's the same for custom components in Vue.
If a component should talk to its parent and let the parent
know that something happened,
that component should emit an event
to which the parent can listen.
And indeed you can emit your own custom events
inside of your Vue components.
For example here, when toggleFavorite is triggered.
In this method, instead of changing
this internal friendIsFavorite data property,
we can use this and now a built in method,
which ships together with Vue
and therefore it starts with a dollar sign,
just like refs did in the behind the scenes module.
But now it's not refs, but emit, dollar sign emit.
That's a built in method, which you can call from inside
a Vue component under this keyword.
And this allows you to emit your own custom event
to which you then can listen
from inside the parent component.
Now emit wants at least one argument,
and that is the name of the custom event.
And here you can name this event, however you want.
It's your event.
So you can use any name you want.
And I'll use toggle-favorite.
Here the convention is to always use kebab case
no matter where you use it.
So that's different to props where in the component
that receives it, you use camel case
and you only use kebab case for passing in the values.
For events it's always kebab case.
So now we're emitting this toggle favorite event.
Our own component is emitting this custom event.
And what do you do with that?
Well, you listen to it just as you can listen
to clicks on buttons.
In the app.vue file, where we use our own component,
you can listen to it with v-on or the @ shorthand.
And here we can listen to toggle-favorite
and bind this to any JavaScript code that should execute
when this event is emitted.
Here, we could now add methods
to our Vue app config object,
and add a method named toggleFavoriteStatus, for example.
And then bind this method here to our toggle-favorite event.
And if we save that, that should work.
Of course at the moment, that does nothing,
but we also don't get an error.
And we can tell that it works
if we add an alert here
in that toggle favorite status method.
This works, which of course is not the final code,
but a good test.
Now you'll see, I get this alert if I click toggle favorite.
And that is how we can communicate back
from a component to its parent.
But of course we're not done.
We're now emitting a custom event,
but this event should probably carry some data
so that we also let the parent,
the app.vue file know which of the two contacts
changed its favorite status.
Because we got two and here we got no easy way of telling.
Well, in FriendContact.vue, when we emit
we can also pass a second argument.
Actually, you can pass as many arguments as you want.
And every extra argument will simply be data
that you pass together with your event.
So for example here,
we could expect that we get one extra prop,
the ID of the friend,
which is of type string and which should be required.
So I'm adding this extra prop definition.
In app.vue, we do have IDs so we can easily pass them in
simply by binding the newly defined ID prop
and passing in friends.id like this.
And now with the ID provided to FriendContact
on the ID prop, we can emit it here with our custom event.
This idea is now available
because I just added a prop named ID to this component.
And now the toggle favorite event, when it's emitted,
will carry this as an extra data.
And that will then be provided as a first argument
to a method that listens to this event.
So in app.vue, we're pointing at the toggleFavoriteStatus
method on our own event
and the toggleFavoriteStatus method
therefore will now receive this friend ID.
You can name this argument however you want here,
but you will get this second argument we're providing here
when we're emitting the custom event.
This ID is accepted here as a first parameter
in toggleFavoriteStatus.
And this now helps us identify the friend
where we want to change the favorite status.
So now we can reach out to our friends array
and use the built in find method,
which exists in JavaScript to find a friend
where friend ID is equal to the friend ID
we're getting here.
That's default JavaScript code for finding
that friend object in the friends array,
where the ID property holds the same value
as the friend ID argument we're getting here.
This is then the identifiedFriend we could name it.
And on that identifiedFriend,
we can now set isFavorite to what it's currently not.
And this will change that data.
And the cool thing is when that data changes,
Vue will detect this change
and it will then automatically pass the updated
favorite status back to the component and update DUI.
So now we never changed the favorite status
inside of the FriendContact component,
but we always changed it in the app.vue file.
And still, you will see that everything works.
The only change we'll need to make for that
is back in FriendContact, we now get rid of this
friendIsFavorite data property we added there before.
And instead we use our isFavorite prop,
which we're getting and which we're now changing
eventually in app.vue.
We're using this prop here in our template
because that will now work.
If we save that, you'll see I can toggle this
and Vue detects all the changes
and updates everything correctly.
And now we're using this unidirectional data flow
in both directions.
We're using it to pass prop data from app.vue
into our component,
but we're also using it the other way around
to emit a custom event inside of our own component
with the dollar sign emit method
and listen to this custom event in app.vue
to then make changes to the data in app.vue,
which we're storing in the data property
of our main app here, to then feed that updated data back
into our component where Vue will then see that something
changed and where Vue then updates the UI.
And this is how you work with components.
You can emit your own events
and you can set your own data.
It's actually quite similar to working
with default HTML elements,
just with the difference that you now control the code
behind the HTML element, so to say.