So as you can clearly tell
custom events are important,
an important feature for a component communication.
Now, just as with props,
you can define them.
You can let Vue know
about the events your component will emit.
For props, this is actually required.
For events, it's recommended.
Now I'll just close this here to gain some space.
The props are still there,
I'm just collapsing this so that it takes up less space.
And I'll add a new property
to the FriendContact configuration object.
And that's the emit property.
Now emits, so to say,
is the counterpart to props.
In props you will define
which props this component receives.
In emits, you will define which custom events
your component will eventually at some point emit.
And you're doing this to document your component,
to make it obvious to other developers,
how your component works,
and to which events they can listen.
This is simply useful.
It makes it easier to understand your component.
Because otherwise I have to look through all your code
to see that there is some code
where you emit toggle-favorite.
With emits, you would simply add
toggle
favorite here as a string to this disarray,
and that would make it clear that
there definitely is some code in your component,
which leads to an event with that identifier to be emitted.
And you can also take emits to the next level.
This is the basic form of using it,
and it already helps with understanding your component.
But just as with props,
you can also specify an object instead,
and then add your admitted events
as keys here
like this,
and then provide a more detailed configuration.
The configuration you should then add is a function,
a function that receives the data,
which you eventually will emit as parameters.
So in this case,
we will eventually emit an ID.
So here we would add
ID as a parameter,
and I'm doing that to make it obvious that "toggle-favorite"
is an event that should be handled by a function
that expects an ID.
Because I will emit an ID here.
You can then also add validation here
to make sure that when the event is emitted,
this data, which should be part of the event
is not forgotten.
We can check if ID exists,
if this is true
and return true, if that's the case
and else return false,
and maybe also issue a warning in the console that
ID is missing,
to help developers that are emitting this event,
catch this error.
And now, for example,
if I remove this second argument here,
and I saved that
and I click "toggle-favorite",
I get an error here.
But before that error,
I actually also get a warning
invalid event arguments,
event validation failed for event "toggle-favorite",
ID is missing.
So this is something which you don't have to add,
but which can make your life as a developer easier,
especially again if you're working in a team.
Now let's bring this ID back
and I will not add this detailed of a validation
to the custom events throughout the course.
But since it is the complete guide,
I of course want to show this to you
so that you know this feature.
Nonetheless, I will revert to this here,
and go back to this simpler definition,
which is the approach I will use throughout the course
simply to make it obvious
which custom events this component will eventually emit.