I'm fully aware that this was a lot
of new information about components, props and events.
The key takeaway of course is that props are there
to send data into a component and events are there
to send data out of a component, you could say.
Now let's practice this together, you will later also have
an assignment which you do on your own.
But let's start together and let's add
a brand new component to this app.
And a brand new functionality as well.
Because at the moment, our friends here are fairly static.
We got an array with two friends and yes isFavorite
is able to change, but we got no way of adding
or deleting friends here.
And that is a feature I'd like to add to
this demo application.
So therefore, we'll add a new component that allows us
to enter the data for a new friend.
So the name, the phone and the email address let's say.
And then I want to be able to confirm that data
and that data should be added here.
Now we could absolutely add this form here.
Let's say below the header, we could add a form.
And in here we could then add our inputs, like this.
And we could then also add proper styling and make sure
that we got all the input elements we need and whenever data
is entered and confirmed we add it to this array of friends.
This would work but it is exactly not what you should do.
Instead of having large view files with a lot of logic
in there, you should
have multiple smaller specialized components instead.
And then build your UI by combining these components.
So in reality, we would not add the form here
but instead in the components folder, we would add
a new component.
NewFriend could be the component name.
So I'll name the file NewFriend.vue.
And in there we will add our template again
and our script section.
And we would create that form and handle the user input
in this component, and then just emit
a custom event once everything is confirmed
to the App.vue file
and pass all the entered data onto App.vue.
Now, definitely feel free to try this on your own.
Here's your chance to pause the video and implement
this on your own, but thereafter we'll do this step
by step together.
To practice this component concept and also the props
and the custom events concept.
Nonetheless, if you wanna try it
on your own, here's your chance to pause the video.
So, were are you successful?
Let's now try together.
In NewFriends.vue, I'll add a form.
A default HTML element therefore.
And in here I now wanna have various inputs.
So I'll add an input of type text for the name
and maybe also add a label where we say name.
And then I will repeat that a couple of times here.
I'll actually also put each label input set into
a separate div to make it easier to tell them apart.
So here, we also have an input for the phone number then.
And here we can set the type to tell because we want
to get a telephone number here.
And here we got the email address and we can set the type
to email to get an email address.
And that's all regular HTML.
Below that let's say we have another div, in
there we have our button, where we say Add Contact.
And since this button is inside of a form
when it's clicked, that form will be submitted.
Now here in the script text, I'll export
a default JavaScript object
which will hold the configuration for this component.
But for the moment it's empty, we'll add more later.
And in main.js, we can now import this component.
We can import the new friend component
from ./components NewFriend.vue.
And register this as a component with app component.
New-friend could be our custom HTML tag.
Keep in mind that it should be a two word tag with
a dash between new words.
And new friend is our component configuration, even
though it currently is an empty object.
But the template will already be picked up.
And therefore in App.vue, here between header
and unordered list.
We can add our new-friend component.
Opening and closing.
And if we do that, we see our form here.
Now the styling is not super beautiful.
So I will tweak that a bit in the style tags
in the App.vue file.
And in the end I will just reuse the styling I used
for a list items.
So here, I will target the form element with that as well.
And now we have this form.
Now it's still not super pretty when it comes to
the labels and inputs.
So for that I'll quickly add some new styling,
but I don't want to bore you with that.
So attach to find a form dot CSS file
which contains these styles, which I'll add here.
And now with these three styles added to the style text,
this is what you should see on the screen.
So now this is our own component,
a brand new form component which allows us to enter data
for the name, the phone number and the email address
and then click Add Contact.
So now for the logic, which props do we need here?
Well, I would say we need no props.
Because this component will gather some user data
and eventually it should provide that to App.ue,
but it doesn't really need any external data.
So I don't see any props which we would need here
at the moment.
But as I just said we'll definitely need to emit an event.
And therefore I'll already at the emits property
and add an event name of my choice here or of your choice
of course in your case.
And I'll name it, add-contact because that's the kind
of event we'll emit here.
But you can also pick a different name, any name
that makes sense to you.
I will also add my data property here
and manage some components specific data.
So data that is required by this component.
And here essentially I want to store what the user enters
as a name, as a phone number and as an email address.
And therefore I'll just add three data properties here.
Entered name, which initially is an empty string.
Entered phone, which initially is an empty string
and you guessed it, entered email.
And I will bind these data properties with v-model.
So here v-model is bound to entered name.
Here, I'll bind the phone number input
with v-model to entered phone and the email
with v-model, to entered email.
So that with every keystroke we store what the user enters.
I'll also listen to the submit event
on the form with @submit.
And I will use the prevent modifier to ensure that
when this is submitted, we prevent the browser default.
Which would lead to the page being reloaded, which
is not what I want.
I want to handle this fully inside
the running view application.
Here we can point at a method of our choice
and I'll name the method submit data.
But again it's your code, your method you can name
it whatever you want.
But we do have to add that method of course.
So here after data, we add methods to
this NewFriend component config object.
And there I'll add to submit data method, which now
will be triggered when the form is submitted.
And here I have one simple thing which I wanna do.
I want to emit my custom add contact event,
so that I can forward that data to whoever
is listening to that custom event.
Which later will be the App.vue file.
So here we use this dollar sign emit.
And then emit, add-contact.
So the Custom Event I'm announcing here, basically.
And we forward this entered name, this entered phone
and this entered email.
You could also group this together into an object
and just emit one argument they have for or, like I'm doing
it here emit three arguments.
And now we can go to App.vue and listen
to this custom event on the NewFriend component.
With @add-contact.
And then point at a method which we need to define here.
And I'll named add method add contact as well.
But again this name is up to you, it doesn't have to be
the same one as we used for the event.
These two don't have to be the same.
So now down in methods, I'll add addContact
and we expect three parameters here.
Because we're emitting three pieces of data the name,
the phone number, the email.
So here I expect to get name, phone and email.
These parameter names are up to you, but the order
of course matters.
Because it's the same order as specified here
when we emit the event.
And then here, we can create a newFriend contact
which should be a new JavaScript object.
Which now has the same structure
as our dummy starting objects.
So name, phone and email but also in id
and also isFavorite property.
Now we can generate a pseudo unique id, by
for example using the current date, which we can get like
this in JavaScript.
And converting that to an ISO string
so that we basically have a string that reflects
the current timestamp, which is not perfectly unique
but unique enough for now.
And then we can set our other data properties.
Like the name, which we set equal to
the name we're getting here.
So that's the property name in this object.
This here on the right side of the colon,
is referring to the name argument we're getting.
And I'm going to do the same here for phone and email.
And that I picked the same names for the arguments
as I did for the properties is a pure coincidence.
You don't have to do that of course.
But the property names should be the same ones
as in your dummy objects, because you're referring
to those properties here when you're setting values
for the props of the friend contact component.
Now we also need the isFavorite property here
and let's say that's false as a default.
Now we got the newFriendContact
and now we can reach out to this friends.
So to our friends data property, which we have
in our app config object here.
So reach out to this friends and push
the new friend contact here, this newly created object.
And with all of that in place if we save that, I should
be able to enter a new contact here.
Click Add contact and here he is.
Here's Max with the data I just entered, working like
the other components.
So that's now working, we're able to add our own contact
and we're doing that with help of a new component,
the NewFriend component.
Which also is using custom events.