Now as I mentioned before,
I also want to be able to delete friends.
And for that, let's say in the FriendContact.vue component,
I will add a third button, besides the other buttons,
which we already have.
Let's say below this list,
which we have in every friend contact item,
there I'll add a new button where I say Delete,
and I want to do what this name implies.
So of course, I wanna listen to a click
and then for example, trigger the deleteFriend method.
And in this method,
which we add in a FriendContact.vue file,
in this method, we now wanna do what?
Well, in the end,
we need to emit a custom event again,
because the friends array is managed in App.vue
and if we wanna delete a friend,
we need to delete it from this array,
because it's this array which we're rendering with v-for.
So instead of FriendContact, we basically just need to,
you could say forward the information
that the user clicked the delete button here.
So here, we again,
just call this emit, dollar sign emit, with any event name
of your choice, like delete.
Now, if that is all you're doing, of course,
you can also not use a separate method like this,
though you absolutely can do it, nothing wrong with it.
But you can also not do that and instead go to your template
and just call emit in here, like this
and here without this keyword, like always in the template.
This is just an alternative and it's up to you,
what you prefer, I'm doing both for toggleFavorite.
I am taking this extra method in which I call this.$`emit
and for delete, I'm now not doing this
and I'm instead directly calling emit in the template.
Nonetheless, you wanna add this to your emits array
to make it clear that this friend contact component
has a delete event which will be emitted at some point.
And now we can listen to this custom event
on this FriendContact component.
So in the place where we are using that component.
In this case, again, the App.vue file,
and in here, we can listen to the delete event with @delete
on this component, and then point at a method
that should handle this,
deleteContact sounds like a fitting method names to me.
So now in App.vue, I'll add this deleteContact method
and in here, I now want to remove that contact
from my array.
Now what's missing here?
Well, some identification criteria, right?
We need to know which contact should be deleted.
So just as before for toggling the Favoritestatus,
it would be good to get the idea of the friend
that should be deleted.
And therefore all the justice before,
we can go to FriendContact.vue,
and pass this as a second argument to emit,
and forward the id Prop, which we are getting here,
so refer to that here and pass it with delete.
So now in App.vue, here in deleteContact,
we now want to find the friend with that id
and delete him or her.
And an elegant way of doing that in JavaScript
when you have an array and you want to delete an array
based on some information you have about the item
that should be removed is you can overwrite the array
and assign a new value to this property
that stores the array.
So the friends property in this case,
and use the old array but called the filter method on it.
Filter is a method that's built into JavaScript,
which will return a new array based on the array
on which you're calling it.
And it will return the array on which you are calling it,
except for the elements you are filtering out.
For that filter wants a function,
which you provide as an argument,
and if that function returns true,
an element is kept around,
if that function returns false,
the element is deleted.
It's a function which will receive the element as an input,
automatically by JavaScript, so this will run
for every friend in friends and JavaScript
will feed in every friend step by step.
And we should return true if you wanna keep the item
or false otherwise and this arrow function syntax
is just a different way of writing a function in JavaScript,
by the way, and here, I can therefore now check
if the friend.id is not equal
to the friendId I'm getting here.
I'm checking for non-equality, because if it is equal,
I want to keep it.
So in checking for non equality,
I ensure that if the ids are equal, I return false,
because if they are equal, I want to remove that friend.
And I mentioned that items are dropped
if we return false here, so I wanna return false
if we find a matching id.
With that, we generate a brand new friends array,
which is the old array minus the friend with this Id
and then we store that back into our friends data property,
Vue will then detect this change in friends,
it will see that friends changed, it will rerender that list
and update the UI appropriately.
So if we now save that,
and I click on Delete here on Manuel,
you'll see Manuel is gone
and of course, we can also delete Julie.
If we reload the data as back,
because all of that is of course,
just happening in JavaScript and therefore in memory.
But later, we will also see how we can send
such data to a server and store it permanently
on a server site database.
But for the moment, this is a huge step forward,
because it shows us what we can do with components
and we got more practice with components now.