I prepared another project for you,
which you'll find attached.
NPM install and NPM run serve brings it to your screen.
And I did create this project for you
so that we, A, can again get a feeling
for how components work together
and B, also see a little problem you will often face
when you build bigger applications
and you need to pass data around.
But first of all, let's understand the project
I'm providing to you here.
So make sure you download and install it
and start up that development server.
And you should then see this on the screen.
Now here, I got a very basic dummy application.
We can select a topic if you wanna learn more
about the basics or components.
And we can switch between those topics.
And depending on what we choose,
the content up there updates.
Now that's definitely not too fancy,
but it is about the code,
not about what we see on the screen here.
And the code is quite interesting.
Here in App.vue, in my main app,
I'm rendering the active element component
and I'm rendering the knowledge base component.
So this component.
These two components here are getting used
in the App.vue file.
Of course, all components are registered in main JS.
So they are available to this entire Vue app.
Now here's how this app works.
Active element is quite straightforward.
I get a topic title and a text.
That data is then received as props.
And in App.vue, I'm providing these two props
to active element based on the activeTopic.
Now, what is activeTopic?
That is some component internal data.
So that's some data I'm managing in this app here
in this App.vue file, here in my data property.
There, I got an entire array of topics.
But below that, I got the activeTopic.
Initially, that's null.
But when this method is triggered
and we'll see when this method is triggered in a second,
then I set the activeTopic to one of these two topics
I got in this array.
Now, if activeTopic is null,
thanks to this check I have here,
we'll basically not pass anything relevant to topic title.
But if it's not null, if we do have an active topic,
then I provide the title and full text values
to active element.
Now, how is a topic set as an activeTopic?
As I said, that happens with the activate topic method here.
And in there, we receive a topicID
and use that ID to identify one of these two topics
in this topics array.
So when is the method getting triggered?
Well, that happens on the knowledge base component.
There, I have to select topic custom event
to which I'm listening.
And when that event fires, activateTopic is triggered.
Please also note that I'm feeding the entire topics array
as a value to the topics prop
on the knowledge base component as well.
So let's have a look at the knowledge base component then.
In there, I'm getting this one topics prop
and I'm declaring that I'm eventually going to emit
select-topic.
And here is where things get interesting
and where we can see a little problem.
I'm forwarding the topics to the knowledge grid,
which I'm using here.
And I'm basically also just forwarding select-topic.
I'm emitting it here in knowledge base, yes.
But when do I emit it?
Well, I emit it when knowledge-grid emits select-topic.
So basically knowledge base
just acts as a pass through component, you could say.
I pass my topics through to knowledge-grid
and I pass select-topic, this event
through to App.vue when it is emitted by knowledge grid.
So knowledge base doesn't really have its own logic.
Now still, it's not unrealistic
to have components like this,
maybe because we have certain markup in there
which you wanna contain in this component,
maybe because you have certain styling.
So having such pass through components
is absolutely not unrealistic
and definitely something you will encounter in Vue apps.
Now let's have a look at knowledge grid.
In knowledge grid, I'm using topics.
I'm also getting this as props and I'm using it there.
So this is no longer a pass through component.
There's needs and users topics.
But I also emit select-topic here,
and that is still being passed through basically.
Because ultimately it's the knowledge element.
It's this component here,
which emits select-topic when we click this button.
So that's where this custom event is generated,
the select-topic event.
And then both knowledge grid as well as knowledge base,
just forward that custom event to App.vue in the end.
So the event gets funneled through to components
and topics also gets funneled through at least one component
through the knowledge base onto knowledge grid.
So everything here works
and that's also not a bad way of writing code.
And it does hopefully again,
show you how props and events work
and how you can connect everything.
But we still are facing a problem here.
We have the problem
that we're having these unnecessary pass through steps.
I mean, it would be nice if knowledge base
wouldn't have to deal with props
and with emitting this event,
because neither of the two is used or generated
inside of this component.
We're just using both to connect it to knowledge grid.
And it turns out that Vue has a solution
for problems like this.