So how does Vue help us solve
such pass-through problems?
First of all, it's really important to understand
that this is not necessarily a problem, and not bad.
You can do it the way we're doing it here,
but to save writing that extra code,
you can also get rid of, let's say the props here,
let's start with topics.
You can't get rid of that here,
get rid of it here, on KnowledgeGrid.
And for the moment, just keep that emitted event,
and then pass the topics to KnowledgeGrid
in a different way.
Because we need to topic steer.
and we definitely, also need to manage them in App.vue.
Since App.vue, is the place where active element,
which needs to know about the topics, and KnowledgeBase,
and therefor, ultimately KnowledgeGrid are connected.
So how can we pass the topics to KnowledgeGrid,
which needs to topics,
if we don't want to pass them through KnowledgeBase?
Well, first of all, let's remove them here,
and let's explore another feature Vue offers us,
and that is, provide and inject,
a pattern you can use to provide data
in one place and inject it,
which means use it, in another place.
Now here in App.vue, we could, for example,
provide our topics here.
We do this by adding a provide option
to our conflict object, anywhere in the conflict object.
Here I'm adding it between data and methods.
And provide can hold an object then,
in which you, for example, provide your topics.
So here, I could then grab this topics array,
and provide it down there.
So now I'm providing this topics array.
Now this is step one.
Now we're providing this data,
and that uses an internal mechanism built into Vue,
but providing is only half of the story.
We also need to listen to that provided data.
We need to use that provided data somewhere,
and that in our case,
which take place in the KnowledgeGrid
because that is where we need the topics.
For that here,
rather than expecting to get topics as props,
we add another option, the inject option.
Which works together with provide.
Inject, basically works like props, you provide an array,
and now you reference all the provided data
you wanna use in this component.
So at the moment, there's just one piece of data
we are providing, and that would be topics.
We're providing that in App.vue, under the key topics here.
So we can use that key, and inject here in KnowledgeGrid.
And here's one important note,
you can only inject what has been provided
on a higher-up level.
Which basically means, in a parent component,
or an ancestor component of KnowledgeGrid.
So we can inject topics here,
because it is provided in App vue,
and App vue, ultimately is above KnowledgeGrid, right?
App vue is a parent to KnowledgeBase,
and KnowledgeBase is a parent KnowledgeGrid,
and therefore KnowledgeGrid also is below App.vue.
If we, for example, provided something in ActiveElement,
we could not inject it in KnowledgeGrid.
Why?
Because ActiveElement is a neighbor of Knowledgebase,
and KnowledgeBase den contains KnowledgeGrid,
and therefore, ultimately, ActiveElement is a neighbor
to KnowledgeGrid.
And this will not work, provide, and inject
needs this, parent-child relation.
So you can't provide and inject between neighbors,
but here it will work because we are providing an App.vue,
and that is an ancestor of KnowledgeGrid,
So it is above KnowledgeGrid.
And there for, now if you save this,
you will see that everything still works as before,
but now data is ending up differently in KnowledgeGrid.
And we're avoiding this passing-through of topics
in KnowledgeBase, which is definitely an improvement here.
However, there is a problem,
we're now basically, creating this array twice.
We have it here, in App.vue in our data,
and we then have it again, in the provide object.
This works in this case, but it is code duplication.
And if we had any logic in this app to change
this data stored array,
this change would not be reflected in the provided data,
because that's a brand new array.
It's a brand new object in memory there for.
So if we ever changed his original array here in data,
such changes would not be passed on to components
that rely on the provided topics.
Therefore, it would be nicer if we could provide
our data here, so that eventually changes are picked up.
And it turns out, we can do that for that,
for that we need to change the way we use provide though.
Instead of setting it equal to an object
with the provided data,
we now convert provide to a method,
so now to provide option holds a function in the end.
And in there we return our provided object,
so it now basically, works a little bit like data.
And then here, we can still set up any keys of our choice
so I will stick to topics here,
but now we can use the this keyword to reach out
to our instant specific data.
So with these topics,
I now reach out to topics which we manage in our data.
And I'm using this, to provide it under a topics key
to any potential child components.
Of course, this key you're using here,
doesn't have to be the same one you're using in data.
It is in this case, but it doesn't have to be.
If I now save is, it still works,
but now we are working on one and the same object in memory.
Now let's simulate that topics changes here in our data
to verify whether this is really works.
For this, I'm going to add the mounted lifecycle hook here,
and in there, I'll set a timer to let's say three seconds.
And after those three seconds, in this array function,
which is just a different way
of defining a function JavaScript.
I will reach out to this topics and push a new topic
to the array.
That topic will have an id of events let's say,
and then a title of events as well.
Description text of events are important in Vue,
and then a full text of events
allow you to trigger code on demand, something like that.
So I'm having the same structure here
as in all the topics we have initially,
but now that topic down there,
is only getting added three seconds after the Vue app
has been rendered to the screen.
Now let's save that, and let's see if our list here updates
after three seconds.
And it does, and we can use events
just like the other pieces of data we've got here.
So this proofs that provide inject works.
Now that is provide and inject a very helpful pattern
if you want to avoid pass-through components
and passing-through props unnecessarily.
The question now of courses,
whether it can also help us with custom events,
because we're also funneling our custom events
through a couple of components.