So can we use provide inject also for custom events?
The answer is yes,
but by implementing that a bit differently.
We don't have a similar mechanism for events,
But we can think about this event thing differently.
Ultimately, when a custom event is emitted,
we at some point connect a method
here in App dot Vue in this case, which should be triggered
upon this event.
Well, of course, we could also pass such a method
with props down to the component where it should be called.
So we could remove this SelectTopic custom event here
on knowledge base in App dot view.
And we could then go to Knowledge-Base
and therefore remove it here as well
and removed is emits option and the same in knowledgeGrid.
Remove this listener here on the KnowledgeElement
and remove this emits option.
And in knowledgeElement where we emit this
also not emitted here, but instead do something else.
Instead here, we could expect to get the function
that should be called when the button is pressed as props,
or in this case, as an injected value.
So we can add inject here, and then simply expect
any key of our choice any name we pick, for example,
SelectTopic,
but this name is up to you,
and then bind this here to the click.
So I expect that select topic,
the value which I get injected here is a function
in the end.
A function, which is then executed when this click occurs.
So I point at a function here
and I want to get this function as a value
for this Provide inject mechanism.
Now injecting it is not enough, we also need to provide it.
So we can go to App dot view.
And there we now need to provide that.
Now we got function that should be used
for activating a topic.
And that is our ActivateTopic method here.
So we can provide this SelectTopic key,
because that's the key I'm listening to
in KnowledgeElement. That's the key I'm injecting there,
so it's the key I want to provide
and the value for that is this activateTopic.
So I'm pointing at this method. I'm not executing it here.
I'm just pointing at it to let you know,
hey, that method here, ActivateTopic, that is the method
and therefore the function you should provide
as a value for SelectTopic.
And then when SelectTopic is injected
here in KnowledgeElement,
We can execute it in this component.
Now keep in mind that activatesTopic wants to know
which ID we selected. So therefore, in KnowledgeElement
where I'm pointing at selectTopic
as a to be executed function when this is clicked.
I should make sure that this ID,
which we're getting as a prop conveniently, is provided.
So I'm now calling it myself telling view
that this is how the function should be called eventually,
and that this ID should be provided to the function we get
on this selectTopic key.
And if we now save that and reload, this is our application,
and we can still pick and select the different topics.
So now this works without passing props,
through multiple components and without emitting
our custom event through multiple components.
It's simply a different approach.