Now that's it for the course,
this was a lot of content.
So definitely,
it's time for some Congratulations,
you did an amazing job.
You pulled through this entire course.
And you therefore learned a ton about view.
This course obviously has a lot of content
because it's well,
the complete guide on view
and not that I do cover some parts only guide.
But that was a lot of content to digest
and therefore the obvious question is,
how should you continue?
How can you make sure that you don't lose the knowledge
you gained in this course?
Maybe you lost some concepts already.
And that wouldn't be horrible by the way,
that would be totally normal.
Well, here are some next steps I recommend.
The most important step as boring as it is,
is that you practice, practice and well guess what?
Practice.
Also revisit course lectures and modules,
So that concepts which you have forgotten by now,
are refreshed.
And then use all of that to do the assignments
you find in this course,
to rebuild the course project
without looking at the solution first,
but instead on your own,
and then maybe go through the solution again with me,
so that you can see how you build it,
where that differs compared to my approach,
and why maybe something might not be working.
Maybe something is also better than the way I built it.
But also explored the official docs.
This course covers all the core concepts view
has to offer in great depth.
But of course, this does not mean that
it's the only resource on view out there.
The official docs are really well written,
and a great resource to dig deeper
or quickly look up a certain concept.
But last but not least you can only grow as a developer,
if you build stuff.
You need to build demo and dummy projects,
maybe build clones of popular websites,
build your own simplified Facebook site,
at least the front end of it,
and dive into challenging problems.
And then don't give up.
But look for solutions with Google with Stack Overflow,
Maybe with the community you find linked
at the beginning of this course,
there are plenty of resources for that.
And all of that will allow you to grow as a view developer.
You can also dig into some average view courses
like my next course,
which uses a technology that builds up on view to build
view applications where some code is actually rendered
on the server and not just in the browser.
All these things can be great next steps.
And with the very solid foundation you gained
in this course,
you have everything you need to take these steps.
I wish you all the best for this,
and I really want to thank you for being part of the course,
and for allowing me to be part of your journey
in this course.