Up to this point in this course,
we always build projects locally.
We tested them locally on an address
like localhost8080.
We had our local development server running
in our projects to test the code we wrote
to see our application in action,
and that of course is totally normal.
You're in development.
You do develop locally on your machine,
but of course ultimately your goal is not
to have your Vue application locally on your computer,
but you want to deploy it.
You want to bring it onto other servers
and share it with other users.
And therefore this module will be about deploying
and optimizing Vue apps so that we can get
from development to production.
And you will learn what exactly deployment means
and which files you need to upload where
to share your Vue app.
We will have a look at optimization techniques
or deployment steps you could say,
and we'll see all of that in action and a concrete example.