Now, what does deploying
a view app actually mean?
For this, it's important to keep in mind
that Vue apps run in the browser.
I mean, any website is loaded with a browser,
but Vue apps are driven by browser-side JavaScript code.
All the code we're writing here,
in the end, is transformed by this project setup,
and then converted into JavaScript code
which our browser understands.
So what we see on the screen here
was loaded from a server,
but it was rendered on the screen by Vue,
by this JavaScript code we wrote
and that happened entirely in the browser,
not on some server.
A server was just serving this HTML file,
this HTML skeleton,
and then the JavaScript code, which again,
lost and executed in the browser,
not on the server.
And I'm emphasizing this because this influences
how we deploy a web application, a website.
Here, we really just have a couple of files
which are all interpreted by the browser.
We got our HTML files, in this case just one HTML file
since we're building a single page application.
We got CSS files possibly,
here in the projects we worked on,
we didn't have separate CSS files.
We merged that with the components and therefore
the project setup will take care about extracting this
and adding it to the page.
We have no separate CSS files.
And most importantly,
we have a bunch of JavaScript code.
Here for example, we have our project setup
and that project setup will have certain scripts
for transforming the code we wrote,
to code the browser understands.
And I'll show you these scripts throughout this module.
But therefore, we just have HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
We have no code that would run on a server.
And therefore, we have a static web app, a static website.
Which means, it's just a website with code that
is evaluated by the browser
and has no server-side code.
And hence, a static website hosting provider is all we need.
And options here would be AWS Free,
Firebase Hosting, Netlify.
There are tons of static hosting providers.
You can just Google for a static hosting provider
and you'll find a couple of examples.
So that's what we need.
And I will show you an example
and the full deployment process,
step-by-step throughout this module.