Now as a first step
before we upload anything anywhere,
we wanna finalize our code, we wanna polish our code
and make sure it's optimized.
That of course means that we wanna test it,
we wanna test different scenarios
and find possible errors in the code and fix them.
We also might wanna consider refactoring our code
so that we don't repeat ourselves too often,
or that we solve a certain problem with less code,
because the less code you have,
the less code the users of your website have to download
before they see something on the screen,
so less code means faster websites.
And there's one specific optimization technique
which I wanna take a closer look at,
and that would be asynchronous components,
which are supported by Vue.
Now, what is that, what are asynchronous components?
I'm taking this course project,
which we built earlier in this course,
and you'll find that code snapshot attached
in case you don't have that at hand.
Here, we have a bunch of components, a couple of components
which we load as pages through the Vue router,
and a bunch of code in general.
Now we can definitely test this
and we can definitely refactor some code,
but that's not what I wanna focus on here.
Instead of wanna focus on that async component approach.
What do I mean with that?
Well, there are certain components
which we don't need every time this application is loaded.
A good example could be that dialogue,
which we see here during login.
When we log in, we need it, but in the rest of this app,
we don't use it too often,
so we might not always need the dialogue component.
And the implication of that is that
we don't necessarily need to download the source code
behind that component all the time,
because as I mentioned, if users visiting this webpage
have to download less code,
that means the website can be used earlier,
you don't have to wait for as much code to download.
So the dialogue could be a component
which we can load lazily, asynchronously,
only when we need it and not in advance,
because right now, all those components,
all pages and all other components are downloaded
all the time, no matter if a user needs them or not,
and that means we have everything
available when we need it, that's great,
but it also means we download a lot of code in advance,
which we don't need yet, or which we might never need.
And a similar example could be found for many routes here,
the register as coach route, for example, for this user,
since I already am a coach, I can't even visit it,
so I definitely don't need to code for that.
And that is something where Vue can help us,
and let's start with that base dialogue,
which we don't need all the time.
In main.js, we register this base dialogue.
We import base dialogue from this file
and we then register it.
Whenever you have an import statement like this,
this in the end tells Vue that the code
in that file you're importing is needed,
and you can imagine that all these imports are in the end,
when you build your project, when you finalize your project,
all these imported files are basically merged
into one big file, kind of, that's how you can imagine this.
So therefore it would be great if we wouldn't import this,
if we would only import it when we need it,
then it would not be merged into this big file,
but instead Vue would try to download
the required code only when it's needed.
And for that, Vue has a function we can use,
the defineAsyncComponent function.
With that, we can define a component
which is loaded asynchronously, only when it's needed.
Here, we could then create a constant named base dialogue
so that I don't have to change the name down there,
and the value I store in there is the result
of calling defineAsyncComponent.
defineAsyncComponent wants a function,
and here I'm using an arrow function.
It wants a function that in the end
then returns the imported component,
but Vue will only call that function
when the component is really needed.
So here I can use the shorthand notation
of arrow functions and call import,
which also exists as a function like this in JavaScript.
So it's not the import statement we have here,
instead now I call import as a function.
And when we call import as a function,
that will only do that import
when the surrounding code executes,
which in this case, it's this function
we pass to defineAsyncComponent.
Well, and this function is executed by Vue
only when that component is used, when it's needed.
And with that, we ensure that the code
of the entire base dialogue component
is only imported when needed.
Now for that, we still need to provide a path
to that component here to import though,
but now with this dynamic import,
we don't import it in advance, but only when it's required.
And now we can still assign base dialogue
as a component here for base dialogue,
and Vue will know how to handle that
when it needs to bring a dialogue to the screen.
So if we save that and reload,
if I log out and log in like this,
we still see the dialogue, so that still works,
but actually code is only downloaded when it's needed,
and I can prove this to you, log out again,
and go to login and reload there,
we can open up the dev tools,
ignore the warnings here and go to network.
And now I have to reload again,
you see a couple of files
that were downloaded from our development server,
and one file you see here is this 0.js file,
maybe it's named differently for you,
but you should see an extra JavaScript file
next to app.js which is your main app,
and maybe this chunk-vendors.js file.
Now, if I log in, you won't see any changes in here,
but if I now go to register as coach,
if I now clear this network log and reload,
you still see 0.js, but you see it only once.
If I now clear this again and go back to all coaches
you see now here, that's where
this file is actually downloaded, and 0.js in the end
holds the transformed code for this dialogue.
Hard to tell if you look at this code here,
but that is what you'll find in there.
You see some hints at it here, like this name.
So what I wanna show you now
is that Vue now checks the template
of the components you're currently working with,
and if none of those templates uses the dialogue,
it doesn't download the dialogue,
and the coach registration component
doesn't use the dialogue, neither does the coach form
or any other child component there.
That's why here, if you're on this part of the app,
Vue won't download the dialogue.
On the other hand, for the all coaches page,
it does download it because here on coaches list,
we do use the base dialogue,
and that's a pretty neat feature.
Now regarding that warning which I'm getting here,
this might just be a bug by Vue at the moment
because everything seems to work correctly and we are
definitely using defineAsyncComponent correctly.
Now we cannot just use defineAsyncComponent
for global components like this, though,
we can also use it for local components,
and, and that's pretty interesting, for routes,
because here, we probably got
the biggest code splitting potential.
If we never visit a certain route,
fetching all the code for that route component
and all the child components there is really redundant.
So therefore, here, we can also
use this defineAsyncComponent function,
so we can import from Vue
this defineAsyncComponent function here inside of router.js.
And then we can replace the routes
which are maybe never visited
with asynchronously loaded components.
For example, CoachDetail,
maybe a user never clicks that detail button,
so then we can also set CoachDetail
equal to defineAsyncComponent, passing a function to it,
calling import there, and then pointing at this path.
And then we can comment out this static import
here at the top, and just work with the dynamic one.
We can do the same for, let's say, the coach registration.
And that should be CoachRegistration as I see.
We can also grab this here, call the defineAsyncComponent,
and import this dynamically so that if the user
never visits the coach registration page,
we don't bother loading the code for it,
so we can comment this out as well.
And we can do this for all those components
or for most components it makes sense I would say.
For ContactCoach, for example,
maybe a user never sends a contact message,
well, then we don't need to load to code
for that component and its child components,
so that's another component
we can turn into an async component.
And why don't we do the same for RequestsReceived?
Maybe this page is never visited,
so therefore here, we can also load this lazily,
asynchronously, and not all the time,
so let's comment this out as well.
And the same for auth,
if a user is authenticated and reloads the page,
we don't need to load the auth page again,
we won't need it, so we can copy that,
and also load this lazily with AsyncComponents,
and comment this out as well.
And you might find more places where this makes sense,
but I will go with these components.
And now also change the coach registration name,
which I mistyped earlier.
And with this, if you save this,
what you will notice is if you open the network tab,
you see a bunch of chunks are downloaded here,
you can ignore these chunks up here,
you see only 0.js appears twice,
and that's then the only extra code chunk
which is really downloaded.
So only 0.js appears twice, but for example,
if I click on requests, we see 1.js was downloaded,
so looks like this was the code
for the requests received page.
If I go to register as coach,
we see another code file was downloaded,
so now really the files are only downloaded as we need them,
and that of course is very useful, because with that,
we can download a slimmer initial bundle and then only
download the extra component code as we need it.
And that's the idea behind async component,
and that's therefore a key optimization step
you should be aware of, especially when it comes to routing.