So let's deploy our dist folder content,
and they mentioned that there are many options
for hosting static web apps.
AWS is free, Netlify, Firebase hosting.
I will go with Firebase since we've been using that
in earlier parts of the course already.
So you probably have a Firebase project by now,
and hence hosting will be easy to set up.
You can simply click on hosting and your project,
and you could also create a new project for hosting.
It's doesn't have to be the same one
as you have for your Firebase database, just as a side note.
But here, I will use the same one
and I will click on hosting,
and you'll find instructions here, but in the end,
hosting is really simple.
If you click on, get started, we see that we first of all,
need to install an extra tool, okay?
So let's do that.
Let's run this command on Linux and Mac iOS,
you might need to add pseudo in front of it,
on Windows You don't need to do that.
To run this command, and this will then install
extra tool provided by Firebase globally on your machine,
and we'll need that tool to then upload our project later.
So let's wait for this installation to finish.
And once it is finished, we can go to that next step.
Now we need to log in by running Firebase login.
So let's run this and this should open up a tab
in the browser and allow you to log in,
if you're not logged in already,
or it prompts you for password and your username,
your email address,
and you have to log in with those credentials,
which you used for logging in into your Firebase account
before as well.
Once that is done, you need to run Firebase in it.
So copy that command, and now in your project folder,
in your entire project folder, here,
you can run Firebase in it.
And this will ask you a couple of questions.
It asks you which part of Firebase you wanna manage
with this command line interface, where using at the moment.
And we really only want to use hosting here.
So select hosting with the arrow keys,
and press space to market, and then enter.
Now, then you're prompted wherever you wanna host this
into an existing Firebase project or create a new one.
As I said, you could create a new one,
but I will use an existing one.
And then it should list all the projects you have.
And I'm simply picking that project
with which I worked early already.
Now we have the interesting part.
It asks us what our public directory should be.
And that's important because that's the directory
which holds the files that will actually be uploaded.
So here that would be the dist folder.
So we should enter dist here.
Once you entered dist, hit enter,
and you're asked whether this should be configured
as a single page app and rewrite all URLs to /index.html.
Now that can be confusing, why does this matter?
What's this about?
For a single page applications,
you have to be careful when it comes to routing
and hosting your app on a server.
When a user visits your webpage,
let's say it's hosted on a domain like "mypage.com,"
a so-called request is sent to the server.
Now let's say that request is not to your main domain,
but it's "mypage.com/products" or anything like that.
Now, as I just said, that request hits the server.
The server where your static web application,
your Vue single page application is hosted at.
Now, this server should actually ignore the path
that's part of the request,
because if it does not ignore it,
then the server will try to find something on the server
that matches this request.
For example, it looks for a product folder
in your hosted files and tries to find an HTML file
in such a products folder.
And for our app that would fail
because for our app, the folder structure we deploy is this.
We have just one HTML file.
In our app, for example, we have a /coach's route,
but we have no coaches folder here inside of this,
which is the content that will end up on a server though.
That's why we need to tell the server to ignore the path
and instead, always return the index.html file,
which then in turn contains the JavaScript code
off our application where then the Vue router can take over
and handle this path on the client side, so in the browser.
And that's really important, the Vue router
does not run on the server.
And therefore, it can only handle the path
which is in a URL, if the server ignores it.
That development server was already configured
to work like this,
which is why we didn't have to worry about that before.
But the web servers, real web servers,
typically do not ignore it by default.
And that's my Firebase is asking us here,
if we wanna configure this as a single page app.
If we choose yes here, which we should,
then Firebase will ignore all requests on the server
and as mentioned here, rewrite all URLs to index.html.
So that always index.html is served.
So let's choose yes here.
And now it's tells us that we already have a index.html file
in this, if it should override this
and here we wanna enter, no, because we wanna keep our file.
And now with that we initialized everything.
Now to really get deployed this,
there's just one change I wanna make.
In the public folder in index.html,
we can edit the index.html file before the project is built.
So any changes you want to make to your project,
to your HTML code, and here, for example,
should be made here, not in this.
You should never touch the code,
which is generated in a dist folder.
Instead, edit your input files and rebuilt the project,
if you wanna have a different output here.
And here, for example, I wanna edit the title.
It's actually using a placeholder here, in the end,
pulling in the title from somewhere else,
but we can delete this and overwrite this with Find a Coach,
for example, which is my title.
And now we could also add a meta tag
with a name of description
to then also add a description for search engines.
Like find a coach and grow as a developer.
And now with these final tweaks made,
I will run npn run build again so that these changes
are picked up and reflected in the dist folder,
which is now recreated.
And now we configured Firebase,
we have to final dist folder,
now we want to push the code onto Firebase.
And that's done if we follow the Firebase instructions
by now running Firebase deploy.
So now we do that, run Firebase deploy,
and this will now take our code and uploaded onto Firebase.
Now it shows us a progress here,
let's wait for this to finish.
And once it's, it also gives us the URL
where we can visit this app.
So I'm going to copy that open it here,
well, and here is the application which we built before
now running on their real web server.
Now I'd will be offline when you're viewing this,
but you can try it on your own with your own project.
And for anything else you wanna configure
like a custom domain or anything like that,
check out the Firebase console there
once you deploy your app under hosting,
you can see your app, you can add a custom domain
and you can do a bunch of different things here
to fine tune this to your requirements.
And that's it for deployment.
These are the steps and core concepts
you should keep in mind when you wanna deploy
Vue apps to a real server.