Now with all the course modules
you completed up to this point, you learned a lot about Vue.
And of course, you already practiced a lot with Vue too.
We already had a couple of projects,
and we had tons of demos, assignments and challenges.
Now however, it's time for our main course project,
the Coach Finder application.
Now, here is the web app we are going to build
throughout this module.
It's an application where we got a bunch of coaches here,
we can filter those coaches, to for example
find a coach that is able to teach us backend development,
we can then contact this coach,
leave our email address, and share a message.
Now this message has been sent to the coach
and under requests, we can view all the incoming requests,
all the incoming messages.
We can then use the email address to reply back.
Now this application,
has basically all we learned throughout this course.
It uses routing and animations as you can tell.
It also uses Vuex to manage data
and it uses a bunch of components as you can see here.
It uses all kinds of ways of communicating
between components, Vuex and props and route parameters,
and you will see how all these things work together
step by step and in great detail.
This is a big Vue application,
which we are going to build together from the ground up
where all the things we learned will come together.
Routing, Vuex, Components, HTTP, everything.
It'll all be in that project and therefore
with this project you will get a complete demo
and a lot of practice
when it comes to building an entire app from the ground up.
You can definitely also take this as a challenge
and try this on your own first,
but we will build this app from the ground up,
including the planning phase together
step by step throughout this module.
We'll add routing and Vuex and a lot of other features
and with this module,
you will not just get another app and more practice,
but you will also see a lot of common conventions
and practices and you will learn how to solve problems.
So with that, let's dive right in.