Now I'll start with the data here.
So I'll plan my data first,
but this is just one approach.
I'll then move on to the sign
of the components as a next step,
what do we need here?
Well, obviously we got these two main features,
we got the Coaches
and we got the Requests
so the messages basically.
I hope you can read my writing here,
I'll soon start to draw and this will not be better.
So yeah, that's why I'm also talking
hopefully we're all on the same page at the end.
So we've got Coaches and Requests,
these are our two main pieces of data.
Now we will probably need
a list of Coaches.
So we want that
and we probably also need a list of Requests, right?
Because multiple Requests can be sent
also multiple Requests to the same Coach.
Now every Request item of course,
should point at Coaches.
So a Request
will definitely be an important data piece
and a Request will definitely hold some Coach ID
because a Request needs to be connected
to the Coach to which it was sent.
Now in addition our Request
will need a message,
like the text that sent to the Coach,
and so that the Coach is able to respond
let's say a Request should contain an email address.
So these are the three pieces of data
I want to have in a Request.
And we'll have a list of such Requests
also as part of the application.
Now back to the Coaches,
what is a Coach?
Well obviously, Coaches are important.
A Coach will have an ID,
a Coach also will have a name.
Let's say we have a first name
and we have a last name here.
Now we can have more data
I want to have a,
description
where the coach simply is able
to describe him or herself
and I want to have a rate
so the hourly rate we would charge for a coaching.
Now that looks like a good set of data for me
and with that,
we should have the core data entities
to core data models we'll need in this app.
Coaches and Requests and Requests through to
Coach ID are connected to Coaches.
Now that's just a rough data model.
You can definitely do this in a more professional way,
you can use what you maybe learned in university.
This is just a general plan
and that's how I like to start my projects.
I now have a general idea of the data I'll need,
and this will help me lay out VueX later.
For example, we'll probably have two VueX modules,
We'll have a module for our Coaches
and we'll have a module for Requests.
Now of course data where planning data and planning VueX
is not just about planning the data we want to store,
it's also about planning our Getters,
our actions, our mutations.
So regarding the Getters,
it will be straightforward.
We want a Getter to fetch all Coaches
and a Getter to fetch all Requests.
Now what about the mutations though?
What about those?
Well for a Coach,
we definitely need a mutation to
register as a Coach
and we need a mutation to set Coaches,
which might not be obvious,
but when the app starts,
I want to load Coaches from a database,
from a web server.
So from a backend and from Firebase in this case,
and once the data is loaded,
once the list of Coaches is loaded from the database,
I want to set it in my local VueX store.
So these will be the two mutations I need for Coaches.
Now for requests, I need a contact
Coach mutation,
which basically sets or adds a new Request.
And I also need a set
Requests mutation here
so that I can set my Requests
once I loaded them from a backend,
because just like Coaches,
Requests will be sent to a database,
will be stored in there
and I want to be able to load them from there
and then set them through a mutation.
So when it comes to actions,
we basically have actions for loading Coaches
and loading Requests,
and we'll have actions for adding a new Coach
and for adding a new Request.
And this is about it regarding the data of this application.
Now let's move on to the layout, the components,
and also their routes where we are going to work with.