So now that we've got a plan
it's of course time to implement it
and to write the code we need.
And here I would like to get started by setting up
the routes sent to pages we need for this application.
I then wanna continue building all the core components
we need for now and then I wanna slowly step by step,
add in the data and to functionality we need.
So therefore, first of all,
I'll install two extra packages in a new project,
which you again, by the way, find attached,
you find this basic project set up,
which has just Vue and nothing else attached
to this lecture
but in this project set up all now npm install
with dash dash save,
I'll npm install, view dash router,
and view X, these two packages,
because we're going to use both through out this module.
Notice we'll download and install these two packages
into this project and once this is done,
we can use both
but as I said, I'll start with routing.
Now for this here, next to main js,
I'll add a router js file because I wanna store
all my routes and my routing logic in there
to keep main JS lean,
and therefore, as so often, or first of all,
import create a router from Vue-router here
in the router js file,
and then create a router by calling createRouter.
And then we will export this router
so that we can use it in our files,
namely in the main js file as well.
Now you'll learn how to configure the router,
you simply pass an object to create router
and here we then add our routes.
Now you might remember that besides the routes,
we also need to set his history property here
and there we import another function from view router
and that's to create web history function
and we call this function here
and the value provided by calling that function is then set
as a value for this history property here.
With that, we can add our routes array here
for the routes property
and in their setup all the routes we want.
And here we made a plan, right?
We thought about a couple of routes
which we will need.
So I'm going to add those routes here.
And this was a slash coaches route
which should load our coaches component later.
We don't have that component yet
so for the moment I'll set this to null,
but later we will point at the coach has component here,
besides that we also want that coaches slash ID route
where the dynamic coach ID part of the path,
and then we load the details page for different coaches.
So that was another route we wanted here.
We also wanted another path here to register as a coach.
So to sign up as a coach,
that is something we'll need.
And we'll need a route where we can also contact a coach.
And now that could be slash contact.
But, I would say actually,
we want to contact a specific coach identified by ID.
So maybe that's something
where we can use a nested route even
so we could add children here to coaches slash ID
and in there register a nested route
where we have contact after a coaches slash ID
so that would be loaded with slash coaches
then some coach ID slash contact.
That's how this route and this component
should be loaded later
so that we reached a contact page
with a form for a very specific coach.
So therefore we won't have contact down there,
but we will definitely need a requests route here
where we can view all the requests we might've received
so all the messages sent through that contact form.
And that's almost it there's just one more route
which I'll add here and that is a catch all route
and not found route for when the user adds
or enters something invalid as a path,
then I wanna show a not found page.
And you might remember from the routing section
how that worked.
You need a dynamic segment here in the end
with any text of your choice,
but then important this bracket syntax at the end,
where you in the end have a regular expression
just saying that no matter what was entered here,
you wanna handle it with this route.
And actually now that I think about it
there's one more route which we'll need
since we have no slash route here,
we just have slash coaches slash register
we're not doing anything
if the user reaches just slash nothing,
which will be the case though,
if just our domain is entered and therefore
if just our domain slash nothing is entered
I want to redirect to slash coaches here.
So that's the route set up
I wanna work with for this module for this project,
now we need to build those pages, those components
that should be loaded for the different routes.
Now, as for everything else in this module,
definitely also try such things on your own,
maybe don't continue with the next video right away
instead try building these page components
for these different pages and wire them up to the routes.
You can try building the entire project
as a challenge as well, it's up to you,
how much you wanna progress together with me,
and how much you wanna try on your own.
Starting in the next lecture,
I will add those page components though.