So let's work on the pages.
Here in the source folder,
I'll add a new pages folder,
which will hold the components
that are loaded as pages through routing.
It's not a must-do to use a pages folder for that
but I like to set those components apart
from the other components,
which are not loaded as pages.
That's just personal preference though.
And in there, I'll actually add two subfolders.
A coaches subfolder and a requests subfolder
because these are the two main features we have in this app
and will have different pages for these different features.
And in the pages folder itself,
I'll also add a file, the NotFound.vue component,
which will be our Not Found page.
In the coaches subfolder,
we can then add all the coach pages
and that would be the page for all the coaches
for a specific coach
and for registering as a coach.
And for requests,
the pages will be the contact page here
and the open requests page.
So let's start with the coaches pages.
Here, I wanna have a CoachesList.vue component.
CoachDetail.vue component.
And a CoachRegistration.vue component.
In requests, that would be ContactCoach.vue
and RequestsReceieved.vue.
Now, obviously, how you name these files,
how you name these components is 100% up to you.
You don't have to use the same naming I do here,
it's just my personal preference.
Not something you have to use.
Now, all these components are created.
Obviously though, they're all empty.
Nonetheless, we can wire them up to the router file already
and then fill them with live step by step.
So for that here in router.js,
I'm going to import all those page components,
like the CoachDetail component
from ./pages/coaches/CoachDetail.vue
and well, all the other files as well.
CoachesList from pages/coaches/CoachesList.vue.
And CoachRegistration
from the pages/coaches/CoachRegistration.vue file.
Import ContactCoach from pages/coaches,
not coaches, sorry, requests/ContactCoach.vue.
And import RequestsReceived
from ./pages/requests/RequestsReceived.vue.
And last but not least, import NotFound
from pages/NotFound.vue.
Okay, these are all the components.
So now we can wire them up to the routes.
For the /coaches route,
we wanna load the CoachesList component.
For coaches/:id, that would be the CoachDetail component.
For contacting a coach,
that would be the ContactCoach component.
For registering, that would be
the CoachRegistration component.
For requests, so for the requests we received,
that would be the RequestsReceived component.
And here it's the NotFound component.
So now with that, we registered all components.
Now we can fill them with life.
Before we do that though,
we need one other important component.
The app component, the main component
that holds all the other components in the end.
So therefore, next to main.js,
I'll add a App.vue file
and this will be, of course, the main entry point
of our application so to say.
Here, I wanna render my router-view.
So in the template here,
I want to output router-view
so that we tell the view router
where to render these different components we registered
and it's the App file I wanna import here in main.js.
So import App from App.vue
to load the App here as our main App.
In addition, we of course, also need
to make this app aware of the router,
so besides importing App.vue here,
I'll also import router from ./router.js
and store the App here
in a constant
and on that app, we can then use router
so that we really use the router in this app.
And now we're done with the routing
and we're all set to continue.
So with all that out of the way,
now it's time to fill it all with life.
And it's totally up to you
what filling this with life means.
We'll definitely need a couple of different things here
but in the end,
I would say that when we visit just our domain,
we redirect to /coaches,
so that is probably the first page we're going to see
if we use this page, this application in a normal way.
So maybe we should start with CoachesList,
at least with a very basic first version of it.