So CoachesList.vue it is
that's the first page I wanna start with.
And this will become a quite complex page in the end
because you might remember that on there
I don't just wanted to output a list of coaches,
I also wanted to add some filtering logic so that
we can filter the list of coaches which is displayed.
And outputting a list of coaches also means that we need
coaches to begin with
and at the moment we're not managing any data at all.
But we can get started with the base template at least.
And here to get started with this base template,
I of course add a template here to CoachesList.vue,
but now in there, what do we need?
We will have a section or a div, whatever you want,
where we later we'll have to filter.
And below that we'll have another part of this page,
another section, another div,
where we will have our list of coaches.
These will be the two main areas.
Now I will create two separate sub components for that
so that our coaches list components stays relatively lean.
But at least we now got a basic template, a dummy template,
which should allow us to see something on the screen
when this page is visited.
So if you run our development server with npm run serve,
let's see if we can at least see this on the screen
when we visit our application.
And indeed, if I load this page, I'm redirected to /coaches
and I see filter and list of coaches.
Now the styling obviously is off,
I mean the entire content is missing
but I can already tell that this is also
not the font I wanna use.
So I wanna set up some global styling,
some base styling in App vue,
which will apply to the entire app.
And this is therefore not scoped styling but just a style
so that it is applied globally.
And I prepared to the styling for you
because I don't wanna write the styles together with you
as this is not a CSS course
and I know from other courses
that it's boring to some people if you write too much CSS
hence I'll provide all the CSS code for you.
Of course, you can also tweak it to your own needs.
You can adjust it to look the way you want it to look,
whatever you want.
So attached, you find this app CSS file
and in there you find the styles which you should copy
into these style text of your App vue file.
An import to Google fonts, where I load a font
and then well, I set up some basic stylings,
set up that base font, remove the margin on the body
and with this applied, we now have this font in effect.
So now that works, that looks well,
not the way I want it to look
but it has the space styling at least.
Now, how should we continue though?
I mean, this page is pretty much worthless
if we don't have any coaches that could be output here.
So therefore I see two possible routes we can take.
We can either now start adding the Vuex
and start adding data,
or we first of all finish up the entire base layout
and navigation, we add a header to this application
so that we can reach all pages
and we have some dummy code on all pages
and we then add to data and I'll go with that second route.
I'll first of all wire up the navigation and the base layout
before I then come back to the data.
So to add some basic layout and some basic navigation,
I will go to the source folder
and add a components folder next to pages.
And in there, I'll add let's say a layout folder
and in that layout folder, we can add TheHeader.Vue file,
which should hold the base header
with the navigation we want in this application.
This, TheHeader component will be used in the App vue file
above the router view.
So here we can add a script already in App vue
and import TheHeader from components/layoutTheHeader.Vue
and register this as a local component here in App vue.
A local component because we only use it here.
And then here we can render TheHeader above the router view.
Now here, back in TheHeader.vue,
the question is what do we want in here in the template?
Well, I want TheHeader HTML element,
which should hold my navigation
and as part of the navigation, I'll have the main title
of this page so to say, where I wanna say something like
Find a Coach.
And next to that, also an unordered list
where we have our different navigation items
and that of course should be a router links.
And actually even that text here in the h1 element
should be a router link because it should be clickable
and should always lead us back to the starting page.
So here I want to go to /nothing
which will then redirect to coaches,
but this will basically always go back
to the root entry page of this app.
Here, I also wanna go to /coaches let's say,
which of course is basically the same
as clicking on this title, but here I wanna say All Coaches.
So this will be one of the navigation items we have.
And the other item we'll have, we'll go to /requests
to show us the requests we received
so the messages that were sent by users to us
if we are registered as a coach.
If we are not, we won't see any requests here.
So this is the basic set up here for TheHeader let's say.
I don't need any script here at the moment
because there's nothing dynamic in here,
nothing that would need a Vue script code.
But of course, I want to have some styling here
and I want to have some scoped CSS code in here.
And again, you find that attached,
you find TheHeader CSS file attached,
which contains a bunch of styles I prepared for you,
which you can just copy between those style tacks
so that we all use the same styling.
I'm basically just giving TheHeader
a certain width and a certain color
and then it's all just about styling the links
and the active links, that's important,
the active router link
by using that router link active clause,
which you learned would be applied to the link
that's responsible for the current page.
And then I also have some other styles
for laying things out correctly.
With that we got TheHeader and if we now reload,
this is what we should see.
You see All Coaches is active
and we could also go to Requests
where we don't see anything on the screen,
but switching to page works.
So that's TheHeader off this application now.
And with that, we made a good step forward
because now we've got a first basic way
of navigating around.
Now let's also work on the other pages
and add some meat to them.