So let's add some dummy content to the other pages
and I'll continue with requests received,
because we can easily reach that page by clicking
on requests in the header.
And well we got no requests yet
so for the moment, I'll just output requests here,
just so that we see that loading this works.
So therefore we now see requests here.
Now the other pages are a bit hard to reach at the moment,
we got no links to get to the contact page
or to get to the registration page,
but we can at least add some of those links already
I guess.
For example in the coaches list,
yes, we don't have any coaches yet,
but outputting the list of coaches
will actually just be a part of this component here.
Let's say we will have an unordered list down here later,
but above that unordered list
I want to have a div,
so a different container here in the end,
which will give us CSS class of controls,
which should have two buttons let's say,
one button that allows us to refresh the list of coaches,
later we'll have coaches stored on a database in the web
and this button should then fetch the latest
snapshot of that data.
But besides that refresh button,
which we need,
we'll also have a button here
which should allow us to register as a coach.
And therefore actually this should not be a button,
but a router link.
So here I wanna have a router link, register as coach,
which goes to /register
because that was our registration route here.
So this is our link I want here on the coaches page.
This one.
And therefore we can now also add some dummy code here
to the coach registration.
For now I'll just say register here,
but soon we'll add a form on this page,
which allows us to fill in all the details
we need to provide to register as a coach.
So now if I click this, we should see register at least.
Now we also have this contact page,
which we later can reach by clicking on the contact button
of a specific coach.
At the moment we have no specific coach,
which is also a problem for the coach detail page,
which we can't reach for that reason.
But of course we can manually reach it
by filling in coaches/
and then some fictional coach ID here.
And if we do that, we would theoretically
reach the coach details page.
So we can therefore add a dummy template
to coach detail as well,
details for coach.
And if we save that, we should see this on the screen
if we reach this path here in the URL.
And with that, of course, we can then also
add a router link here, in that,
or on that, coach detail page,
where we say contact, where I wanna go to, /coaches,
then the ID, which later will be dynamic,
but for now I'll hard-code it, /contact,
because you might remember that the contact page
was this nested child route here,
which we reached with coaches, some ID, /contact,
and therefore that's just what I'm using here.
And if I save that,
we now have that link on the coach detail page.
And if we click that we reach contact here.
But what we also notice is that we reach it
but nothing changes on the page.
Well keep in mind that this is a child route.
Contact is a child route of that detail route here.
And the consequence of that
is that it will not be loaded to replace the route
that was on the screen previously,
but that instead it needs a new router view.
It needs a separate router view,
which has to be inside of the parent component
of the child route.
So in this case, in the coach detail component.
We need to add a router view there.
So here we can add a router view
and that's where then the child routes of coach detail
will be loaded, in this case, the only child route we have,
which is this contact route.
So with that if we now also add some dummy content
to contact coach,
contact a coach or anything like that,
you see that this now shows up here if we are on /contact.
If we are on just /c1 it's not there,
if you click contact it is there.
And with that we can reach all the routes
and we can see some dummy content on those pages.
But of course we're not just there for dummy content only.
So therefore why don't we as a next step,
add Vuex so that we at least have a list of dummy coaches,
which we can display and start working with
before we then later add the functionality
to add our own coach data.