So as mentioned, I wanna get started adding some data.
And we're going to use Vuex for managing that data,
because it will not just be static data,
which never changes,
but obviously we'll be able to add coaches.
After all we will be able to register as one.
And we'll also be able to send requests ends on.
And that's why we already installed Vuex.
Hence I'll add a store folder
next to my pages and components folders.
And then that store folder,
I'll add a index js file,
where we set up the store in general.
But I also wanna work with modules here,
because we have two main features, coaches and requests,
and I'll make each feature and the state and actions
that belong to this feature, a module.
Hence, I'll add a modules folder in there.
And now it's up to you how you wanna split that code.
One file for the entire module or multiple files per module.
And I'm really just to show you different approaches,
I'll go with multiple files per module.
So I'll add another sub folder here,
coaches and a second sub folder next to coaches,
which is requests.
And now we're going to start with some coach data.
So here I'll add a index js file inside of coaches.
This is the file where we will merge all the coach related
mutations actions, getters ends on together.
And then we'll have a mutations js file,
a actions js file, a getters JS file.
And we then split our logic across those files.
This may be overkill. This is not something you have to do.
But again, my idea with this course
is that I also show you different ways of doing something.
So therefore now here in index js,
inside of the coaches module,
I'll export an object which will hold
all the coach related state and so on.
And therefore here will have some state,
but will also have mutations,
which I import from the mutations file.
So import mutations from ./mutations js
and assign mutations to mutations here.
And since key name is similar to value name here,
we can use this JavaScript shorthand
I showed you a couple of times already
where we merged just like that.
Simply to write less code.
And I'll do the same now with actions,
which I import from actions js
and import getters
from ./getters js like this,
and also add those to this module object.
So then we have actions and getters in there as well.
And now we export this module
to merge it into our main store,
which we have yet to create.
So in the index js file in the store folder.
So this file here, I'll now import
create store from Vuex
and then simply create a store by calling create store
and I'll export this store
so that we can later use it in main js.
Now this store takes a conflict object, as you learned,
and here we can add the modules option
to then import the coaches module
from ./modules/coaches/index js in there.
Because it's this nested index js file
where we set up this entire module
and combined the mutations action, scatters
and state of that module.
Hence it's that file
where we combine it all which we import.
And then modules takes an object
and I'll give this a key coaches
and point at my coaches module here.
And that key will be important
because I want to use name spacing.
So in the index js file in the coaches folder,
here I'll add name spaced,
true to use this name spacing feature
I taught you in the Vuex section.
Now all those files were importing from mutations,
action, getters, they're all empty.
So here we should also export objects.
They can be empty right now
because we don't have any mutations
or actions or getters yet,
but you should export at least an empty object in every file
so that the imports here work,
and we at least have empty objects in our module here.
Okay, so that is the first step.
Now in the state here, in index js, in the coaches module,
I want to return my state object.
And in here the state should be that we of course have
a list of coaches.
And we're going to start with some dummy data here.
Now you'll find that dummy data
attached in the coaches js file,
which you can open with a text editor.
And in there, you'll just find an array full of coaches,
which will be my value for this coaches key
in our coaches state.
And here I prepared two dummy coaches for you
with some dummy IDs and data.
So did we have something on the screen right from the start.
Now, did we have a state?
I of course all the want a getter to get that state,
because as I mentioned in the Vuex module,
whilst you can directly access the state
from inside your components,
it is recommended that you always use getters and stat,
and we are using getters here.
So in the getters js file for the coaches,
I went to add a getter and that will be to coaches getter.
Let's say where we received a state we always do in getters
and where we then return state coaches.
So nothing too fancy,
no transformation or anything like that,
but at least a getter in place now.
I will also add a second getter already though.
And that's the hasCoaches getter.
Because later in this coaches list component,
I only wanna render this list if we have coaches.
If we have no coaches at all,
which will be the case once we switched to real data
away from the dummy data
and we haven't added any coaches yet,
if we don't have any coaches at all,
I don't wanna show that list
because it would be an empty list anyways.
So then instead I wanna show a message
like no coaches found.
So therefore I'll add a helper getter
where I simply check whether we have coaches or not,
and where I then return true or false.
So I wanna return to result of checking
if state coaches is truthy
and
state coaches length is greater than zero.
This returns true if we have coaches,
at least one coach.
And it returns false otherwise.
And now with the getters in place, the state in place,
we can go back to main js and import our store here
to make sure we use it in this app.
So import from the store folder index js file,
and then
app use our store.
Now that Vuex store is part of this Vue app.
And with this, I'm getting an error, state is not defined.
I assume in my getters here, yes.
In has coaches I'm using state.
Of course, I should also accept this argument therefore.
But now with this, we're all set regarding that.
And we can now go to coaches list
and pull in our dummy data, our coaches.
So for that, we should add a script here.
And to reach out to our coaches getter,
and we do this with a computer property.
So we add to computed option here.
And there, I will now add a computed property,
which I name filtered coaches.
We are not filtering right now,
but we soon will be once we also added
this filter functionality.
So I will already name the computed property as such.
But for the moment here,
I just want to return this store dollar assigned store
getters, and then get the coaches
from this coaches getter.
Now, how do we get access to that coaches getter?
It's not getters.coaches because keep in mind,
this module is name spaced.
So therefore we have to reach this getter
that belongs to this module through its namespace.
And the namespace name is defined in index js here,
this key, which we set up here for this module.
So we get access to our coaches here through getters
and then square brackets, coaches/coaches.
The first coaches here is the namespace name.
The second coaches after the slash is the getter name.
This now gives us our coaches here under filtered coaches.
And now we can utilize them
to output our real list of coaches.
So here we can now render list items.
And with the four, we can go through to coaches
and filtered coaches,
bind the key to coach.id because every coach stored
in our store here has an ID.
And then of course,
I'll put whatever we wanna, I'll put for the second,
just to see whether this works.
I'll just interpolate coach.firstName here.
We will of course,
I'll put this in a different way very soon.
If we now go to all coaches and reload,
we should see two coach names here.
And that proves stat Vuex is wired up correctly
and that we're able to access our coach data.
And that of course is a great first step.
Now we can also use that other getter we set up,
hasCoaches, to make sure we only rendered this list
if we have coaches.
So here on this unordered list,
I'll add a v-if check
and check if we have coaches
and I'll add a h3 tag below that let's see
with v-else on it, which is the fallback.
Whereas say, no coaches found in case we,
well, guess what have no coaches.
Now adding this year however
now implies that we need to have
a hasCoaches data property, or computed property
in this component, which we don't have yet.
So here in the computed of this component,
I'll add hasCoaches
because just having a getter off that name in Vuex,
of course doesn't do much.
It's not a way level
as a computed property in every component then.
That's not how this works.
So we have to add a separate computed property here
in coaches list.
And now here we can return
this store getters.
And then again, access coaches,
which is the namespace/hasCoaches,
which is the getter name.
Now with that, let's test this
and temporarily remove the coaches
here from our coaches array in the module.
And we should see no coaches found now.
And if I bring back those coaches here in the module
and save this, we see the coach data again.
So now that's working.
Now that dummy data is wired up,
and with that we can go back to working on our components,
and also improving the styling here.