So let's now work on the components
we need here.
And I'm going to start with the coach items here.
For that I wanna use a separate component,
because we'll have quite a lot of markup and styling
related to this part, related to this list items,
and I don't wanna put that all into coach's list,
even though that of course would work.
I mean, technically you can build
an entire Vue app with just one component,
but the idea behind components is to split your code
into smaller reusable pieces.
Therefore, in components,
I'll add a new sub-folder, coaches,
where all the coach-related components should go in.
For example, the CoachItem.vue file.
Now, in this CoachItem.vue file,
I want to define my template, which is a list item,
or which holds a list item.
And in there, I now wanna output all that coach data.
For example, in a h3 tag, the name of the coach.
Here, I will interpolate the full name.
And this doesn't exist yet,
but we'll add the logic to make sure
we will have such a full name property at the end.
Then below that, a h4 tag,
and I recommend that you use the same tags
so that the styling which I provide works for you as well.
Technically, of course, you can use
any tags you want and any structure you want,
but here in the h4 tag, I wanna output dollar,
then the rate which we get for this coach,
/hour to show the rate this coach charges.
Then I will actually add a div here,
where I wanna output the areas of expertise of that coach.
Because the dummy data I gave you
already has this areas property,
which holds an array with some clearly defined keys,
frontend, backend, and career,
which are the areas of expertise
I wanna support in this app,
where a coach can be an expert.
I'm an expert in all these areas, of course.
Julie, for example, is an expert in career and frontend.
And I wanna output that here in CoachItem in that div.
Here, I wanna go through these areas
and render a batch for every area,
so to show which areas of expertise this coach has.
For the moment, I'll simply add a span here,
and add v-for on that to go through the area in areas,
so to go through all the areas of expertise of a coach,
add the key, which is the area itself,
because it's unique anyways,
a coach can't be an expert in the same area twice.
And I then simply want to,
for the moment, output my area like this.
This will also become a separate component in the future,
but for the moment I'll leave it like this.
And then below that I'll have a div with a class of actions
where I wanna render two buttons in the end,
or two links, we could say.
One to contact the coach, and to, therefore,
go to this contact route,
and one to view the details of a coach
and go to this detail route.
So therefore here I'll add a router link,
like this, and on the first router link,
we're going to go to /coaches/ and then the coach ID.
So that should be dynamic.
For the moment I'll hard-code it though.
/contact and say Contact here.
And the second link will then show us the details,
so I will say View Details here,
and there, I wanna go to just /coaches/ that coach ID.
Again, I'll soon make this dynamic,
because, of course, the ID shouldn't be hard-coded here.
That's the general markup.
Now, for the styling,
we're going to use some scoped CSS style,
and attached you'll find the Coach Item CSS file,
which contains those prepared styles,
which you can simply paste between your style tags.
And with that added, we can add a script here,
and now make sure that this coach item works.
The plan is to use this coach item in a coach list.
So we will receive all the data we need
through props in the end,
because we're going to render the coach item here.
Here we have all the coach data,
so we can then pass the coach data,
which we need in coach item, through props.
And we would do it like this
because the data for a specific coach,
especially in such a list,
is of course not managed with Vuex.
This is not application wide state or anything like that.
It's really just internal local state
in this loop here, in this v-for loop.
And therefore that is a clear case for props.
Hence here we'll get some props,
and I want the ID of the coach,
we need that to construct this link.
I want the first name and the last name,
I want to have the rate and the areas of expertise.
And then we can add a couple of computed properties here
to make our life easier.
For example, for the full name,
which of course is a combination of first and last name,
for that, I'll add a full name computed property here
and return this.firstName + a blank + this.lastName,
but also maybe for those links,
which shouldn't be hard-coded.
Here we could add a coachContactLink
computed property, where we return
/coaches/ and then the ID.
So this ID refers to this ID prop
which we're getting, plus /contact.
This will then construct a path
like /coaches/c1/contact, for example,
and another computed property, the coachDetailsLink,
where I wanna return /coaches/ then again the ID,
but then slash nothing, because here we just want
to go to something like this.
Now we can also replace /coaches here,
if we want to, it's not necessary,
but to make this component a bit more flexible
in case we should ever change this /coaches path
to a different one, we can use this.$route.path
+ '/' to use whatever the current path is
as a starting point to then build a longer path.
This is totally optional,
but it ensures that if we ever change our path
from /coaches to something else in our route config,
we don't have to adjust everything
in this specific component.
So that's why I'm doing this here.
And now it's the coachContactLink,
which I wanna bind to to here.
So I wanna bind to with a colon to coachContactLink
and bind to here with a colon to coachDetailsLink.
And with that, we should have
a reusable coach item component.
Now back in the coaches list component here,
I will replace this list item
with my coach item component, which we just created.
But, of course, for that, we first of all need
to register this component, so that Vue knows it.
And of course it will be a local component in coaches list
because we only use it there.
So I will import CoachItem from going up one level,
going up another level, because we're in the coaches folder
in the pages folder.
And then diving into the components folder,
going to coaches, going to CoachItem.vue,
and here in this Vue components config object here,
we add components and add our CoachItem component here.
And with that, we can use it like this in the template.
And here, of course, we now want to loop with v-for.
So coach in filteredCoaches,
bind the key to coach.id,
but now all the paths, all the other props
which we need here.
So for example the ID, bind it to coach.id again,
then pass in the first name.
So first-name and bind that to coach.firstName,
we format that to make it a bit easier to read,
bind the last name, by the way,
I'm using this Kebab case here
as I explained it earlier in the course,
and bind this to coach.lastName.
And then bind the rate to coach.rate,
sorry, hourlyRate, because on our coach data,
if we have a look at that in the state,
it's the hourly rate property, which holds the rate.
So hourly rate is what we have to access here
in coaches list.
And bind the areas to coach.areas.
And if we do that and save it,
we should see these coaches.
This is clearly not super beautiful,
but it is a start.
Now, to make this a bit nicer,
in coaches list, I'll also add some scoped styling
and attached you'll find a CoachesList.CSS file,
where you find two styles,
which you should copy into that style tag.
With that, at least the bullet points are gone.
But it's taking up the entire width here
and it's going from edge to edge,
even if I zoom out a bit.
And I would rather want that card look here.
I want to have these items in a box
with a light drop shadow.
Yeah, I want to have this typical card look,
which we also saw earlier in the course already.
And I want that card look
in other parts of this app as well.
For example, the filter should later also be
in such a card, and other parts on other pages as well.
Therefore, as a next step,
I'll build this card-based component,
which we can then use in different parts of the app.
And whilst we're at it,
we'll also build a button-based component,
because we have a lot of buttons,
and also links that should look like buttons,
like Contact and View Details.
And therefore, this is something that makes sense as well.