So it's base component time.
In the components folder, I'll add a new ui folder.
You could also name it base,
but I'll go with ui
because I have some core UI elements in there.
And I'll add a BaseCard.vue file in there,
and also already a BaseButton.
And also, didn't mention before,
but we'll need it as well, also a BaseBadge,
which will basically render a badge.
For example, the areas of expertise here,
there I wanna use that.
But let's start with the BaseCard.
That will be a very simple component, in the end.
The template is just a div,
and then a slot inside of the div,
because I want to use this card as a wrapper
around any content you want.
Now, I'll give this a class of card,
and then add some scoped CSS code.
And attached, you find a base card CSS file
which holds the styles you should paste in here.
This will give us this classic card look
and also restrict the width we're taking.
And that's already it for the card.
Now we can use that card by registering it
in main.js as a global component,
because I'm using it in many different areas of the app,
hence, I wanna use it as a global component.
So in main.js I'll import BaseCard
from ./components/uiBaseCard.vue,
and then here use my app to call the component method
and register a base-card component,
which points at this BaseCard component we're importing.
And now we can use it in CoachesList, for example,
to wrap everything in this section,
so this controls div and the unordered list.
So here I'll use base-card, my opening tag,
and then close it after this h3 tag here.
And with that, if we save this,
this looks much nicer already.
But now we got all these buttons.
And, actually, these here, of course,
are links and not buttons,
but I would argue they should look like buttons
because, whilst they technically are links,
well, in this UI,
having them look like a button makes more sense.
And, of course, we also got a button here, for example,
which should look like a button.
So I wanna build a BaseButton component
which supports both real buttons and links.
And we can build something like this
and apply the same styling
no matter whether it's a link or a button.
And we're going to do this in the BaseButton component here.
Here, we need a template.
And in that template, of course, we also have a button,
the regular HTML button, which takes a slot.
But it will not just have the button,
we also wanna support links.
So I will actually also add router-link here as a component,
which takes a slot.
But, of course, only one of the two should be rendered
at the same time.
So, therefore, I will add a script
and accept some props.
And here I'll actually use the object form
of the finding the props,
simply to also practice this again.
Most of the time, I used just the array form
because it's shorter,
but using that object form, of course,
allows you to be more explicit about your props.
So which props do I need here?
I want to have a link prop.
The link prop should signal to us
whether we wanna render a button,
or if link is true,
if we want to render a link.
So, therefore, here I will set the type here to Boolean
because I expect to get a Boolean here.
Set it to not required. It's optional.
You don't have to specify it.
And set the default value to false.
So, by default, we don't render a link but a button.
And we can use the link prop now here
to use or to render the button if not link,
hence the exclamation mark,
and render the link, the router link, in the else case
if link should be true.
This allows us to switch from outside the component
between a button and a router link.
I also want a to prop here,
which I need if a link is set.
This will get a string value.
And here I want to set this to not required,
but set the default value to /, nothing.
The to prop is a useful prop if we do render a router link
because in that case, of course,
I wanna bind to on the router link to my own to prop
which I just defined
so that we know where this link should go to.
And then there's one last prop which I wanna support,
and that's the mode prop.
This is a prop that allows us to control the styling,
the look of this button from outside.
Here, I simply want to get a string,
and this is also not required.
The default, then, is just an empty string
or null, let's say,
and I will use mode as a class on the button.
That, of course, would theoretically allow us
to pass anything as a class that will be added,
but I will only support a couple of specific classes
in the CSS code which we're soon going to add.
So now we add class mode on both the button
and the router link.
And now it's time for styling.
So let's add some scoped CSS styling down there,
and attached you find a button CSS file
with all the button styles in there.
And here I set up a base styling,
and I'm always targeting button and anchor tag
because the router link will render an anchor tag
in the end.
And then here the hover and active styles
and also the flat and outline styles.
And these are the two modes which I support
because here I'm selecting the flat class
and the outline class,
so these styles will kick in
if a flat or outline class is added to the button or link.
And that's exactly what we do with mode.
If mode is set to flat,
the flat class will be added,
and therefore these flat styles will kick in.
And that's my base button.
This base button can now also be defined in main.js.
So we import BaseButton
from ./components/ui/BaseButton.vue,
and then also call app.component BaseButton here like that.
And now we can use the BaseButton
in various places of this app.
In CoachesList, for example, I have these two links here,
or one button and one link,
both should be a base button.
So here I'll use base-button for my Refresh button.
Currently, it's not doing anything,
but that will change soon.
And here we can replace router-link with base-button.
The to prop still exists
because we added that to our router link in the base-button.
But, here, since this should be a link,
I now also set the link prop.
And just adding it like this
automatically sets it to true already.
And therefore this should now look like a link
or should render a link.
On the other hand, for this refresh button,
I wanna use mode and set this to outline
to make sure that here I'm using a different look.
And in CoachItem, we also got buttons,
or links, in this case.
And these should look like buttons, though.
So, these two router links,
here I'll also use base-button
and replace router-link with base-button,
and then add the link prop on both.
And on the first base button,
I'll set the mode to outline as well to use that look here.
If we save this, this looks a lot nicer, I would say.
Now we get these buttons,
which still act as links,
but which look like buttons.
And with that made a huge step forward.
Now I want to render these areas of expertise
in a nicer way.
And for that, I prepared this BaseBadge component.
Here, we're going to add a template
and render a span, let's say
where in the span we simply output a title
or a text property, whatever you want.
On the span, I'll add a class of badge,
but then, in addition, bind class dynamically to type.
Now that of course means that here
we should also accept some props.
And I'll be lazy again here,
I expect to get a type prop here
and, let's say, a title prop.
We have text here,
but that will be a computed property soon.
And now we can add computed here
because actually my text computed property here,
that should actually be the title prop toUpperCase.
It's just a transformation I want here.
Of course, it's nothing you have to add,
but I wanna make sure that the title we receive as a prop
is turned to all uppercase
and then output like this here.
And now we can add some styling here,
some scoped CSS styling,
and as so often you find those styles attached
in the badge CSS file.
And I got a basic badge style here
where I just give some base colors,
some padding, display inline-block.
And then I got three specific class styles here
for frontend, backend, and career
where, essentially, the background color is changing.
And these classes will be added
by adding the type prop
because here we bind the class to type.
So if we set the type to frontend
on the badge when we later use it,
the frontend CSS class will be added,
and therefore these styles will be rendered.
And now we just need to register this
as a global component again.
So here in main.js, I'll import BaseBadge
from ./components/ui/BaseBadge.vue,
and then add component base-badge, BaseBadge, like this.
And with that added in CoachItem,
we can use this BaseBadge component now.
So, there, instead of rendering a span like this,
I want to loop through my base-badge,
so replace span with that.
And we no longer pass something between the tags,
because this component has no slot.
Instead, we should set a type here
and bind this dynamically to area
because the areas I have in my data
are frontend, backend, and career,
and these are exactly the CSS classes supported here.
Therefore, by the way, we could argue
whether that really is a base component.
It's very specific to the coaches areas, of course.
But we do have some base styling as well.
That's why I keep it as a base component,
But that's just a side note.
But, now back to CoachItem,
besides setting the type,
we should also bind the title.
And that's also bound to area.
So it's the same value bound to different props here.
We could theoretically use one prop,
but since these props are used differently
inside of the component,
I want to make it clear where we use these props
by picking different prop names.
So with that, if we now save this,
we got these nice badges
and therefore this already looks
much, much nicer, I would say.
Why don't we make sure that as a next step,
we can also go to the Details page
and view the concrete details for a selected coach.