So onwards to the coach detail page,
it's time to replace the dummy content we got here
with some real content.
For that I'm going to get rid of all the continent here
and write this from scratch again.
In this component, I want to have a section,
where I first of all, let's say using that base card,
I would put the name and the rate of the coach.
So here we could have the h2 tag,
where we output the full name.
And below that age h3 tag, where we output it to rate.
So dollar sign then interpolate to rate
and then make it clear that it's an hourly rate
by adding /hour.
The next section of data which I wanna have
on this page here is let's say the contact button.
So here again using the base card,
I will add a number h2 tag actually, like this
where I wanna say interested, reach out now.
And below that render a base button, which of course
will technically be a link, so we should add the link prop
going to the contact page for this specific coach.
Now of course this coach will have a dynamic ID,
We can view this page for different coaches.
So I will bind to two contact link,
which is a computed property just like full name
which we will add soon.
And on this button, I'll just say contact.
Actually, I'll put this into a header tag here,
the h2 tag and the button.
And below that now at the router view,
where later does nested child route
to contact forum will be rendered.
And now below that section with the contact forum
at the contact button below that section.
I'll add a number of section where I use a base card
in which I want to show the badges.
So the areas of expertise using the base badge component
and below that the description for that coach.
So here a paragraph where output description.
Tt's not something we rendered before in any component
it should of course be included in the details.
And on the badge we use v-for to go through the area
in areas, bind to key to area, bind the type two area
and bind the title two area.
So basically as we did it before.
Now for the script section here,
of course we get props here and actually I don't get
all these values here as props,
but I just get an ID as a prop.
Now, why do I get an ID as a prop here?
keep in mind, how does component will be loaded.
It will be loaded through routing.
The coach detailed component is loaded here
on this path.
Therefore, theoretically, it wouldn't get any props at all.
The router loads it and the router by default
passes no props.
But you learned in the routing module
that by adding props true to the route config,
you can ensure that this dynamic value.
So the concrete value for the URL, which is then visited,
is passed in as a prop of that name into that component.
So here I named this ID and therefore,
when adding props true here, the view router will pass
the value ID holds in the end as a prop to coach detail.
And that's why I wanted, or I expected as a prop here.
And we can then later use that data, that ID to fetch
the relevant coach data from our Vuex store.
For that, I'll add a data option here where I add
a selected coach field, which initially is null.
But which soon will not be null
because when this component is created
using the created lifecycle hook,
I want to reach out to Vuex
and fetched a concrete coach data for this ID,
and then set selected coach equal to that.
So in created, I'll set this selected coach equal
to this dollar sign store getters,
and then go to coaches, so to the coaches namespace
/coaches getting all coaches.
But of course here I don't need all coaches
instead I'll call find and find once a function
where I go through all the coaches
and compare the ID of every coach to this ID.
So to the ID where you received as a prop
which is part of our URL
and if that returns true, that's the coach
which we ultimately return
and which we store in selected coach.
And that's how we find a coach in our coaches list.
Now, theoretically, this could of course fail
If the user enters this with a URL
that contains the ID of a coach we don't know.
But this is only possible if a user directly enters
this URL not through the links on our page.
And therefore if the user does that,
I'm fine with a broken experience
because that is actually not even a way
of using that app which I want to support.
So therefore fine for me to fetch
the selected coach like this, store it in data here
and then add some computer properties to make sure we have
things like the full name or the contact link here.
So here let's add full name where I return
this selected coach, first name,
plus a blank , plus this selected coach, last name
and add a contact link, computed property
where I return this dollar sign route path
plus slash plus this ID plus a slash contact.
Now, keep in mind we're all to referring to rate
and to areas here in our template and to description.
And currently these data properties don't exist,
we just got the selected coach.
So this should actually be SelectedCoach.areas,
or actually better use computed properties.
So here then add the areas, computed property,
for example, where I return this selectedcoach.areas
and add the rate computed property,
where I return this selectedcoach.hourlyrate.
And return the description computed property,
where I return this selectedcoach.description .
with that, if we now go to the details here,
we see the details for this coach.
So that is working and we see our different data
on the screen now.
So that's that details page ,
of course you can tweak the styling to whatever you want
but I'm happy with this.
Now it's up to us with what we want to continue
the register page, the contact page,
maybe the filter components to make sure we can filter.
I would say that's a good next step.
So I will continue with adding that filtering logic next.