So let's continue with that filter component
on CoachesList at the moment, I'm just saying filter here,
and of course, we'll need a bit more than that.
Now all the markup at the logic related to the filtering
or to the filtering form, I would say,
should go into a separate component,
again to keep CoachesList relatively small.
And therefore in source, components, coaches,
I'll add a second component next to coach item.
And that's the CoachFilter.vue file.
In there, I wanna set up all the markup and base logic
that we need to let the user choose
between different filtering options.
Now, I will use the base-card component in here as well,
so that we have that base container style here.
And then in there, maybe say an H2 tag, Find Your Coach.
And then below that, render a couple of checkboxes.
Now, he I wanna present three filtering options.
Because in our store, we have free areas of expertise.
In this entire app,
I support these three areas of expertise,
frontend, backend, career.
So these are the free filtering options
that should be presented here.
Therefore, I will actually use, let's say,
a span as a wrapper,
add a class of filter-option to it,
this will become important for styling later.
And in that span, have an input of type checkbox
with an ID of frontend, let's say
and which is checked initially,
because here I'll make sure that all filter options
or all inputs are checked initially,
and then the user can uncheck them and check them as needed.
So that's the input here.
I also will add a label of course to make it clear
what this input refers to.
And here at the for attribute, to make sure that we point
at this input with this label so that clicking the label
also checks this input and then add a text of frontend.
And we can now repeat this twice,
because we also need our backend checkbox here,
so let's add this.
And we need the career checkbox,
so that's also something we should add.
Okay, so that's nice.
Now we got these three checkboxes.
Now we need some logic to react to the user clicking
on one of these checkboxes.
So therefore, I will add my script block down there
and add a data property
because in this CoachFilter component,
there is some internal data that we need to manage.
I want to manage which filters the user chose
or which options to user chose.
So here is this returned data object,
I'll add a filters key which holds another object
where I want to have a frontend filter
which initially is true,
a backend filter which initially is true,
and a career filter, which is true.
And that basically means as long as something is true
coaches that have that area of expertise should be shown.
And then I'll add a method to change that data.
The let's say setFilter method.
This method should be bound to these inputs,
that when they are clicked
or changed to be precise, setFilter runs.
For that we can listen to the change event here on input
which is triggered whenever the value changes
from checked to unchecked or the other way around,
and that's when setFilter should be triggered.
And therefore that of course gets added on all these inputs.
Now setFilter therefore received default event object,
since we bind it to a default dom event.
And we can now extract two important pieces
of information from that event.
The first one is the ID of the input
that was checked or that was changed.
We get this by accessing event.target.id.
So that gives us access to these IDs
which we added to these inputs.
And then the second piece of information is, isActive,
is that currently checked?
For data we can access.event.target.checked
to find out whether data input
for which this event was triggered, is now checked or not.
And then I can derive my updatedFilters object here,
where I copy the existing filters,
so does existing filters the option here?
With the spread operator, I copy it into this new object.
So I copy all these properties into this new object,
but then we override one of these three properties.
We do this by dynamically setting the property name,
which we wanna override and set it to our inputId,
so to this constant.
This whole frontend, backend or career,
and these are the input IDs we have here.
So with that, we accessed one of these keys,
and set a new value for this dynamically set property.
And the value is, isActive, which is true or false.
And then we can set this filters,
so our data option to the updatedFilters.
With that we should be able to manage
the filters internally here.
But of course, that's not all.
I also want to let the component that uses
the CoachFilter component, know about my filters.
That's why I wanna emit, $emit a custom event here
to communicate back to the parent component.
And that's the change-filter event,
let's say where I pass my updatedFilters,
so where I provide the information about the updatedFilters
to the component that's listening.
And now it's of course,
a good practice to also add the emits option here,
and therefore make it clear that this component
emits a change-filter event.
Now we can add some styling,
so that's add some scoped styling.
And as always attached you find the CoachFilter CSS file
with all those styles here,
which you can copy between your style tags.
With that we can now use CoachFilter
in the coachesList component.
So let's go to CoachesList and there first of all,
import CoachFilter from going up, going up, components,
coaches, CoachFilter.vue, and added here
to the components option,
and then added here instead of filter.
Here, I wanna add coach-filter
like that, no, not like this, but like that.
Of course here, I now want to listen
to that change-filter event which is emitted eventually
and call a setFilters method,
which we now have to add here.
So going down in this component, I'll add a methods key.
And in there add a setFilters method
where I get my updatedFilters as an argument,
because that is the kind of data we're emitting
in the CoachFilter component, right?
We pass the updatedFilters as an argument here
when we emit the event.
And therefore in the place where we listen to the event,
we received this as a parameter.
And here I now want to manage a new piece of data
or any data at all.
So let's add the data option in CoachesList.
And here in that object,
I want to have an activeFilters data property,
which also has frontend true, backend true, and career true.
But this should now be overwritten
whenever new filters are emitted.
So here in setFilters, I'll set this active filters equal
to the updatedFilters.
And now with all of dead we can go back
to the filteredCoaches computed property.
And now not always return all coaches,
but coaches that match our filters.
So here I get my coaches which is stored in a constant,
but I will return coaches.filter,
calling the built in filter method
which you can call on arrays in JavaScript,
where we now execute a function on every item in coaches
and receive to coach as an input automatically
as a parameter.
And now in here, I wanna have a couple of if checks,
and check if this.activeFilters.frontend is true,
which means I wanna show coaches
that have the frontend area of expertise.
So therefore I know that I want to show coaches
with the frontend area.
But now I can check if this coach in his or her areas
has this frontend key.
We can do this with coach.areas.includes
which is a number built in method in JavaScript.
And to that I pass frontend.
And here I then return true if that is matched,
because that means that we want to see coaches
that have the frontend area of expertise
and this coach has it.
So we return true to keep that coach
in our returned coaches array.
And now we can duplicate this twice to do
the same I'm here for backend.
And of course, here for career.
And ultimately, if none of these if checks match,
we return false here inside of that filter method
or inside of this filter function,
which means this coach, which doesn't have the fields
we're filtering for is excluded.
And that should be it.
With that saved, we now have this filter component here.
And now for example, Julie doesn't have backend.
So if I uncheck career and frontend, only Max's left,
if I'm checked backend, we got no coaches at all.
If I check front end, we see both coaches
because both coaches have that.
And that's the filter working.
So now with the filters added,
let's work on the contact and the register as coach forms.
And let may be start with registering as a coach.
This page just pretty white right now
and of course here, I wanna have a nice form
where we can fill in all the details to sign up as a coach.