So for that, let's go to coach registration,
and replace this dummy text with a proper template.
Here, I want to have a section, let's say,
where I say an h2 tag, register as a coach now,
and below that, I wanna have the entire form for signing up.
Eventually, this component will grow a little bit,
later once we add HTTP requests.
Therefore I will outsource this form into
a separate component right away.
Add the coachform.vue file here in components coaches,
and then we'll have the actual form in there.
So here in the template,
I want to have a form element of course,
because we'll well, have a form in here.
This form needs a couple of controls,
because every coach has a first and last name,
areas of expertise, a description,
and an hourly rate.
We need these input fields in our form.
Hence here, I'll get started by adding
a div with a class of form-control,
which is important for styling later.
Where I now add a label saying first name,
and below that input field with a type of text
and let's say an ID of first name therefore this label,
it gets the for attribute and points
at this element with this ID.
Then I'm going to duplicate this
because we also of course need a last name.
So here is last name on the second input,
and then we also need an input for the description.
Duplicate it again for the description here,
pointing at description, but now here
it's not an input, but let's say a text area element.
So that we have a multi-line input.
I'll give that an idea of description
and let's say five rows.
Then again, I'm going to copy the default input here
and set up the hourly rate input field,
so here the ID is rate,
and the type here can be number, or should be number
to make sure that well, we allow the user
to enter a number here in a pleasant way.
Now as a last step, users should be able
to choose their area of expertise.
Now that means that I wanna have free checkboxes
where users can check the expertise they have.
So front and back and then career,
and you can select as many as you know,
or as many as you feel comfortable teaching others.
So therefore again, I'll add a div here,
with a class of form control, this doesn't change.
But inside of here, I now first of all want
to have a h3 tag where I say,
areas of expertise to let the user know
what these checkboxes will be about,
then I'll have more divs in there.
Every div then holds an input of type checkbox,
and this first one, will have an ideal front-end
and a value of front-end,
the value will be important later
for retrieving the checkboxes.
After the input, also a label for front-end in this case,
where I'll say front-end development,
letting the user know what this checkbox means.
Now we replicate this twice,
to also have a checkbox for back-end
with a value of back-end for back-end,
and here saying back-end development.
Then on the last checkbox here,
I say career, with a value of Career,
for a career and saying career advisory maybe.
These are the different checkboxes here,
now with that, below all those divs,
I'll add a base-button,
which will be the submit button in the end,
where I simply say register.
Now that's the basic form.
We'll come back to that markup later,
we also need to add bindings
and I also wanna add validation later,
but that's a start.
With that form created now,
we can add our script area here, our script block,
and add some data here.
So here I return the data object
and in there, I of course want to manage a first name
and a last name field,
which we will bind with the model later,
add a description and a rate
which initially is null let's say,
areas which initially is an empty array and that is it.
Now we can bind these data properties
with two way binding.
So here, on the first input with the model,
I bind this to first name,
which is that first name data property we just added.
Then here on the second input,
I of course, bind it to last name,
here on the text area that is bound to description,
and here the rate that is bound to rate.
Now here I will use the number modifier
to force a conversion to number,
I showed you that this should happen automatically
if the type is number but to be super safe,
I'll force it here, and whilst we're at it,
I'll actually add trim on the other V model such as,
so that we always trim excess whitespace,
and with that only the checkboxes are left,
Here we can also use V model
as you learned earlier in the course,
here we can bind this to areas,
here we bind to the same property on all checkboxes,
of course, because they all belong together.
Now with that, I'll go down to the script part again
and add a method, a method that should be triggered
when the form is submitted.
Hence, I'll name it, submit form.
In here, we will later validate the form,
but for the moment, I'll just create
a form data object
where I group all those values together.
Here, I wanna have a first key,
which points at this first name,
a last key, which points to this last name,
a desk key, which points at this description.
You could use the same names of course here,
but I'll go with these names
I will also use these names later in the course.
So maybe you should stick to them to follow along smoothly.
bind the rate to this rate, and areas to this areas.
For the moment, I'll just console.log,
my form data here to see whether that worked.
Now it's submit form which is bound here,
to the submit event on the form element
where I used the prevent modifier
to prevent the default of an automatic request being sent
to a server that doesn't exist
which I don't want here and bind this
to submit form like that.
Now we can use the coach form here in coach registration,
so there in the script area,
we import coachform from going up and going up
to components, coaches, coachform.vue,
then adding this here to the components option like that.
Now we can simply add the coachform
as a HTML element, so to say here in coach registration.
If we load this, we see this form.
Now it's of course super ugly,
so there are two changes I wanna make.
First of all, in coach registration in this section,
use the base-card to wrap the h2 tag and the form,
and inside of coachform, I of course prepared
a couple of styles which we can use.
Here at the bottom, we add scoped styling as always,
then attach to find styles
which you should copy in here.
The coachform CSS file.
There are some styles which we're not even using yet,
like the invalid styles,
but we will need them later once we add form validation.
With that, if you save this,
this all looks much nicer,
now we got our registration form in place.
If I click Register,
I print an empty object here, and I get a warning,
which we can ignore here for the moment.
But I'm getting this object here,
in this object, we see of course,
that everything is empty
because we haven't entered anything.
So if I clear this now and do enter some values here,
like that, and register this.
Now we see our values here, in areas
which is wrapped by a proxy to be reactive,
we see front-end and career being checked,
we see the other data as well and therefore,
we are ready to pass that data on
to coach registration, and in there,
then use it to create a new coach
in our view x store, that's what we're going to do next.