So it's time to edit our state
and add more coaches.
We now got the form in place
so we got all we need
inside of that form.
Inside of the coach form component,
we now just need to expose the data that was entered,
so this form data here,
to the components that uses coach form
which is the coach registration component.
Theoretically we could also directly reach out
to the store from inside of coach form
because ultimately we can interact with Vuex stores
from any component.
But I like this component to be reusable and independent
and just work with its parent
even though we only use it in one part of this app here.
This is just a personal decision though
so I will make sure that this component robber
emits an event and let's the parent know
about the data that was entered.
And then the parent,
so the coach registration component in this case
will do the communication with Vuex.
But that's just one possible way of approaching this.
However with that, in coach form,
I'll emit here in submit form,
I'll emit safe data
and emit the form data.
And yes this data is not validated at the moment,
we'll add this later.
So now this is emitted
and that of course means
that we should also add the emits option here
and make it clear that we emit safe data.
And once we did all of that,
inside of coach registration
we can accept this incoming data.
So there on the coach form we can listen to save data,
which is that custom event we're emitting
and call maybe a method named saveData here.
Of course we have yet to add this method.
So here I'll add methods,
saveData.
And in here we'll get that formData
which we pass with the event here in coach form.
We get this as a parameter therefore in the save data method
which we bind to this event in coach registration.
And that's good because we need that data here
to communicate with our store.
So now we wanna add a new coach in our Vuex store
and that of course means one thing,
we need to add mutations and actions
because you shouldn't directly change your state
from outside.
Hence here in this empty mutations object in mutations.js
I'll add a new mutation, registerCoach.
You could of course also name this add coach
if you preferred this.
And in there I get my state and my payload
and I now reach out to state coaches
and push the pay load as a new coach.
Now actually that would be invalid though,
or not really great.
Because we must keep in mind that payload ultimately
is just the foreign data I'm setting up in coach form
and there I have first, last and desc as key names.
That's not in line with the key names
I have in the rest of my data.
That's no problem though,
because we have to add an action anyways
and I'll transform that data instead of ...
So here in the actions.js file
we now can register coach or add a register coach action
and there we'll get context and also pay load
or we can also name this data.
It's our method
so we can name the parameters however we want.
And that will be this foreign data in the end.
And here I'll then construct my coach data
where my coach or whatever you wanna name it
as a new object which now has a first name,
which points at data.first,
which has a last name which is data.last,
which has a description which is data.desc,
which has an hourly rate
which is data.rate
and areas which is data.areas.
I also want to add an ID here
and for that of course
we can use new date to ISOstring
to generate an ID like this
or we hard code this to c3,
which of course is not perfect
because that means that as soon as we register twice,
we have two coaches with the same ID,
but that shouldn't be allowed anyways.
You should be able to register more than once.
So I will hard code this for now,
later we'll send it to a server
and the server will give us a better real ID.
But for the moment we can use this dummy hard coded ID here.
So now we got this coach data
and now I can context commit,
register coach
and commit this mutation with that transformed coach data.
And therefore now in this mutation,
adding this data like this is okay
because that now is in the same format as the other coaches.
So now we got this register coach action
and we can therefore now dispatch this
in the coach registration component
whenever safe data is executed.
Here we can use this store dispatch
and then dispatch coaches/register coach,
this is the name space,
this is the action name.
And of course not just like this
but also provide a second argument
which is that data we're getting
and that should now be adding a new coach
once we've filled out all the details.
So with that if I now reload here
and I enter Max Schwarz,
this is a test.
15 and backend.
If I register and go back to all coaches,
we see that data down there
and of course we can also view the details.
Now maybe it would be nice
if we would automatically be forwarded
once we submitted that form,
be forwarded to that all coaches page I mean,
and that's something we can simply implement
by going back to save data in coach registration,
and using this $router.push to push us to /coaches.
Or use something which I haven't shown you before
and that's the replace method on the router.
It's also navigating us away,
just like push,
but the difference is that we can't go back
to the page we came from thereafter.
And that's good because here
I don't want to go back to the form
once it is submitted.
So that's why I'm using replace instead of push here.
Now with that out of the way,
let's try this again.
Let's reload,
and every time we reload,
we lose our generated coach by the way
because it's only stored temporarily in memory
that's why we later add HTTP in the server
so that's why we lose it when we reload at the moment.
But that's good because that means
we can register the same coach again
without having an ID clash.
This is a test,
add that data
and now if I register I'm forwarded to this page.
Now I think it would be good
if this button would not be available anymore
as soon as we did register though.
And therefore I want to make sure that we are aware
of when that user signed up.
And I want to make sure
that we can check for the user being a coach by using Vuex.
In the root index tray as follows,
the store folder.
We currently just register the coaches module.
Here I actually now want to also have some root state
and that I want to manage the ID of the user
who's using this app.
At the moment,
this ID is of course hard coded.
I'll use c3 here.
Later, after the authentication course module,
we will actually have a real user ID here.
For the moment it's this dummy ID,
but that's okay.
So we'll have a use ID here
and that user ID should now be used
when we sign up as a coach.
But should thereafter be used to verify
whether we already got a coach with that ID.
Now first of all here in coach's actions,
I no longer wanna hard code the ID here
but instead use this user ID.
So for that,
thankfully we can use our context
and access the root getters here.
Now we just need a root getter that gives us this ID.
So in the root.js index file here
I'll add getters and then add a user ID getter
where I just return state user ID
and get state as a parameter.
And now we can use this root getter here in this action
by accessing context rootGetters.userid
so that we use the real user ID here
and then here in the coach getters
we can add a isCoach getter
which returns true if the user already is a coach
and falls otherwise,
and her we can utilize the fact
that we get the state in a getter
but also other getters and also the rootState
and the rootGetters.
That's what I showed you in the Vuex module.
And therefore here we wanna get our coaches
by accessing getters.coaches or state coaches,
doesn't really make a difference here.
And then we wanna look through those coaches
and see if we got a coach with our user ID
which we can get from rootGetters.
We get our userID by accessing rootGetters.userId.
And then we can return coaches.some
which is a built in method that returns true
if some coach fulfills a criteria
and here we run a function every coach
and return true if coach.id is equal to userId.
With that this will return true
if we find at least one coach
that has our user ID as ID
which means we are a coach already.
Now I got two unused parameters here
which this specific project set up wouldn't like.
So here I'll use an underscore and _2 as parameter names
which is a specific convention
that signals the ... of this project
that I have to take these arguments
but I'm deliberately not using them.
Well and with that we hopefully get true here
if we have a coach with our ID.
Of course the downside of this approach by the way,
is that we always go through all coaches
to check whether we are a coach or not
so an alternative way of solving this
would be to simply add a new state
to our a coaches state here
where we say UserIsCoach where we set this to true
as soon as the user signed up.
This is absolutely an alternative.
I'll still go with the other approach to also show that,
but it's up to you which approach you wanna use.
With that however,
I have this isCoach getter
and now in coach registration
we can also add computed properties
and add a isCoach computed property
where I return the result of reaching out
to this store.getters
coaches/isCoach.
Which is that new getter we just worked on.
And now we can use the isCoach property
to control whoever we wanna show this register button or not
but I'm in the wrong component as I noticed
so let's cut that and removed that.
It's in the coaches list of course,
here we have this register as coach button
so here in computed,
I wanna add this isCoach computed property I just worked on.
And now we can use isCoach here
with the v=if to only show this button if not is coach.
So if the user is not a coach yet.
With that if we save this,
if I reload
the button's available.
But if I do now sign up here as a coach
this hopefully is no longer the case thereafter.
Now the button is gone
because now I am a coach.
So now adding a coach or registering as a coach works
at least in this dummy version.
But with that our core coach feature is pretty much done,
there's just one thing missing if I reload,
I want to add validation to this form
so that we can't submit and empty form
because that won't work for us.
So that's what we're going to work on next
before we do work on the context and requests features.