So let's work on the validation of this form
because at the moment we can submit it
without entering anything
and that's of course not the idea behind this form.
So in the coach form component here,
we're fetching the input,
but now I wanna add an extra step when we submit the form.
I also want to validate it
and for that I'll add a separate method, validateForm simply
to split the logic in two methods
and not have one super long method
and in submitForm right at the start,
I'll simply call this validateForm,
so this new method which we're adding here.
Now in here I want to go through all the inputs
and check whether they are valid or not,
and I will add an overall new data property here
to this entire component, the formIsValid data component,
which initially is true,
but which will be false as soon as one input is false.
No actually I'll make form validation
even a bit more complex than just that.
I also want to manage the validity of every single element,
so that I can later re-highlight the elements
by coloring the label red for example, that were invalid.
Therefore, the other data which has managed here
is no longer just devalue of a certain property,
but instead here that will be an object now,
where I want to have a val key,
which holds the value the user entered
and a isValidKey which initially is true,
which can become false if data input should be invalid.
So I'm going to replace my values here
with that new concept.
Here val is null initially,
and here it's an empty array initially.
So now the data got a little bit more complex
and now we need to update v-model
and bind this to firstName.val, lastName.val
and so on because now first name, last name, description,
actually hold objects where we have a val property,
which then holds to value that should be bound,.
so that's why I'm updating my v-model bindings
for all the inputs here,
including the checkboxes of course like this
and now with that in our validateForm method,
I will go through all these inputs,
have a look at each of them
and see whether it's valid or not.
For this initially I'll set thisFormIsValid to true
in case it got invalid and therefore falls in
between since the last validation
and then I'll go through all these inputs.
The first one I'll check is the firstName.
Here with an IF statement I'll check if the value is empty,
keep in mind we're trimming it already,
so therefore excess white space
will already have been removed.
If it's still empty it's invalid
and therefore then I would set this firstName.isValid
to false and since the overall form is invalid,
if at least one input is invalid,
I'll set this formIsValid to false here.
And then we can repeat this for the lastName
and set this lastName is valid to false here.
And again, repeat it for the description
and set this description is valid to false.
Now for to rate the check is a bit different,
here I'll not check whether it's empty,
but I'll check if we don't have a rate, so if it's null
or zero or anything like that, or even if we do have a rate,
I'll check if this rate val is smaller than zero,
because you shouldn't be able
to have a negative hourly rate of course.
So in these cases, rate is valid would become false.
And for the areas I'll check if this areas val.length
is equal to zero which means no areas
of expertise have been added, that's also not valid,
you need at least one area.
So in this case, this.areasisValid would become false
and this.formisValid would become false.
So that's my validation logic,
that means that after calling this.validateForm,
this.formIsValid will be false if the form is invalid,
so therefore in submitForm I can check,
if not this.formIsValid
and in this case just return to make sure
that the rest of this method doesn't execute
because I don't want to continue if the form is invalid.
And now we can go to our template
and actually show users some feedback if inputs
or the overall form are invalid.
Let's start with the overall maybe, for that
before the base button I'll add a paragraph where I say,
please fix the above errors
and submit again or anything like that
and we only show this with the IF, if not formIsValid,
so if the form is invalid, if formIsValid is false,
But that's not all instead I also wanna highlight the inputs
that were invalid, so let's start with the first name.
There on the overall div I'll bind a class dynamically
and I'll use this object syntax for that
and here, I wanna add the invalid class,
which is defined down there in the CSS rules
to then change the label color and so on.
I wanna add that invalid class here on first name,
If not firstName.isValid, if it is invalid therefore.
Then this invalid CSS class will be added to this div.
In addition, below the input I'll have a paragraph,
where I say first name must not be empty
and this has shown IF not first name is valid.
Now I'm going to copy that paragraph
because for last name I wanna say this,
to say the name just with last name
and check if last name is not valid,
and I will also copy that class assignment
and assign it on this divv as well
but of course, checking last name is valid
or it not being valid to be precise.
Now for the text area for the description it's the same,
copy to paragraph and say
description must not be empty
and also copy this CSS class assignment to the div
by checking description is valid
and again, copy the paragraph over to the rate
and here, I of course wanna say
rate must be greater than zero
and also add the CSS class here
to the div if rate is not valid.
Copy the paragraph again and go down to the checkboxes
and here below all checkboxes, I'll also add this paragraph
and say, whoops here,
say at least one expertise must be selected.
and of course show this if areas are not valid,
I forgot this on the other paragraphs,
here I should check if rate is not valid here,
if description is not valid
and I did update it for first and last name,
but also now I'll copy that class here
and add it on that form control div
around the checkboxes if areas are not valid.
With that, we hopefully have some validation,
if I now reload and submit the empty form everything is red,
we got these error messages
and we got this main form error message.
If a reload again and I do enter something here and here,
but I have a negative rate here for example,
only the invalid values are marked as such.
And of course if we enter something valid in all the fields,
we are able to submit this but of course we get an error
because at the moment I'm still not extracting
the values correctly in my form data,
that's something we'll fix later.
Before we fix that, there's one other thing I wanna fix.
If this is invalid, it would maybe be nice,
if it wouldn't stay red after we entered a valid value here,
it's a minor thing,
but I think it's a better user experience if as soon
as this was fixed, this would go away,
this red color and this error text
and therefore that's a functionality I also wanna add here.
For that, we can add a new method, clearValidity
or anything like that and expect to get the input name here
as a argument and then reach out to this input,
so to a data property, first name, last name, description
and so on, of that inputs some value.
So if input is first name,
we'll reach out to this first name.
If this last name we'll reach out to this last name
and set isValid of that input to true
and clear validity should be called
whenever an input loses focus
and for that on every input element in HTML,
we got the blur event, it's a built in event,
which is triggered whenever well, this loses focus.
That's when I wanna call clear validity
and in this case forward first name,
because that's for the first name input.
But now repeat this also on the last name here
also on the text area,
here it's description,
and also repeat this on the rate
and then of course is on the checkboxes,
so in every checkbox element, I'll clear areas, whoops,
copy that to all the checkbox inputs.
Reformat this to make it a bit easier to read
and with this, if we now saved this,
if I submit the invalid form, it's all red
but if I enter a valid name that becomes black.
This is a test.
If I enter something invalid, it also becomes black
because we have to validate again,
but at least it recognizes that we did something
and when I, I blurred something here it also becomes black.
Now of course, if I do have an invalid input here,
we still get an error,
but at least we give the user the feedback that we see
that he or she changed something.
With that though we got validation in place
and I'm happy with that.
Now, I just wanna make sure data is submitted correctly
and for that here in the submit form method,
we need to drill into the val properties
of all our input properties,
because that is where we store the concrete values.
WIth that though, if you reload,
if I have something invalid, we get an error
but if I do enter valid values here,
like this, this is submittable and we see our coach here.
So that's all working, as a next step we can move on
to their requests feature and make sure
that we've got a contact form
and that when we do use that contact form,
we send a request which
then also shows up here under requests.