So for the moment we got the coach part
implemented pretty well,
let's now move on to Requests.
And with that, I mean that we can, for example,
contact a coach and send the request from this page.
Now, at the moment on this page, we always get a warning,
but that warning will go away soon.
So for the moment we can ignore that
because that warnings should go away
as soon as we replaced this text here
in the Contact coach component with some actual HTML markup.
So let's do that.
In here, I want to render a contact form.
So of course,
a form element sounds about right to be rendered here.
And in that form, I want to provide two inputs,
one for an email address,
which a user can enter to let the coach
who is being contacted to know how to contact the user.
So therefore we want to leave our email address,
and we also want to send a message
along with the email address to coach we're contacting.
So therefore here I'll add a div
and in that div add a label,
which says your email and which is for an element
with an ID of email.
And that's the next element I add there after
our input field of type email with an ID of email,
which is added below this label.
And then we can have another div here like that.
And in that div I want to have another label for
let's say the message.
So for an element with ID message
and I say message in that label,
and then we want to render a text area here,
let's say so that the message is,
can be multi line and it's a bit easier
to enter a longer texts.
So therefore here I'll have five rows,
let's say, and give this an ideal message.
And then below that, I'll add another div
with a class of actions,
which will be important for styling later.
I will provide some styles to you though.
And in there I want to render a button.
And of course,
here we can use our base button component,
which we created a while ago,
and in there, say, send message.
Now to these other divs,
I actually want to enter, add a class of form control.
So add that to the first and the second div
that holds an input, and now we can add some styling.
So for that let's add scoped styling.
And as always,
you find styles attached to this lecture here,
you find the contact coach CSS file,
which contains the styles
you can copy and paste into these scoped style text
in the contact coach component.
And that will give this form some general styling.
Now, of course, this is not just about markup and styling,
but we also need a script for some logic.
We want to fetch the inputs for email and message.
We probably want to do some kind of validation.
It's up to you if it should be as detailed
as on the coach registration page or not,
but some validation won't hurt.
And ultimately once we got a valid input,
we want to do something with that input,
and we want to, in the end, create a new message,
which is attached to the coach to whom the message is sent.
That's the idea here.
So therefore in this script,
I'll start by adding some data
because we definitely want to manage some data here.
And the data we definitely want to manage
is the email address and the message.
I guess that makes sense
because these are the two inputs we got here.
But in addition to that,
here I will also add a form is valid, data property,
and set it to true initially.
And this should be set to false
if either the email address or text area is invalid.
So as a next step,
we can add methods here to this object here,
to this component, conflict object,
and a submit form method sounds about right,
because that's the method that should be triggered
when the form is submitted.
And of course we can therefore add a submit event handler
to this form and prevent the browser default
as we did as many times before in the course,
and then point at submit form when this form is submitted.
So inside of submit form, I now want to validate,
and if the data is valid,
create a new message or ensured
that a new message is created somehow.
So let's start with validation.
First of all, I'll set form is valid to true
so that if it was false in between,
we now clear any error message we might be showing.
We're not showing one yet, but we will soon do that.
So as a next step, we can then check if this email
is empty, let's say,
or if this email
includes no at symbol.
So here I checked for the opposite.
If it does not include an at symbol,
or if this message is empty.
If either of that's the case,
then I want to set this form is valid to false
and return so that the rest of this method doesn't execute.
So now that we manage this validity,
I want to do two things in the markup,
For one, I want to bind my input and my text area
to email and message with two way binding
so that this is updated with every keystroke,
and I want to show an error message if the form is invalid.
Now we'll start with the two way binding with V model.
I'll automatically trim the input
and then point at email here
and on the text area, all to trimming it,
point at message.
And then we can show an error as well
by adding a paragraph here, for example, above the button,
which has a class of errors,
which should be shown with V-if
if forum is valid is false,
so if it's not true,
and then here you can output any message you want.
I'll say, please enter a valid email and non empty message.
So this is a less complex validation approach
than we took it in coach registration,
but that of course is always a perfectly fine way
of doing it.
And ultimately it comes down to your requirements
and your preferences, how you want to validate a form.
With that, however, we are validating,
we are fetching the input values,
and if we make it past this validation here,
then we want to create this message.
And now of course the question is,
what exactly does create a message mean in this app?
Well, keep in mind that we have this Requests page
where we want to show all the requests
we as a coach received.
So that of course requires us to be registered as a coach.
But once we are, if we as a coach receive a message,
it should show up here.
And that of course means that in the end a message,
a request is just another piece of data
we want to manage in this Vue application
and therefore probably with VueX.
So let's do this in the next lecture.