So creating messages means storing data
in our Vuex store.
Thus far, we only got our coaches module.
Now, of course, we also need a module for requests
because we also wanna manage requests.
So in the store, modules folder, under requests,
I'll create an index.JS fault just as I did it in coaches.
And I'll also create all the other files,
mutations.JS, getters.JS, and actions.JS.
Again, it's up to you whether you want this layout or not,
but I'll go for that,
also to be in line with my coaches setup.
Now in index.JS here in the requests folder,
we then export an object and we import that object
from index.JS in requests into our main store
in this index.JS file in the store folder.
So here just as we imported the coaches module,
we can import the requests module
from modules, requests, index.JS,
and then simply add the requests key here
in the modules object in our store
and point at requests module.
Now, instead of this exported object,
I will now also set namespace to true,
so that we use namespacing for this module as well
and we don't just merge it into the global state,
into the global store, which we could do,
but which I don't wanna do here.
And then we need to bring in our mutations hands on.
But first of all, we need a state.
We need a state in this module, and that state should manage
one simple thing, our requests.
So all the requests we know, and then every request
will have a certain coach ID attached to it,
and then later, if that coach ID matches our ID,
that's a request we'll see,
all the other requests will be invisible to us.
So now that's our state and array of requests.
Now, of course, since we already are fetching data
for our request in the contactCoach component,
we now need a mutation and an action
for creating a new request.
So let's start with the mutation here.
Here in mutations.JS, we also export an object.
And in here we can add addRequest mutation,
sounds like a fitting name,
where we get our state, like in all mutations and a payload,
which in the end will hold the request data.
And then we can simply reach out to state.requests
and push the payload onto this array
assuming that the payload already is the finished request
as we wanna add it.
And that's done already here for the mutation.
Now, let's add an action.
So here we export an object as well in the actions file,
and we could name this action, contactCoach.
Now we will get our context here and also probably a payload
because we need that data that was fetched from the form
in the contactCoach component.
Then we can create a new request here,
which can be an object where we can add a user email field
where we point at payload email, for example,
assuming that the payload we get is an object
with an email field and add a message
where we point at payload.message.
But there's one more thing we need to add here.
And that's the coach ID because every request
needs to be attached to a coach ID.
So for that, I wanna get to the idea of the coach,
to whom this request was sent.
And therefore here, I assume that this is all the part
of the incoming payload, the coach ID.
And then we just wanna add an ID to the request itself
so that every request object has a new ID.
And we can simply create a dummy ID for the moment
by taking the current date and getting a string snapshot
of it, so to say.
And with that, we already got all we need.
Now we can call it context.commit, commit the add, whoops,
the addRequest mutation.
That's the name I chose here in the mutations.JS file.
And then also pass on our payload,
which for me here will just be this new request
we're building here.
And that should now add a new request to our requests state
if this action is dispatched with the appropriate payload.
So now it's up to us to dispatch this.
So back in the contactCoach component here in submit form,
we now wanna reach out to this store and call dispatch.
And then since our module is namedspaced,
it's the requests namespace we have to access,
and therefore it's the requests/contactCoach here.
ContactCoach is our actual name,
requests is our namespace name.
Now, of course, we need to add some data here
and that data should be this object,
which we're extracting here in our action.
So we need a coach ID, an email, and a message field
in our payload object.
So therefore here, I wanna create a new object,
which has an email field pointing at this email,
a message field pointing at this message,
and then one other important thing,
the ID of the coach to whom this message is sent.
And we can get does ID here because you have to keep in mind
that when we contact a coach,
this URL contains the coach ID.
So therefore, since this is a child route,
the contactCoach component is a child route of coach detail,
which has this ID parameter,
we can extract that here as well.
We could do it with Props to Route,
but to also see that other approach you learned,
here in contactCoach, I'll get the ID differently.
I'll set my coach ID field here to this dollars and route
and then ID because that parameter holds the ID of the coach
to whom this message is sent.
And that should then dispatch this successfully.
Now, last but not least,
I then also wanna navigate away from this page.
So we can do this with this router and then replace maybe
instead of push so that we can't go back to this page
thereafter and go to /coaches.
But it's up to you where and how you wanna navigate.
With that saved, we should now actually be able
to send requests.
So if we contact a coach here and we fill out this form,
first of all, if it's invalid, we get an error message.
But if I fill it out there after,
we at least leave the page,
but I get an unknown action requests/contactCoach.
Yes, because in the requests module,
remember that's a nice object I'm exporting here,
which I'm in the end importing into my store,
but what's missing here?
Well, the mutations and actions I defined
in those separate files,
I don't import and add them to my module here.
That's of course something we have to do.
We have to import mutations from ./mutations.JS
and import actions from ./actions.JS.
And once that's done, we can add mutations
using the JavaScript shorthand here
and actions as key value pairs to this module object.
And with that done, if I try to contact a coach,
this is a test, now we no longer get this.
We also don't see the requests anywhere though.
So as a next step, let's work on the requests page.