So let's move on to the Requests Received page.
Here, I wanna show all the requests for the active coach.
And for the moment, I'll simply show all requests here
since we don't really have an active coach yet.
That's something which will follow soon though.
So here I'll simply add a new section let's say,
in which I wanna use my base-cart
to have that general container style
we're using throughout the app.
And in there, we can add a header
with a HQ tag inside,
where we say requests received,
because that's what this page is there for.
And now below that,
I want to render an unordered list
with all the requests we received,
or at the moment, with all the requests in general.
And below that I actually wanna have an H three tag,
where I say "You haven't received any requests yet",
which should show up
if no requests have been created and stored yet.
So we'll come back to the list items later.
For the moment,
let's add styling and a script section.
So first of all,
I'll add scoped styling.
And as always,
attached you'll find the Requests Received CSS file,
which contains the CSS styles,
you can copy and paste between your scoped style tags here.
And with that done,
now we can work on the script part of this component.
And here, the goal is in the end simple.
We wanna get access to the requests
we're managing in Vue X.
And therefore,
as we did always before,
when we wanted to get access to Vue X data,
we will use a computed property.
So we can add our computed key here,
and then in here,
I will add a computed property named Received Requests,
where I now wanna reach out to the store,
and for the moment, get all the requests we find in there.
So in getters, in the requests folder,
I'll export an object,
and add a requests field here
where I get the state automatically as argument
as you learned,
and where we can then return state.requests
to return this list of requests.
And in Requests Received,
we can now reach out to this getter
here in this computed property.
We can reach out to this store.getters.
And now since it's named spaced,
then reach out to requests,
which is the namespace name,
/ requests, which is also the getter name here,
and then return this here in this computed property.
I will add a second computed property,
where I say "hasRequests",
and where I simply wanna return this,
store.getters,
requests/hasRequests,
which is a getter we have yet to add,
to Vue X.
So let's quickly do that.
Copy that and
go to getters in the requests module,
add the hasRequests getter,
and there, I wanna return
basically state.requests and
state.requests.length greater Zero.
So this will yield true if we have at least one request.
Otherwise it yields false.
And I added this extra computed property here
because we can use that with V-if
to show this unordered list, if it's true,
but then with V-else show this H three tag if it's not true,
if we have no requests.
So now with that, we got access to the requests.
Now we need to render them.
And for that, we wanna
render a bunch of list items here in this unordered list,
though I will outsource the concrete item
into a new component.
So for that, I'll go to components.
And then in there,
next to coaches, layout, and UI,
we can add a requests subfolder
to manage all the requests related components.
For me here, that will be just one component though,
the request item component,
which has a template where we render a list item, let's say.
And in that list item,
we have a div in which I simply have an anchor tag
where I wanna output the email address and make it clickable
to automatically open an email client once you click it.
And below that,
the message, the paragraph maybe.
So here, I wanna interpolate the message of a user.
Here between the anchor tag,
I wanna output the email address
that was sent along with that request.
And I wanna bind the ref attribute here,
que,
well, to a link that
automatically opens the local email client.
For that we can add a script here.
And first of all, accept props,
because we are going to render a request item
as part of the list in Requests Received.
Requests Received has those requests.
So we can then simply feed the data
into the individual list items, fruit props.
And the data will need is the email address and the message.
So the keys I'm using here in the template,
but I'll also add computed prop here,
and that's the email link
simply to put that logic into Java script
and into the template.
And here, I wanna return mailto:
plus this email.
And that's a special instruction the browser understands,
if this is your link in an anchor tag,
the browser will automatically open your email client
with this email address,
pre-filled into a new email that opens up.
So here we can then point at email link.
And as always,
attached you'll also find
some styling, which you can add here,
it's the request items CSS file,
copy and paste the styles into your component.
And we should then have the look and the behavior
of this component, which we need.
So back in Requests Received,
we can now register this component as a local component.
So import requestItem from
going up,
into components,
into requests,
to requestItem.Vue,
and then here at components,
and register request item as a local component.
And that of course allows us to use it here in the template
like this.
And now render multiple instances
off this component with V-for,
by going through all the requests in Received Requests,
which is our computed property down there.
And now here, we wanna add a key,
set this to request.id because every request has an ID,
and also pass in the email address,
which is the user email field
in Vue X in the action here.
I stored the email under a user email field.
That's why I have to access it by that field here
in Requests Received,
and feed the message prop into request item
by accessing request.message.
So with that,
we implemented almost all we need to do.
There's one thing left.
Our getters here are defined,
but just as before,
we need to add them to our module object.
So we need to import getters from ./getters.js,
and then add them here in this module's object,
into this module object for the requests module.
With that done,
if we reload this app,
we see you haven't received any requests yet.
But then if we contact a coach
from our email address,
"Hi, I'd like to get some coaching.
Can you help me?"
If I sent this message,
under requests, we see it here.
And if I send another message to the other coach
for the moment, we'll see messages of all coaches.
"Hi, I am
Max and I
really need some
support in web dev."
If I add this request, we see this as well.
And if we click such an email address,
this opens up the email client
with that email address prepopulated.
So that's another nice feature.
Okay.
So now we also can send requests,
but of course, now we always see all requests
of all coaches.
And that's not what you want.
So let's try to restrict this.
And in our root state,
we actually already got a user ID
assuming that this is us.
So if we register as a coach,
this will be the ID off the registered coach.
And thereafter,
only messages sent to that coach
should be showing up for us.
So that'll be the next step.