[Maximilian Schwarzmuller] So in order to make sure,
that we only see requests that are for us.
So, for this userId in the end,
we can go to our requests getters,
and here on the requests, which we're,
fetching.
I no longer wanna get all requests,
but instead I wanna filter,
for requests that have our ID as a coachId.
So therefore we can utilize the fact that in a getter,
we can take more than just one argument, besides the state,
we can get access to our getters,
then also to the root state, and to root getters.
And the root getters are what I need here,
because the userId is part of the root store.
And there we have a userId getter already.
That's the getter which will be useful now.
Here we get the coachId,
by reaching out to rootGetters.userId,
that's the getter name.
And then here, we wanna filter the requests,
which we got, and go through all the requests,
and check if the request coachId,
is equal to the coachId we extracted here.
And only these requests are then the requests,
that are returned here.
This also means that we should change hasRequests,
and not check all requests in our state, but instead,
simply use,
our, requests,
getter here,
by reaching out to getters.requests,
so that we check the filtered requests,
and not all requests.
Now as before I'll replace the unused arguments with,
underscores here,
but now we should have a set up,
where we really only see the, requests made to us,
as a coach.
So if you save this, if I reload,
and I send the request to the first coach,
which is not us,
we don't see this here.
If I now register as a coach though,
I am a coach,
and I then send a message to me,
which of course doesn't make too much sense,
but for the moment, that's the only way we can do it.
If I send this, we should now see that request.
And we don't,
and the error actually is quite subtle,
and a bit hard to spot, or actually it's easy to spot,
as soon as you console log,
all requests, for example,
to see what's inside there.
If you do that, you'll notice one important thing.
If you contact a coach,
and we then inspect the logged getter,
we see that the coachId is undefined.
And that's the problem.
That of course ensures that we're not able to filter.
Now it's undefined because in contact coach,
where I set to coachId,
where I get it from the route, I access this routeId.
Well that's incorrect, this should be this route.parans.id.
That's the correct way of getting access here.
So now with that done,
if I go back, and I send a message here,
to the first coach.
This is a test,
it still doesn't show up here under requests as it should.
But if we now register as a coach, again,
and soon we won't have to do this over and over again.
Soon we're going to add a backend,
and then the data will be stored permanently.
But for the moment we have to register,
and if I now sent myself a message here.
This is a test.
Now, we do see this message, and only this message,
here under requests received.
So now that filtering part is also working,
and with that indeed, the entire app is kind of finished,
but of course only in this dummy (mumbles).
One important thing is missing.
And that's a real backend where we store our coaches,
and where we store our requests.
And where we then of course also fetch the data from.
So that is what I wanna work on together with you,
in the next lectures.