So up to this point,
all the data we're working with is dummy data.
And it's not permanent.
If we register ourselves as a coach, once the app reloads,
it's no longer there.
The data is lost.
In addition, of course, it's only here on our computer.
If this would be a web app running on a server,
being served to users all over the world,
every user would only see his or her own data
and not the data of other users,
which of course is totally not the idea
behind an app like this.
I wanna see all coaches from all over the world after all.
That's why we now need HTTP and why we need a backend
and a server on which we can store the data.
For that, I'll again use Firebase,
not because it's the only option,
but because it doesn't require us to write
any server side code and this of course
is no server side code course, so that's great.
And because we can get started for free.
If you wanna use it for your real projects though,
of course, definitely check out the pricing page
to learn what costs money,
and how much you can get for free.
Now you need to log in with your Google account
and then go to the Firebase console,
and then there's simply create a new project which I did.
And they're, you should then go to real time database
to make sure you use this database for your project.
Now, for the moment, this is empty.
When it gets created, make sure you create it in test mode
and ensure that your rules over there
look something like this.
They should not say false here or anything like that.
Instead, they should look something like this.
And with that done, we can now get started
and use this as a backend to which we send requests
from inside our View App.
And now of course, the question is
where do we wanna send which request?
Well, in the end, it's quite simple.
In our app, when we were just there as a coach,
we wanna send the request as soon as this is done.
When we're on the coaches' page,
we wanna fetch all the coaches and also re fetched them
whenever their refresh button is pressed.
On requests, we wanna fetch all requests
and we wanna send a request
once this contact form is submitted.
So in the end, this aligns with our Vuex store.
In coaches, when we have this register coach action,
we wanna send the request to create a coach.
In requests, when contact coach is submitted,
we wanna send a request to add this coach on the server,
and then we'll need a couple of requests to fetch data.
I still wanna use Vuex to manage my data in the View App
and I wanna use Vuex for sending those requests.
And therefore let's maybe start with coaches.
Here in actions in register coach,
we're creating our coach data object at the moment,
and that's the object that should be sent to Firebase.
So therefore, here, we wanna send the request.
We can do this with the fetch function
that's built into the browser.
It takes a string which is the URL
to which the request should be sent,
which is this URL in your real time database,
where at least that's a part of the URL,
but then you can add any segment thereafter
for example, slash coaches and then for Firebase,
you need to add dot json at the end,
but that's only a Firebase thing, nothing Vue specifically.
So this will send the request there,
but by default, that will be a get request.
A get request is useful for getting data,
but here we wanna store a coach data.
Hence we need a second argument, an object
where we configured the kind of request we wanna send.
We can do this with the method key,
and we could set this to POST,
but I actually don't want to.
Because here's one assumption which I'll make.
The idea of the coach
will exist before we register as a coach.
Because later we'll add authentication to this app
and you will need to sign up before you can register
as a coach anyways.
So you need to sign up and then in addition,
you can also become a coach if you want to.
Therefore, I assume we already got the user ID
who wants to become a coach.
And we kind of do.
In our roots state, we got this dummy user ID.
Now later, once we added authentication,
this will no longer be a dummy ID, but for the moment it is.
So for the moment, I'll just take this.
So in this action here, we already get this ID here.
I'll no longer add it as ID field in the coach data
instead all stored in a separate constant user ID like this
and then actually here point at slash coaches slash
and then this user ID to create a separate entry on Firebase
for just this user.
Now to conveniently add this user ID into this string,
I'll use back ticks instead of single quotes here,
which allows us to use this JavaScript feature
of injecting data into a string like this
with this dollar sign coli brace syntax.
So now we send the request to Firebase slash coaches
slash this user ID slash json.
And I'll send a put request,
which tells Firebase that data in there will be overwritten
if it existed or will be created if it didn't exist yet.
And the difference to POST is that with POST,
a new entry would be added all the time,
which I don't want to do here.
I only wanna have one coach entry per user.
Now we still need a body though.
We need to attach some data.
And that is the JSON stringifyed version of our coach data.
So that converts this object into this JSON format,
which we need to send along with the request.
So this sends a put request to this URL with this data.
And now we, of course only wanna continue
with the next steps once this is done.
Now fetch returns a promise as you learned.
So we can use then to define the code
that should execute once this request,
once this promise is done.
Or we use an alternative, a more modern syntax,
the async await syntax.
It makes your code look like it's a regular code
without promises, though it still uses promises
behind the scenes.
But it's a bit easier to write and maybe also to understand
so that's why I wanna switch to that different syntax here.
To use it, we need to add the async keyword
in front of our method name,
and then we can use the await keyword
in front of our promise.
So in front of the result of calling fetch.
Then we can store to result in a regular variable
or a constant and it will actually only be stored
when this is done.
So it's a bit like putting this into the vent block
we saw before, but now the code is,
well working without the vent block.
It's transformed behind the scenes though.
So that's the response we get back from the request.
And the next line will now only execute
once this request is done.
So here we know we'll have a response
and then we can get our response data
by a waiting response.json,
because the response, this object has a JSON method,
which all the returns a promise.
So we await that
and then we got the post response data eventually.
We can then check if the response should not be okay.
The response object has an okay field,
which indicates whether the response is okay or not.
And then here, we had an error if that would execute,
but we'll take care about error handling later.
So for the moment, I'll do nothing there.
Instead, I assume that it always works for this moment
and then thereafter we can commit our data.
Actually I'll commit a different kind of data,
I'll commit an object where I copy coach data
with the spread operator.
So I take all the key value pairs in coach data
and merge them into a new object.
But in addition, I add an ID field, which holds the user ID.
I did not wanna send this along to the server
because I already store it under that ID
in a separate node on the server.
So I would then just be using the ID twice there,
but I definitely do want to add it
to my locally committed data here
so that we still have the coach ID quickly available
in our data object here in Vuex.
So then committing still works as before
and this will only execute once all these promises are done.
By the way, I'm not doing anything with response data here,
so I guess we can also delete this or comment this out.
Now data should be stored on the server
when we register as a coach.
Let's give this a try.
Let's reload, click register as coach and enter your data.
I'm a web developer online instructor,
and I love sharing mine knowledge.
Hourly rate, check the boxes, click register,
and we see nothing here,
but after a short while we see the coach appear
and that kind of looks good.
Now, if we check Firebase, we see a coach's node
with our dummy coach ID and then below that the data
that belongs to that coach.
So this is looking very good, submitting the data worked.
Now, there are a couple of areas we could improve.
For one, for example, we were redirected here
and we only saw the coach show up
after a couple of milliseconds or seconds.
But in addition, in general,
we're not fetching the coach data here.
If I reload this app, I still see just the dummy coaches.
Now that we got at least one real coach,
it would be nicer to fetch that, right?
So that is what we should do next.
Make sure that we don't just store
coach data on the backend,
but that we also fetch it from there.