So how could we implement the fetch mechanism?
It's clear that data should be fetched
when we visit this coaches page
or when we click refresh.
So therefore we wanna initiate data fetching
when the coaches list component
is loaded onto the screen.
Right because that is what we need to coach data.
And it's true. We wanna initiate it here,
but initiate doesn't mean that we have
to do the entire sense, the request
and parse the response logic here.
Instead, we can still leverage view X
for that, because there, we still managed
to coach data once it is in our app locally.
And therefore here, we could also add an action
for fetching data
and a mutation for then using that fetched data.
And that is a great approach
because it allows us to do all the heavy lifting
of sending the HTTP request
and parsing the response
out of a component into view X.
And that allows us to keep our components lean,
which is always good.
So therefore, we can add a new mutation
in our coaches mutations fall,
and maybe named as mutation set coaches,
because I wanna set my local coaches
into view X state queue to coaches,
we will have fetched from Firebase.
So here we get our state and our payload,
and we can assume that
the payload is a list of coaches.
So we can just set our coaches equal to payload.
Now the action will be more interesting.
Here i wanna add a new action, a second action,
which is the load coaches action.
Where we get a context
and then also probably a payload.
And here we wanna send the request
to load to coaches from Firebase.
And this action will be dispatched
from any component that wants
to trigger this loading process.
So here we wanna send a request
to the same URL as we used for storing data.
So we can copy this part here
of the old fetch request
and use it here again.
We don't need a second argument though,
because here I'm fine with a get request.
I again, wanna use a sync await
instead of then and so on.
So therefore here we can adjust a wait this
and store the response in a new constant.
In the next line
we can then get our response data.
So response data by a waiting response.json,
and once stat is parsed
we can again check if
the response is maybe not okay,
and then do any kind of error handling,
which I will again not do here,
but which we can implement later.
Again, let's assume that everything works though.
And therefore now
we can almost commit our mutation,
but there's one other thing we got to do first.
We need to transform
the data we're fetching such that
it has the format we need here.
Because when we get data from Firebase,
we'll get it as one big object.
And we rather wanna have an array of coaches,
not just one big object.
And actually there,
I also noticed one other thing,
I don't wanna fetch the coaches
for just one user ID.
Instead, I wanna fetch all coaches
from the coaches node.
So that we fetch all the coaches
we eventually have here below coaches,
but that will be one big object then
where we have to coach IDs as property names
and then nested objects with the coach data.
And that's not the format we need here.
So we need to transform this first
and for derby country to help her
constant here, coaches, which is an MTI rate.
And then with a four in loop,
we can go through our entire response data,
which will be this object full of coaches,
where we then get each coach ID as a key here,
and then simply construct
a new coach object here,
which has the same format as
the coach data we use here
when we store a coach. So first name, last name
and so on.
Let's just copy that and bring it down there.
And now it's that first name equal
to response data forward the given key,
forward the given coach ID
at which we're currently looking at
in this iteration.first name,
accessing the first name property
of the nested object
for this coach with this ID,
because every coach has this first name property
on Firebase.
And we repeat this game,
for the last name
and also here for the description,
here of course for the hourly rate
and its hourly rate here on Firebase as well,
and also for the areas.
And we now also need to add to the ID here.
And that's just our key for this iteration.
Right because key will be this ID.
That's the main object for which we loop
with all these keys.
And therefore key will be our coach ID.
Yeah, that's looking good.
So now we build this coach.
We can then reach out to these coaches array.
There's help array here
and push this coach into disarray.
And now we dare after having an array
full of correctly formatted coaches.
And therefore now we can
commit set coaches
and set our coaches here.
As to coaches reloaded.
And I'm getting an error now
that I'm not using payload and that's correct.
So let's remove it.
Now we have to load coaches action
and we can now dispatch this in coaches list.
Here i wanna dispatch it when this component loads
and also when the refresh button is clicked.
So therefore we can add a new method here.
Load coaches and in there reach out
to the store.
Dispatch coaches/loadcoaches.
Load coaches was the action name defined here.
Like that.
And load coaches.
This method should now be triggered
when this component is created.
So therefore we can add
the created life cycle hook here,
that created life cycle method,
which view executes
when this component is created.
And in there, we can point at this load coaches
and execute that.
And in addition, I wanna do it when
this button is pressed.
So we can bind the refresh button,
the click event there
to load coaches,
the method we just added.
If we now give this a try and reload,
if it loads up,
we see the old dummy data briefly,
but then we see the coach
and then the register as coach button
also goes away.
Now of course the flickering here
is not what we want though.
So as a next step,
we can work on showing a loading spinner
and maybe also ensure
that we handle errors in a nicer way.