At the moment when we visit All Coaches,
we get no feedback that we're fetching new coaches,
that we're loading coaches in the background.
In addition, we don't have any error handling in place
and that's also not optimal.
So it would be great if we could do both,
check the current loading status
and also add error handling.
And of course, I wanna do that into components
because that is where I wanna update DUI, eventually,
but we're sending the HTTP request in the Vue X store.
So that kind of clashes.
Well, not necessarily, thankfully.
Let's start with fetching coaches,
because that is easiest to test for us here at the moment.
We wanna show a loading spinner
whilst we're fetching coach data,
so that we don't have this flickering
whenever we reload the page,
hence we, first of all, need a loading spinner.
Now, I prepared a complete component for you
Which you'll find attached.
The base spinner zip file holds this Base Spinner Vue file,
which you can copy into your UI components folder.
The base spinner component,
in the end just renders a loading spinner on the screen.
It's a bunch of markup and a bunch of CSS.
And we can use this base spinner here
to render it on the coaches list page whilst we're loading.
Now, thankfully, as I said,
we can find out if we're loading or not
even though the request is being sent with help of Vue X,
because when you dispatch an action,
there is a nice feature, which I haven't shown you before
because we didn't really need it before.
This patch can also return something
to the component where you call it.
And for example, here,
when we dispatch the Load Coaches action,
since we use async keyword here,
it automatically returns a promise
which we'll resolve once we're done with all these steps.
And that's great because that means
since this promise is returned that in coach's list,
we can basically listen for this promise completion,
and we know that when it is completed,
we're not loading anymore
because then we clearly got a response.
Hence, we can add a new data property
in the Coaches List component next to active filters,
and that's the IsLoading property,
which initially is false, let's say.
And IsLoading, this data property, should be set to true
in the load coach method when this method is executed.
So here it then set this to true.
Then we dispatch the action where the request is sent.
And once this is done,
once this promise returned by dispatch resolves,
we know we no longer are loading.
So since dispatch here returns a promise,
we can also use Async Await here
to wait for this promise to complete,
and then set IsLoading to false thereafter.
So this will then be set to false once the request is done,
and that will allow us to show a loading spinner.
Maybe here above the unordered list, we can add a div
where we check with v-if if we are loading,
so that this is only added if we are loading.
And then I render my base spinner here,
this loading spinner component I just gave you.
We now just have to register this in main JS.
So here in Maine JS, we import the Base Spinner
from ./components/UI/BaseSpinner.vue,
and register it as a global component
with app component pointing at base spinner.
So now the base spinner is available
and in Coaches List,
we are rendering it here if we are loading.
Now, that also means
I wanna adjust my hasCoaches computed property here a bit
because this list should, of course, only be rendered
if we have coaches and we're not loading at the moment
so that it disappears if we are loading.
So in the hasCoaches computed property,
we should adjust this a little bit
and I'm not just check this here,
but also check that we're not loading at the moment.
So add this to the computed property
so that if we are loading, we never show the list.
So that if I save this, now we see that loading spinner.
Now it's only there briefly because this is all super quick,
but hey, at least we see it briefly.
We also briefly see No Coaches Found
because we show this whenever the list is not rendered.
And at the moment, this of course means that
it's always rendered whilst we're loading.
So the list is not rendered then,
but this isn't always rendered.
But we can fix this by turning this from v-if to v-else-if
so that we either are loading
and showing the loading spinner,
or we have coaches and show those,
or we have none and show this text.
And then we only have this spinner here.
Now we also see the Register as Coach button flickering,
Of course, that button also shouldn't show up
if we're loading.
So here, I wanna check, not just if we're not a coach,
but also we're not loading.
Only then this should show up.
If we are loading, it should not show up.
So then if I reload, this button is not flickering.
Okay, perfect.
So now we've got this loading spinner here.
When I refresh, we also see it.
Now, what about error handling?
At the moment if things go wrong,
for example, if I introduce a deliberate error here
by going to the Load Coaches action
and removing the N at the end,
if we get an error, we just see an infinite loading spinner
and we see the error here, but of course,
our users don't have the developer tools open typically.
So we wanna show an error message here
to the user as well in that case.
So therefore, error handling is what I wanna implement next.