We are checking if a response is okay or not.
But besides that, we could also have a technical error.
In both cases, I want to throw an error,
which I can then handle in the component
that dispatched this action.
Now, if we've got a technical error,
an error object will be thrown automatically,
but otherwise I want to throw one manually.
So here, when I get an error
or create a new error and in this error object,
I want to set the message either
to response data dot message, if we have such a field,
or to fail to fetch as a fallback.
And then I want to throw this error object.
So I'm creating a new error object
and the error constructor function is built
into Java script.
And I'm throwing this here.
Now, whenever an error is thrown here
in this dispatched action,
the components that did dispatch it,
in this case coach's list, can handle it.
And that's exactly what we want to do here.
So here in load coaches,
besides changing the is loading status,
I'll now also add a new second data property,
the error data property,
which initially is null, like this.
And this error should be set whenever
this dispatched action froze in error.
Here, we can use try catch,
which is built into JavaScript to try executing this line.
But then if we fail,
I want to catch the error and do something
in the error scenario so that the app doesn't crash,
but we can define which coach would execute if it fails.
So what do I want to do here?
I want to set this error equal to error dot message
or as a fallback in case this error object
shouldn't have a message property
to something went wrong.
And now we're setting this error data property,
which we now can use in our template
to show the user an error.
And now it's up to you how you want to show such
an error message to the user.
I want to show the error message by opening an overlay,
a modal that shows the error to the user,
and then the user has to confirm,
and maybe he or she wants to try again or whatever,
but at least we will show the error to the user.
So let's add such a modal here.
Now for this error modal, which I wanted to show,
I prepared a number of component for you.
It's the base dialogue component which you'll find attached,
which you can copy into your UI folder.
Now I've prepared this component for you simply so that we
don't waste too much time on creating yet another component
that's really not doing that much.
It's just a dialogue, a default HTML dialogue,
being rendered with a backdrop behind it.
It's shown with a show prop that is received here,
which has to be a Boolean and which is required.
We used that to show both the backdrop and the dialogue.
And I use teleport here to teleport that to the body so that
it's not rendered in the Dom hierarchy where we use
this component, but always directly in the body.
Then we get a title prop and a fixed prop title
is for the title, which is shown
in the header off the dialogue.
The main content is dynamic. We can use a slot here.
We could also use a slot to replace the header
and also use a slot to replace the actions,
the button we show here.
But by default, I show a close button here,
which triggers the try close method,
just as clicking on the backdrop does.
And the try close method is a method which emits
to close event, but it checks if the fixed prop
is set and if it is set to true,
it actually does not emit to close event.
The idea is that you could use this dialogue also
in a non-closable way,
which ensures that it can't be closed
by clicking the backdrop.
That could be useful if you, for example,
want to show the dialogue to hold a loading spinner
and it should then automatically go away controlled
from outside of this component
when the loading spinner isn't needed anymore.
So it's really just a flexible dialogue component,
which shows an overlay.
And we're going to use this component.
For dad and main JS we have to register it
as a global component.
So base dialogue from components,
UI base dialogue dot vue.
That's the import we need.
And then with that import added,
we can register it as a component
with the app component method here,
base dialogue pointing at base dialogue.
And now that component is available.
And I want to use it in coach's list
to show an error message to the user
if fetching data failed.
For that here, we can simply add base dialogue
in the template of this component.
Again, it will not be rendered in that position
of the Dom hierarchy.
Instead, it will always be teleported
to the body because of the teleport inside of base dialogue.
But I want to use it in this coach's list component
because here I want to show the error message.
So in a paragraph,
which we pass between the base dialogue text
to use the default slot in there,
which is this slot in this content section here,
this slot receives this paragraph,
and here in this paragraph,
I want to output error
because the error data property in coach's list
is null initially, but is actually set to an error message
if we do have an error.
And now I, of course, only want to show the dialogue
if we do have an error,
so we can bind to show prop off base dialogue queue, not,
not error.
That might look strange,
but this ensures that if error is truthy,
it's converted into a real Boolean.
If it would pass and just error,
I would pass in a string as a value for show,
but show once a Boolean.
If I add one exclamation mark,
I pass the opposite and I don't want the opposite.
So two exclamation marks convert a string,
a truthy value into a real true Boolean.
That's why I'm using that here.
So here we pass in true if we have an error, and false
if we don't have one and internally the show prop
is then used to show or hide the dialogue and the backdrop.
We can also pass in a title
and set this to an error occurred.
And with that,
we should show this dialogue whenever we have an error.
So if I reload since fetching always fails,
we now see this error dialogue.
Now it would be great if we could close it
and the base dialogue does emit the close event.
Whenever we click on the backdrop or the close button,
and therefore back in coaches list,
we can listen to the close event here.
And then, for example, execute a handle error method
which we have yet to add.
So handle errors should be added here
maybe after loading to coaches.
And in here, I simply want to set error back to null.
And once it is null,
it's a falsey value and therefore show will receive false
as a value and therefore it will not be shown anymore.
So with that, if we reload, you see this is the error,
but if I click the backdrop, for example, then we close it.
Or if I click close.
Now at the moment,
you always get this error because this is a forced error.
After all I manipulated the URL here in the coach's actions.
This needs the end at the end.
So we'll bring this back,
but now we can see that error handling also works here.
Now we could also bring a loading spinner and error handling
to the coach registration if we want to,
but I will not do it here,
but you can absolutely do this and think of ways of adding
it there as well, that would be a nice practice.
But another practice, which I also want to implement here,
or which I want to do here in the next lectures is bringing
that loading spinner and the error handling to requests.
When we fetch requests here,
I want to fetch them from the backend.
We're not doing this yet.
And I also want to store requests on the back end.
I want to store requests on Firebase.
As always in this entire module, try this on your own.
Tn the next lecture,
we'll start implementing this together.