So I now basically want to implement
for requests what we already did for coaches.
When we contact a coach,
this data should not just be added locally
to our Vuex store,
but instead a request should be sent to Firebase.
And I then also want to load data from there, of course.
So let's start with contacting a coach.
When we do that, I no longer want to generate a dummy ID.
Instead, Firebase indeed will generate an ID for me.
So I will then use that later.
But this is the raw data which I want to send to Firebase.
The ID of the coach to whom the request is sent,
the user email and the message.
So again, we can use fetch here, the fetch method,
to send our HTTP request,
and it will again be this Firebase URL here.
Or at least again, that will be a part of the final URL.
Because now I want to store all the requests
being sent to a coach under the ID of that coach.
So maybe we sent that to requests, slash,
and then the ID of that coach.
So payload.coach ID here,
and for that I'll convert this to a template literal
by using back ticks instead of single quotes,
so that we can inject something into that string
with this special syntax here.
And add payload.coachId.
And then .json at the end.
And this will create a new requests node
on this Firebase backend.
And there a node for this coach ID.
And then under that node,
all the requests sent to that coach will be stored.
Now this shouldn't be a get request though,
so we need this second argument to configure the request,
and set the method to post.
This time it's a post and not a put request
because I don't want to overwrite the existing data,
I just want to add a new request.
With every request that's sent, it's a brand new request
that's being added to a list of requests,
that's the idea here.
And then here we need a body,
so the data attached to the request,
which of course should be the new request
we're generating here.
Now, justice, before this returns a promise,
so we can use async await to await the response.
And then thereafter, we can get the response data
by awaiting response.json.
I need that data here, because for a post request,
Firebase will return the generated ID.
It automatically generates a new unique ID
for every entry that's posted, so for this new request.
And I want to use this generated ID locally here
in my Vue app.
So I want to extract it from the response data
that's being sent back from Firebase.
We can simply set newRequest.id to responseData.name.
Now I'm adding a new ID property to new request
with this line.
And the response data object, which I get back from Firebase
will have a name field,
which holds this automatically generated ID.
That's something you have to know.
You can read it into Firebase docs or simply of course,
also console.log responseData to look into it.
And there you will see it has this name field
with the unique ID that was generated.
Now just as before, we can also check
if the response is okay, or if it's not okay.
And if it is not okay, we could also generate a new error
where we check if response data maybe has a message key
that contains an error message.
And otherwise, we add our own fallback message,
failed to send request.
And then we could throw this error here, if we wanted to.
So now with that, we sent requests to Firebase
and it's up to us how we now want to handle this
in our front end.
In the contact coach component,
at the moment we dispatched this,
and then we don't care whether that's finished or not.
We immediately redirect and behind the scenes,
the request will be sent,
but we don't show the user any feedback.
We show no error message, we show no loading spinner.
And it's up to you whether you want this or not,
it's up to you which experience you want to offer
to the user.
Maybe you don't want the user to wait
until this request is sent,
because for the user using the app,
it's actually doesn't make a difference.
But maybe you do want the user to wait.
So this is up to you how you want to implement this.
I will not do anything here in contact coach.
I will just dispatch this action,
behind the scenes the HTTP request is sent.
And then here, I don't implement loading or error handling,
but of course you can absolutely do this
as an extra practice if you want to.
But with that, if we save everything,
we should actually have a working experience
where we can contact a coach,
at the moment, ourselves here.
Send a message and don't see it here,
or actually we do because we stored it locally.
But this is not fetched from Firebase.
But we do see it on Firebase as well.
Here, requests, then the ID of that coach,
and then here, that request that was sent.
Actually, we could also remove coach ID from that field
now that I think about it.
Let's maybe do that, let's delete it here
and let's make sure that's in the data we're sending
in our action here we actually don't include coach ID.
Instead, let's add the coach ID only here
after we send the request,
so that we have it in the local data with which we work,
but not in the data which we sent to the server.
So here I will still get payload.coachId.
And add it to the local data,
but it's now not getting sent to the server.
Awesome.
With that, our data will in the future
always end up like this.
Now we also want to fetch that data, of course.
So here I will implement fetching just as I did it before.
In the actions for the requests,
we can add a fetch requests method,
however you want to name it.
And here, of course, we get a context.
And I want to load all the requests
for the currently active user.
And that's important, only the requests that were sent
to this currently active user.
So therefore, we need that user ID from our global state,
from our global getters.
We can get this through context.
You might remember, there we also can access rootGetters
and then simply get our user ID.
So that's the did have to coach
for whom we want to fetch all the requests.
And with that ID, fetching will be easy.
In the end, I will just copy this line of code here
and execute it here as well.
But the coach ID will now be coach ID,
which we get from our getters.
And this will now send a get request
and fetch all the requests that can be found
for that coach ID on Firebase.
Again, we can use async await to handle that promise
in a pleasant way, get our response here,
and get our response data by awaiting response.json.
Check if response is not okay.
In which case we can create an error just as before.
So here, create an error,
and maybe say failed to fetch requests, throw that error.
And otherwise, if we make it past this check,
we know we got a successful response,
we can now use the response data.
And the response data will now hold everything
below that coach ID in the requests node.
So here, we'll actually have an object full of these IDs
as property names.
And below these ideas, we'll find nested objects
with the concrete request data.
So again, we need to transform this
so that we can work with that data locally.
Because locally, requests should have a user email,
a message, but then also an ID and a coach ID field.
So we need to transform the data we're getting
so that it looks like this.
For this all again at a helper, constant requests.
And then again, loop through all the keys in responseData.
Create a request helper object here.
And then add an ID, which is my key.
That's the unique ID for that given request.
Add a coach ID, which is the coach ID we get up there
from the root getters.
Then add a user email field,
which is response data for that given key .userEmail,
because it's stored under that user email field
on the backend.
And then also here, add a message which is responseData
for the given key .message.
Then we can add this to requests.
And finally, once we're through that for loop,
context.commit and commit a mutation
that receives these requests.
Now that's a mutation I have yet to create.
I'll name it setRequests.
Here, we get a state and a payload.
And basically, the same as we did it for coaches,
will be done here.
We said state.requests equal to payload, just like that.
And payload should be an array full of requests, therefore.
Hence we can now commit setRequests
and pass our requests as a payload.
So these will be the requests our local requests are set to.
And now we just need to dispatch fetch requests,
well, whenever they should be fetched.
And that of course should be the case
on the requests received component.
So there it'll be the same pattern as for coaches.
We can add methods and add a loadRequests method
where we reach out to our store
and dispatch the requests, slash, fetchRequests action.
And then again, this will return a promise in this case
because we use async await in there
and that automatically returns a promise
in the dispatched action.
So we can also use the isLoading approach here
to show a loading spinner to the user
whilst we're waiting for requests to be loaded.
So here in requests received,
we can add our data and return a new data object
with isLoading, which initially is false.
Maybe already also with an error property
so that we can handle errors.
And then we can set this as loading to true here.
Add async in front of load requests
so that we can await the promise
returned by this action being dispatched.
So that will then resolve once the request has been sent
and the data is there.
And then we set isLoading to false again.
And we can also try catch this
to catch any potential errors we might be getting.
And then we can set error equal to error.message,
or as a fallback, something failed, whatever.
And now we can show a loading spinner if we're loading
and show the error dialogue if we got an error.
So in the markup of this component, in the template,
we can add our base dialog here for error handling.
And actually, we can copy the base dialog
from coaches list, I guess.
Just copy this base dialogue over two requests received.
Of course, we now also need to add a handle error method
to clear the error if it has been handled.
So add handle error, where we simply set this error
equal to null again.
And now for the loading spinner,
here I want to add the base spinner below the header,
above the unordered list and show it if we are loading.
And here, we turn this into an else if.
And showed this if we have requests and we're not loading.
Of course, we can also merge this
into one computed property if we want to.
And else, show this text.
And if we now save that I get an error,
because this should be this error to which I'm setting here.
But now with that, we can save this successfully.
And now we have to call loadRequests
when this component is created.
So in the created life cycle here,
we can call this loadRequests.
So this method will be executed
when this requests received component is created.
And if we now save this and be reload here,
we see a spinner and then our data.
And with that, we got all the functionality we need here.
Now, if I quickly change my user ID in my main store
from c3 to c1, let's say,
you'll see we got no requests for this coach.
And we can now still register as a coach,
Manual Lorenz, let's say.
I'm a web developer and data analyst.
Let me help you with your career.
Let's say we got our hourly rate, frontend and career.
We can register this coach as well,
because now we have a different user ID,
which of course is some dummy data
we're still managing here, but it is good enough for now.
Well, and with that, of course,
we don't see requests here for this user.
But on the other hand, if I switch this back to c3,
we now still have both coaches,
but we now see the requests sent to the c3 coach.
And that's the pretty much finished app,
of course still with the dummy user ID.
That's something we'll fix or change
in the authentication module.
And there's one other tweak I want to do first
in this module.