Now, this was a long module
and this course's project is pretty much done,
but there's one final tweak I wanna do or implement.
At the moment in this app, we don't really need Vue X.
Whenever we visit a page,
we load all the data we need anyways.
And especially here on the coaches page,
I'm not sure about that.
It's not likely that new coaches will be signing up
all the time and we therefore
always need to load the latest data,
whenever we go back to this page.
We could in stat cache data locally
and only refresh it after let's say a minute or so,
or once we manually clicked the refresh button
and that's something we can easily implement with Vue X.
And then again, all the shows us why we might need
locally managed state,
which we do with Vue X
side by side with service side managed data.
Because currently we almost replaced Vue X with Firebase
and that's not the idea.
So what could we do here to not fetch
new coach data all the time.
And instead reuse the existing data.
In our coaches module in the state,
besides managing the coaches,
we could add a last fetch key, which initially is null.
Now last fetch should hold a timestamp.
It should save a timestamp.
Whenever we fetched new data.
For that, we can add a new mutation,
which we name set Fetch Timestamp, for example,
where I get access to my state.
And where I then say, state last Fetch,
which is this new data property we just added
equal to new Date.get Time.
And this gives us the current time and date
as a timestamp, as a big number,
basically the time in milliseconds
since the beginning of time,
which in JavaScript is at the beginning of 1970.
So now we store this time snapshot
this timestamp in last fetch.
Now we can commit this action whenever we fetched data.
So in our actions,
here in load coaches,
that's where we fetched data.
There at the end, we can commit more than one mutation
and we can also commit
our new mutation set, fetch, timestamp,
which we just added.
And we don't need to provide any payload here
because set, fetch, timestamp doesn't need any.
So now we store that timestamp
when we lost fetched the data.
Why am I doing that?
Because now we can add a Getter to this coaches module,
which we may be name, should Update.
And here I in the end, want to get my last fetch timestamp
and find out if it is, let's say less than a minute ago.
So here we get our state
and then we get last fetched by accessing
state.lastFetch.
And we, first of all, check if last fetch is faulty.
For example, at the beginning, it's null.
If that's the case I return true
because then we should update.
If we have no timestamp yet we should update.
Else, if we do have a time stamp,
I need to find out if it's more than a minute ago,
so we can get a current timestamp now
by getting you date get time.
So that's the timestamp when we use the Getter.
And now we can return
the result of comparing the current timestamp
with the storage timestamp.
We simply, deduct last fetch from the current timestamp,
divide that by 1000 and check if that's greater than 60.
That means that it's more than a minute ago.
This will return true if it's more than a minute ago.
So we then should update again, it returns false,
so we shouldn't update again,
if it's less than a minute ago,
divided by 1000,
because both these numbers are in milliseconds.
So now it should update yields true.
If we should fetch again and false otherwise.
And where exactly do we use should update now?
Well, in the actions of the coaches module.
Here in load coaches, before we send the request,
I wanna check if we actually should fetch coaches.
So we can check if context,
Getters,
should update
is true or to be precise,
if it's not true.
If it's not true, I will just return here.
I will not continue with the rest of the code
and therefore, we will not send the request.
Instead, we'll stick to the data
which we currently have in our store.
So we'll not fetch again then.
If should update is true.
This if statement will be skipped
and we will fetch data again.
By doing that, if I saved it, if I reload,
we fetch data, but if I then go to requests and come back,
you see no loading spinner, because now we don't load again.
And after a minute you would see it again.
Then it would fetch it again
and store it for another minute.
But refreshing with the refresh button should work.
We should always be able to do that.
So in order to implement that,
I will actually change this action a little bit
and expect a payload,
which holds a property that tells me
that I absolutely do have to fetch again.
So which overrides the scatter basically.
Here, we can simply add an additional check in this
if condition here, and check if
payload let's say has a false refresh property,
and if it doesn't have that,
if that's false and we should not update,
then we skip this.
Otherwise, if either does is true or this true,
this if check will be skipped and we will fetch again.
So now we will be able to set a false refresh payload
to this action.
And if it's true, we will fetch again,
no matter if it's more or less than a minute ago,
since we last did it.
Now we just need to make sure this payload is passed
into this action.
And for that, we can go to coaches list,
which is where this action is dispatched.
And here in load coaches,
we now wanna pass this payload.
The false refresh key.
And this should be false,
if load catches is called from inside
there created lifecycle hook,
because there I wanna use the caching,
but false refresh should be true,
if this is called through the button
Through this refresh button in the template.
So therefore we simply need to make this load
coaches method a bit more flexible.
We can add a refresh parameter
and set this to false as a default value.
This is supported modern JavaScript syntax
and provide, refresh this parameter
as a value to false refresh in our payload.
And that way, if we call load coaches without an argument,
the default value of false will be used,
but we can ignore all the call load coaches
when we click the button
manually and pass in true, which false is a refresh.
So if we do that and save that and reload,
it fetches this initially because the time has passed,
but not thereafter.
But if I click refresh, we force that
and we do refresh everything
and load our data again.
And that's just a tiny tweak and optional addition,
but I think it makes sense here.
And it hopefully shows you what you can do with
Vue, a backend and Vue X.
And of course, that's just the tip of the iceberg.
You can do much more than that.