Now I wanna conclude this part
of the project.
So this main project without authentication
by adding some animations, some transitions.
And there are a couple of things you can animate here.
For example, the route switches when we switch from one page
to another page.
But in addition, also the modal we're showing
if an error occurs, we can animate that in as well.
And actually that's what I want to start with.
In actions.ji here when we fetch coaches, I
will again reintroduce the forced error by using
an incorrect URL.
And now we get this modal, and this modal just pops up
and is there.
Of course this works, but having a little transition
can provide a better user experience.
And here since in the dialog
in the base dialog we're using v-if to show
or hide this dialog.
Here we need Vue's help.
Because we learned in the animation module
that transition the transition component Vue offers you,
can help you if you wanna animate elements that are added
and or removed with v-if.
So we can simply wrap this dialog with transition here.
And I'm only wrapping the dialog and not the backdrop
because I don't want to animate the backdrop.
So I will just wrap this dialog
with transition opening here and closing here.
Inside of that teleport component that works.
So I have to transition in here
and then give this transition a name, for example dialog.
But this name of course is up to you, as you learned
in the animations module.
And now we can add a bunch of CSS clauses
that will be applied by Vue to the dialog
when it's added or removed.
So for this, I'll go down to the CSS code
and maybe here we can add a dialog-enter-from clause
to define the state or the styling we wanna start animating,
when the element is added to the DOM.
And actually set the dialog-leave-to clause,
to the same styles.
So that we make sure that we leave to the same styles
as we came from, when the element is added or removed.
And here I want to start with opacity zero or, go
to opacity zero.
And also transform it a little bit and scale it down
so that we start at a smaller size, or we go to
a smaller size when the dialog is added or removed.
Now the state we wanna reach when it's added or
the state we start at if it's removed, can be defined
with dialog-enter-to or dialog-leave-from, like this.
And here I of course I wanna go to full opacity
so that the element is visible.
And transform it such that the scale is at
the original scale of the element.
So that it's not smaller or bigger than intended.
And now we just need to in between clauses, which
would be dialog-enter-active.
And also dialog-leave-active.
And for entering, I will you set the transition CSS property
and transition all CSS properties.
So no matter which property changes, it will
be animated over .3 seconds with ease-out.
And basically do the same for leaving, but there I
will use ease-in.
And with that we should have a nice animation,
a nice transition for the modal.
If we save that and reload, now you see
that looks a bit nicer.
Now we got this little animation here for the modal.
And of course you absolutely can play around
with the concrete styles, with the timing, with
whatever you wanna play around.
But that's now the modal.
We also of course can animate route switches.
And I covered this indeed transition module as well.
For that we go to the place where we render the router-view,
for the routes we wanna animate.
In this case I wanna animate all main routes, so not
this nested child route but all these main routes
should be animated.
And therefore, in App.vue we have
to use transition combined with router view.
And you'll learn that here the syntax is
a bit strange, maybe not what you're used to exactly.
Here, we need to pass something between the router-view tags
and that something is to build in transition component,
with a name of your choice route, for example.
And then in there the dynamic component component
which you bind, like this with is prop
which is bound dynamically to the component
the router decided to load.
And to get that component to router wants to render, we
have to use the slot feature view provides
with the v-slot directive.
And get the slotProps the router view sets for us.
And on those slotProps we can access .component
with a capital C and this is then pointing at the component
the router wants to load.
And now this will be animated.
We should also set the mode here on transition
to out-in, so that we first animation the removal
of the existing page and then the appearance
of the new page.
And as of it's up to you
which styles you wanna use here, with
how you wanna animate this.
I will define my CSS clauses down here
and that will be a route-enter-from, route-leave-to.
Here I'll not use the same rules because I wanna
have different styles, slightly different ones.
And we of course also need to route-enter-to
and route-leave-from.
And then also the active clause in between
so, route-enter-active and route-leave-active.
So now regarding the styles in enter from, I wanna set
the opacity to zero to make it transparent
and also use transform again but now with translateY
to move it along the y-axis.
And here basically start a little bit higher,
a little bit further up on the page than normally.
I will use almost the same styles for leaving
but here I will have a positive number for translateY,
to shift the leaving page down effectively.
For the active clauses I wanna use transition again.
Animate all CSS properties over .3 seconds
with ease-out and do the same for leaving but,
as before with ease-in.
And then here for enter-to and enter-from, there actually we
can merge this into one rule.
So let me do that, because here I will use the same styles.
Here, I wanna have an opacity of one
and also transform translateY zero to move the elements
to the actual position it should have in the end.
Okay, let's give this a try.
Let's save this, reload and you will notice a warning.
Now actually we also still got this error here
so let's first get rid of that and let's then have a look
at the warning.
So here I'll fix that URL, so that we're not forcing
this error anymore.
And you'll now see a warning, and you will see
that animations are broken.
The reason for that is that, you are allowed
to have multiple root level elements
in your components templates.
But, if you plan on wrapping those components
with transition as I'm effectively doing it here.
I'm wrapping all those routes, those page components
with transition then the wrap components must only
have one root element.
And I guess this makes sense because transition
as I explained in
the animations module, needs exactly one child element
with some rare exceptions.
Therefore, child elements routes
with multiple top level elements
will not work with transition.
So to fix this we need to go to all our pages
and on every page make sure we
have just one root level element.
So here are two side by side sections, are not allowed.
So here we then need a div or anything like that, which
in the end wraps all the other elements in this page.
This is something we need if we wanna use transitions here.
Because otherwise we violate this rule
of having only one child element inside of transition.
So let's make sure we have just one root element
in all those page components.
Which is now almost the case I also need
to add one here, yep.
And now with that, NotFound is something we also need
to work on I just see but with that, if we reload.
Now we got the nice transitions here
if we move between our pages.
So, now we also added that
and with it out of the way, we can quickly add NotFound
in the next lecture and then, we're done
with this main project for now.