Now for the not found page,
I will keep this very simple.
We can add a template here
and then maybe use the base card
to have our base container.
And maybe also wrap
this in a section element here just for semantics.
And then in the base card,
have an h2 tag where we say page not found
and below that maybe a paragraph
where we simply say this page could not be found,
maybe check out all our coaches.
And now coaches should become a link,
so we can wrap this with router link here
and point at to slash coaches here like this.
And if we do that
and we now enter any URL,
which is not supported,
we see that not found page,
and we can go back to coaches there.
And that's already it.
That is to not found page added.
With that though, we built a very nice project
where we see a lot of core Vue
concepts working together.
We got a bunch of components,
we got routings, we got animations,
and we are of course also using Vue.js
to manage all our state and our data.
I showed you a bunch of different approaches
and concepts you can use in your projects as well.
But of course as always practice makes perfect
and what works for me or what I like
might not be useful for you in your next project.
But you should have a very good idea
of how Vue works,
how Vue components work together
and how you build Vue apps by now.
Now we still got more in this course.
We got an entire new feature
to Composition API into which I'll dive later.
But for this project I also got more.
I want to add authentication,
so that we don't have to work
with this dummy ID, which we assume,
but that we have real user IDs.
We'll cover that in the authentication module.
But by now you already learned a lot about Vue
and you'll learn how to apply that knowledge.