Throughout the last modules,
we learned a lot about components
and therefore, of course, all about Vue.
Now, it's again time to practice what we learned
and we will apply all that knowledge
we gained in a course project here.
We're going to see components in action
and we're going to build a course project from A to Z.
Now, this is the project we're going to build here.
It's an application where we have two areas
between which we can switch here with our tabs.
We got a list of our favorite learning resources,
including links on which we can click
that take us to those resources,
and we can add new resources.
And if you wanna get rid of one,
we can of course also just delete it.
We can then also add a new resource.
You need to know how to Google, like this,
and it works, but if we decide to enter something
invalid here, we get an alert which you of course
then can confirm and fix our error.
That's what we're going to build
and whilst this application of course still doesn't have
20 different features, it does actually use
all the important features you learned about
over the last modules.
And you will get a good idea of how components work,
how these different features are used,
how components are combined,
and how you can build Vue applications
that use all those important features.