Now to get started again as before,
attached you find a starting project
which you can download, run NPM install in there
in the downloaded and extractive folder
and once you installed all the dependencies
with NPM install, you can start that
development server with NPM runs serv.
So basically what we did all the time
throughout the last modules as well.
Now, we got a huge project to build
and as you can imagine, we'll also use
a couple of components to build this project.
Because, and I wanna really emphasize this here,
because that is what Vue and Vue projects
are all about, you could say.
You wanna build a user interface by combining
multiple components.
And every component has it's clearly defined job.
The job could be to just look good
and provide a certain styling and just
output some information or the job could be to
fetch some user input, show a warning if that
input is invalid or otherwise use that input
to generate some data.
And we are going to see all those different
kinds of components in action
in this module here.
Now how do we get started
with this kind of project?
Well, you might remember the monsters layer
project we built earlier in this course.
And there I also just get started step by step
by adding feature after feature.
I wanna do the same thing here
and we can always split our code
into more components when we get a feeling that
a component is getting too big and we might wanna
split it up because that will also be
an important part of writing Vue code,
that you from time to time re-evaluate the code
and split it into smaller pieces
to keep it manageable.
Now was that enough of talking.
I'll start by adding a components folder,
into source folder because we will need that
and in the source folder
not in the components folder but in the source
folder, I'll also add a App.vue file.
Because we'll definitely need that
route component.
That route Vue application that will hold all our
other components in the end.
Well and then, I'm going to start by adding a
template here in App.vue and in that template
here, I want to start by out putting a list of
dummy learning resources.
Later the user will be able to add
his or her own ones but we'll start with
some dummy resources.
Hence we can start by adding an order list
and we can of course then manage those resources
here in the data property off this App.vue file.
So we can return our data object here and then
have some stored resources here for example
which could be an array, an array full of objects
where every object is one learning resource.
And in that an order list, we could use V4,
the V4 directive to output those storage
resources.
And that sounds like a good start to me.
So I'll start here by populating this with some
dummy data because for the moment,
we have no way of letting the user generate data.
And every learning resource should have an ID.
for example because we need that ID to add a key
when we use V4 but an ID will also be helpful
when we later add functionality
to delete resources.
I'll have the official-guide as an ID,
you can use any string you want here.
And then let's say every resource
should have a title, official-guide.
Because the official-guide,
the official documentation of course is a
learning resource, you wanna keep around
when diving into Vue.
We can then add a description,
because I also to output a short description
of the resource on the screen
and that description here could be
"The official Vue.js documentation"
and last but not least,
I'll add another field here, let's say a link
property which is to link to that documentation,
which is vuejs.org.
Now that's my first resource with which I wanna
start.
I'll also add a second resource here and that
second resource is Google because Google is
super important if you are learning anything.
Because you need to learn to Google.
There you will find all the resources you could
possibly want.
Okay, now we get two dummy resources here and
now we can output them here in our
an ordered list and I'm fully aware that this
is quite a bit away from the final
app we wanna build but we can simply get there
step by step by adding feature after feature.
So feel free to now output those resources
on your own, in list items and potentially
also consider creating a separate component
for every list item.
We'll do that together in the next lecture.