So let's output the resources here,
and for that we could use a list item
with v-for on it of course,
to loop through all the stored Resources.
But as I mentioned at the end of the last lecture,
I rather create a separate component
which contains the list item,
and then I'll put all the data in there.
Now you might wonder why,
why would we create a separate component
instead of just writing all the markup here.
Well first of all, let me be very clear
you don't need to create a separate component,
it's optional, it's just the idea
behind using Frameworks like Vue.
If you build bigger and bigger applications,`
you could theoretically put all the markup
into just one Vue component.
All the markup could go into the template of App.vue,
but this would become a super huge file
and maintaining it, editing it,
finding the code you wanna edit right now,
that would all become a nightmare,
if you have all the markup, all the logic, in one file.
That's why we wanna split our code
into small reusable pieces.
Now, there is no hard rule
when you should go for a new component,
versus putting the markup and logic
into an existing component,
it's something you will develop over time.
It's a feeling you will get
and it also comes down to personal preference of course.
But things like list items for which you loop
are typically candidates for a separate components,
and therefore, I'll create a brand new component
here as well.
And that component which I wanna generate here
is the Resource Item component.
Now the name is up to you,
but of course you wanna describe
what you will use this component for.
And I will use this component
to show a learning resource item,
of course we could therefore also name it,
Learning Resource, if you prefer that,
and actually I do prefer that.
So let's maybe go with that, LearningResource.vue.
Now, just because I named the file like this,
it's not automatically the name
by which I will use the component,
but it is considered a good practice to keep that aligned.
So if you named a file Learning Resource,
you should also name to component Learning Resource later.
Now, I don't wanna store this component
in a components folder like this though.
we're going to add more components later
and to keep my code organized and keep the files organized,
I'll create a subfolder here,
and I'll name it, resources or learning-resources,
because I wanna store all the learning resource
related components in that subfolder.
So instead of components
and they're in the Learning Resources folder.
And then in App.vue,
I wanna import this newly created component.
It's still empty, but we're going to change this soon.
So let's import the LearningResource
from './components/learning-resources/LearningResource.vue'
that's the file we just created.
And with that import added here in App.vue,
we can add the components option to our object
and register Learning Resource like this,
this is how you learned it.
You could also give it another key separately
or the same key which will be assumed anyways,
but there is no need to do so
you can just register it like this,
and thanks to this modern JavaScript Syntax.
This is automatically expanded to this code
and that in turn will then tell Vue
that you want to be able to use
the Learning Resource component by using this tag
or the kebab-case version of it.
But that's all something I covered in the last modules.
So now we've got the learning resource imported,
and now here I will output learning resource
and I'm a fan of this Kebab-case for my elements,
so I will use it and I would put it here,
but of course not just once,
but instead with v-for,
I will loop through my stored Resources
and create one learning resource component instance
per item in my stored Resources.
So in this case, we have two stored Resources,
and that simply means that we're going to create
two learning resource instances with v-for.
For that we can loop through the stored Resources like this
with res in storedResources,
and we should bind the key prop here,
which Vue wants, in this case to res.id,
because every resource which I extract
into the res variable here has an id field
and that id is guaranteed to be unique,
so it's a perfect key.
With that we're going to create multiple learning resources,
and that means that we can now go back
to the LearningResource.vue file and add a template there,
because ultimately we want to be able to
output something there.
So in this template, I will now output a list item,
opening and closing text and inside of the list item,
I want to have my content.
And here indeed I want to have a div inside of that,
which that in turn holds a header.
And in that header, I want to have an h3 tag
which outputs the title later, and next to that,
so in the same row you could say,
I want to have a button which allows us to delete this.
Now as a side note, I'm aware that I challenged you
to go ahead and create your own component with a list item
and I'm fully aware that you probably did not create
this markup, and that's fine,
you can now create it together with me.
I just wanted you to also practice creating and registering
and using components on your own,
and you hopefully did that,
and you hopefully succeeded there,
if not, we're doing it together now.
So we get the header, we get the h3 tag,
we got the button, and it's all in that div,
below that div I wanna have a paragraph
that's where the description should be output later
and below that I'll add a nav element,
which is a default HTML element
in which I then want to have an anchor tag,
which should lead to the link the user provided.
So here we could have a text of View Resource
and the link value, Well that's something I wanna set
to the link value stored in the respective resources.
So you can already tell that the learning resource component
needs external data in order to work correctly,
because we've got all the markup here,
but the title is missing, the description is missing,
and the link is missing.
And how do we get this external data?
How do we make this component reusable and configurable?
With props of course.
So here we can now add our script tag like this,
and then add the props option
to let Vue know about the props
we want to get in this component.
And the simplest form here is to provide an array
where every prop is registered as a string.
So we could for example, expect to get a title prop.
You can also use the longer form and be more specific
about the prop you wanna get
and describe the type of data you wanna get there,
describe whether it's required or not,
but I will keep things simple here and just use this array.
So we'll get a title, I will also need a description
and I also want a link.
Now all these names here, are 100% up to you.
It's probably best if you use the same names as I do
in order to follow along with ease,
but you can use any names you want here.
It's your components, so you can name the props
whatever you want.
Now, with that, we can now output the prop data here.
For example, here in the h3 tag,
we can output the title, so this prop.
In the paragraph, I wanna output the description.
So here we can interpolate description
and you'll learn that all the props here,
so these props are available just like this in a template,
they are available as if they would be data registered
into data option of this component.
We can then all bind ref here with v-bind or to short-term,
which I'm using here and bind this to link,
so to the value in the link prop.
And now the missing piece of course,
is that we actually do provide the props here
so that we ensure that values are passed in
for all those props.
So let's go back to App.Vue
and here where we are using learning resource
and where we are using v-for,
we now wanna bind all those props
and provide values for all the props of learning resource.
So we wanna set a value for the title prop, for example.
And of course that value should not be hard coded,
but dynamic because it depends on res.
So here I'm binding title to res.title
and the same for the description,
which should be bound to rest.description.
And I'm reformatting this to make it easier to read
and bind the link to res.link.
And with that, we're feeding in values for these free props,
title, description, and link,
which we are expecting on the learning resource.
And now we can also try and see that on the screen,
for that in main.js, I will now import App from '/App.vue'
and pass that here to create App
and in App.vue, I'm already registering Learning Resource.
So if we save it all, we should see this on the screen.
Definitely not beautiful, but it shows that this works
and that our own component is working.
Now let's work on some styling next.