So we got our first components.
Let's now work on the styling.
Now there are some base styles
which I wanna set application wide.
For that I'll go to App.vue
and there below the script tag, I'll add the style tag
without scoped.vue, just style like this.
So the styles in here are applied globally
to the entire application.
And as a side note, the structure
of having template first, script section,
and styling last is the typical structure
you wanna use in those dot.vue files,
just in case you were wondering.
Now attached you find an app CSS file,
which contains some styles,
you should copy between these style tags.
I'm importing some Google Fonts here.
And then I'm just setting
some general application wide styles.
For example, applying the imported font as the default font.
If you say if that and reload, we have a different font.
Now, I also wanna change the styling
of the learning resource, and therefore here,
I will also add styling, but now with the scoped attribute,
because the styles here
should be exclusive to this component.
Now you'll also find a learning resource
dot CSS file attached, and as you might be guessing
that contains two styles,
you should copy between these style tags.
And I'm giving you these styles for copy and pasting
because it's not a CSS course I know many students are bored
if we write CSS code here.
So here are the styles you can just copy them in.
And you should now see this on the screen.
Now obviously, that's not the final style,
but it looks a bit better at least.
To get closer to the final styling,
I'll add another component
next to the Learning Resource component.
That will be a component which should actually contain
this unordered list and then also this loop here.
And I'm creating a separate component for that
not because this would be so much markup,
but because I essentially don't want to have it
in my root App.vue file.
I really just wanna have a minimal template in there
and just have the application wide styles in here.
So I don't wanna start styling
an unordered list here in App.vue,
when we might be using unordered list
in other components as well,
since I don't wanna use scoped here.
So therefore, I'll add a brand new component
and I'll name it StoredResources.vue
add a template, and basically just copy the template
from the App.vue file,
or cut it into that template
of the StoredResources.vue file.
Now of course, we're now missing the StoredResources here,
which we need for v-for, the StoredResources
are still part of the data option of our app,
and therefore not available
like this in the StoredResources.
Well, you of course know
how we can make them available here.
We can add props here
and let Vue that we need some data from outside.
And here, I want to get my resources,
again this name is up to you.
So that here I can loop through my resources.
And resources should now be those StoredResources.
So in App.vue, I'll actually remove the existing import
which I had in here, and then state import StoredResources
from ./components LearningResources, StoredResources.vue
and register the StoredResources here
in components instead of LearningResources,
and then use stored-resources here
in my App.vue file template,
and pass the StoredResources I have here in my data,
through props to the StoredResources component.
So there, I wanna bind the resources prop,
which is the prop I added in there.
And I will pass the StoredResources key here.
So the StoredResources array I have in my data option
that's passed as value through the resources prop
to the StoredResources component.
And now inside of the StoredResources component,
we're using the LearningResource component.
So I wanna import and register it there.
And I'm working with local components thus far,
because at the moment, I only have components
that I need in specific areas
or in specific parts of the app.
So therefore, here I'll import my LearningResource
from ./LearningResource.vue,
it's in the same folder as the StoredResource.vue file.
So we just need this import path.
And then here, I'll add components
and register LearningResource as a LocalResource
in this StoredResources component.
Now with that it looks like before,
but now I got a brand new component,
the StoredResources component.
And I added this because now here, I can add scoped styling
to the StoredResources and add component-specific styling
that takes care of this unordered list
without affecting unordered lists in other parts of the app,
which we might have.
Of course, there would have been alternatives
to this solution as well.
We could have worked with CSS classes, for example,
but I want to keep my App.vue file lean as I mentioned,
and by adding this extra component, I'm achieving this.
Now, as I also mentioned before in the course,
things like that also come down
to personal preference of course.
I'm just teaching you one possible approach of doing that,
there is no single right or wrong approach.
With that, however, you can now download the attached
StoredResources CSS file,
and copy the style you find in there,
this unordered list style between the style tags
of your StoredResources.vue file.
And if you do that, you should now see a slightly changed.
Look here, the dots in front of the list items are gone.
Now it's still not the final look, but it's one step closer.
With that we're outputting some dummy resources.
As a next step, I wanna work on a header
which I wanna have in this application
and I wanna add a card look to my resources here.
And as before, you can definitely try this on your own,
come up with solutions for that,
for adding a header and a card look,
and we'll do it together in the next lecture.