Now, I will start with the card look
and for that in the Components folder,
I'll create a new subfolder which I will name UI
because I wanna store some general UI components in there.
And my card should be one of those general components.
So in there I'll add a BaseCard.vue file
following this Vue style guide recommendation
and in here we now need a template of course.
Now how should a card look like?
What should a card component do?
It's a very simple component.
It will have no logic attached to it.
It's just about being a wrapper to other content,
which then has a certain look.
And for that in this template, I'll just add a Div,
opening and closing,
and then provide a certain styling.
So for that, I'm again adding my scoped styles
and attach to find the BaseCard CSS file,
which as before contains the styling,
the CSS rules you wanna add between your style text here
in the BaseCard.vue file.
This will style the div in a certain way,
but now one important thing is missing here.
I mentioned that this card should be usable as a wrapper
around any content we want
and Vue has a built-in feature
that makes building such components easy slots.
So here I will add a slot now between those divs
so that we can feed in any markup,
any HTML code of our choice
and it will be wrapped by this div with this style,
that's the idea.
Now we don't need to give this slot a name
because it's the only slot here
and with that we can now go to the LearningResource
where I wanna use that card
and replace this div here with that base-card.
And actually here, I just noticed
the div was placed incorrectly.
The div should of course wrap all the content
inside of the list item.
So it wraps the header, the paragraph and the nav here.
That's all part of this base-card.
But, wait a second,
is base-card available already?
It's not because we haven't registered it.
Now since we're using it here
in the LearningResource.vue file,
we could of course add it as a local component here,
but this BaseCard component will probably be used
in other parts of the application as well.
Therefore, adding it as a global component
might make more sense.
And in general, these base components
will typically be global components
because typically being based components,
they will be used multiple times
in different parts of your app.
So therefore I'll go to main.js
and I will import BaseCard there
from ./components/UI/BaseCard.vue.
And now store my created app here in a constant
so that on this app
I can then all the conveniently call component
and register the base-card HTML element name
for this BaseCard component we're importing here.
And with that if I saved this,
we now got this card look for our LearningResources
and that already looks quite a bit better.
Now let's work on the header
and for that I'll add yet another subfolder,
the Layouts subfolder,
which should hold my layout specific components,
so basically the header and the footer
if we would have one.
Here I'll add the header
and since we'll only have one header
in the entire application,
I'll name it, TheHeader.
Side note, I could have also named the StoredResources,
TheResources
because we're also only using that ones,
but here I think StoredResources is the better name
because it describes in greater detail
what this component will be about.
Header on the other end
would otherwise just be a single word
which is not recommended anyways.
Keep in mind that your components
should consist of two words
and therefore TheHeader is a great name here.
Long story short, that's my header.
I'll add my template here
and in that template
I of course want to have a header element,
the built in HTML header element
and in there I'll have h1 element
and between those tags,
I wanna output the title
and I could hard code the title here,
but also for practice purposes,
I'll make this a prop here,
but you could also just hard code it here.
That would be fine as well.
So now I'll add my script here
and make it clear that I want to get a title prop
so that I can output it here.
And this header should now be used in our App.vue file
above the StoredResources.
Hence here, I want to import TheHeader
from /components/layouts,TheHeader.vue,
and I will register it here as a local component.
And then here I can add the-header, like this,
and now also set the title prop
and I'll name my demo application here RememberMe
because it's all about remembering learning resources,
right?
So that's TheHeader component.
Let's now also add some styling to TheHeader.vue file
and for that you know what we add,
our style tag here with the scoped attribute
to make sure that the styling only affects this component.
And as before you find a file attached
in this case a header.css file,
which contains the styles you should copy
into those style tags here.
And then, if we reload,
we see this header above our StoredResources,
so this is slowly taking shape.
As a next step,
why don't we also turn the button into a separate component.
A separate component which has some default styling.
Again, try this on your own,
come up with a solution on your own.
We'll implement it together in the next lecture.