So let's add a default button,
which we can use, and that will be another base component.
So I will add it to the UI folder.
And I'll name the file name BaseButton.vue.
Now in there, of course we'll have a template
and there I'll have my button element,
the default button element,
but now it's all about having some default styling
for the button.
So for that I'll add my style tag here
and of course scope it.
And I'm providing some default styling you can take
attached to this lecture in the buttoned dot CSS file.
I'm fully aware that this is probably not the styling
you came up with, but you can now use it.
This sets up a general button style,
also when it's hovered or active.
But then I also have a CSS class,
which we can add conditionally to give it
an alternative look so that we can actually have
one base button component,
which can be configured to look differently
and it should be configurable with props.
So for that I'll also add a script tag here
and add the props option.
And the props I wanna accept here is let's say the type prop
so that we can set the type of the button
and bind the default type attribute to this type prop,
but I'll always accept the mode prop,
which I want to set as a CSS class here,
so I'll bind to class attribute to this mode prop value.
And my idea is that you can then use this base-button
with the mode of flat later, in another component of course.
And if you do so, this flat text here
will be added as a CSS class.
And we do have a selector for this class
giving this button an alternative look.
And of course we could add more classes
to support more alternative looks.
Now that's almost it, but one important thing is missing.
And that's another slot because of course
the content inside of the button, the text for example,
should be passed in from outside.
We could also accept another prop for that, for example,
a captioned prop and use that.
But by using a slot, we give the user,
the developer using our button a bit more flexibility
because now you can not just feed in text,
but you could also pass in an icon,
a SVG icon or any markup of your choice.
Now that's the base button, just like the base card,
I'm going to register it globally so that we can use it
anywhere in this application.
So in main JS, I'm importing it from components,
UI BaseButton.vue.
And I will register it with the component method here
based dash button points at this imported
base-button, like this.
And now that we've got this space button set up.
We can go back to the learning resource
where I'm using a button and replace that default button
with the base-button.
And if we do have that, we should see our new button here.
Now that's the default look.
And I liked that look in many places, but not here.
Here I wanna use that alternative look
and we can achieve this by adding the mode prop
and setting it to flat,
which in this case is the only supported mode, of course,
except for the default look.
But with that, we now have this flat look,
this hopefully also gives you an idea
of what you can do with components.
We now are building a button which can easily be configured
through some props, through some attributes you could say,
and we don't need to write complex styling here.
Instead, the styling is all inside of the button
and whoever then uses our buttoning code
just needs to set these props.
If you were working on a bigger project, in a bigger team,
writing components like this, of course is super powerful
because just one person needs to create the component
and the styling, and then the entire team can use it
and could figure it through props.
So through attributes in the end.
That's also why I'm showing you something like this
in this course, because you need to be able
to do things like that, and you should be aware
of patterns and approaches like that.
Well, and that's our button.
That is the next component added.
And with that, we spent enough time on visual components,
let's come back to adding some logic.
At the moment, we have a list of resources,
but we're still working on all the dummy resources
we started with.
So as a next step, let's make sure we allow the user
to go to add resource form where data like this
can be entered into form inputs
and where then ultimately a new resource can be added
by the user of our web application to this array.