So as a next step
I want to allow the user of this web app
to actually add his or her own learning resources.
So for that we need a form
where users can enter a title, a description and a link
and I actually want to give the user two buttons
which can be used to switch between this view here
where we see the list of learning resources
and that form which we still have to create.
So therefore I will start by adding a new component
in learning resources, and that's the add resource.view file
which is the component where
eventually new resources can be added.
And for the moment in the template
I'll just add a h2 tag
where I simply wanna say add resource
so that we can identify this component
when it's on the screen.
Because I actually wanna start
working on another component first,
and that's the theresources.view component.
I chose this naming because we'll only use that once
in the entire application
and it will be a main entry point
of our resources area here.
And the idea of the the resources component
is that in there we in the end have tabs you could say,
we got two buttons that allow us
to switch between stored resources and add resource.
So therefore in that resources
I'm of course also adding a template.
And in that template, I now wanna have these two buttons.
I'll actually wrap them in the base card component
because I wanna have that card look around the buttons.
And in there we can add a base button.
We'll add two base buttons to be precise,
and so I'll copy that.
And the first button says stored resources,
so this button takes us to the stored resources component.
The second button says add resource
because that, you guessed it will take us to the
add resources component.
And how could we implement this now?
How could we implement this tabs feature?
We can actually use the dynamic component feature
you learned about in the last course module.
So for that, in the script part here
I will add my data property to store some data
that belongs to this component only.
And here I wanna manage the currently selected tab.
Of course that name here is up to you.
And I'll start with the stored-resources tab,
but this can also be changed to add resource
and then I'll use that
to later switch between the two components.
So now I also want a method of course
which allows me to change the selected tab.
So let's add this methods option
to this configuration object,
and here I'll add a set selected tab method
where I get the tab
that should be selected as our argument,
and then we can set this selected tab equal to tab.
Now where should this method be called?
That would be our buttons.
So here on the first button, upon a click
I want to call this method.
So I will point at set selected tab
and tell you how to execute it.
Here you should then execute it
with an argument of stored resources.
And here for add resource,
I'll also add a click and set selected tab to add resource.
And now let's take a quick pause here at this point
because I'm doing something here
which we actually haven't done before.
And do you see what that is?
It has nothing to do with dynamic components.
I'm adding a click listener on base button.
Well, on the one hand this might not be too fancy,
we added click listeners to buttons
for all the entire course.
But keep in mind, this is no regular button.
This is our own custom component,
why can't I add a click listener on it?
I mean, click after all is not a custom event
I'm emitting in there.
If we have a look at the base button,
this component doesn't emit any event,
and here on this button, on the native HTML button
there is no click listener.
This is actually a special behavior Vue has.
When you add props or event listeners on custom components,
then by default they fall through
to the root level element
in that custom components template.
So if I add any props or event listeners
to base button for example,
they will fall through and will be applied
to the root HTML element in base button's template,
which in this case is the native HTML button.
So this click listener here
falls through to this native button here in this template.
So it's automatically added to this button you could say,
that's happening behind the scenes.
And that's an important behavior of Vue.js
which I'm utilizing here.
Which we haven't seen before
because we didn't really have a great place for using that,
but here it's absolutely something that helps us
for wrapping this button.
So with that we can add this click listener here
and change the selected tab upon clicks on those buttons.
Now of course I don't just want you change that data here,
I also want to reflect the change in the user interface.
To be precise I want to render either the stored resources
or the add resource component.
And therefore below my base card here,
I'll now add the built in component, component
which is that component you use for
dynamic components as you learned.
And here we bind the is prop
to tell you which actual component should be rendered here.
So we need to pass the HTML element tag
off our custom component.
Now that's why I'm using my tags here
as selected tabs stored resources and add resource
that will be my custom component HTML tags.
And therefore here we can point at selected tab.
Of course this will now only work
if we register my own components here though.
Because currently add resource is registered nowhere,
and stored resources is registered in the app.vue file.
Now if we register it there,
it's really only available there in the template,
it's not available anywhere else.
So to ensure that stored resources
can be used here in their resources,
I'll remove it from here
because we'll not need it here anymore.
If we would we could register it there as well.
You can register a component locally in multiple components,
but we won't need it here.
Instead I now go to the resources
import stored resources here,
though I need to adjust the import path
because actually the stored resources.view file
is now in the same folder as the resources.view.
And then here in components,
I want to register stored resources.
And the same of course
for the newly added add resource component
imported from add resource.view.
And then register it here as a local component.
Now we'll be able to render both
but we'll have a couple of problems.
Now for one in app view,
I no longer can use this stored resources component,
so we should remove it there from the template.
But in addition, stored resources also wants a prop.
It wants this resources prop
which I use for looping through all the resources.
And now that we're using a dynamic component here,
I'm no longer passing that prop.
So how can we work around that next?