To work around that we got two options.
Option one, is that we pass our props,
to the dynamically rendered component.
There actually is a syntax we could use for that,
and I did add a text lecture about this syntax,
in the last module, after D dynamic component lectures.
But I'll not use it here.
Instead, I'll use that provide inject feature
we learned about, so that we also can practice this again.
And for that, I first of all wanna move,
my stored resources from App.vue.
So move this key NDRA,
and bring it to TheResources.vue.
That of course means that we can now get rid
of the data property, in App.vue,
because we no longer have any data in there.
But now in TheResources.vue, in this component,
we can add this key.
We can add the stored resources to our data here,
and now I wanna provide those stored resources,
so that in the stored resources component,
I can inject them.
And you'll learn how that works.
For this, we can now add the provide key,
and add it in its method form,
so that the we return an object,
where we can provide our resources,
and point at the stored resources,
we have in our data property here.
And with that we're providing the resources,
to all lower level components.
So, to all child components,
and child components of child components.
And that means that in stored resources,
we now only need to change one thing.
Instead of getting resources as props,
we need to inject them.
So that we inject this resources key,
and that is the key I'm providing here,
and with that, we get access to those resources here,
just like that.
So now with all of that done,
I of course need to go back to App.vue though,
and use TheResources component we've been working on.
So import TheResources,
from ./components- learning resources/TheResources.vue,
and register this as a local component here,
in the app config object.
So that here in the app template,
we can render TheResources,
and hence surrender this component
that we've just been working on.
And with that if we reload,
here we got our tabs,
and we can switch between these two components,
and we see the stored resources there as well.
Now, let's maybe highlight which tab is currently selected.
Because currently that's not easy to see,
and thereafter let's of course, work on adding resources.
But to quickly highlight these select the tab,
we can go to TheResources,
which is where we have these buttons.
And in there, I can set the mode,
depending on which resource is selected.
So I will bind the mode here of is first button,
which is used for selecting the stored resources,
and check if the selected tab,
is equal to stored-resources.
If it is, I wanna use the default button style.
So then I'll set the mode to null,
and not pass in any note mode at all,
but otherwise I'll set it to flat.
So that if the other tab is selected,
this first button has the flat style.
And since having all the logic here
in the template is a bit ugly,
though it's also not horrible,
but since I don't want to have it here,
I'll grab it and instead add a computed property.
So here, I'll add computed, the computed option,
and add the storedResButtonMode,
and return this result here.
Now of course, referring to this selected tab.
And we can also already add the addResButtonMode,
and here return this selected tab,
checking if it's equal to add-resource.
And if it is, we'll set it to null,
otherwise we'll use this flat mode.
And now we've got these two computed properties.
We can now use them in the template to bind to mode.
So here mode is bound to storedResButtonMode,
and on the other button,
the mode is bound to the addResButtonMode.
To the other computed property therefore.
And now with that out of the way, this looks much nicer.
So let's next work on this add resource screen,
and let's make sure we can add resources.