So let's work on the Add Resource screen.
On this screen here,
I in the end, want to have a form.
And I'll wrap that form into my good old base card
to have the card look around the form.
And then we can add the form element in there,
the native HTML element,
and now add the different input fields which we'll need.
That will be input field for the title of the resource.
I also want to give it a label to make it clear
what the user should enter here,
and I'll say Title here.
And I'll give the input here, not just a type,
but also an id of title and a name of title.
And on the label,
we can add the four attribute and point at title
to make it a bit more accessible and make it clear
what we're referring to.
I'll also wrap that all into a div,
which will help me with styling later.
And I'll give this div a class of form-control
because that is a CSS class
for which I already prepared some styling,
which we can soon add.
Now let's copy this entire div
because we need more than one control.
We also need a control for the description of the resource.
And actually there,
I don't want to use an input element, but a text area
so that the user has a multi line input field available,
which makes entering longer texts more convenient.
So here, I'll set the id to description
and therefore also set the for attribute on the label
to description,
set the name to description here,
and set the rows attribute here to three,
to define how big this text area will be.
Now I'll copy the first div again,
because now I want an input again for the link.
So here I'll set the for attribute to link,
the id to link, the name to link, and the type to URL,
which is one of the native HTML input elements types,
helping us with entering a URL here.
And now last but not the least, one other div.
And in that div we want to have the button
for submitting this.
So I'll add the base button, set the type to submit,
and also give it a caption, of course,
which will be Add Resource.
One short note about the type on the base button,
I added this type prop,
and I forwarded to the regular type attribute
on the button.
I did mention this fall through behavior earlier though,
and therefore we could actually also remove that
and remove this prop here,
and therefore just use the props
which we really added on our own.
And it would still work because this type,
which I'm setting here on the base button
will automatically fall through to the root HTML element
inside of the base button template,
which is this button.
That's just another note on that.
With that, I have to submit button in place though,
and now I want to add some styling,
which I, of course, prepared in advance.
So I'll add some scoped style slots here.
And attached you find, Add Resource CSS file.
As always, copy the CSS roots you'll find in there
into this style tag in the addresource.view file.
And this will give us some nice styling for this component.
Okay.
So if we save this now,
we should see this form on the screen.
Not too bad, but of course, it's not doing anything.
And we want to ensure that the user is able
to click this button.
We then collect all the user input,
and then we add a new resource based on that input.
Now as before, definitely feel free to try this on your own.
We'll implement it together, step by step
in the next lecture.