So, where are you successful?
Let's implement it together.
And for that I'll first of all add my script section here,
and we definitely need a method here,
a method which should be triggered
when the form is submitted.
I'll name it submitData,
but you can of course use any method name you want.
Here, I now want to get the values entered into this input,
this text area, and this input.
And we've got two main ways of collecting this.
Option one is that we use some data properties
and then we use V-Model or an input listener
to update it with every keystroke.
So to collect the free values in free data properties
and update each data properties value with every keystroke.
That would work and there is nothing wrong with it,
but I will use the good old refs again.
And for that here, I'll add a ref key,
a ref property or attribute on this first input
and named as titleInput.
You know that these ref identifiers are up to you,
but of course you want to pick a name that describes
which elements you are pointing at.
Here I'll add a ref which will be to descInput
for description input.
And on the last input,
I'll add a ref with an identifier off linkInput.
So now we've got these free refs registered
and we can now use them.
We can now use them here in submit data
to get the enter title by referring
to this dollar sign refs titleInput,
which is the ref I did use here, right?
TitleInput, that's the ref I used on this input.
And then this points at the input HTML element object,
which has a value prop,
which holds what the user entered.
And I'm going to repeat that for the entered description
referring to the descInput value.
And for the entered url referring
to this dollar sign refs urlInput.value.
Sorry, that was linkInput,
so it should be linkInput.value.
So now these are the free values the user entered,
and of course they may be empty.
We'll take care about that in a next step,
for the moment I'll assume they're not empty,
and if they are not empty,
then I want to ensure that they get added
to all our resources.
So how could we do that?
We could of course emit a custom event,
and then listen to it in the parent component
of this addResource component.
But since we add this addResource component dynamically,
like this, that will not be super easy to do.
Of course, we don't have to use
this dynamic components here.
We could use VF to switch between two components
and then we could use custom events.
But again, I want to practice provide and inject here.
So therefore I'll stick to provide
and inject and I'll implement it differently.
I'll start in TheResources.vue by adding a new method,
the addResource method.
Here, I want to get the title,
the description, and the url,
and I wanna generate a new resource
and add it to this storedResources array,
whenever this method is triggered.
So in here, I'll create a newResource JavaScript object,
and that object needs a unique ID.
For that I'll just create a timestamp here
by instantiating the date object,
and I'll then get a string timestamp
by calling toISOString.
That is unique enough for this purpose.
Then we need to set a title property in this object
because all our storage resources have a title property,
and they also have description and link properties.
So we'll need to set those two,
and of course, stored values we're receiving
as arguments in those properties.
So add description and set this equal to description
and add link and set this equal to url.
So this now is a new resource,
which now can be added to the storedResources
by simply pushing it there,
or if we want to add it at the top by unshifting,
which is basically like push,
but at the beginning of the array.
So here I'll unshift the newResource.
And I will then also set this selectedTab
to storedResources so that we switched to tab
when we added a new resource.
Now with that back in addResource,
I want to make sure that from inside submitData,
I can call the addResource method
we just add it to TheResources.vue.
How can we make this work?
Well, we can provide this method as well.
So here in provide,
I can add a addResource key.
This key name is up to you though,
but I want to point at this ad resource,
hence I'm pointing at my method.
I'm not executing it here,
I'm just pointing at it.
And now we can inject this addResource key,
entity addResources component.
Here we can add the inject key
and inject addResource like that,
and this allows us to call it here
instead of submitData.
Here, we can now call addResource
and forward the enteredTitle,
the enteredDescription, and the enteredUrl.
We can save that all.
And now if we go back
and I enter some test data here,
something like that,
if I click Add rRsource,
well, I forgot one thing.
Obviously it's nice to have to submitData method,
but I also need to trigger it when the form gets submitted
and currently that's not happening.
So on the form here,
I want to add a submit listener
and all to prevent the browser default
with the prevent modifier.
And then point at submitData
so add this method we've been working on.
And now with data added,
which of course is a quite important step,
with dad added if we go back,
I can add my test data again here
and now if I click Add Resource,
this works and here's our test resource.
And if I click the link, I'm indeed taken to Google.
So that's working,
if I go back by the way the data is lost
because it only exists in memory
as long as our app is running,
we will later learn how we can persist data
and store it on a server just as a side note.
But with that, we added this.
There is one thing I want to fine tune though,
at the moment if I start entering data here
on the Add Resource tab,
and then I leave to tab,
and I come back my entered data is lost,
and that's a scenario we also covered
in the last course module.
We can simply fix this by going to TheResources.vue
and wrapping our dynamic component
with the keep-alive component like this.
If we do that,
the component will be cached
and the data will not be lost.
So if we do that and I now enter data here,
if it switched to tab and come back,
my input is still there.
And with that, the addResource form is almost finished,
but one important piece is missing.
I also want to let the user know
when he or she tries to submit invalid data.
For example, when the title field here is empty.
And at the moment, this is possible.
I of course want to prevent that this happens
and I want to show the user an error message.
And I want to do it as with a nice overlay
with a custom dialogue.
So just as before,
feel free to try this on your own.
Build such an error dialogue
and show it when the user submits invalid data,
we'll build it together,
starting in the next lecture.