So how we ensure that the user is not able
to submit empty data in the add resource component.
Well, of course, we got our free entered input values
and we can edit if check
and check if entered title is empty or to be precise,
I will even call trim on it,
which is a built in method that exists in JavaScript,
which you can call on strings to remove excess white space
at the beginning and end.
This avoids that the user enters a bunch of blanks
and dead would be treated as valid.
Trim Will remove those excess blanks
and we'll therefore still give us an empty input.
So that's why I'm checking it like this.
And if that's the case, or if I entered description,
once we trim it is empty
or if entered U R L trimmed is empty.
If any of that is the case,
then I know the input is invalid.
Now for one,
I will return them to a white
that this line of code here executes
because returning stops the function execution.
But in addition, I also wanna show my alert
and I could do this with the built in alert function,
but I wanna have my own custom dialogue,
which looks a bit nicer,
and therefore I will add a new component
and it will actually add it into UI folder,
a base dialogue dot view file,
which could be used for anything,
but which I will use for showing an error message.
Now in this base style Octa view file in the template,
I will add the built in dialogue,
HTML element and add the open attribute already
so that it's always open,
but will then control visibility by adding
or removing base dialogue to and from the Dom.
And here in the dialogue, it's now totally up to you,
how you wanna structure this.
I will add a header element here.
And in that header,
I will add a slot so that the user is able
to set the header.
But I will actually also provide a default content
between the slot techs,
which will be used if no header would be provided.
And there I'll even take it to the next level,
and I'll output a title property,
which I expect to get as props.
So here I'll add the props key
and expect a title prop on this component.
This gives us as a developer full flexibility.
When using the base dialogue,
we can either just provide the title prop
or we provide our totally customized HTML structure,
which will then be inserted in this header slot.
So we can do both use default with our own custom text
or override it entirely and not just provide our own text,
but also our own HTML code
that should be used in the header.
And therefore I'll actually add my prop differently here,
and be very clear about the fact that title is optional.
It's type is string, but it's definitely not required.
You don't have to provide a title prop
because of course you might also just provide
your own HTML content for this slot.
Now after the header,
I'll add a section and this will hold the main content
off this dialogue.
Here again, I want to give us as a developer
as much flexibility as possible,
and we should be able to bring our own HTML code.
Hence does this again, time for a slot,
but since we now have two slots, we need named slots.
One slot may remain unnamed, but all our slots need names.
So I'll name this slot here,
header because it is our header slot after all.
And then I'll add a third part in this dialogue after header
and the main section, I'll add a menu element,
which again is a default HTML element where I want to allow
the user to display buttons, which the user can press.
And again, the HTML code should be provided
by us as a developer.
So here I will also give this a name actions,
and now we can pass our own HTML code in here.
Now I'm only using this dialogue in one place in this app
and therefore we don't have to build it as flexible
as we're doing it here,
but of course, this is about practicing this all.
And this is about showing you
how you could build a really reusable dialogue,
which you could then use in different places off your app
and use and configure it in a totally different way.
Every time you as a developer use it.
That's why I'm building it in this highly flexible way here.
And I also don't just wanna have the dialogue.
I always wanna have a backdrop behind it.
So I wanna make sure that the page behind
the dialogue is great out.
For div I'll add a div here next to the dialogue like this.
And with that added, we can add some styling,
which I of course also prepared for you.
I'll add my scoped styles again, as always and attached.
You find this dialogue CSS file as always,
it contains a bunch of CSS rules,
which you simply should copy and paste
between your style tags here.
And that will give the dialogue and the header
and this backdrop, the desired styling.
with that we have a base dialogue here.
Now let's see how we can use it.
And first of all, I will, of course, register it globally
so that we could use it everywhere in this app.
So in main JS, I'll import based dialogue
from dot slash components UI base dialogue dot view,
and then added with app component based dialogue
and point at my base dialogue config object.
With that, the dialogue is registered now in ad resource,
we can use it and here it should be shown.
If the user entered something invalid.
for data I'll add my data property here
to the add resource component.
And the one piece of data I wanna manage in here
is information about
whether the user input is invalid or not.
So I will name my property here, input is invalid.
And initially that's false because initially the user input
isn't invalid yet because the user didn't have a chance of
entering anything,
but I'll set this to true if we make it into the safe check.
So if at least one of these inputs is empty, then I'll set
this input is invalid to true.
And now we can use this newly added property
to toggle our dialogue.
Here next to base card.
I will add the base dialogue like this,
and I'll show it with VF.
If input is invalid is true
and now we can provide content for our different slots.
Now I will actually not provide my own header slot.
Instead there I wanna utilize this default fallback
and just set my own title text.
Therefore I'll set the title prop on the base dialogue
and set it to invalid input.
But I do want to provide HTML content
for the other two slots.
So here, I'll now add a template tag
and target the default slot with this shorthand.
The alternative would be V slot colon default,
but you can use the short end and between here.
I wanna have a paragraph where I say, unfortunately,
at least one input value is invalid
and add another paragraph here where I say,
please check all inputs and make sure you enter
at least a few characters in queue, each input field,
something like this.
Of course the error message is up to you.
and now we also need a second template here
to provide the content for the second slot we have
for this actions slot.
So here with v-slot actions or using the shorthand,
we can tell view that's the content inside of the template
should go into that slot.
And there, I want to have one base button
where I simply say, okay.
And I add a click listener to this button.
And now I wanna trigger a method
which allows us to close this dialog.
So they are for a year,
I will register a new method
D confirm error method For example,
where we set this input is invalid back to false,
which will then close the dialogue
and confirm error should be triggered.
If this button here is clicked
this button in the actions of our dialogue.
With all of that, if we saved it and reload this page,
and we go to add resources and we try to submit this,
we should see our dialogue and clicking, okay, closes it.
Now it would be great if clicking the backdrop
would also close it, but currently that's not happening.
So let's add this functionality to the base dialogue.
And therefore on this stiff,
I will add a click listener that div here is our backdrop,
where I want to emit a custom event,
which I'll name close.
And of course this custom event name is up to you.
And actually I will also stay here
and add a fallback content to my actions slot,
even though we don't need it for the way we use it here,
but to make this really reusable.
And I'll add a base button here as a fallback content
where I say close and where upon a click,
I also emit this close custom event
so that if the user would not provide any content
for the actions slot,
this button would be shown at least.
And now with that, I will just let you know about
our emitted custom event about the close event
by adding D emits option to this conflict object.
And now with that, we can go back to add resource
where we are using the base dialogue.
And we can now listen to this close event on this dialogue.
And when this event occurs,
I want to run my confirm error method.
So to same method we execute
when this okay button is clicked
and therefore now with that added,
if we save this and we reload this page,
if I go back here and submit an empty form,
I can now also close the dialogue
by clicking on the backdrop.
And of course also still by using the okay button.
And on the other hand, if we enter something valid here.
So if we do not provide invalid input,
creating the resource still works.
So if that there's only one last thing left
and that is deleting resources,
we'll implement debt as a next step together.