So let's make sure Resources can be deleted.
For that we got this Delete button here
in the learning Resource.view file.
At the moment this button isn't doing anything though.
Now of course it should remove the Resource
on which we click this from our storedResources array
in the Resources.
Now, since we're using dynamic components,
custom events are probably not how we wanna solve this.
And therefore, instead I will do it just like we're handling
it for adding Resources.
I'll add a removeResource method here,
where I expect to get that Resource ID
of the Resource that should be deleted.
And now we need to update our storedResources.
Now, there are two ways of doing that,
and I will, first of all show you the way
that will not work and let you know why it's not working.
The first approach would be that we set our storedResources
equal to a new array, a new array,
which is the rive from storedResources,
but where we use the filter method to filter out
the Resource that has this ID.
For that we could execute a function on every Resource.
JavaScript does this for us automatically.
And we will ensure that the Resource
with the ID we're getting here
gets dropped by adding this code.
This will indeed if I Console.log this,
this will indeed ensure that the Resource
is removed from storedResources.
We can now provide this function
just as we're providing addResource.
We can add deleteResource as a key here,
and point at this removeResource.
Of course you could always use the same names here
if you wanted that.
And now we can inject deleteResource
into the learning Resource component.
Here we can now inject deleteResource
so this newly added key,
which points at the removeResource method.
And when the user clicks this button here
with a click listener, we point at this
deleteResource method, which was injected.
Actually we don't just point at it we also execute it.
And for that we need the idea of the Resource.
So we should expect that as a prop.
And once we do get the idea of this Resource as a prop,
we can use it here to provide it to this
deleteResource method, and therefore
to the removeResource method in the Resources.
Now we just need to ensure that this ID prop is provided.
So in storedResources where we are creating
all the learning Resources, there we now also provide
this ID prop, which we just added.
With that it should work, but you'll notice
that if I click Delete, nothing happens.
On the other hand if I open the developer tools,
we will see that the Resource was deleted.
We can actually see this best if I don't log the Resources.
But for example, the length here.
If the length is one, that means that the Resource
was deleted because initially we have a length of two.
So let's try this again.
If I reload, click Delete, you'll see,
we get a length of one.
So the Resource was deleted,
but we don't see this on the screen.
Why?
Because of provide inject and how it works.
We do provide our storedResources here right.
Now, view executes this provide method
in the end when it creates this component.
So it then injects this storedResources array
into all the components that need Resources.
The thing is, this is an array,
and therefore it's a value stored in memory.
It's a reference value in JavaScript.
When we change this array by pushing or by unshifting,
as we're doing it for adding a Resource
that changes the same array in memory,
which we originally provided,
and therefore view as able to recognize
the changes we made to it.
And all the places that injected this Resources key,
will get notified about those changes.
If we however use this approach,
I'm overriding this storedResources with a brand new array.
And this brand new array is then not reprovided
to all the other components.
So all the components that inject the Resources
are still working with the old, with the original array.
So how can we work around that?
Well, one easy way of working around that here
is that we don't overwrite the old array,
but that instead we use a slightly different approach.
We get the index of the Resource we wanna delete
in our storedResources array.
And we can do this with the findIndex method,
which exists on JavaScript arrays.
Here I wanna find the Resource where the ID
is equal to the Resource ID we're getting as a argument.
That's then giving us the index of the Resource
we wanna delete.
And then we can use the splice method
on the storedResources array to splice.
So to remove this element at this index
and just this element.
This manipulates the original array
instead of creating a new one.
So it's just like pushing and unshifting,
and therefore here view will be able to recognize this
and all the components that injected this array
will notice this as well.
So now if I reload and click Delete,
we are able to delete Resources.
So let's also add a new Resource here
and we can delete that as well.
So that's now all working,
and with that, we got this app finished.
And we used a lot of the concepts you learned about
throughout the last modules.
And therefore hopefully you now have a better idea
of how to work with components,
how to build at least a little bit bigger view applications
and how all these different features are working together.