Now, there's one last feature
which we can implement here real quick
and that's related to the base dialogue.
It works like this, but at the moment,
if we see that dialogue,
it is added deeply nested into our DOM.
It's somewhere nested in some divs
and whilst that works, we did learn about
a nice feature that can help us move it in the DOM,
and that's the teleport feature.
So here in the BaseDialouge.vue file,
I will add the teleport component, which is built into Vue,
and that will wrap both the dialogue
as well as the backdrop with this teleport component.
So here's the closing tag
and now, teleport needs one prop, the to prop,
where are we add a CSS selector telling Vue
where this content should be moved to in the real DOM,
and I will move it directly to the body tag like this.
And if we do that, everything works like before.
It looks like before, but if we inspect this,
we can actually see that now this dialogue
and the div for the backdrop is added here
at the end of our body section.
And that's just a tiny thing, not a must have,
but since we learned about teleport
and since it helps us with our HTML structure,
why wouldn't we implement it?