And for that as so often,
you find a starting project attached, downloaded, extracted.
Run npm install and then npm run serv
once you installed all dependencies.
And this brings up the development server.
Once this up and running,
this is what you should see on the screen.
Now here I prepared a very basic form for us.
We got input field for a text here,
input field for a number.
We got a drop down,
we got some check boxes and we got some radio buttons.
And then also a button to submit the form.
Now let's first of all focus on how we can connect view
to all those inputs
and get information out of these inputs.
Since this is probably something you'll need a lot
in apps you're building.
Let's there after talk about form validation
and how we can add basic validation here.
And let's at the end, also build our own form control.
But step by step, here's TheForm.vue file.
And here you see all the markup for the form
you see here on the screen.
Now this component has no script logic at the moment.
It just has a template and some styles.
So let's actually get started by adding a script object
and let's start by extracting some data out of these inputs.
And for the moment,
I will simply log that data to the console
so that we see that extraction worked.
So we will need a method for that of course,
which is triggered when the form is submitted
and I'll name it submitForm.
That's my method name.
And that's something we already did in this course.
We can now trigger this method here
when this form is submitted.
We could also add a click listener
to the button we have here.
But since buttons, inside of forms,
submit those forms and trigger the submit events,
you typically wanna listen to those submit events instead.
And here, that's also something you already saw quite a bit
in this course.
Here, you typically add the prevent modifier
to ensure that when form submission occurs,
we don't have that browser default.
Which would be that a request is sent
and which would therefore result in a page reload,
which in the end restarts our view app
and we therefore lose all our data.
That's definitely not what we want.
So here I wanna trigger the submitForm method,
and now let's see how we can connect view
to those different inputs.
Now let's start with the text input here for the name.
We have two main ways of getting data out of such an input.
Option one, is that we use the model
or our own custom input event listener for example,
to listen to every keystroke
and store what's the user entered in some data property
with every keystroke.
This is perfectly fine and especially useful
if you maybe also want to validate this input
on every keystroke to show an error message,
even before the user tries to submit anything.
In addition, if you use the model,
you of course have two way binding,
which can also help with resetting the form.
With two way binding,
you can not just listen to what the user entered,
but you can also overwrite what's in the form
and you can change the value which is stored in the input.
And that also can be helpful.
And actually that is what I will do here.
I will add a couple of data properties
and therefore we need this data option
in our component configuration object here,
and I will start by adding a data property
for this name input I have up here for the username.
So let's go down here and let's add a username field.
This name of course is totally up to you.
You can name it whatever you want,
but I'll name it userName
since I'm going to store a username in a here.
And I'll start with an empty string as an initial value.
Now we can bind this with v-model here to this input.
And that means that view will automatically detect
every keystroke, update the value stored in username,
but when on the other hand we change
what's stored in username with our code.
For example, when the form is submitted
and we reset the value,
then our change will also be reflected in this input.
And that's something we can test here.
We're now storing this in userName.
So now in submitForm, we can of course console log username.
So output that we're going to print the username
and then output the concrete values stored in username.
And there after, I'll set this username
back to an empty string.
Effectively resetting what the user entered.
If we now save all of that and open up the developer tools,
I can enter Max here in this name field.
And if I click save data, you see username Max.
So using the value worked.
And you see the input field is empty now
because I did set username back to an empty string here.
And that is all something you learned already.
I'm aware of that.
But this is the foundation of working with user input.
Now, let's build up on that foundation.
Let's learn more about v-model
and let's learn how we can extract values
from these other control types here.