Let's continue with the age.
The age input here is actually of type number.
Now this can be confusing,
just because it's of type number does not mean
what you entered here
will be treated as type number in code.
It looks like a number
and you won't be able to enter anything but numbers here,
but you will not automatically,
get a value of type number in code.
Sounds confusing, let me show you what I mean.
Let's add a new data property userAge, maybe.
Let's set this to an empty string as well,
or maybe to a number, or maybe to null.
Let's maybe use null because I don't wanna use zero.
I also don't wanna use an empty string
because it should be a number.
So I will use null to make it clear
that we have no value yet for this.
Now let's bind userAge to this input here, to this input.
We can do this with v-model that works on this input
just as it did on the first one
and here I can point at userAge now.
Now with that, let's go down here, whoops, to the method
and I will console log userAge,
and I will deliberately use two console logs now
so that I don't concatenate the user age with a string
to a longer string, but so that I keep the type of user age.
Below that I will log a random number, in this case 31
and you'll see why I'm doing this in a second.
I can then also of course, reset it back to null thereafter
to also reset it in the input fields.
With all of that, if we go back,
I can, of course still enter max here,
but I can also enter 31, or 32, or whatever you want here.
If I click save data, you see it was submitted
and you will see that 32 looks just like 31.
So what's the special thing here.
Well, watch what happens
if I retrieved the value not with v-model
or not only with v-model, but if I also add a ref here,
ageInput could be the ref identifier.
And with that ref added, let me go back here
and I will then console log the value
of this ref's ageInput.value.
So I am accessing the native dom element
and I'm then getting access to the value property,
and I'm outputting this here.
If I do this and I enter 32 here,
you'll see something interesting.
This 32 is our internally managed data property,
which is bound with v-model.
This 31 is the dummy number I'm outputting here.
The value, which I'm outputting with refs here is this 32
and the interesting thing is that
this is black and this is blue.
Blue means it's of type number,
black means it's of type string.
So it's a different data type.
Why does this matter?
Well, let's say you continue working
with that number you fetched.
Maybe you add five, let me do this in both cases.
For the property we're managing in our data
and for the property we're getting with refs.
If I am doing that and I enter 32, again,
we get 37 for the data property
but 325 for the ref property,
and that's not a mathematical error.
This is simply a concatenated string,
32 and five combined to one string.
So the interesting thing of what you should be aware here
is that v-model,
if used on an input of type number
automatically fetches the user input
and converts it from a string to a number of data type.
By default, if you would be using just JavaScript
or if you're using refs and therefore
the native JavaScript object representing this input.
By default, what's stored in the value is always a string.
It's an extra feature added by Vue and v-model that it sees
that this input is of type number
and that it therefore converts this string value
to a number of value for you.
You can also force it to do that.
For example, if you use another type here,
you can force Vue to do that conversion
by adding a modifier after v-model here,
the number modifier.
This forces this conversion,
which v-model does automatically here
in case of type number.
Speaking off these modifiers, you might've seen it already,
there are a couple of other modifiers as well.
The lazy modifier allows you to change
how Vue updates the bound property.
If it does this on every keystroke
or if for some inputs, it does this at a lower frequency.
Trim allows you to tell Vue
that it should remove excess white space
at the beginning and end of the text that was entered.
It's the equivalent to manually doing that
with the trim method on this string here.
So with trim added you ensure that you always get an input
with no leading or trailing white space at the end,
which of course is also something that could be useful.
That was a lot of talking about v-model
and it's modifiers and numbers,
but this can be a common bug,
which you add to an application.
That you will think you've got a number
and actually you're working with a string.
It's especially important
to be aware of this special behavior v-model offers to us
because I already mentioned earlier in the course
that you can either use v-model
for getting access to some data or a ref.
Well, turns out you can but behind the scenes
these two approaches have different behaviors
and if you use a ref, which is perfectly fine,
you should, for example, be aware of the fact
that no automatic type conversions take place.
That was enough of the talking about this.
With that, let's see how we can interact
with all the other inputs we got on this page.