So we got the name, we got the age,
what about this drop down this select component?
How can we get the value there?
Well, good news V-Model works on select
just as it does on input elements.
So you can use V-Model in exactly the same way.
For that, we can add a new data property,
which I'll name referrer,
because I'm getting the referrer
or I'm finding out how a user was referred to our page
and I want to bind this to this select drop down.
For this we can just add V-Model
and bind this to referrer,
so to this data property I just added.
And then these values here,
which are set on the individual options
will be stored in referrer whenever we change a value.
Since we're dealing with a drop down here, though,
We might not really want to start with an empty value here
for referrer, this was fine for the text inputs,
where indeed, the inputs are empty at the beginning.
But in the drop down,
we want to start with a default choice.
And to do that, we should have a look at the values
that are used behind the scenes for these options
and pick our favorite starting value,
maybe word of mouth, so the wom identifier.
And that's then the value which I want to store initially
here in the referrer.
It's also the value to which I want to reset it here.
So I will console log referrer and output this referrer.
All that a plus here,
enter after set this referrer equal to wom.
Was that if we saved as you see word of mouth
is pre selected if we reload
and I can change this,
and if I save that we get referrer Google here.
And I'm getting referrer Google because I've changed it
to Google before I submitted this,
just in case you were confused.
If I submitted with word of mouth selected,
I get the word of mouth identifier here.
So that is how easy it is
to get values for a select drop down with a view.