So, now we know how to get values with v-model.
We also already saw that an alternative to that
could be refs.
Refs behave differently,
but if you only want to read data once,
they can be a great alternative.
Now I will stick to v-model here,
and I want to dive at least briefly into input validation.
We already did some validation in the last course project
where we showed this error alert if one input was empty.
And of course that is something you can do.
In your submit method you can check all the values
and if some value doesn't satisfy some condition,
you want it to have satisfied,
you can show an error alert, nothing wrong with that.
We could also validate certain inputs on every keystroke
or whenever the input blurs.
For example, here on the name,
we could watch for the blur event.
So, when the input loses focus, and then we could check
if the value stored in there is valid.
And if it is not, we could show the user an error message.
Here's how we could implement this.
We can add a blur listener to the input.
Blur is a built in event,
and we could then trigger a method,
validateInput for example,
which we add to our methods down there.
Here, I'll add a new method, validateInput.
And now we could add a new data property here,
userNameValidity, which initially let's say
is pending because we don't know it yet.
The user didn't have a chance of entering anything.
And here in validateInput,
we could then check if this.username,
so the data property which we're updating with the model,
if this.username, once we trim it,
or we already trim up there with v-model as you learned.
So, let's maybe do that so,
that we don't need to do it again in the code down there.
So, we check if this username is equal to an empty string,
which means it would be invalid.
Then we can set this.usernameValidity to invalid.
Else, we set this.usernameValidity to valid.
It's no longer pending because now we know that it is valid.
And with that, we could then for example,
go up to the input again,
and add a paragraph below the labeled input
where we say, please enter a valid name.
And we only show this with the if,
if userNameValidity is equal to invalid.
So, not if it's pending and not, if it's valid.
We could also add a conditional clause here
to this form control.
Let's say we add an invalid class
if userNameValidity is equal to invalid.
So if that yields true,
this invalid class is added to this div
and we could utilize this in our CSS code
here at the bottom.
For example here, to check if we have a form-control div,
which also has the invalid clause on it
and then target the input element in there
to give it a border color of red.
And maybe repeat that rule here to all the target label
and give that a text color of red,
to highlight the invalid input.
And if we do all of that and reload,
it initially looks fine.
But if you click in there
and then don't enter anything valid
and click out of there, it gets this blur event.
And hence we get our error message and our error styling.
And if we enter something valid here
and then blur it again, we remove that.
And if we enter a bunch of white space
that also gets this styling
because we have the trim modifier.
And that's just one idea I want to give you.
There are thousands of different ways
of implementing validation,
and you can also definitely implement it
in a more flexible and dynamic way than I did it here.
But it is important to be aware of patterns like this,
since this allows you to build
the user interfaces and user experiences,
you probably want to offer to your users.
So, that's it for now about validation.
One possible way of adding live validation
before something is submitted,
not that the other approach would be wrong,
but just to also show this,
now, let's see how we can build our own form controls.