Well, it would be nice
if we could use our own control, the rating control,
just like the built in inputs.
So if I could use the model on this
and then simply bind the value
that this control has internally
to some data property I store here
so that I have a rating here initially, it's null,
and I bind rating with v-model to the rating control.
It would be nice if we could use it like this.
And we can, you might remember
that at the beginning of the course
relatively at the beginning,
I explained that v-model on an input element was
in the end, just a short cut.
It was a short cut for a manually listening
to the input event and binding the value attribute.
You might remember this.
I mentioned this at the beginning v-model is
just a shortcut for this
and that's something we can leverage.
Now the input event and the value prop.
That's specific to input elements here,
but if you use v-model on a custom component,
that is something which is supported by Vue
and Vue will set a very specific prop.
If you use v-model on a component,
it will set the very specific prop in that component.
And it will listen to a very specific event,
which you can emit in that component.
Now, which prop is that and which event is that?
Let's go to rating control,
as I just said, v-model we'll set a specific prop.
So therefore we should declare that prop
and that prop, which will be set is the model value prop.
So using v-model on a custom component is
like manually binding the model-value prop like this
that's one thing v-model does
under the hood on custom components.
The other thing is the special event that's submitted
that is the update model value.
Yes, this looks strange,
but you can name your events, however you want.
And this is the name Vue will be waiting for,
when you use v-model on a custom component.
So using v-model here is like manually binding model value,
the model value prop and listening
to the update model value custom event.
If you use that,
it's the same as if you use v-model.
So therefore, if we accept this prop in our component
and emit this event, we can use v-model on our component
and therefore back rating control.
All we got to do here is we have to emit
this update model value event in our activate method.
And forward this option to v-model,
and also initialize our active option
with the model value we get on the prop here,
so that the form component.
So this component here is able to set our initial value
so that this rating initial value here,
which we bind to v-model is the initial value reflected
in our component.
And if we do all of that,
we can go back to the form
and now start console logging this console log rating,
and console log this rating therefore whoops, this rating,
and also reset rating to null their after
and see whether that works.
And if we reload,
we can choose our different options.
But if I submit this,
we also see the option we picked here being output
in the console.
Now, what we also see though is
that resetting doesn't seem to work.
If I submit this, I do set rating back to null here,
but unfortunately this does not reset it here.
And therefore our visual feedback is not in sync
with the value stored in rating here.
Now, why is this happening?
Well, because we only use the model value prop
to initialize active option,
but there after the model value is not reflected
in our active option here.
And that's of course a problem.
We can work around that though.
Instead of using the data here,
which wouldn't react to changes in our model value,
which come from outside,
we can simply use a computed property here.
We can set up active option as a computed property.
Now what's my idea here?
Well, we are emitting this event here.
Whenever we pick a new option.
And this event is picked up by the model
and the option which we picked will
then be stored in our rating data property there
because it's that property which be bound to rating control.
Now v-model works such that this value is
then fed back into this component.
So this prop value
the model value prop value will be updated
whenever we emitted this event.
So now we can just use active option here
and return this.model value,
or of course, skip this altogether
and just use model value
instead of active option here in the template.
That would also work because that holds the value,
which we passed here to activate.
And of course, then inactivate,
we can get rid of this line as well.
So now if we save that and reload,
we can still select different options,
but now if you reset it, this has cleared
and now this stale for in sync with the rest of our form.
And that is how we can build custom controls.
We build regular components
and we listen to this special prop,
or we use this special prop
and we emit this special event.
That's the whole idea here.