And that is it for this module.
We had another look at v-model,
and how we can use it to get user input,
but also how we can manipulate this user input,
for example, to reset it.
We had a first look at validating user input,
and how we could show an error message
before the forum was submitted,
which is not a must to do,
but simply an option you could use.
And we had to look at different inputs,
different ways of using v-model
with trim or with number inputs.
We had to look at using v-model
with selects, with check boxes,
both groups of check boxes and single check boxes.
And we had a look at radio buttons.
And last but not least,
you learned how to build your own control on
which you can use v-model thanks to this special prop
and to special event, which v-model uses under the hood
if you use it on a custom component.
And that's all we got to know about forms for now,
with that, you should have a pretty good toolbox full
of useful tools that help you build the user experiences
you need in your applications.