Now, before we dig deeper into components
and we learn more about this amazing
and very important feature,
we need to change how we write our code.
I mean, not the language or anything like that,
but our setup, because it turns out that this setup,
which we're currently using of having one JavaScript file,
which we import here into one HTML file,
which we simply opened by double-clicking on it,
and where we have to reload the page
whenever we wanna see a change,
that setup will not really scale well.
We'll have problems with that setup
if we start building bigger, more realistic applications,
and therefore, in this module,
we're going to dive into a better development setup
with the Vue CLI, so with an extra tool we can use
to basically give us a better project setup,
which in the end will help us write Vue apps,
build Vue apps at scale, so build bigger Vue apps
and simply have a better time building Vue apps.
Now, for that in this module,
you will of course learn what exactly the Vue CLI is,
and even more important than that,
why we need that extra tool,
why specifically we need that better setup,
and of course, I'll show you how to use that Vue CLI tool
and how to create better project setups,
and then, work with them.