Before we start using the Vue CLI
before we start creating those better project setups,
which I talked about.
Let's understand why exactly
we might need such better setups.
Now here's one thing which we will, for example need,
a proper development web server.
Now, what do I mean by that?
Currently we're testing our Vue application
by double clicking the index HTML file,
and then seeing it in the browser.
This works, but it's actually unrealistic.
It's actually not how we wanna test this, why?
Because with that,
we actually use the file protocol
instead of the HTTPS protocol, you can see this here.
This is loaded as a file in the browser.
Now, if a load, a page like google.com,
this is not loaded as a file, instead here,
this is loaded as a website using the HTTP
or actually the HTTPS protocol.
And that is a totally different thing that influences how
the pages served and also which features
are available in our code.
So which features we can use in our Java script code
and with that file protocol thus far, everything worked,
but that wouldn't stay that way
because indeed certain modern JavaScript features
would not really work in that file protocol set up.
And in addition, there's one important thing you have
to keep in mind the users of your website,
of your Vue web app.
So the users you wanna target with your app,
they will in the end wizard a website, right?
You're building a website which eventually
will be hosted on some server.
So therefore the final app,
which your users see will be hosted by a server
and therefore will be served via HTTPS,
not wired a file protocol
that filed protocol is only available locally
on your computer if you double click the HTML file,
that's not what will be used once the webpage is served
to your users by a server in the end,
and therefore you are doing something which is not really
good, you are testing your web application under different
circumstances then your users will see them in the end.
Now I can tell you thus far that wouldn't make a difference.
What you learned over the last modules
applies in exactly the same way
no matter how the HTML file is served,
but going forward,
we definitely wanna switch
to a more realistic development set up.
And we, for example,
definitely wanna have a development web server,
which is a web server running locally on your machine so
that you don't need to pay for any server right now,
you can still test everything locally on your machine,
but with an important difference,
this development web server,
which I will show you how to set up,
it will be very easy, no worries.
This development web server will serve your web app,
your HTML file, why are the HTTPS
or the HTTP protocol on your machine?
Not why are the file protocol.
And that will be one important difference.