Now, besides to need
for a web development server,
there also are other reasons for switching to a different,
to a better development setup,
because you might not have noticed it yet,
but actually you might want a better developer experience,
thus far the way we wrote code, it worked,
but it has certain flaws.
Our current way of writing and testing
the Vie App has flaws.
So let's see what our current state is.
At the moment, we always need to reload the page
whenever we make any change to our code.
So for example, here,
if I go to my JavaScript file, and let's say,
I do change some data here,
changed the name to Manuel Lorenzo
and when I see this on the page,
after saving the JavaScript file, I need to reload the page.
Now this might not sound like a bad thing,
I mean it's really easy and quick to do,
but if you're working on an application on a web application
for hours and days
and you're writing a lot of code and you wanna test
a lot of things,
always having to reload can be very annoying.
It's also worth noting that when you reload,
of course you lose all the state of your application.
If this was expanded and you reload,
you're back to the initial loading state again,
and those tiny things can add up
and actually cost you a lot of valuable time
and make development unnecessary, harder,
or simply take longer.
And that's not something you might want.
In addition at the moment in our IDE in our code editor,
Visual Studio Code,
the support we get by that tool is highly limited.
For example, the auto-completion is highly limited.
If I, for example, want to call Vue.createApp,
Visual Studio Code doesn't even understand
that there is a vue object available.
If I type a dot,
it doesn't know which methods I can call on this.
It suggests create app here because I used it before
in that file,
but if I didn't, it wouldn't know that it exists.
So that's all the something which is annoying.
It would be nicer to get better IDE support,
to get more IDE auto-completion and for example,
to also get warnings and errors,
if we add a typo.
At the moment,
if I call creatApp like this, because I forgot to E,
yes, the app won't work and we'll get an error here
in the browser into JavaScript console,
but we don't get any warning in the editor.
And it would be nice to get a better support here
so that we don't even try to run code,
which has a simple typo will like this.
Now last but not least thus far,
I always worked with one HTML and one JavaScript file,
and we could add more files and combine them,
but we would have to manage all those imports
with script source text, for example, manually.
And from multiple HTML files,
it wouldn't even be that easy
because whilst we could have multiple files,
if we switch between those files,
we would always in the end load a new page
and therefore lose all the states
that might've been saved in JavaScript.
So any intermediate results of calculations and so on.
So currently we're kind of limited regarding
how we can split our code,
how we can make our code more readable.
And of course at the moment having just
one JavaScript files works,
we don't have that much code,
but it's easy to imagine that as we build
more and more complex applications,
we have more and more code,
and we might want to split that code across multiple files
to make every file itself a bit more readable.
And for example, things like this template here,
which we have for this component,
having it in a string like this is a bit annoying,
but at the moment, it's all we can do.
We have no better way of defining this template,
we can't do it in the HTML file because for components,
we can't mount them to HTML as we do with Vue Apps.
So that's another thing that would be great
if we could get rid of it.
And therefore, our current state clearly
has some room for improvement.
Our wanted state might look like this.
It would be great if saved changes.
So whenever we change something in code
and we saved those changes would be auto-detected,
and then the page would automatically reload,
or maybe even better than that, not just reload,
but simply update that part of the page that did change
and therefore keep all our state around.
That would be great, it would save us a lot of time.
The IDE, so the code editor,
we're using should provide better auto-completion and hints
to make sure that we're able to find errors quicker
and avoid writing code that doesn't work.
And it would be great if we would have an easy time
splitting our code across multiple files,
defining the templates of components in a nicer way,
and using modern JavaScript features like ES modules
for export and import in JavaScript code
into each other for that.
That would be nice and that's our wanted state.
And that's exactly where the Vue CLI is able to help us.
So let's find out what exactly the view CLI is,
how it helps us and how we use it.