Now, the Vue CLI
is not a mandatory tool.
Let me really make that clear.
It's not the same as the Vue framework
which we've been using thus far.
It's just an additional tool,
also managed by the team behind Vue.
It simply helps us create projects
with a certain configuration
and with certain built-in tools
that give us all those nice features I was talking about
in the last lectures.
So it helps us create projects
and manage projects that allows us
to build more realistic, bigger applications.
So how do we use the Vue CLI?
Well, the Vue CLI under the hood uses certain tools,
which you will need.
The most important tool, which you will need is Node.js.
Node.js is a JavaScript runtime,
which in the end allows you
to run JavaScript code outside of the browser as well.
You could use Node.js to write server-side code
with JavaScript but that's not what we're going
to do in this course.
This is not a Node.js course.
So you will not learn Node.js here
and you will also not need to write any Node.js code.
No worries.
But we need Node.js installed on our machine
because the Vue CLI uses it under the hood.
So make sure you visit nodejs.org
and simply download the latest version there.
This gives you an installer,
which you can download
and you can simply walk through that installer
and confirm all the defaults.
It's available for all operating systems
and it's a really straightforward installation process.
You don't need any special settings or setup
or anything like that.
Simply walk through that installer
and install Node.js on your system,
no matter if you're using Windows or macOS or Linux.
Now, once this finished,
you've got Node.js installed,
which the Vue CLI needs,
but you've also got this npm tool installed here.
That's another tool that comes together with Node.js.
Npm stands for Node Package Manager
and that's a tool which we're also going to use,
for example, to install the Vue CLI on our system,
but also later to install extra packages
into our project which we might need.
I'll come back to that when we need it.
So let's finish that installation
and let's now see how we install the Vue CLI.
For that, we can to installation, the official docs
but it's really straightforward.
You need Node installed, as I mentioned,
and then once you did install Node,
you can run this command here
in the terminal or command prompt of your system.
So open up your system terminal or command prompt.
Every operating system comes with one.
So here I'm in the macOS terminal.
On Windows, you would use the Windows command prompt.
And in there, run npm install -g @vue/cli.
Like this.
On Mac and Linux, you might need to add sudo
in front of this to get the right permissions.
On Windows, this is not required
and actually also will not work.
So on Windows, it's just npm install -g @vue/cli.
Now, once you entered this command, hit Enter.
Maybe enter your password if you're prompted for it.
And now this will go ahead
and install this Vue CLI tool globally on your system
so that we can thereafter use it
to generate Vue projects with it.
So let's wait for this installation to finish.
Now, once it finished successfully,
which you can tell by the fact
that you see a message like this towards the end
of this output,
once it finished,
you can find a place on your system
where you wanna create a new project.
And with find a place,
I mean here in the terminal.
You can navigate around with the cd command
in case you're not sure about that
and make sure you pick up some terminal
or command prompt basics.
Now, once you've found that place on your system,
so the path on your system
where you wanna create a new project,
for me, it's in the udemy folder somewhere on my system,
you can run vue create to create a new project folder
and a new Vue app therefore in that place.
And then pick any name of your choice.
I'm going to name this vue-first-app
with dashes between the words.
But the name is up to you.
It should be a name without any white space though.
So it should be one word in the end
where you can separate words with dashes
if you want to.
Hit Enter thereafter
and you will be prompted a couple of questions.
Now, the exact look of this menu might change
but here, I'm currently asked
whether I wanna use the default settings
for Vue 2,
the default settings for Vue 3.
Now, most likely, Vue 3 will be the first choice
in the future.
I'm recording this at a point of time
where Vue 3 is not fully final yet.
It is not really released yet,
hence for me it's just the second option here.
Or you can manually select features you wanna have
in your new project.
Now, I'm going to go with that.
And now here, you've got various features,
which you can configure into your project.
Now, if you don't know what all these things are,
you can really just go with the default,
otherwise you can add them as needed.
There are a couple of features in here,
like Router and Vuex,
which we'll learn about throughout this course.
So for the moment, we can really go with the defaults here
and simply hit Enter to confirm them.
Choose the Vue version if you're prompted for it.
I'll go with 3.x, which this course is about.
The latest version of Vue.
And you should choose that as well if you're prompted.
And here, with the ESLint settings,
I'll go with that ESLint
with error prevention only strategy.
Confirm the default here as well
if you're asked for it.
And you can go with the first options here
in this last question as well.
Again, the exact options might differ
but the process should always be close
to what you're seeing here.
Now, we could save our picked settings here
as a default or as a preset for future projects
but I'm going to pick no here.
And not save it as a preset.
And now, this will create a new folder
with the name we chose initially
with the Vue project inside of it
but now with a Vue project
that has certain extra features
to make our life as a Vue developer easier.
No worries though,
you'll still write Vue code
as you learned it over the last modules.
It'll just be a nicer experience.
So let's wait for the Vue project generation to finish.
And once this does finish,
you see two commands here,
which you can execute
in order to see your generated Vue app in action
because you get a little dummy app
in that newly created folder.
So we can, first of all, cd.
So navigate into this newly created folder
and then run npm run serve,
which executes a predefined script
to basically spin up such a testing web development server
I was talking about,
which will then host this default dummy app we got here.
And you can view that app in your browser
under this address now,
which now uses the HTTP
instead of the file protocol,
which, as mentioned in an earlier lecture,
is exactly what we want.
So let's copy that address
and enter this in the browser
and you should see something like this.
Now, the exact screen you're seeing here
might change over time.
This doesn't matter too much
because we're going to write our own app anyways.
But you should see something on the screen,
which proves that your development server
is up and running
and that some Vue project was generated.
Now let's explore what was generated,
which features we have available here
and which extra settings and tweaks we might need to do.