Thus far, we're using Visual Studio Code
in a fairly simple and trivial configuration.
Now, it's time to install one extra extension
that will help us with Vue development.
For that go to view extensions in Visual Studio Code
and their search for vetur.
This is an extension which you should install
into your Visual Studio Code.
I already got it installed,
but I will need to enable it.
And once you installed it,
you will see that in those .vue files,
you now do get highlighting.
You now do have an IDE that understands those files.
And with that I can go to the explorer view here.
And now, vetur is an extension
that does not just make Visual Studio Code
understand .vue files,
but which will help you with Vue development in general.
So, vetur is a must have extension for Vue developers.
It will help you with auto completion.
It will ensure that you have a better development experience
just by installing that extension.