So now that we got this extension installed,
that we've got our project created,
and a running development server,
let's see what else we got here in the source folder.
We got this .vue file which maybe is still something
you need to get used to, but in the end,
that's just a file that contains the configuration
for a Vue app or a component,
and then, the template for that app or a component.
So what we previously defined just in the DOM
in the HTML file or as a template string,
which was pretty unreadable,
what we defined like this before is now simply defined
in such a template tag in a .vue file,
in such a single-file component.
You also got a assets folder with a little image,
that's in general where you would add images your app needs,
and a components folder holding another Vue component.
Now, the exact code you're seeing here
and also here might differ over time, by the way,
but you should have some component
in your components folder,
and that is indeed how we will write Vue apps
for the rest of the course.
We'll split our code into components
and compose our user interface
and the entire Vue app by combining those components.
And I'd say that's already enough
of the talking about the setup.
We now understand why we have it and how it works.
Let's now go back to components
and build up on such a Vue CLI-generated project
to dive deeper into components
and again, learn more about Vue.