For this, I got a brand new project for you.
You'll find it attached to this lecture, simply download it,
extract the folder and store that folder
anywhere on your system, as you did at many times before.
And you'll notice one important thing.
This is a project which I created for you
with the Vue CLI.
So therefore here, you don't need to create it on your own.
You can just use this attached one.
It is a project which I created with Vue create though.
I'm attaching it,
so that we're all using the same project set up.
Now in here, you'll notice something interesting.
The source folder is pretty empty.
There's just a main JS file in there
with not a lot of content.
So therefore here I got no view code,
no view app and no view components in there.
And I'm doing this on purpose so that we can get started
with that together and you will learn step by step,
how to write Vue code and how to add Vue components
in a brand new Vue project like this one.
Besides that, we got the public folder
with the index HTML file,
which I already explained in the last module.
Now to get started writing code,
there are two things which we need to do first.
The first one is that we install all the dependencies
of this project.
So the dependencies mentioned in the package dot Json file.
These dependencies and also D development dependencies.
Because the attached folder D attached sip file
has no node modules folder.
Not because I forgot it,
but because it's super big and the sip file
would be multiple hundred megabytes big,
if I would have added it.
That's too big and there is no needs to add it
because all you need to do is run NPM install
inside of the project folder.
And here's the easiest way of doing that,
in visual studio code,
in which you should open this attached folder.
Go to terminal, New terminal.
And this will open up your default system terminal,
your default system command prompt here
as part of visual studio code.
The advantage is that you don't have to switch
to a different screen and even better,
that you're already navigated into this folder.
So you don't need to use the CD command
to navigate somewhere else.
Instead, this terminal already is navigated
into this project folder.
And therefore in this terminal,
you should now run NPM install
to install all the dependencies of this project.
And whenever you're downloading one of my code snapshots,
which you will find throughout the course,
you should also run this command If you want to run my code.
Because all code snapshots attached to any lecture
will be missing the node modules folder.
So hit Enter,
and this will now download all the required dependencies
and also the dependencies off dependencies.
And it will generate these node modules folder,
and store all the dependencies in there.
So let's wait for this process to finish.
And once it is finished we got the node modules folder,
and we're now ready to get started
running our development server.
By the way,
you can ignore that this file changed the color here.
That's just because I'm using Git,
a version control system as well,
but you don't need to use that.
So you can ignore that.
So as a next step, let's now run NPM run serve.
This will start this development script,
which spins up D development server.
And I'm doing this in the same terminal,
which I used for running NPM install.
So did I do it in this project folder,
which is where you should run this command.
And now we got that development server up and running
and we should keep it up and running as mentioned before,
as long as we're writing code.
This ensures that any changes will be picked up
and we can see them on the serve page.
And the serve page will even reload automatically
whenever we do change anything.
So therefore we'll keep this up and running
and it'll just shrink it a bit
so that it doesn't take up as much space.
But I will still have it around.
Now we can visit local host, 8080.
And that's our running Vue application.
And as you can clearly see, initially it's empty.
There's nothing here.
And the reason for that simply is that,
well, we don't have anything here.
We just got this main JS file,
which creates an empty view app without any configuration.
Well, now that we got all set up,
let's dive into writing some component code
and let's learn more about components.