Let's come back to the example
you saw earlier in the course about this list of contacts.
I mean, that is how we got started with components.
So that's where I want to pick up.
For that, here in the source folder, I will first of all,
create a brand new file and I will name it App.vue.
You don't have to name it App,
but it is a convention to name your main file,
which holds your main vue app configuration, App.vue.
.vue is the extension which I'll use
so that I can use these signal file component features
in that file.
Having a separate template, script and styling section,
I like that a lot.
It helps me split that logic
and yet have it all in one place.
And therefore, we will work with such vue files
a lot throughout this course and in any Vue application
you are going to build.
So App.vue it is.
And now in here, we can create two of these three sections
you saw before.
Create a template tag, opening and closing, like this
and create a script tag, opening and closing.
We don't need a style tag for the moment.
We'll add it later.
Now I will emphasize, again,
this is not code that would normally work.
It's also not a JavaScript file.
It's a DoD vue file.
So only does vue project set up knows how to handle it.
And behind the scenes Vue will basically transform this all
to just regular JavaScript code,
which the browser will understand.
But we're going to use this setup
since for us as a developer, that will make life easier.
And now in these script tags,
we provide the configuration for our Vue app here.
For the app, we wanna mount to this div here
in the index HTML file.
So therefore we create a standard JavaScript object here,
and we can also store this in a constant named app
if we want to.
And in here, we can now add what we learned about.
We can add data, we can add methods, we can add computed.
We can add whatever we need in this Vue app.
Now for the moment, I don't need methods and computed,
but here in my main app,
I wanna add some data.
And therefore, we'll return our object here,
as we learned it.
And in there have my friends, right?
Because that is what we had
in the component intro module as well.
And there we had two friend elements
where every element was just an object with an ID.
For example, we had Manuel here with a name,
which again, could be Manuel Lorenz or whichever friend name
you want to add, with a phone number
where I just going to a random phone number here
and an email where I will also just enter
a fictional email address.
And then we can duplicate this to also have a second friend.
And I used Julie before.
So I'm going to repeat that name,
Julie Jones, also with a random phone number here.
And again, this is all really up to you.
And here I have julie@localhost.
So now we got data in our app config object here.
And if we leave aside how we use this object,
because currently we're not using it at all,
except for storing it in this constant.
If we leave that aside, it's just what we learned, right?
We have an object with a data method
where we return the data object.
So that's all what we learned before as well.
Now this should be the config object for our main app here.
How do we now get this config object in the App.vue file
into our create app method in main JS?
Well, we're going to use this import syntax here,
which you already see here.
This is a modern JavaScript feature,
which we use in Vue CLI created Vue projects
to combine different JavaScript files
and export a feature in one file
and use it in another.
For that, we import something from,
and then you point at the file from what you want to import.
And here you should use a relative import
starting with ./,
which means it's in the same folder as this file,
and then the file name.
In this case, App.vue.
The import here looks a bit different.
It's not ./vue here
because here we're importing from a package
from this Vue package.
And if you're importing from a package,
you just reference the package name.
But if you're importing from a custom file,
like App.vue, you specify the path to that file.
Now that ... is not the valid syntax though.
Instead, we could import a named export
by using curly braces or a default export.
Now you might not know what the difference is.
Here, we're going to use a default export
by just coming up with any name of our choice here
and importing that from that file.
And this identifier here is really up to you.
It could be hello.
It could be something.
But typically you name it just like the file was named
because in there we have our main app configuration.
So I'm going to name it App here as well.
And this is now what we pass to create app,
because App, what we import here
should just be this JavaScript object,
this Vue config JavaScript object.
However, at the moment, we're not exporting this here.
To export it, we should rather not store it in a constant,
which would only be available in this file
and not in any other file, but instead we use a syntax,
which is also default modern JavaScript.
Export, the export keyword and then the default keyword.
And this tells JavaScript that this object here
is the default export of this App.vue file.
And that means that whenever we import like this,
we're going to import that default.
So we're going to import that object.
So we're sharing this object from the App.vue file
to the main JS file.
And therefore, in the end,
we passed this config object to create App here.
And we're splitting this in multiple files
just to organize our code
and to make every file focused on a certain task
and therefore, the overall project, more readable,
which will really shine if you're building bigger,
more complex projects.
So now, long story short, we got our app config object here.
Now you'll notice one thing.
This Vue app, which we create here in the end
has no template.
We mount it to the div with ID app,
but this is an empty div.
Now, if we would have something in there like h2 tag,
we could, for example, use Vue features in there.
That's what you learned.
But in Vue CLI created projects like this,
this is typically not what you do.
You'll leave that index HTML file alone.
Instead, that is what we have this template section for
in a .vue file.
Here, we can now define the template of this Vue app.
So here we could now add h2, tag,
and say, my friends.
And then below that, for example, add an unordered list
where we wanna output all those friends here like this.
And we could also wrap this all into a section
if we wanted to.
So we can write our HTML code for this script here.
And this is just regular HTML markup.
Now, if we saved that all and we go back to the page,
local host 80:80 with the development server up and running,
this page automatically updated without you reloading it
to show our app content.
So to show this parsed and rendered template,
which we defined for our main app.
And that's how we work with those .vue files
and with a project set up like this.
Now this has nothing to do with components thus far.
That's just a different way of creating our Vue app.
But it's important to understand this
because we will create components basically in the same way.
So let's do that as a next step.
Let's add our first component in the setup
before we then really dive into component communication.