So let's now add our first component
because this is just our main Vue app.
But I mentioned before in the component introduction module,
that in Vue you have both.
You have Vue apps and you have Vue components.
And every component is like a mini app where you just have
the possibility of combining multiple components
into one app and where eventually covered
in the next module.
Those mini apps,
those components will also be able to talk to each other
and you'll be able to build complex user interfaces
by combining different components together.
Now, it is a convention that you create a new folder
and you fold another file named components
and your source folder to hold your components.
Simply just to make it clear that these are now components
and not just any Vue app.
Now in here,
I'm going to add my new FriendContact.vue file to hold
the friend-contact component,
which I want to create.
You might remember that is the component we created
in the component introduction module.
Now, if we have a look at the file name,
just like with app.vue,
I want to make clear what's inside of this file.
It will be a component of otherwise,
it wouldn't be in a components folder,
but it will be the component
for displaying a friend contact.
You could name just whatever you want.
Could all just name it, just contact.
But since I plan on naming the component
to custom HTML element FriendContact,
I want to reflect this and the file name as well.
And you could also name it like this.
This is the so called cab up case naming convention,
but it is more common to use this PacalCase naming,
where you have one word
possibly consisting of multiple words,
where you start every word,
including the word inside of the word
with a capital character.
Now inside of FriendContact.vue,
since it's a Vue file,
we can again create our template area here
and also our script area just like before.
And again, in this script area,
I'll export a default object.
This will be the configuration object for this component.
Because keep in mind,
an app component is like a small Vue app.
It takes the same configuration object.
So of course we need to export one.
Now in the component introduction module,
we then added a template key here to define
the HTML code of this component in a string.
We don't need to do this anymore.
We now got this template area
in the FriendContact of Vue file.
And that's exactly why we use those .vue files.
It makes it much more convenient to create such components
and defined their templates.
We don't need to do this in JavaScript strings anymore,
where we get no auto completion and which is really,
really just not fun.
So instead here,
I'm going to create my component markup.
So that's the same markup I used
in the component, introduction module, our list item,
and in there and h2 tag where I output
the friend.name,
and then also a button below that,
where I said show details though,
we're soon going to make this dynamic
and then a nested unordered list in here
like this,
whoops, like this,
where we then have to list items
one for the phone number,
one for the email address,
and here I have a strong tag where I say phone,
and then here we output friend.phone,
and on the second list element we say email
and then we output friend.email.
That's just the same markup we used before
in the component introduction module.
Now for this to work,
we need to add the data field again here
and return some data for this component,
which is now specific to that component,
and only to that component.
So which is independent from our main Vue app data.
And there we had the details or visible property,
which initially is false,
which we'll use to make this button work
and toggled this list.
And we had a dummy friend property,
which will later replace,
but where for the moment
I will just store manual so that
we can output something here.
Again that is something will change later though.
And now we will also need to add methods here
in our conflict object
and add a toggle details method here
to set this details are available
to what they're currently not.
And here I'm already getting
better IDE auto-completion
simply because we're in such a .vue file
and we got the virtual extension installed.
So that's already one first advantage in action.
Which we have just by switching to this project set up,
with this extra view extension.
Now we can connect our template here
and add a click event listener to the button
where we trigger toggle details and
add V=if here on the onward list and check
if details are visible is true
and only showed us if it is true.
And now we've got the finished friend contact component.
Now we register it just as you learned it
in the Vue component introduction module.
In main.js, we create our app.
We can store this app in a constant
and call mount on this app,
but then we can also call the component method here.
And again, here,
I'm now getting auto-completion by the way,
the IDE suggests to me that there is a component method
and it even tells me which arguments I should provide.
And we provide a name friend contact.
And as a second argument,
the conflict object for this component,
which lives in a different file
and therefore needs to be imported.
So I'm importing FriendContact from ./
now we need to go into the components folder
and in there, we have FriendContact.vue.
So that's the import path we need here
to reach the friend contact of your file,
and friend contact.
Now, again, in the end,
just points at this JavaScript object,
which we're exporting in the friend contact.vue file.
And that's now what we pass as a second argument
to the component method .
With that,
we unlock the friend-contact component in our app.
So we unlocked as custom HTML element.
And now in app view here in our onward list,
we can add friend-contact as often as we want.
And here I'll edit twice.
And if we saved it all,
it'll rebuild and on our connected page,
we'll see our components.
Without the styling,
because for the moment the CSS code is missing,
but we see our components and it works just as before.
Of course it's pretty ugly like this.
So let's next also see how we add styling here
before we then ultimately
learn more and new things about components.