So, let's now work on the styling.
Because, at the moment, this is quite ugly.
There are different ways of adding styling.
But, I will show you the way you will most commonly use,
and which is the recommended way.
You might remember, that in our ".Vue" files,
we not only had a template and a script section,
but we could also add a style section.
Now, adding it is optional.
As you can clearly tell. It worked without it too.
But, here you can define the style of your app,
or component.
So, here I added the style section "App Vue"
And attached, you will find the styles CSS file.
Which we used before, in the component introduction module.
You can simply download it
and then copy all the styles you find in there,
and add them here,
between these style tags.
Save your code, thereafter.
And if you now reload, you should have some styling back.
Still not the final styling. But better than nothing.
Especially our components, don't look too bad.
Now, to also improve your overall styling,
here in the App Vue template,
I'll wrap this h2 tag here, into a header.
Like this. And actually, also convert it to h1 tag.
And if we save that, this now looks better.
And now, we've got our styling back.
Now, there is actually more you can do
with that styling here.
You can for example, later,
also lock it to a specific component,
to make sure that only that component receives the styling.
But, that's something we'll explore later.
For the moment, the styling added here will do the trick.
And with that, we now have a nicer project setup.
Where we've got this realistic development server,
where the app automatically reloads,
whenever we save a change.
And where we also get better IDE support.
And in general, have a setup,
which will not only work for small apps,
but also for bigger apps.