To install this routing package
quits this running development server
by pressing control see here,
and then run NPM install - - save, Vue-router.
This is another package developed by the official vue team.
So it's an official package,
which you can add to your Vue projects
to add this routing functionality.
Now this will install this package
and once you're done installing it,
you can restart your development server with NPM run serve
but now we'll be able to add a routing to this application.
And what does this mean add routing?
Well, now we can go to main JS
where we create our main Vue app this single app,
which we have here in the end.
And on this app, we can now register this router,
which we just installed
and more importantly,
the routes we wanna have in this project.
So simply the different URLs we wanna support.
And to do that we need to import something
from Vue-router
so from this newly installed package
and that this something is a function create Router
so we have create app from Vue to create a Vue app.
We have create router from Vue router to create a router
for such an app.
We can now create the router here for example,
simply by creating a new constant router,
sounds like a fitting name and calling create router
and storing the result of that call in this constant,
but create router needs some configuration
now it needs to know which different routes
so which different URLs we wanna support
and we can also set up more things.
So for that, you pass a JavaScript object to create router
and in that object, we now got two important options,
which we can set the obvious important option is the
routes option.
Here we register all the routes, the different paths,
the different URLs you could say which you wanna to support
this will be an array because typically
it's not just one route which you want to have in your app
if that would be the case, you don't need to router
so we'll have an array full of routes in here
and I will come back to this route conflict
in just a second,
but there also is another option which you should set.
And that's the history option.
Now that is basically telling the router
how to manage the routing history in this app
so when a user clicks somewhere goes to a different page,
then this new page is added to the browsing history
you could say and if the user then clicks a back button,
the history makes sure that well,
the router knows what the last page was.
And there are two different kinds of history
you could use here.
and we want to import another function from you router here
and that stick, create web history function,
which we then call here as a history option.
Now this might sound confusing,
but historically Java script in the browser,
wasn't always able to manipulate to browsers memory
on which page the user is on
and where the user came from.
Therefore, historically the router
had to emulate this behavior you could say,
and we didn't use the built in browser history,
but since a couple of years, does this no problem
and with create web history by calling this function,
we tell the router,
Hey, just use the browsers built in mechanism
for remembering where to user came from and so on.
And that's the end what we're telling the router here
use to build in browser support simple has that.
Now that's all we got to do related to that.
Now we can focus on those routes
because that's the heart of the router
here we'll be able to tell the router
which Vue component should be loaded
for which URL ,because ultimately that will be our goal.
We wanna to load the team's component,
let's say when we're on our domain slash teams
and we wanna load to the users component,
let's say when we are on our domain slash users,
so let's work on registering routes and loading them next.