So how can we register routes now?
while we get this routes array,
and here we now pass JavaScript objects tutors array,
and every object represents one route,
and to configuration for that route.
And here, one very important option,
which we need to set on every route,
is the path option.
This tells the router for which path that's the part
of the URL after the domain,
a certain component should be loaded.
For example,
that we want to load a certain component
for slash teams,
so that if our domain.com/teams is loaded,
a certain component is loaded.
And that's the second option we wanna set here.
The component option,
here, we then define which components should be loaded,
by the view router when the user visits slash teams.
And in my case that would be the team's list component here.
Currently, I'm loading the team's list component here,
in app view with the dynamic component.
I got my navigation,
which emits a set page event,
that happens when either of the two buttons
is clicked in there.
And then upon setting a page the active page,
data property changes either to team's list
or to users list.
And that are my two components here,
team's list and users list,
the two components which are all the registered here,
in my app component.
And that's simply den switches between these two components.
This is a way of doing it but it does not update
the URL and it's not shareable,
but it is the team's list component,
which I wanna load here for this route.
So, in this main JS file,
we now wanna import team's list,
from dot slash components, teams list dot view,
and then set component here equal to team's list telling
the view router that it's the team's list component.
That should be loaded if we visit slash teams.
And that's not the only route we wanna load.
Instead, I will duplicate this configuration here,
to also register a slash users route.
And here we wanna load the users list component.
So therefore we now also import users list,
from components, users list dot view,
and load this for this slash users route.
And now we registered these two routes.
Now the routes are configured,
but a couple of things are missing to make this work.
For one at the moment,
does router is only stored in this router constant,
but we're not doing anything with constant.
We need to make our view app aware of this router,
which holds these routes.
We do this by going to our app,
and on this app, we have to use method.
This is a built in method,
which in the end allows us to connect our view app,
with a third party package,
with some other functionality.
And here we simply pass the router to use.
And this makes the view app aware of this router.
Now that's a first step,
but one important piece is still missing.
The view app is now aware of these routes,
thanks to view router and theoretically,
the view router sees,
that if we visit our domain slash teams,
we want to load this component,
but it's missing one important piece of information.
It doesn't know where to load
this component to.
At the moment we're giving no hint at all to the router,
where does components should be rendered,
and thankfully it's not just taking the component,
and replacing everything on the screen with it.
Instead, we need to use a special component,
to let the view router know where to render it.
And we can replace this dynamic component
with that new special component,
since we're not going to use this dynamic approach anyways.
So instead here in app view,
let's say instead of this main element,
I want to render the selected route component.
And to let view router know about this,
we can use a number of component,
which is now built in, I'm saying now,
because it's built into view router,
and there for only a wadeble because we're using
the router in this view app.
But since we do that,
we now got a new built in component,
and that's the router view component.
And that's in the end of placeholder telling view router
that this is the place where to select it.
Routed to component, should be loaded.
And we can by the way now all to get rid
of these two imports here, team's list,
and user's list in app view and not registered
them as components anymore,
because we don't need to do that.
We're not using these components in our template,
by using dare selector.
Instead we select them here through the router.
And if you do that, if you load a component through routing,
you don't need to register this component.
Additionally, as a global or local component,
you don't need to do that.
So with that, we now let the router know,
where to load that.
And hence we can save everything and reload,
and we won't see anything on the screen,
because at the moment we're just
on our domain slash nothing.
Now the routes we registered were slashed teams,
and slash users.
So let's try those, let's enter ,
local host, 80, 80 slash teams,
and we see the team's page.
Let's try users, and we see the users page,
and now we got shareable links,
but of course our navigation isn't working anymore.
And the debt's definitely not what we want.
We want to make sure that we can still navigate
from inside the page,
and that we don't have to enter the difference
you ELLs manually, nobody uses webpages like that.
So let's see how we can navigate around with routes then.