(Narrator)So now with our routes registered,
let's make sure we can also reach those routes
from inside our application.
And we got this that navigation.vue file
where I got two buttons,
where I emit a custom event
to which I previously listened to hear in an app view.
I'm still listening to it.
But actually, now we're not going to navigate like this,
we now don't need to manage manually
which page should be loaded,
we can get rid of the active page data property in app view,
we can get rid of this event listener here
on then navigation, and therefore we can also get rid
of this set active page method here of course,
we can get rid of the entire methods block therefore.
In the navigation we no longer emit set page
and we therefore no longer have to set active page method
and we can hence get rid of the entire methods here.
And therefore actually, we can get rid of
of the entire script block since
we got no specific component configuration in there anyways
Instead, we'll now navigate differently
and will not use a button anymore,
instead we will use another built-in component that comes
with the view router.
And that is the router link component.
It's a little bit like the built-in anchor tag,
HTML element, you could say,
but it's a special anchor tag,
A special anchor tag,
which actually will not load a different page
and reload the entire app,
and hence loose the current state.
But instead a special anchor tag where the browser default
of loading a different page is prevented.
and instead, the view router takes over,
analyzes the link the user clicked
and that downloads the appropriate component
and updates the URL.
Things like that are handled by router link.
You can still pass your text between there,
you can actually pass any HTML element in there,
which you might need because
router link internally uses slots.
But here I just want some text.
And now of course, we need to configure router link.
And the most important configuration here is the to prop,
which it expects.
The to prop takes various different values.
and the simple way of using it is to provide a string to it
which holds the path you want to go to.
So in this case, slash teams.
So of course, that should be one of the routes
you are supporting in your routes configuration.
And that's already all then
we can also replace the second button
with such a router link.
Here, I want to go to my users,
and hence the two probe points at users.
Now we'll get some problems with styling here
because previously I used a button
now it's a Link hence I will replace the
button CSS selector down there with an anchor tag,
because router link under the hood will render
an anchor tag so we can style an anchor tag here,
and I'll delete this font CSS property.
Keep the rest though,
and also replace button hover and button active
with an anchor tag,also add a new CSS property
to the anchor tag rule here and set text decoration to none.
With that styling updated, if we save this and reload,
we get the same buttons as before,
but now these are actually links
and if we click them,
we switch between these different routes.
And if we inspect these elements,
we see what I just explained in theory.
We got anchor tax here,
which has href attribute but
this router link component actually makes sure that,
the browser default is prevented,
and the browser doesn't really try
to load a different HTML file.
But instead, the router then analyzes
the value in the ref attribute
and checks your routing config
to find the appropriate view component
that should be loaded.
In addition, you see that some CSS classes were added here,
router link active and router link exact active.
And we only have this on teams at the moment.
If I inspect the upper list item,
we don't have the classes there.
These classes are added automatically by view router
on the link which is currently selected.
So for the route that's currently active,
so that you can actually style these links based
on the selection to give the user a feedback
regarding the route he or she is currently on.
Now, that's something we're going
to explore next.