I want to come back to this navigation here.
We're currently using router link to have a way of
getting to different parts of our page here from inside
our app.
So to have different links that lead to different pages.
This is a very common way of navigating around.
Sometimes, though, you also need to navigate
programmatically.
Let's say for whatever reason on the user's list
page here, above this under list you had
a button, where I say confirm.
So this is a button, not a link.
We see it here, now it's obviously totally unstalled
but it's good enough for what I want to show you.
Let's say upon clicking this button
you want to run some code.
So we have a method here in our methods option,
confirm input, whatever.
Here you do something you store some data in
a variable, you send some data to a server.
You're doing something important.
Once you're done with that, you want to change the page.
This is actually a common scenario that you want to navigate
away once some task finished.
Here it's just a dummy example but in bigger apps
you could have real use cases, where a form is submitted
and once it is submitted you want to navigate the user
away from there.
It's also something we'll see in action later
in the main course project.
So here we don't want to use a link because
we don't just want to navigate away we
also want to do something else.
Hence we have a button, which triggers our confirm input
method here up on a click.
There we then do our important stuff but then at the end
we want to navigate away.
So we want to navigate away programmatically.
We don't have a link on the page which the user clicks
but we want to trigger the navigation
from inside the JavaScript code from inside
our component config object.
How can we do this?
Since we're using the router here on our view app
we have a special property available in our
component config objects.
We can access it through the this keyword, and
there we have dollar sign router available.
Dollar sign router is available
because we added the router package.
On this router we now got various methods, which we can use.
For a navigating programmatically we, for example,
got the push method to push a
new route onto this routing history.
So simply to add a new route to this routing memory
the browser keeps.
Push in the simplest form
takes a string, which again, has just
the path in it to which you want to go.
So slash teams for example.
If I do that and save this and reload I can click confirm
and you see we go to slash teams then because of push.
Now there also are other methods on the router,
which you can access.
For example, you got back
or forward to basically
emulate the back and forward buttons in the browser.
You got more methods, which you of course,
can find in the official docs.
But here we need push for programmatic navigation.
So with that if you click this confirm button
we're taken to the Teams page programmatically
For any cases, where you have some code,
that should execute before you want to navigate;
programmatic navigation with the
dollar sign router is your friend.