So now added navigation in different forms,
it's time to explore more things
we can configure here on our route configurations.
And there's one especially important feature,
which you need in many apps,
which you're going to build.
We get this team members component here, right?
And in this team members component,
I wanna render the different members
of a team we selected
now at the moment, this is kind of a dummy component,
which we're not even using.
It has some built in dummy data
and we're not rendering this component anywhere.
Now a common scenario,
which you have in many apps is
that you might have another route here
for a path of /teams.
But now not just that path,
we already have a route for that
and you should only have one route per path
and instead we use /teams/
and now we want to have some dynamic ID here.
So did we support pops like teams T1,
if T1 would be a team ID or a T2
and we would load the same component with different data
for these different teams.
So we need a dynamic route with a so-called route parameter,
and that's a feature supported by the view router.
You can define a dynamic path segment by adding a colon,
and then any name of your choice.
For example, team ID.
Now that means that this route will become active
if the user enters /teams and then anything thereafter,
therefore the order matters by the way,
if you had another route here /teams/new,
so not a dynamic segment, but simply the text new,
you should put this first because otherwise this path here
this route would match this route as well,
because new would be interpreted as a team ID.
Now we don't need the new route here.
I just wanted to make you aware of this and make
you aware of how these different routes will be parsed
and prioritized.
Here we don't need this new route though,
but we want to set up this dynamic route here
with the dynamic route parameter.
So here I wanna load a component and the component
that should be loaded is a component
we need to import the team members component
from /components/teams/teamMembers.Vue
that's the component that should be loaded here.
And with that, if we now save this,
we can enter teams/T1 and reload this component
the same for anything here.
It's always the same component,
because anything after teams/ will be interpreted
as a value for this dynamic segment.
Now at the moment,
it's always the same component with the same dummy data,
but now we can change this because we will get access
to this concrete value,
which is used for this route parameter
for displace holder here.
We can get access for the concrete value
the user entered inside off the component
that is being loaded.
So inside of team members,
I don't want to use my dummy team data here.
Instead, we do have dummy team data
for all teams to find an app view.
Here we got teams and we got users.
And for every team we have a list of members.
Now, my idea is simple.
When one of these free supported team Ids
is being entered here
in the URL after teams as a value for this route parameter,
I wanna load the appropriate team,
find out which members we have in that team
and also load the appropriate users.
Now we are already providing teams
and users here in app view.
So we can inject both in team members
and we'll need to do that.
So that we, get access to that data.
So here I will add inject and inject users and teams.
Now we just need a way of getting access
to this dynamic segment, the user entered.
So to the concrete value that was entered
for this route parameter,
and we could do it as in the created lifecycle hook.
That will be called when the component is created
before it's shown on the screen.
But once all the data is available,
so here in created,
we can now get access to the inject the data,
but also, and that's the good thing to our routing data.
And for this, we got another special property,
which is available.
We saw $router, which gave us access to the overall router.
We also have $route.
So without an r at the end,
the route is available in this component
because this component is loaded through the router,
and then the route gives us access
to various pieces of information.
For example, to the path that was responsible
for loading this page,
which in this case would be something like /teams
and then the concrete team id.
So we could parse the team id from that path,
but we don't even have to do that.
We have another property available, the parent's property.
This holds all the route parameters
that were used for getting to this page.
And in this case, we have one route parameter for this page.
Everything that starts a colon here is a route parameter.
And the name you chose here will be the name
by which you can extract the value provided by the user.
So in my case, the name is teamId.
And hence here in team members,
I can access params.teamId.
If you chose a different name in your routing conflict here
after the colon,
you have to use the same different name here.
So with that,
we got our team Id and I'm storing it in an extra constant.
And we can now use the team Id to find the correct team
in this injected team's array.
So here I got the selected team, let's say
by accessing teams, this.teams.
So the injected teams array,
and then their defined method,
which is a built in array method,
which needs a function that executes on every array element,
which gets the team for which has currently running
as an argument.
And it will run for all the teams in there
and which should return true
if it's the team we're looking for.
And that would be the case.
If the team Id is equal to the team Id we got here.
So this helps us select the right team.
Of course, we might have entered an Id, which doesn't exist,
but let's ignore this case for now.
And let's instead then once we got a team,
find the members in there.
Now for that, of course in every team,
we've got the members key,
which holds Ids of members we find in users.
So we got our members by accessing selectedTeam.members
But now we want to reach out to users
and find the full user entries for those members
because members is just an array full of Ids.
And for that, I will write a simple loop here.
I will have my selected members here,
which is an empty array initially.
Then I go through all the members
of my members array, which is this array full of Ids.
And it will then reach out to my users.
So to do some check that user's array
for every member Id I got.
And find the user where the user ID is equal to member.
Keep in mind member is just a number user Id
because we have a bunch of user Ids in members.
This then is my selected user,
or at least one selected user.
So I added two selected members by pushing
it onto this array, like this.
So this goes through all the member Ids.
We got for the given team.
And we then select the user,
the full user object for every user Id
we got in our team and then I added to selected members.
So that selected members
then is an array full of full user objects.
Well, and that's then something
I wanna store in a data property here
because I need to team name
and a member's data property in my template.
So we'll add both here.
Team name initially is an empty array
and empty string I mean,
and members is an empty array.
And then here in created, I set this members.
So my data property equal to my selected members
I got here.
So to this array filled with the concrete member objects
and I set this team name equal to selected team.
And then on every team, we got a name property.
So I can access .name here.
And with that, if we save this,
if we enter something like Teams T1,
I see nothing because I have an error here.
Kind of read property, push of undefined.
Yeah, here it's not this selected members in this for-loop,
it's just selected members
because this is a local constant, my bad.
So selectedMembers.push is correct here.
And with that if you've then reload, this looks better.
And now I see Max Schwarz and Praveen Kumar
for team T1 for T2 I see different members
and for T3, I also see different members.
So now this works now of course it would be nice
if we could not just get there by manually entering a URL.
But for example,
by clicking these buttons on the teams page
and therefore that's what we're going to work on next.