And for that, we should go to this
teams list component, and there we see
it's the teams item which is being rendered,
which holds this button, which turns out to be a link,
and this link currently is a regular anchor tag,
and I instead want to use what?
A router link, that reaches to this route,
but of course where the ID of the team is different
for every different team item.
So, we're going to replace the anchor tag
with router link here,
like this,
and now set the two property to what.
Previously it was just slash teams, but now it needs to be
slash teams, and then the ID, but the ID is different
for every teams item.
Well, first of all, we should get the ID as a prop here.
I will add ID as a prop, so that we have it available
instead of the team's item component,
because without having the ID of a team, it will be hard
to construct the correct link here.
So in teams list where I loop for my teams items,
I will actually bind ID to "team.id"
so that we have the ID available
in this teams item component.
But with that, we still need to build this link.
And we can do this, because two does not just have to
be set like this, you can also bind it to a dynamic value,
with the bind, or the shorthand, ":to".
And now this points at a JavaScript expression,
or simply at a data property, whatever you have,
and here we could then derive the full path
you wanna go to, by combining slash teams
which is a string here, with single quotes,
since this is now a JavaScript expression,
slash, and then plus ID.
This constructs this URL, this path,
where ID is different for every usage of teams item.
So for every usage of this component.
And hence, if I now save this and we reload,
we get different links here,
which lead us to the different team members.
So, that is working.
And of course, we could now also take this, and outsource it
from inside our template here,
into a computed property, to have less logic in a template,
and have our team members link computed property,
for example, where we return
this generated URL, and then here
we point at team members link.
That of course is 100% optional.
So with that, if I reload, this still works.