Route parameters are useful,
but they also can be tricky.
There are various aspects
you should be aware of
which you might or might not want
to change or take care about.
Here's one gotcha
Which you could face in an application.
We don't face it here,
but I can add it so that we do face it.
Let's say on TeamMembers...
So on the component,
we load for this route with the parameter.
Let's say in there,
we actually,
for whatever reason,
have another router link,
which says,
"Go to...
"Team two,"
which always goes to slash teams,
slash T2,
which is the idea of the Team two.
Now this is a very constructed scenario,
but you could absolutely have an app
where on the page that was loaded for a given parameter,
you wanna go to the same page
with a different value for that parameter.
And that's what I'm trying to emulate or to simulate here.
So if I save this,
we got this,
"Go to Team two," link here.
Now, if we are on the page for team two,
of course, this does nothing.
But if we are on the page for Team one...
Oh, this also does nothing.
And that's the gotcha I'm talking about.
If you are on the page
that was loaded for a dynamic parameter,
if you then wanna go to a different page,
say with a different value for this parameter,
which in the end of course is kind of the same page,
at least the same view component,
you face this problem here.
Now you should be aware that if I go to Team one,
we have T1 in the URL.
And if we then click this link,
this does change to T2.
But the date on the screen doesn't update.
Is this a bug?
Well, it's not a bug.
It's an intended behavior.
The view router does not destroy
and rebuild the components that were loaded
when you navigate around.
It's more efficient to cash them
than to always destroy and rebuild them
when the URL changes.
But that's the problem here.
I'm loading my data for the team members in created.
And this is called when this component is,
well, guess what,
created.
Now, as I just said,
the view router does not destroy and recreate the component
just because the URL changed.
Therefore, the code in created does not run again
when the URL changed.
Hence if you are on the page,
which you now want to load again,
but with different data,
with a different parameter.
By default,
the view router will do nothing.
That's of course not what we want here.
How can we react to this changed URL?
Well, in the end,
when the URL changes,
one other important thing changes.
This dollar sign route property.
It holds the latest information about the loaded route,
and it will update when the URL changes.
So this dollar sign route object
will always hold the latest parameter, for example.
And therefore,
you can add a watcher here,
and you can watch dollar sign route here.
So this built-in property,
you can watch that for changes.
And this watcher will now run
whenever to route changed.
So here you get the new value then,
the new route you could say.
And in here,
we can now run this logic again.
So therefore,
to not duplicate to code,
I will actually add methods here,
load TeamMembers,
and put my code in there,
and call load team members here,
in created manually,
and also call it here in my watcher.
So that I load this method and run this method,
which loads my TeamMembers
when the component is created,
but also when route changed.
Now, one thing I want to do here, though,
I wanna pass my new route
as our argument to load TeamMembers.
And here,
when we call it and create it,
I'll pass this dollar sign route.
So I wanna pass the route object as our argument,
and add it the method a little bit,
so that we get our route object here,
and I will replace this route with just route.
It's not a must do,
but I wanna do it here
so that we get the route from outside,
so to say,
seen from inside this method
and we pass it as our argument
when we call the method.
With that,
if I save this and reload,
our links here on the Team's page still work.
But if I click on go to Team two,
now this page updates
because now we're watching changes on the route.
And this is just one way of making this work though.
It's a perfectly fine way,
but it's not the only way.
Because there is another problem you could face here,
or another thing about this TeamMembers component
you might not like.
Let's see what that is.