Our TeamMembers component has one potential disadvantage.
It's not only loadable through routing, why?
Because in the code,
we rely on $route in the end,
we use it here in created and we watch it here.
So if you would use this component by simply embedding it
in the template of another component,
let's say you change your application,
and you now suddenly want to use this differently,
or you use it in different places,
one time loaded through routing
another time used through its tag in the template,
then this would be problematic.
It might be better if TeamMembers would be loaded such
that you get props
that you simply get your
teamId as a prop.
That's how you would build this component,
if it would not be loaded through routing.
You would get the teamId through props
and in all the places where you need the Id,
instead of using this $route,
you use this teamId, referring to that prop
and here, you could then watch this
prop for a changes, for example.
And then we would get our newId here
would maybe forward that to LoadMembers.
And we will change the LoadMembers code here,
to not expect the route as argument but the teamId,
and therefore, we now just got teamId as an argument here,
and we can delete that old first line.
But if we save that it won't work,
we see nothing on the screen /t2
and if we open the developer tools,
we see that the problem is
that we cannot read the property 'members' of undefined.
And the reason should be obvious,
teamId is expected as a prop
but we're loading this through routing
and the router by default doesn't add
any props to this loaded component,
but that's something you can change.
In your route config, here on this route,
which is the route responsible
for loading the TeamMembers component,
you can add another option,
you can add the props option and set this to true.
And this does one important thing,
it tells the view router that the dynamic parameters
should be passed into this component as props
rather than just on the $route property.
So now, you will have a prop off the name
you defined here after the colon,
in my case, teamId, the value which is now part of the URL
will now be passed in as a prop into this component
when it's loaded.
So with props true if you save that and reload now,
this works again.
And now we have one advantage,
now, this component TeamMembers is more reusable,
because now we can use it anywhere,
as long as we provide this prop,
it's not strictly tied to routing anymore.
So this is simply an alternative,
which you could consider when it comes to
routing and loading components through routing.
You can make your components more reusable
by using props instead of $route
and even if you don't plan
on using the component anywhere else?
You might prefer getting your data through props
than having to search for it
in the $route parents property.