Now in this demo app,
we've been working on thus far,
we actually have one problem.
"Teams" works, "Users" works,
and we can view our team's members.
But in reality most users would probably reach this page
by just entering your domain.
And if you do that, you don't have an error,
but you also don't see anything on the screen.
The reason for that can actually be seen in the console.
The router doesn't find any matching route
for "slash nothing."
So, for just our domain "slash nothing."
And that's not a technical error
but it might not be what you intended.
You definitely might wanna handle this
and display something on the screen.
Now, it of course depends on the kind of app you're building
and which routes you wanna have.
Maybe you'll have some component which you wanna show here.
Maybe you simply want to show the team's list
if the user enters "slash nothing."
But here I want to have "slash teams" in the URL
when team's lists are shown.
Simply to kind of have an expressive URL
which is all the describing the type
of content we're seeing on the page.
Of course I still wanna add a new route here,
as a first route.
Which is "path slash nothing."
Which should be responsible
for loading team's list as well.
Now as I've just said, we can offload team's list here.
Save this, and now see our teams
when we visit "slash nothing."
And everything will work
but I always wanna have "slash teams" in the URL
and not just "slash nothing" for loading the team's lists.
So therefore, actually what I wanna do here,
is I don't wanna load the team's list component.
Instead I wanna redirect to this route.
And that's possible with the router.
In the route conflict, you have another option
which you can set on a route.
And that's the redirect property.
And you can set this to a path you wanna redirect to.
So that if "slash nothing" is entered,
we redirect to teams.
And of course you can redirect to any path you want.
And if I save this
and I now enter my domain "slash nothing,"
if I had enter, you see it changes to "slash teams"
and we redirect it to this page by the view router.
So that's a pretty nice feature.
Being able to redirect.
It is something which you might need a lot
in your applications.
There also is kind of an alternative to redirect.
You could also set the alias option.
Well, you would actually not set it here,
instead you would remove this route
and go to the route you wanna load
when this route is loaded.
And then add alias to that.
So, in this case the "slash teams" route.
And here you then add your alias path,
which leads to the same component.
So, here "slash nothing" would be an alias
for "slash teams."
If you do that and you enter "slash nothing,"
we still load the "team members" component.
So, it's a bit like defining "slash nothing"
with component team's list,
as we did it a couple of minutes ago.
With alias you can write this on a shorter forum.
But of course, the downside, which I don't wanna have here
in this use case, is that the URL doesn't change.
And that's the difference to a redirect.
With a redirect the URL is changed.
You are really redirected to a different path.
With an alias, the URL does not change.
You just load the same component as on a different route.
And it depends on your requirements and your application,
which behavior you want.
I don't want an alias here.
Instead I want to redirect as I did it before.
I want to redirect with "slash teams,"
save everything and therefore make sure
that when I enter nothing, I end up on "slash teams."
Another thing which we're not handling in this demo here,
is the use case that the user enters any route
which is not supported.
So, here "slash something."
if I enter this again, we see nothing.
Because we have no route defined for that.
Now of course we can't define routes for all possible values
that could be entered here.
There is an infinite amount of paths the user could enter.
That's why you can define "catch all" routes.
So here I'll add a new route at the end,
because it should have the lowest priority
and only kick in if no other route handles this.
But here the path should be slash and then something
which tells the router
that anything should match this route.
And for that you add a dynamic segment,
then any name of your choice for example "not found"
or "catch all," whatever you want.
I'll go with "not found."
And then brackets, and in the brackets "dot star."
This certainly looks strange but in the end this means,
it's a dynamic segment.
And this here is actually a regular expression.
This text is supported by the view router.
And it simply means any character combination
which is being used as a value here,
should in the handle lead to this route being loaded.
That's why this needs to come last.
Otherwise it would also overwrite the other routes
which you wanna have.
But if none of these routes is handling the entry path,
this route should kick in.
And here you can define which component should be loaded
in this case.
Or if you wanna redirect.
For example, we could redirect to "slash teams"
for any invalid value that's being entered.
So, if I saved this and I enter something,
I'm redirected to "slash teams."
Alternatively you create a "not found" component.
Let's say, here in the Nav folder.
With a simple template where I say, "Page not found.
"Maybe view our" and then a router link,
"teams" and then close the "h2" tag
and then here point at "slash teams."
That could be our "not found" page.
And now we could load this component,
which just as a template because it doesn't need more,
you could add styling but I wanna keep it simple.
And we could load this component now
by importing it here into our main JSK file,
"not found from components, nav, not found, dot vue."
And point at that component here on this "not found" route.
Like this.
If you do this and save everything,
if I enter some unsupported path here,
we see our "not found" page,
where we can go back to "teams."
so, that is how you can handle any
invalid input the user might provide.
It should come last
so that it doesn't overwrite your other routes
but then it's really useful.
And together with the redirect feature,
this allows you to have full control
over where the user of your website is going
under which circumstances.