There are more things
you can configure when it comes to your routes
which you set up on your router.
For example,
we have this pretty nice feature of nested routes.
In some applications, you might want to have,
you can say a router inside of another router.
Let me give you an example.
Let's say our team members should not be loaded
on a new stand alone page,
but instead when I click view members here,
I want to load the members
for that team above the list of teams.
So, on the same page I want to embed my members
of that team.
That's something which you might wanna do.
And that's something which is possible with the Vue Router.
We got this route here which is responsible
for loading our team members
and currently it's a stand alone route to find next
to the teams route basically on the root level
of all our routes.
These routes are all on the same level.
They're siblings to each other.
Now you can set up a nested route
by going to the route where you want to nest routes inside
and adding the children option on the route config.
Children takes an array
and it takes an array of routes.
So, the same routes we set up here in routes
are added to children.
So, here on teams we can now take this route
and move it in there
and now I reformatted this to make it a bit easier to read.
So, now inside of my teams route,
I have a child route which is this one.
And here you don't need to repeat the entire path.
You can just add the segment
which should go after this segment.
So after slash teams.
And you can have more than one route in here.
If you had multiple routes
that should be nested inside of teams
you could absolutely add them there.
Here I just needed one route though
but this route will now be reached
with teams slash and then some Id like t1.
And, now what's the difference
with having a nested route?
Well one difference is that if I save this,
if I click view members
now we don't load our team members route anymore.
And the reason for that is
that Vue, the Vue Router to be precise,
doesn't know anymore where to load this.
Because now the team members route,
this one here,
is no longer a root route.
It's no longer registered directly inside of routes.
It's a child route of another route.
Now the router-view component,
which we use is app view
is our top most router-view component
we have in this entire app
and it's only responsible for the root routes.
So, for the routes directly registered
in the routes array.
So, this child route cannot be rendered
into this router-view.
Instead you now need to add a second Router Vue
in the component where this route
is defined as a child component.
So, in this case in our teams list component,
that's the real component
which has this as a child route.
So, it's the teams list opponent
where you now need to add an extra router-view
for all the child routes.
In this case for the one child route we got.
So, in teams list
above the unordered list for example,
we can now add another router-view.
And this router-view will now be important
for all the child routes
of the teams list component route.
So, of this route.
Hence, now if I go back to teams
and reload we see nothing because it's just slash teams
but if I click on view members,
now we see our members for that team.
If I change the team here
you'll see that updates up there.
And of course we can do this for all the teams.
And, that's another nice feature,
having these nested routes.
You will also notice
that with the nested route,
if my URL changes to that nested route
teams is still highlighted up there.
It wasn't before if you recognized that.
Before where this route
was a separate root route as a sibling to the teams route
before even though that route also started
with slash teams.
This link was not highlighted
because the active clauses only applied
if the currently loaded path
is actually related to the path this link points at.
And, this link points at slash teams,
slash teams t1, is now a nested route
on this teams route
and therefore whenever some nested route is active
this link is treated as active.
That's why now the active CSS class
is now being added here.
But that's just a extra side note, related to nested routes.
And nested routes can be a really useful feature
for building complex user interfaces
where you want to load different parts
maybe nested in different components
based on different URLs and paths.
And that's exactly what we're doing here.