So now we learned about nested routes.
Now imagine a bigger view application where you have dozens,
or maybe even hundreds of different routes,
some routes deeply nested in our routes.
You can also have multiple levels of nesting,
you could have children here on this nested route as well.
So imagine an application
where you have a lot of such nested routes.
If you have such an app,
constructing links like recurrently doing it,
like this, can quickly become cumbersome,
you always have to add the full path here,
and build it out like this.
You have to build such a long string,
which describes the path you wanna navigate to.
Now, because this can get cumbersome,
the view router offers two very useful features,
which make building such links,
which we pass to router link more convenient.
The first useful feature which we have,
is the fact that the two prop on router link,
does not just take such a string link.
It does take that, but not just.
Besides passing such a string which holds the path,
you can also use an object as a value for two.
For that, of course you need
to bind two dynamically with a colon.
And then this object may have various options,
that allow you to describe the route you wanna load.
In this object, you can set a path property,
and that then takes a string,
which could be slashed teams plus this ID,
so what you returned as a string before.
Now, by just doing that, we of course don't gain much.
We basically do what we did before,
but now inside of an object.
This gets more useful,
if we combine it with another nice feature,
the view router offers, and that would be named routes.
We can assign a name to every route which we have,
simply by adding a name property to the route config.
Here for example, we could name the route, teams.
We could name this nested route here as well,
team dash members, maybe.
The names are totally up to you,
they just should be strings.
So now I assigned two names,
and of course you can assign names to any routes you want.
And now we can leverage that name, team members.
Back in the teams item component,
now instead of setting the path property, which we can do,
we can at the name property on this route location object,
which we pass to two.
And here we can use team dash members for example,
making it clear that this router link,
should load this nested route.
Of course, this route has a dynamic segment,
so we should also set this.
And we do that by adding a second property to this object,
which describes the destination we wanna go to.
And that's the params property.
Params takes an object,
where you now can set up your params as key value pairs.
And of course, I mean the params,
which are expected by the route with that name.
So in this case,
that team members route once a team ID param,
because that's the name we chose here as a dynamic segment,
hence here, we can add team ID in this nested object,
which we provide to params,
and then set our value here to this ID.
Now arguably, that's a bit more code than before,
but it actually has two great advantages I would say.
It's very readable and maintainable,
and it has one extra huge advantage.
If you ever should decide
that you wanna go with a different path,
let's say team instead of teams,
then you don't need to go to this team item component,
and update the path everywhere where you used it,
instead, the name didn't change.
So you don't need to update anything here,
and you can still conveniently change the path,
how often you want.
That's why navigating by name instead of by path,
might be a useful pattern, especially of course,
in bigger applications where you use a route,
in a lot of different components.
You then don't have to update all those components,
whenever you decide to change the path.
And that's why passing such an object instead
of a string to two, can be useful.
By the way, you can provide the same object
to this router push,
in case you should be navigating programmatically.
You can provide the same kind of object to this push method,
but that's just a side note.
And if I do that and save everything, and reload,
our links here, therefore still work fine.
And I can load different team members now,
bypassing this object to two.
And the view router will analyze this object,
compare it to your route set up,
and create the correct anchor tech,
with the correct link
to and to be loaded route and therefore component.