This object form of describing the location
or the destination of a link
can also be useful for other things,
not just for using names and setting up a link
in a more convenient way instead of building a long string.
But also to maybe add extra information
which you might need.
Let's say you want to use a query parameter.
In case you're not sure what that is,
a query parameter is the thing you see in some routes
and some URLs after the question mark.
Like, sort equals ascending
A query parameter is basically an optional
route parameter which is not needed to find
and load a component, but which may be used
to then pass extra information into that component.
It's not a must use but it can be useful
in some Apps and some pages.
Now you could add such a query parameter.
If you build your link manually
by simply adding it to your string
which you're building, like this.
But if you use this object form, it's even more convenient.
You can add a query property.
Next to name and parents to this config object
and query then takes a nested object, just as parents did.
And here you can add any query parameters
you might want to pass to the to be loaded page,
like sort with a value of asc a string saying asc.
I'll reformat that to make it a bit easier to read.
And you can add any query parameters you want
and of course your page, your Component support.
These query parameters are not defined in the route config,
you don't need to add anything here
because they're optional by nature.
But now if I save that and reload.
If I click View Members you see that query parameter
is added to the URL automatically.
Now we're not doing anything with the parameter here,
but we are adding it.
And if you would want to use it in the component
that is loaded through that query parameter.
So in this case, team members, you can extract it
there you get access to your query parameters.
If I console log it through this route dot query.
The query property holds information
about your query parameters.
So if I save that and reload and open the console,
we see we get an object here,
which has this sort key and the value of ascending.
So that's is how you get access to the query parameters,
you might be passing to a component through routing.
As a side note query parameters
are not provided as props.
If I log this dot sort here
hoping that you get a sword prop.
Since we have a source query parameter.
You will see that the value
I get here is actually undefined.
It's undefined because query parameters
are just accessible through dollar sign route.
There shouldn't be a problem though,
because query parameters are optional anyways.
So if you ever use your component in a different way,
so not by routing but by embedding it
in a number of components template.
You might simply not have access to the query parameter,
but since it is optional anyways,
and it might not be added to the URL as well.
Your code should be prepared to handle
the non existence of this query parameter anyways.
But that's it for query parameters here,
I wanted to bring it up, because it is important
to be able to work with those as well.
It is important to know that view router
makes adding and extracting them easy.
We don't need them for this dummy application,
but you might need them for our applications of course.