Now for the moment,
that's it when it comes to navigating around
and building those two values
like that object here with the query parameter.
I now wanna move on to another feature,
which can be useful in some applications.
And that would be multiple router views on the same level.
We already have multiple router views in this demo app.
We have one in App vue
and we have one in the team's list component
for the nested routes that belong to the route
that loads the team's list component.
But you can also have
multiple router views on the same level.
So for the same set of routes,
for example, here in App vue,
we could have a footer element let's see,
but that's not mandatory.
But in there we could have another router view.
Now, of course, having two router views on the same level,
which are there for dealing with the same routes
will not be too helpful just like that.
If I saved that
and I reload,
we now just see that every page has loaded twice.
Of course, because we have two router views.
That's probably not the behavior you want.
But instead multiple router views on the same level,
allow you to add another cool functionality.
You can load multiple components per routes,
and then sent them to different router views.
Now for that let's say,
we have a TeamsFooter.vue component,
which has a simple template where it say Teams Footer,
just so that we can recognize it.
And then I copied that to the users folder,
but name it UsersFooter.
And in there, it should, of course say users footer.
Now in reality, you would have more in there than just text.
But the main thing is that you have two different components
that should be loaded as a footer,
depending on whether you're in the teams area
or the users area of pages.
And that could absolutely be a requirement
you have in your app.
With the view router,
that's easy to implement.
In your route config,
you can register more than one component per route.
Here, for example, on teams,
instead of just having one component here,
we can add components.
So plural. And this now takes an object.
And in this object,
you can now define key value piers where the keys
identify different router views,
and the values are the components
that should be loaded into this router view.
And that now works if you give those router views names,
just as you can give names to slots.
We could give this router view in the footer,
a name of footer, but the name is up to you.
We could also give this router view a name,
but just as we have slots,
you are allowed to have one unnamed router view
on the same level,
which will then be the default router view.
So now you're back in our route config.
We can add a key off default
to point at this unnamed router view
and set up the component that should go into that default,
which in this case is the TeamsList.
But we can then also add a footer key here
pointing at that router view named footer
and set up the component
that should be rendered in this router view.
And that's a component I have yet to import.
That will be the teams footer component,
which is imported
from components/teams/TeamsFooter.vue.
And when we're already importing stuff,
I can also already import UsersFooter
from components/users/UsersFooter.vue.
And now it's the team's footer,
which I wanna set as a value for the footer outlet
on my components here.
Now I don't need to change anything
about the nested child route here.
Here I still only wanna load one component,
but the parent has more than one component here,
as you can tell.
Now we can also do the same here for the users.
On the users route, instead of using component,
we could use components,
set the default to UsersList
and the footer outlet to UserFooter, UsersFooter, sorry.
So now we're using these named router views
for users and teams.
And for all the routes like this catch all route
where we just have one component,
that one component
will always go into the default unnamed router view.
So we don't need to set up components here
if we only have one router view we wanna support here.
With that, whoever we can save that.
And now you'll see our team items, our teams,
and then the teams footer for a user.
You see the users footer and the users, of course.
If I select a team, we see the team members
and then still
are two different teams components down there.
And if I enter anything invalid,
we still just see one not found route,
because as I said,
that then goes into the default unnamed router view.
So named router views can be helpful
to allow you to construct more complex user interfaces
where you wanna load more than one component
for a given path.
For example, to not just have flexible main pages,
but all the flexible footers.