With all the knowledge we gained over the last lectures,
we are nearing the end of this module now.
You now know pretty much all the key features
you have to know about registering routes,
loading components and navigating.
But there are two other nice features,
which can help you provide the user experience
you wanna provide.
And that will be controlling the scroll behavior
of your pages and navigation guards.
Let's start with controlling the scrolling behavior.
What do I mean by that?
Well, let's say we're on the Teams page,
we load our team here and then I scroll down
so that I can load the Client Consulting team.
If I click that, of course you component updates,
but I have to scroll up there to see that.
Maybe we want to scroll up there automatically,
when we switch the route here.
That could be something we might wanna do,
in general, maybe.
Whenever we switch a route,
we wanna scroll to top so that the user always sees
the full new page and isn't stuck somewhere down the page.
And that's something we can add with the vue router.
In main js, where we create our router,
besides registering all those routes
and then setting some global conflict
like the link active class.
You can also add a scroll behavior
property.
That scroll behavior property actually
is a method.
A method which will be called by the vue router,
whenever your page changes.
And this stroll behavior method will then receive
free arguments, automatically.
A to,
a from
and a saved position
argument.
You can name them however you want,
but that is what will be in there.
But what is to from and saved position?
Let's simply
lock this.
Let's lock to,
from
and saved position,
and save this.
Now I reload
and I click
on a link here,
and you'll see I got this locked to the console,
actually we already got it when I first loaded this page.
Q and from in the end are route objects.
Q and from basically are what you also get with this route
inside of a component.
To and from,
are the pages we're going to
and we're coming from.
When I first load this page,
the page we're going to is having this full path,
which this path without the query parameter and so on.
It has this params object, the query object,
and this is exactly the kind of object you would get
with this dollar signed route,
inside of the component that is loaded.
And we're coming from this path,
It's pretty much all empty because I just loaded the page.
If I cleared a console and I click a link,
you'll see this looks different.
Now we're going to this path,
with a parameter of t2,
and the route we're coming from has a parameter of t1.
And saved position is null here,
because saved position is only set,
if you're using the back button.
Then you see saved position is actually an object
with a left and a top property,
describing where the user scroll to,
when this page, you just went back to what's left.
For example,
if I scroll all the way down,
and they go to a different page,
and I go back,
then this
scroll
position,
which is saved here is the scroll position I had
when I left this page before I clicked the back button.
How can this all be useful?
This scroll behavior method should return
an object describing where the browser should scroll to,
up on the page change.
And here the object you return,
should have a left and the top property.
Just as the safe position has it,
when it is available.
And if you, for example, said left to zero,
and top to zero,
that means that you wanna scroll,
all the way to the top of the page.
If I always returned this,
and I've for the moment still console log to, from
and saved positions so that my IDE doesn't complain
about these being unused.
If I locked that,
but we always return this object,
the effect is, that if I scroll down
and switch to a different page,
we jump to the top
and that's exactly the behavior I want here.
Of course, on the other hand, if we go back,
I might want to go back down here
so that I really go back,
not just to the page we're coming from,
but also to the place on the page we were on.
And that's now where the saved position comes in handy
because that is saving the exact place we were scrolled to.
We can tweak this and check if saved position exists,
if it is not now, and if that's the case
we return to saved position.
So that for example, if we do go back,
we use the saved position instead of jumping to the top.
But if saved position does not exist, we do jump to the top.
And with that advice, save that and reload.
I can go to my teams,
load a team,
scroll down,
jump the top.
But if I now click back, I'm scroll down again.
And that can of course enhance the user experience
because now we scroll the user to the place
where he or she is able to see exactly the content,
that we wanna present at this moment.