The last feature,
I wanna explore in this module with you
is the feature of navigation guards.
Navigation guards can be useful if you add features like
authentication where you, for example,
want to avoid that a user is able to access a certain route
if he or she is not authenticated,
but they can also be useful
to simply be aware of changing pages
in case you wanna run some code there
or they can be useful to ensure that a user
doesn't accidentally navigate away from a page
where he or she has unsaved edits in a forum, for example.
We'll see practical examples for guards
in the course project, but of course,
since this is the introductory module to routing,
I'll start showing you all those guards
in this module already.
Now, what exactly do I mean, when I say guards?
I'm talking about functions, methods,
which are called automatically by view router
when a page changes or to be precise,
when a navigation action started.
For example, on the router we're creating in main JS
on this main router before we pass it to our view app,
we can call before each, like this.
Before each is a build in method
and it wants a function as an argument.
Before each once a function as an argument.
And this function will be called by the view router
whenever we navigate from one page to another.
Before each navigation action, this function will be called.
And this function will then receive
free arguments from your router
to, which is the route object off the page we're going to,
from, which is the route object of
the page where coming from
and next, which is a function which we have to call
to either confirm or cancel this navigation action.
Because that's something we can do in navigation guards
which is why they are called guards.
We can cancel a navigation if we're not happy with it.
If we, for example, want to deny the navigation
because the user is not authenticated.
Now, how could this look like?
First of all, I'm going to console log, to and from
so that we see what we're getting there.
And then I'll call next like this, with no special setting.
I will also console log global
beforeEach to make it clear that we're in this
globally on the entire router registered before each hook.
If I saved that, reload and cleared a console
and I go to users, we see global before each in the console
and then we see two logs.
Now, one of these logs is coming from the scroll behavior.
So to avoid confusion, I'll comment this out
and to avoid that my IDE complaints
about the unused to and from,
I'll replace it with an underscore and underscore two,
which is basically an indicator
that I have to take these arguments
in order to reach the third one,
but then I don't plan on using them.
That's something my IDE and my local setup will accept.
So these are just argument names, following a convention
that signals to the set up that I
need to use these arguments, but I don't plan on using them.
So with that, if I reload
and we switched from users to teams now,
we see global beforeEach and then one log
with the to and the from route object.
To, of course is having the team's path
because we're going to teams
and from has users.
And other than that we see nothing special
because I just called next like this.
And if you call next like this,
you allow the navigation, you confirm it.
You can also pass false to next though.
And that will cancel the navigation.
Let's try that.
If I saved that, we already see when I reload,
there's nothing on the screen
because loading the page failed
because I canceled this initial navigation.
If I try to go to users, we get no error.
We see our global before each method runs,
but again, we see nothing on the screen
because with false, we cancel this.
Now here, of course that's not
too useful because we're canceling all navigation here,
but later in the course project,
we'll also see how we could use that feature in combination
with checking whether the user is authenticated or not,
to cancel or allow this.
We also have a third option for next here.
Besides passing nothing or false, we can also pass
either a string or a location object in here.
A string with a route you wanna navigate to,
which of course should then be
one of the routes we registered up there
or such a navigation object which describes that.
For example, by using the name
and then maybe setting up any parameters.
Like here, I could make sure that every navigation action
leads to a route with the name team-members
and teamId set to t2,
which of course makes absolutely no sense,
but I just want to show you how that works.
However, make sure you don't save and reload here
because you would create an infinite loop.
Because even when we go to this route,
because we redirect here, we would then again redirect us.
So here we should then actually check if to.path
or to.name is equal to team members.
So if we are already going to the team-members page,
in which case I wanna call next
and only else, if we're going to a different page,
I wanna forward, I wanna redirect to team-members.
And now we can save this and reload
and we now always end up on this team's t2 page,
if we tried to go anywhere else,
but to another team-member that would also work.
But if I tried to go to users, I still end up on teams t2
because of this global before each hook.
Now, I will say it again.
This of course is no logic
that really makes sense in this demo project,
but it is important that you understand
how this navigation guard works,
what the next method does in there and how you can use it.
With that however, I'm going to comment this out
and just call next like this to confirm the navigation
so that we don't redirect us to just one kind of page.
Instead, now we can navigate around as we're used to,
but you now have a first idea of
what a navigation guard is able to do.
And as you might imagine,
that can be useful if you want
to check whether the user is authenticated
and prevent access to a certain page,
if you are, she is not authenticated.
That would be a typical scenario
which we are going to see later.