Now we don't just have
this Global guard though.
This beforeEach function here will run
on every navigation action,
no matter which route is being used,
no matter from which route we go to which other route,
this will always run.
Sometimes this is what you need, sometimes it's not,
sometimes you just wanna protect individual routes.
You could do this, of course,
with a if check here, where you check your to
and from route objects,
to also run different logic based on different routes.
But you can also set up the beforeEach navigation guard
on single routes.
For example, on users, let's say.
For that you simply go to your users route conflict,
and here you can add beforeEnter, not beforeEach,
because now it technically is just one route.
BeforeEnter is a method here as well.
And just as beforeEach, it gets to, from and next.
So here I console.log('users beforeEnter')
and maybe also console.log(to, from) is you want to
and then call next to confirm it
or do whatever you wanna do with next.
Next works just as I explained it
on the Global beforeEach navigation guard.
Here I'm just confirming every navigation to users.
And now this will be called whenever we go to users.
So if I saved that and reload.
If I go to users, we see Global beforeEach,
because that still executes.
After all it executes for every navigation action.
But we also see users beforeEnter
and then the output of to and from for this page.
To of course, is pointing at the users page,
because that beforeEnter hook was registered
for the users page.
Now, in case you don't wanna register
this on the route level or in your route conflict,
you can also add a new hook,
a new method inside of your component.
Let's say in the users list component.
Here in your component conflict object,
you can add all those view lifecycle methods,
like created or mounted and you can also add
the beforeRouteEnter method.
If you use the view router, which we do,
this will be called before navigation
to this component is confirmed.
And here again, you get to, from and next,
and therefore we can do what he did before.
We can console.log('usersList Cmp beforeRouteEnter').
We can then console.log(to, from) of course
and we can call next or run any logic we wanna run
to confirm or deny navigation to next or redirect the user.
And with that, if I go to Teams,
reload, clear the console and go to users,
we see Global beforeEach and then to and from,
users beforeEnter and then to and from,
and then UsersList Cmp beforeRouteEnter.
And that's the order
in which these navigation guards execute.
Global is always first, then the route conflict level
and then the component level.
All of these hooks run before the route is confirmed though,
which is why you can and have to call next
to confirm it manually or deny it
or redirect the user somewhere else.
We've got two other guards related to loading a component.
One is the before route update guard,
which you call directly inside of a component.
To be precise, inside of components which are reused,
which in our case would be the team members component.
Here we got the parameter, the team ID parameter,
and it's absolutely possible that we are on the page
of one team and we load another team members page.
And then this team members page never leaves the screen
and hence is reused, as you learned.
In such cases, view router will call another nice method
in the component conflict object.
Maybe here next to created,
there you can add the beforeRouteUpdate method
and view will call this method whenever this component
is about to be reused with new data,
because the route changed.
So here we also get to, from and next,
and then you can also deny or confirm the navigation
just as you know it, just as I explained it before
on the Global beforeEach hook, it's the same here.
And besides that of course,
you can utilize to and from, for example,
to call loadTeamMembers based on the new team ID param,
which you get on the, to be navigated to route object.
Now of course, we already have logic in place here
to handle the changing team ID route parameter
in this component, so we don't need beforeRouteUpdate
for that, but using beforeRouteUpdate
would be an alternative to watching
the team ID prop, for example.
Though of course, with that hook,
we again bind this component to be used with routing.
We use props instead of route params
to make this component more flexible.
When we use this alternative,
we would make it less flexible,
because this is only called if this component is loaded
and reloaded through routing of course.
But now this would be an alternative and with that
we can console.log('TeamMembers Cmp beforeRouteUpdate') here
and console.log(to, from) if you want to,
and then save everything.
And now if I go to a different team,
we see beforeRouteUpdate runs and well,
then our logic in there runs, which we don't need here,
but I want to show you this hook of course.
I'm going to comment this out though,
because we are already loading team members
when the team ID changes, we don't need to do this twice.
But that is another navigation guard
or another navigation hook you could also call it,
that is worth knowing.