Now, there is another
global guard we can add on the router
and that is the afterEach guard.
This also wants a function,
and of course, as always here,
it doesn't matter how you define the function,
if you do it like this or as an arrow function,
and this also it gets the to and from argument,
but not the next function because afterEach
will only run once a navigation has been confirmed.
So in here, you can't change that anymore.
You can't deny a navigation.
You can only do this in the before hooks,
in the before guards.
The afterEach guard could be nice for sending analytics data
to your own server, for example,
to log every navigation action
and log when a user changes pages.
That's something you could do here.
You don't use it to control what the user sees
on the screen because as I just said, it's too late here.
You can just console.log to and from
or send data to your server, as I said, but that's about it.
So here, I will console.log Global afterEach.
And if I do that and save this,
we see if I load that, Global afterEach
is the last thing we see on every navigation action.