Here's another feature
which can be useful,
especially used in conjunction with
navigation guards.
And that would be a Route Meta Fields.
On any given route in your route config,
you could add a extra property,
the meta property.
Meta takes any kind of value,
for example an object,
and you can store any kind of values in there.
For example,
needsAuth set to true,
but this is entirely up to you.
Why could this be useful?
Well, you can access this meta field in all the places
where the route object,
the dollar sign route object is available.
And that's the case inside of components
and with that you could pass data
into a component which is loaded for this route,
but you can also use it in your navigation guards
because there you also got access to the
to and from route objects.
And you could then for example add meta
like this to indicate that this route
needs authentication,
to then go to the Global beforeEach route
and check if the route you're going to
in it's meta field needsAuth, if that's truthy.
And then here you could check whether
the user is authenticated.
For the moment I'll just log Needs auth!,
but here you could then check
whether a user is authenticated
and if that is the case, you confirm this
and otherwise you deny this.
With that you could use a global navigation guard
that runs for every route, to then
still do different things based on the meta data
attached to the different routes.
And that is something which also
can be useful to elegantly setup
a global navigation guard that still
does different things based on
the meta data you attached to a route.
It's an advanced concept you'll definitely
not need it all the time, but having
this extra data which you can pass
into a component and into this route object
more importantly when a certain route is matched,
can be useful at times.