Now we know all the core
and even some advanced features which you need to know
about the Vue Router and about routing.
And we saw all those important features
in action in this demo project.
Now we're going to build a bigger project in the next module
where all of that makes even a bit more sense
since we'll then have a more realistic project.
Before we go there though,
let's talk about organizing our different files and folders,
because at the moment I'm working with the components folder
with my different feature areas
and then the different components, nothing wrong with that.
But when you use routing, you could also argue
that you don't just want to have components,
but maybe also a pages or a screens folder.
And I'll go with pages.
This is optional.
You don't need that,
but you could then put the components
which are loaded as pages through your router
into the pages folder to have a clear distinction
between the components which are loaded through the router,
and the regular components,
which you embed in your templates.
Maybe you don't want this distinction.
For team members, we for example ensured
that route parents are passed in as prompts.
So maybe that should be usable
as a regular component as well,
but maybe you do want this distinction.
And then, of course, we could move Users List Vue
and Teams List Vue,
and also the Not Found page over into the pages folder,
and also adds to Users Footer and the Teams Footer diary.
And it's up to you,
whether you also want to use Team Members or not.
Now we just need to update all the imports
and import team's list from pages/TeamsList,
users list from pages/UsersList and so on.
Do that for all those pages.
And again, this is really optional,
but it can make sense especially in bigger apps,
since it makes it easier to see
which components will be loaded as pages through the router
and which components will be used as components
that are embedded into other components templates.
Now, with that you don't just need to update all the imports
in the main JS file, of course,
but also any imports you have
inside all of your page components,
because here the POS are now incorrect.
We need to go up one level with two dots and a slash,
then go into the Components folder
and then here into Users, UserItem.vue for teams list.
I also need to update teams item,
which I get from components.
So going up on level of components, teams,
and TeamsTtem.vue.
And with that that re-compiles and works as before,
but now the pages are organized in a separate folder.
Again, it's up to you whether you want this,
but I want to show this possible way
of organizing components.
Now related to reorganizing our files and folders,
you might notice that the main JS file gets rather big
with all our routes in here.
Now this is of course a small app but even with that,
all the routing logic takes up quite a bit of space in here.
Now this is not bad per se,
but it makes it harder to find the place
where you actually create your app and so on.
Hence you might wanna use a separate router JS file
and actually move all the routing related code
into that file.
So grab all that code here and move it into router JS,
except for the app Import.
And in main JS now get rid of all those other imports
and then take the router
and all the routing logic catted from main JS
and added here in router JS.
And then at the very bottom, export to router as a default
so that we can import it into another file,
because we need to import it into main JS now.
We can import a router from ./outer.js,
and then we can still use router because we're importing it.
But with that, everything will work as before,
but our routing code is now in a separate file
and that makes our code overall
more manageable and maintainable.