Now, that's it for the Vue router.
You learned why we need routing and how to set up routing,
you learned how to register routes,
that there is a lot you can configure there.
You can set up re-directs, paths, names, metadata,
multiple components that should be loaded,
nested routes with children.
We learned how to work with dynamic path segments,
to use route parameters,
which we can extract in the loaded components,
how we can pass those route parameters as props
into the to-be-loaded components.
And, much more.
We learned about all those navigation guards,
and about controlling the scroll behavior.
We learned how to navigate with router-link
or also, programmatically
with the $router property and the push method.
We learned how we can describe the location we want to
go to, for example, by setting up a string path
to which we want to go, or by passing such an object
using the name, adding params and possibly adding
a query parameter.
With all of that, you can provide a great user experience,
you can make sure that users don't lose unsaved changes,
you can make sure that you have URL's
and paths in the URL's that relate to the content
that's visible on the screen,
and you got sharable URL's, which you can copy and paste
to load exactly that place off your Vue application,
even though it's still a single page application.
These are all the things you learned here,
and I can absolutely recommend that you go through
this module again if some things aren't clear,
or maybe in a couple of weeks,
so that you make sure you don't forget all those things
which you learned here.
Because, you will need the Vue router in any bigger
application you are going to build.
And, speaking of that, we are going to build
such a bigger application,
so that we can practice all the things we learned
thus far and also see the router in action,
in a more realistic application.