In the last course section,
we worked on this course project here.
In this course section,
we are going to continue working on this project,
but we will focus on one specific aspect,
and that's authentication.
We will add users, real users to this application.
To be precise, we'll make sure
that you can log in and sign up
and that you then can become a coach
once you are signed up.
Therefore in this module,
we'll explore how authentication actually works
in Vue apps and which steps we need to take to make it work.
We'll then, as I just said, add log in, sign up and log out,
and we'll also add a check to keep users locked in
if they logged in in the past
and then leave the page and then come back.
So plenty of things to cover, let's dive right in.