Before we write any code,
we have to understand how authentication works in Vue apps
or to be precise, in any single-page application.
Because it's a bit different
than the traditional authentication you might know
from websites and web applications
where you use some server-side language.
We're not doing this here.
Vue runs in a browser,
therefore this will work a bit differently.
So, we have our Vue app or any single-page application
using any library or framework, doesn't have to be Vue,
and we got our backend server.
In our case, that's Firebase but it could be
any HTTP server to which we send requests.
Any REST API or GraphQL API.
Now, the thing is that on this server,
we have certain public resources
but also some restricted resources.
For example, in our course project,
we might be able to get coaches
and send messages to coaches without being logged in,
so that would be public data and public resources,
which should be accessible by any visitor of this webpage,
no matter if you are logged in or not.
But then, we also got some resources, some data,
some kinds of requests that should be restricted.
For example, you should only be able to register as a coach
and therefore, create a new coach, if you are logged in.
The same for fetching requests, fetching messages
you as a coach received.
Of course, you need to be logged in to do that.
So we got mixed data on our server
and that's a typical scenario in most websites,
you will have some data that should be accessible by anyone
and some data that's restricted.
Now, the thing is with this setup
where our web application, our website
is kind of detached from the backend,
it's not served by the same server and well,
the backend doesn't really know the front end.
In such scenarios, the server really does not care
about the clients, so about the Vue application
in this case.
The server, in our case, Firebase but again,
you could be using any API, really does not care
about our Vue app.
It doesn't store any information about that app.
It doesn't store, whether the user of this app instance
is actually logged in or not.
Therefore, we'll have to find a way of still keeping track,
whether the visitor of the webpage
who's currently using the website is logged in or not.
Now of course, it always all starts by some login data
being sent from the Vue app to the server.
We have some login page in our Vue app
and once the user entered an email and a password,
that data is sent to the server
to create the user or to log the user in.
And now on traditional websites,
the server would basically store a session,
it would store information about that user
and just send a session ID to the front end,
to the browser, so that there is a connection
between the user using the site and the browser
and the server being aware of that user.
However, that's not how it'll work here
when you have a single-page application talking to an API.
Instead here, the server doesn't store any information
and it'll do something else.
It'll send back a token back to the front end,
back to the single-page application,
in our case, back to the Vue app,
once that login data is validated and verified.
So if it is a valid user who's trying to login,
if that data could be confirmed by the server,
the server generates a token which is in the end,
just a very long string which is sent back to the client.
Now, the thing about this token is that it's created such
that only the server is able to validate it.
Only the server will be able to tell
if a token is valid or not because it was generated
with a certain secret key which only the server knows.
So this token can't be faked.
The token is then sent back to the client
and there, we can store it.
We can store it in Vuex or also in more permanent places
like local storage.
And the thing with that token now is that it can be attached
to these outgoing requests to restrict the resources.
And if that token is attached,
since only a server is able to validate the token,
if the server receives a request
to a restricted resource with a valid token,
the server will grant access
and return the appropriate data.
If the token is invalid or missing, access is denied.
That's how authentication works
in single-page applications talking to an API
and that's exactly the setup we have here
and exactly the setup you will have
in most Vue applications you're going to build.
Therefore, this is the scenario
we'll have a look at in this module.
Now of course in our app,
we also want to have some implications of the user
being logged in or not on our webpage itself,
not just on the requests that are being sent.
For example, this requests menu item
should only be clickable if the user is logged in.
We should only be able to register as a coach
with the button that is sometimes visible here
if we are logged in.
Otherwise, we want to offer a login button to the user.
So, these are also implications of authentication
being added to the app.
And with that theory out of the way,
let's now step-by-step add authentication
and see all of that in action.