So two add authentication
I will first of all ensure
that Firebase doesn't grant access to all resources
at the moment it does that
because in their real time database which we're using
under rules we started in this test mode
where we in the end allow reading and writing
to all resources that are exposed by Firebase.
And that's definitely not the idea here
we definitely don't wanna do that anymore
instead only some resources should be accessible by anyone
and other resources should be protected.
For example in our app here,
the list of coaches here
and sending a message to a coach
that should be available to everyone
on the apprehend viewing the requests here
and then also signing up as a coach
that should only be available to log in users
and we can tweak the Firebase rules to make sure that
this is all the reflected on the backend.
Now, if you're not using Firebase,
if you wrote your own API for example with note JS,
you'll of course have to write
a code to check this on your own on the backend
here with Firebase and the real time database,
we can tweak those rules a little bit
to control how read and write access is granted.
So how does this work here with Firebase?
In this rules object here
you'll see those read and write keys
and then that in the end is a value
that resolves to true or false.
Now we can rewrite these rules a bit.
And for that I'll quickly have a look at my data first,
we have to keep in mind that
we've got coaches and requests now in the end
we wanna allow reading of coaches to everyone,
but saving a new coach
that should not be possible for everyone
and for the requests sending
so saving a new request should be available to everyone,
but reading should be restricted.
So the effort in the rules here,
we can dive into the rules object,
and here we can actually add coaches
because we have a data node called coaches in our database
and now we can set up read and write rules
for that part of the database.
We can do the same here for requests
to set up read and write rules for requests
and then we can have general reader write rules
that apply to the rest of our database.
So, which share rules do I wanna have here?
For the coaches I wanna make sure that
any data in that data note
can be read by anyone
and for that we set the dot read rule here to true.
This makes sure that everyone has full read access,
but write, dot write should be restricted
we can set this to false
and then no one would be able to write,
but I will actually set it to a string
where I check if off is not equal to null.
Now off is a special variable
available in the Firebase rules which will be not null
if we added a valid token to the request,
as long as we don't send along any token it will be null.
So then this is null and then writing will be denied.
Now, I'm just showing you these rules here
because it's not a Firebase course
if you plan on using Firebase for your own project,
you can dive into the official Firebase talks
to learn all about these rules.
Now for requests we have exactly the opposite
read is denied if we're not authenticated,
but writing is actually possible for everyone.
And these are very simple trivial rules
which you could definitely refine a bit more.
Now we can get rid of these general read and write rules
here and then publish our new rules.
If we do that and go back to our application,
we can reload the coaches page and that works,
but on requests we now get an error
because we fail to fetch our requests
and we get back a four 0 one error
unauthorized because now Firebase is blocking access here.
It's not allowing us to fetch requests
because of our new rules.
The same would happen if we tried to register as a coach,
if I send some data here,
you see, we also get back the four 0 one response here
We don't have error handling in the app
which is why we don't see a modal here,
but that request clearly failed.
Now we update it to date on the front end here,
because that's how our app currently works
But if I reload you see that data isn't really there.
Now of course these are all things
we're going to fix throughout this module.
Now last but not least if I try to send a message
that should succeed,
we can view it in Firebase in data if we go to requests
we see there we have a new message,
the message I just sent
because writing two messages is something we allow.
So with that we tweaked Firebase
and now we need such a token.
And for that we first of all
need a way of letting the user log in and sign up.
So let's add a sign up and log in page
then sent that day to Firebase in exchange for a token.
And then thereafter work with that token.