So time to add a signup page.
For that here under pages,
I will add a new subfolder, auth.
And in there, add the UserAuth.vue file,
which will hold our user authentication form.
And as I just said it,
in here, I wanna have a form.
A very simple form
where we maybe have a div with a class of form-control.
And then inside of that div,
we have a label for the email field
where we say E-Mail
and below that, we have an input of type email
where users should enter his or her email address.
So I have an id of email here.
And then we can copy that to do the same for the password.
So here we have type password, id=password
and we say Password on the label.
And below that, we have the base-button
where we say Login.
And the caption of this button should change,
depending whether we wanna log in or not
because I'll add a second button here
where I set the type to button
so that this button won't submit the surrounding form
where I say Signup instead.
And where I set the mode to flat.
This will ensure that this allows us
to switch between signing up and logging in.
Now, for some styling,
I think we can reuse the styling we find on another page,
the ContactCoach page.
Here we can grab the styling defined here.
I don't grab the errors
and don't grab the actions
because I'm not using this here.
And simply add styling to this component now
and yes, we could try to set this up
as general app-wide styling
or create separate components and hold inputs
but I will just copy those styles here
and repeat the styling code a little bit.
And one thing I forgot,
I also wanna put all of that into a base-card component here
for some nice styling.
Okay.
Now, that's the basic UserAuth page.
Let's now bring it to the screen
so that we can fine tune it.
And it should be loaded as a route.
So in the router.js file,
we can register a new route.
Maybe here right before our catch all route,
which is /auth let's say
where the component is this newly added component.
So we import UserAuth from ./pages/auth/UserAuth.vue.
That's the component we just added here.
And now, UserAuth is the component
that should be loaded when we visit /.auth.
So with that added,
if we now enter /auth,
and of course, we'll soon add navigation options
to get there, this is this component.
Now, one thing I wanna change here in the styling,
the form shouldn't have this border,
doesn't need the border radius.
We can get rid of that.
Now this looks better.
And actually, I will also swap this
and move the form into the base-card
and not the other way around.
Yeah, this now looks better.
So now we've got this form.
This button will submit the form.
This button will later help us switch
between signing up and logging in
because of course, this form should be able
to handle both.
And speaking of that,
let's maybe continue with this form right away
and let's make sure that we do gather some user data
and that we do send this to Firebase thereafter.
So for that, back in the UserAuth component,
we, of course, need a script
and we've got some data we wanna manage here
because for example, we wanna manage the user input.
That will be an email address
and that will be a password.
Now, you can also add more complex validation
as we did it in the CoachRegistration component,
in the CoachForm to be precise.
You could do this here in UserAuth
but we practiced this before.
Here I wanna focus just on authentication,
so I will add only very basic validation here.
For example, I will add a formIsValid key,
which initially is true.
And we'll set that to false
if the user submits the form
and email or password should be invalid.
We also need to be able
to switch between signup and login mode
because that will change which action
will be dispatched later,
which HTTP request should be sent.
So therefore, I will also add a mode data property here
and set this to login initially
but this can also be signup
once we added the logic.
And that's the next thing.
Let's add some methods.
submitForm is one method.
SwitchAuthMode is another method.
submitForm, well, you guess it,
should be triggered when the form is submitted.
switchAuthMode should be triggered
when this switch button here is clicked.
So we can already wire this up.
Wire up this second button
and point at switchAuthMode.
And on the form, add the submit event handler
with the prevent modifier
and point at submitForm.
Also, connect the inputs with v-model
and connect this one to email
and the second one to password.
With that done, we can start with submitForm
and check if this.email is empty
and actually, therefore,
I wanna use the trim modifier again
to trim any excess white space.
So check if email is then empty.
Or if not this.email.includes an @ symbol,
which is a very trivial validation
of whether we have an email address or not.
Or if this.password.length
is smaller than six characters.
I think that's the minimum Firebase actually wants,
if any of these conditions is met,
then we set formIsValid to false
and we return so that no other code executes.
And we set formIsValid to true initially
when the form is submitted to clear any errors
we might be displaying
because we can now use formIsValid
to show an error message, maybe here in the paragraph
with v-id, check if formIsValid.
Or if it's not valid to be precise
and then show a message
of Please enter a valid email and password.
Must be at least six characters long.
So now we've got this as well.
And that's the basic validation I wanna do here.
Now, if we make it past this if check,
we will then send an appropriate http request
for logging in or singing up
but that will be the next step.
First, let's work on the AuthMode
and here I wanna check if this.mode
is equal to login,
so if we are currently in login mode,
in that case, I'll set mode to signup.
Else if we are in signup,
I'll set mode to login.
And now we can use this mode data property
to control what's displayed on the button here as a caption
but then also, to later change which kind
of HTTP request is sent here.
Now, to change the button captions,
I will use computed properties
to keep that logic in the script here.
And here, I'll have the submitButtonCaption
and the switchModeButtonCaption computed property.
And on the submitButton,
I wanna check if this.mode is equal to login.
And if that's the case, I'll return a caption of Login.
Else we are in signup mode.
I will say Signup.
And for the switchModeButton,
I'll basically do the same.
I will also check in which mode we are.
And if we are in Login mode,
I'll say Signup instead
because that's the new mode this button should toggle.
If we are Signup mode,
I'll say Login instead.
And now we can use these computed properties here.
So here on the submit button,
I output my submitButtonCaption
with interpolation and here on the switch button,
I output my switchModeButtonCaption.
Okay.
Now we can click the Switch button
and we switch between those modes
but at the moment, this, of course,
only affects what we see on the screen
but that's better than nothing.
Now, as a next step,
we need to really get that user input
and then send that data to Firebase
to exchange it for a token
or to create a new user to start with.