Now in order to use that enter data,
and create a user on Firebase,
or get such a token.
We need to go to the Firebase console
and there to authentication.
And here you need to set up a sign in method.
You can also do this here under the sign and methods tap.
And here we want to go with email password
and enable this only this first one click save
And now Firebase supports creating users
with email password.
And of course it also supports logging those in.
Now, if you Google for Firebase off arrest API,
you also find the Firebase docs
for the rest API day offer
for creating users and signing users in
the two end points here are interesting
sign up with email password
sign in with email password.
This only works once you enabled
authentication in your project though.
So these are the end points
to which we now want to send requests
from inside our view app to create a user
and get a token or log a user in.
Before we sent that, though
we can write some code here
because I don't want to send the request
from inside this component.
But again, i want to use view UX,
because it will also be UX
in which we later need to store that token
and stored the information
wherever the user is logged in or not,
because Dad log in mode in which we are,
will affect what we want to display on the page here,
for example, in the navigation.
So we need that as app white state.
Now for this, we can create a new module,
the off module,
or we managed as, as a root state
in our main store object.
So to say,
Now I will go for a separate module.
The Auth module
and in their Eta index.jS fall mutations.js
actions.JS and getters.js
So what we did before as well,
and in our main store module here,
I will then import the auth module
from thought slash modules off in index.js
and add it here under auth key.
Now here's one thing which i won't do.
I will not namespace the auth module
for one simple reason
because in the past i managed my user ID here
as a global state.
And I don't want to change all the code
all over the application
where I use this user ID getter, for example.
So I will now take that getter
and remove it from here,
but by not name spacing this module,
when that module is added to our roots store,
all the gatherers and so on are still accessible as before,
and therefore we don't need to change any ABRA code.
So with the however,
I will grab this getter object here,
remove it and remove togethers key here
and go to my gatters.js file in your folder
and export that object
and grab the state here,
this state, this entire state actually.
Cut it as well.
And add this to index.js
here i export a default object
and here I'll bring in that state.
And here we then also import mutations
from mutations.js
import actions from actions.js
And of course all the import getters from getters.js
and add all those things to this off module object.
So add mutations
actions,
and getters.
Using these JavaScript shorten's
and now we just need to export empty objects
in actions and mutations.
We got our getter and getters.
And with that, we now are using that off module.
Here i now want to define actions
for logging in and signing up.
And of course, all the mutations
that will be committed once that succeeded.