Now, let's start with the actions.
Here I'll add a login action,
and also already a signup action.
And we have to start with signup actually, of course,
because we first need to create a user before we can log in.
Here, we get this context, object and a payload.
And now here, I wanna send a HTTP request
queued as Firebase off REST API,
to sign up with email and password.
So to this URL.
So let's grab this URL here and use the fetch function
to send a request to that URL.
And actually, this URL wants an API key,
which is unique per Firebase application.
So in your Firebase project, you can click on
this gear icon, project settings
and then grab this web API key.
Now you can't use mine because this project
will already be disabled when you're viewing this,
but grab your key in your project.
And once you got that, enter this here instead
of this square bracket, API key square bracket thing.
This is required for the request to succeed later.
Now this sends a request to sign a new user up.
However, just like this, it would send a get request.
And if we have a look at the docs we see instead
it should be a post request.
We also see which data needs to be added
to the request email and password
and then this returnSecureToken key,
which should always be true.
Okay so let's add this second argument,
this configuration object for the request.
Set the method to POST and also set the body
to adjacent stringified object, which has an email field,
which we should get from our payload, a password field,
which I also expect to get on the payload
and this returnSecureToken field,
which should always be true.
And this should send a request that creates a new user.
Now as always fetch returns, a promise,
and therefore, we can either use then and define the code
we wanna execute once this is done in the function
we pass to then, or we use this alternative way
of using async await, which I'm doing here
so that we can await the response.
And then the next line only executes
once that response is there,
And here I get that responseData
by awaiting response.json.
And then we can also check if the response
is maybe not okay, in which case I wanna construct an error,
a new error, where I look into my response data
and see if I got a message there.
And otherwise I will set this to failed to authenticate.
And then I throw this error.
And if we make it past this if check,
we should have a valid response and authentication
should have succeeded.
Actually I will also console.log response data here
so that we see what's in a response, if it's not okay,
so which kind of data we get back from Firebase then.
So if we make it past this if check,
we succeeded and now we wanna see
what's in the response data in the success case.
Actually, we don't even need to guess because we see it here
in the response payload documentation.
We will get back an ID token, which is this token
I mentioned on the slide.
We get back an email, a refreshToken,
which we don't need here,
information on when that token expires.
For security reasons, it doesn't live forever.
You could refresh it with the refreshToken,
but that's advanced and we're not going to cover it here.
And you get back local ID, which is the user ID
of the newly traded user.
And there are at least three interesting pieces
of information here, the token, which we will need later
to send requests, to restrict the resources,
the expiresin information
so that we know how long that token is valid
and the user ID.
So in the mutation, which we should create here,
I wanna store all that data in the UX.
I'll name the mutation setUser,
because it's not tied to signing up or logging in.
Here, we get that data back for signing up.
But if we check for signing in, so if we're logging in,
we see it's pretty much the same information.
So therefore, I'll have the same mutation.
And here I get my state and also payload.
And I wanna set state.token equal to payload.token.
Set state.userId equal to payload.userId
and set state.tokenExpiration
equal to payload.tokenExpiration.
So this assumes that we get a payload
that has these three fields when this mutation is committed.
Now we wanna commit setUser here in our action.
There, with context commit,
we want to commit setUser,
and now we need to pass an appropriate payload object,
which has token.UserId and tokenExpiration fields.
So back in our action here in this object,
I'll set the token equal to responseData.IdToken
because it's the IdToken field on the response
that holds that token.
And it's a local ID for the user ID.
So therefore, I'll set the userId field on the payload
be passed to the mutation to responseData.localId.
Now regarding the tokenExpiration,
for the moment, I'll just set this
to responseData.expiresIn, but we'll change this later.
We will only need this later.
So for the moment, it doesn't matter too much.
Now, we set these three fields in this mutation
and therefore, in the initial state,
I also wanna set them.
Initially, let's say userId is null.
Token is null and tokenExpiration also is null.
Now with that, we prepared the action and mutation.
Now we can go back to the UserAuth page
and dispatch this action when this form is submitted
and we have valid input here.
So then I wanna check if this mode is equal to login,
in which case the login action should be dispatched,
which we don't support yet,
but else, we have the signup mode.
I want to dispatch this.$store with dispatch sign up.
Since the module isn't namespaced,
we don't need to add any namespace here.
This will dispatch to signup action.
And, of course, we need to pass some payload to this action
because on this action, we expect to get the email
and password on the payload.
So therefore, here we should set email equal to this.email,
to the entered email in this component and password
to this.password.
Okay, if we now save that and we go back.
If we go to sign up instead and we try to submit this
in an empty way, we get our error.
Also, if we are just missing the password,
but if the data here is valid
and we try this, we don't get any visual feedback
at the moment, but we get this response,
which looks pretty good.
It's an object with all that data I described,
with the localId and so on.
And on Firebase, if we refresh this user's page
under authentication, we should also see that user here,
Now if I try creating the same user again,
we will see that we get an error
and that's the response data we got back from Firebase
in an error case where we have a nested error object
with a message of EMAIL_EXISTS.
We can utilize this in our action for better error handling
thereafter but that's actually the next step
because I also want to show a loading spinner
whilst we are submitting, for example,
but the main takeaway is that it generally works.
So now let's work on the feedback we give the user
before we then take the next steps
and also make login work and then use that token.