So let's work on the feedback,
we're providing to the user
both in the error case
as well as whilst we're
waiting for the request to be sent.
Now in our action,
the signup action,
I'm using async await,
therefore as you learnt already,
this always returns a promise.
Sometimes it returns a promise that fails,
for example, if we throw this manual error.
So with that we can go back to UserAuth
and there add two new keys
to the data we're managing here.
isLoading, which is false initially
and error which is null initially
and in submit form,
if we make it past the validation step,
I'll set this isLoading to true
and then once we're done dispatching here,
I'll set this isLoading to false.
Now for that we need to wait for this action
to finish though,
otherwise we set this instantly to false,
after this has been dispatched
without waiting for the response
and therefore I'll this into an async function as well,
async method submitForm
and we can then await this dispatching action.
In addition, we can wrap this all
with try catch,
this if block here,
so that we catch any error
that might be thrown
and we can then set this error equal to error.message
or to a fallback message of
Fail to authenticate, try later,
anything like that.
You can of course
also fine tune the error message you're throwing here
inside of your action.
Check your login data, for example
but you can also be more specific
for example by drilling into that response object
you get back from Firebase.
Here you can really fine tune this
to your requirements
but with that back and user off,
we try catch this,
we set the error.
Now we just need to reflect the loading state
and the error on the user interface
and I will do that with help of my base dialog.
I'll add a base dialog here
and wrap this all into a div
so that we don't have multiple root level components
because as you learnt,
that's not something the transition component wants
but then I have a base dialog here,
where I actually wanna show a loading spinner
and therefore I'll use this fixed prop,
which we also have on the base dialog,
you might remember
that I talked about that
when I added the base dialog component.
It ensures that the dialog can't be dismissed
and I'll bind show to isLoading,
as long as we're loading
this dialog will be shown
and inside of that dialog,
I then have a paragraph,
where I say authenticating
and below that I show my base spinner
and I'll add another base dialogue,
which I wanna show in the error case.
By the way, on this other dialog,
I'll first of all also set a title,
where I also say authenticating,
I guess we can then get rid of the paragraph though.
So let's get rid of that,
just show the spinner
and say Authenticating in the title
but now back to the other dialog here.
I wanna show this if we do have an error,
so with this double exclamation mark trick,
I ensure that this true or false value
is converted to a Boolean.
Can set the title here to
An error occurred
and then inside of that dialogue,
I add a paragraph
where I output my error message like this.
With that added,
if we save it all
and go back,
go to sign up mode
and I entered the same email address as before
and I click Sign up,
we see that spinner
and then that error dialog.
Dismissing doesn't work at the moment as I can see,
because obviously we should listen
to the closed event on the error dialog,
not on the other one,
because the loading dialog is dismissed automatically
but the error dialog should be dismissed by us
with a handle error method,
we should add,
in which we simply reset our error data property.
So here I'll add handleError
in the methods of this component
and set this error back to null.
With that it's a false value
and then this will no longer show the dialog.
So with that,
back in the app,
if I again try this with an email I already used, we fail,
if I use a valid email,
for signing up we succeed.
So that works now,
we got that visual feedback.
We also might want to redirect the user thereafter
but that's also something I'll focus on later
because what I wanna do at the moment,
is also make login work
and then do something with the token.