So, to make "Log in" work,
we can go back to our Vuex actions.
And here, the "Login" action.
We can already add "Async."
Because, we will definitely also send that HTTP request
in here.
We can copy this code from "Signup."
Because, we sent the same kind of data.
We also send a post request.
But, the URL will be different.
If we have a look at the Firebase Auth REST API docs.
Here, under "Sign in"; which is "Log in."
It's this URL, which we need now.
It has the same request body payload though.
So, grab this URL and replace it.
Here, up to your API key. Which is the same.
And with that, this should work.
Of course, you could also refactor this into some function,
to have less code duplication.
But, I like to be explicit here.
So I will keep it like this.
Now, we still wanna get the response data,
check for errors, and commit some action at the end.
So, we can copy all of that, as well.
And with that, we should be pretty good!
We can also commit the same mutation,
because we get the same data back.
It's really just the URL that's different.
That, then, ensures that we're logging in,
instead of signing up.
But, other than that we're doing the exact same thing.
And again, therefore, if you wanted to,
you could absolutely, also, refactor this to be one action,
where we control the URL with a payload, for example.
Or, anything like that. But I'll go for two actions here.
And of course, also get my "Context and payload."
Here, on the "Login action." And with that done,
we now, can dispatch this action.
So back in "UserAuth."
Here,
I want to: "Await this.
$store.
dispatch/
('login')" and send the same payload as before.
Now, we can, of course, also refactor this.
For example:
create an "ActionPayload" constant,
which holds this object.
And then simply use this object,
here
and here.
So, that we are reusing at least a little bit of code.
So, now we're dispatching these actions.
We're waiting for them. We're showing feedback.
And if we give this a try
and save that,
back in our
application here.
If I use an email address and a valid password,
and I click "Log in," this looks like a success response.
If I use an invalid password, I get an error.
So, that's looking good!
With that,
we can now start using that token.
and attach it on outgoing requests.
So, that, we again are able to register as a coach
and view requests.
Because at at the moment, this of course, fails.