Thanks to our mutation.
We are storing the token in UX,
and that means that of course,
we can also access it from anywhere in this app
whenever we need it.
And I mentioned that we would need to add that token
to outgoing requests.
If these requests target and points,
resources on Firebase that are protected.
So therefore we probably should add some getters here
in our auth module,
a token getter,
for example,
where we simply returned state token.
And now we can use this in the other modules.
When we send requests to protected URLs.
For example, for coaches under actions.
When we register a coach,
here this resource is currently not accessible.
If we're not authenticated,
well that's something we can change.
If you send a request to your Firebase realtime database,
you can add a off token
by adding a query parameter to this URL.
That's something you can read in the official Firebase docs.
Here we can add the auth query parameter
after a question mark at the end of this URL
and set the value equal to our token
because that token is just a string in the end.
So now here we need our token, of course,
so we can get debt by accessing
context,
getters,
token,
just like that.
And then we can add our token to this URL
with that registering should be possible.
We already are also using our user ID,
which is now our real user ID
generated by Firebase.
So that's not also an improvement.
Now for
requests
under actions,
it's fetch requests,
which doesn't work.
If we don't have a token.
So here we'll do the same thing.
Get our token with context.
Actually we should use
rootgetters.token,
and also under coaches.
That should be rootgetters
because we access this on our rootstore,
not on this module specifically,
but on our rootstore.
So context rootgetters token it is.
And then add debt token here as well
with question mark of equals plus token.
Now with that,
if we save all of that,
if I go to requests and reload,
we still fail because we're not logged in yet.
At the moment we need to log in manually all the time
will soon change this though,
but let's go back to slash off by entering this
and then log in.
And then go to requests.
And now you see, we don't find messages for us,
which makes sense,
but we don't get an error.
If I go to all the coaches,
I can also register as a coach now.
And if I give this a try,
I'm a web developer and freelancer,
let me boost your career,
And click register.
This also seems to work.
And if I reload now,
this data is still there
because it now ended up in the real time database
on Firebase
here under coaches.
We now see that real user ID has a note for the coach data,
I just to added.
So that's great,
with that we now successfully attached to token
to outgoing requests,
which is a huge step forward.
Now we can start working on the UI a little bit.
For example, at the moment we manually
have to enter a slash off to reach this page,
would be nicer if we had an option here in the navigation,
or maybe here instead of register as coach,
if we need to be logged in,
in order to register,
we should probably not even show this button
if we're not logged in.
So as a next step,
we're going to update that UI.