So for updating the UI,
I got two main areas.
And that's this register as coach button,
which I wanna replace if we're not logged in.
And requests also shouldn't be visible here
if we're not logged in.
Instead, maybe we wanna show a login button.
For that, I will start in my getters
in the auth module though.
So, there in getters.
I'll add a new getter isAuthenticated.
And here, I wanna check if we are authenticated.
And how can we tell whether we are authenticated or not?
Well, if we got a token, then we are authenticated.
Because we start without one,
and I will later reset it
once we added a log out functionality.
So, if we have a token, we are authenticated.
So, I will return state.token;
and convert this to a true Boolean
by adding the double exclamation mark again.
Now, we can use the isAuthenticated getter
into different parts of this app.
For example, under a coach's list.
Here, we have this register as coach button,
and that should not be visible if we're not even logged in.
Instead, I wanna show a login button or link instead.
So, therefore, we can add a new computed property
here to coach's list,
the isLoggedIn computed property, for example,
where I return this.$store.getters.isAuthenticated;
Since this module is not namespaced,
we can access the getter just like this.
Now, we can use isLoggedIn
and only show this register as coach button
if we're not a coach,
we're not loading and we are logged in.
So, if we are logged in and we're not a coach
and we're not loading,
then I wanna show this button.
And, of course, you could also put this all
into one computed property
to take this logic out of the template.
Now, I will add a new base-button here,
which will act as a link to="/auth"
where I say login if we are not logged in.
So, if we're not logged in,
if we're not logged in,
this button will be shown.
Now, with that saved,
here we see the login button.
And we click it,
we go to the login page.
Now, for the navigation bar,
that's TheHeader in the layout folder under components.
And here, we now also need to add a script,
to add a computed property
to get access to our getters.
I will also add a isLoggedIn getter
at our computed property here
and return this.$store.getters.isAuthenticated;
That getter we added a couple of minutes ago.
And I'll only show this list item
with the requests link if we are logged in.
Otherwise, I'll show a different list item
with a <router-link to="/auth"
where I say login.
With that, if we save this,
we now see login here as a navigation item.
If I do log in, you see,
we have requests instead,
And on all coaches,
we would see the register as coach button
if we wouldn't be registered already.
So, now let's also add a log out button
and a log out functionality
and check a couple of other things we can do
here on our front end.