Now to add a log out functionality
here in the header,
I'll add a nother list item
with a base button in it,
where I say,
log out.
Gives us this button
and then buttons should do just what it says.
It should log us out.
Of course this list items should only be visible
if we are locked in,
because it makes no sense to show a log out button,
if we aren't locked in.
And now we need to add a new action,
and that's the log out action.
So here in the off module in the actions file,
I add a log out action.
And now logging out is really trivial.
We don't need to send any request
because you might remember that I said that the server
doesn't store any information about us anyways.
So there's no need to send a request.
Instead, the only thing we gotta do
is clear all that data here,
set it back to null.
Hence, we get our state
and we can simply set state token equal to null,
state user ID and set is equal to null,
and state token expiration and set it to null.
And that's all we gotta do.
Now, since we, for example,
checking our is authenticated headed gather,
whether we have a token,
this we'll set is authenticated header to false.
Once we set the token to null,
because that then is an invalid token.
Now of course though,
that's not the valid way of doing it.
That's an action, not a mutation,
we got a mutation set user already.
And in the end here, we are setting the free fields
which we wanna reset.
So we just need to pass a payload
with null values for all those fields.
So in the log out, action,
we actually get the context of the state
but then here we should simply context commit,
set user,
and pass in our payload object,
where token is null,
user ID is null,
and token expiration is null
for the same reason as just explained.
That's now a proper way of doing it.
And with that action added back in the header,
we can add a click listener
to this log out button
and in our script then add methods
and add a log out method
where we reach out to our store
and dispatched this log out action.
And now this log out method can be connected to this button.
And if we do this once this reloads,
we can log in,
let's say with test2 user
like this
now on all coaches, we also see the register as coach button
because this user isn't registered yet.
We can go to requests and we can click log out
and we see that updates.
Now, one thing that doesn't update
neither when we log out, nor when we log in,
is the page on which we are.
Now, if we do log in, it would be nice
if we would be redirected
back to the coaches' page for example.
If we do log out and I'm on requests,
it may be, would be nice,
since I can't technically go to requests anymore,
if I all did would be redirected somewhere else.
So let's work on that
routing and redirection part next.