Now, whilst we implemented Navigation guards,
I already brought up one problem.
Whenever we manually enter a URL,
we lose all our authentication data.
That of course also means that if we leave this page
and we come back later,
even if we logged in five minutes ago,
we will have to log in again.
Because every time this page is reloaded,
we start a new Vue application with a new Vue X store
and therefore all the data we had
in the Vue X store before is lost.
That's just how the browser and JavaScript works.
But that does not mean that we can't store data,
which survives browser reloads.
And therefore, that's the next thing I want to do.
I want to ensure that users can stay logged in.
For that, we first of all,
need to go to our auth action
and restructured a code here a little bit.
We've got the log in and the sign up actions
and the log out actions.
I will add a new action auth, which gets a context,
and now I will actually refactor the other two actions
so that we don't have as much code duplication
because I will now add even more code
that it would be duplicated otherwise.
So I will wrap this code from login and copy it
and add it here in the new auth action,
get rid of console log,
we don't need that anymore.
And here, I now just expect that on the payload,
which I get here, I also get the mode log in or a sign up.
So maybe a mode key on the payload.
And then we've got the URL, which is a variable,
which by default, let's say, is that log in URL here.
But if mode is equal to sign up,
then I want to replace URL
with the sign up URL,
which we can grab here from the signup action.
Copy it and add it here.
And the idea here is that we now simply can use URL here
in the actual fetch function
and reset URL appropriately before
and the rest of the code then it's the same anyways.
So here we don't really need to differentiate.
Now, I also want to use async here
so that this still returns a promise
and we can use the await keyword,
so auth should be async.
And now we can go to the log in action
and get rid of all that code
and instead use context dispatch
to dispatch the auth action
here from inside the log in action
and pass on an object
where I, first of all,
copy existing payload by using the Spread operator,
hence spreading copying all the key value pairs off payload
into this new object,
which has passed as a payload to the auth action.
And then I add mode and set this to log in here
because we need that mode key in the auth action.
And then we can copy that and do the same for signup
and here set mode to sign up.
Now important, we want to return to result of dispatching
so that this promise, which is returned by auth,
isn't the end all returned by log in and sign up
so that our components can still keep track of
whether we are still waiting for a response,
whether we got an error and so on.
With that changed, if I go to log in,
let's quickly test this.
This is still looking good.
So looks like we still are able to send these requests.
Yeah, that's looking good.
Signing up with a user that already exists fails.
So now I refactored to this
and I did this for a very good reason
because now we have to store that data,
the token, the local ID, and now, or at least soon,
also the expiration not just in UX,
we do need it there but not just,
but also in some storage that survives page reloads.
And a great example here would be local storage,
which is an API built into the browser.
So it's some browser storage,
which we can access from inside JavaScript.
For that here, before I commit sets user,
I will access local storage just like this,
it's available in the browser,
and then call set item to store in new data
in local storage.
And here in the end, I want to store my token,
which I get from response data.id token.
And I also want to store the user ID,
which I get from response data, local ID.
So now we don't just commit it to UX,
but we also store it in the browser storage.
And I'm doing this so that we then also can add an action
where we check for this data when the app starts
and when that data is available,
we automatically log the user in.
Because at the moment, if I save that,
if we reload this app,
if I log in,
it still works as before.
And when I reload that state is lost.
But now if you go to the Def tools of your browser
and there to your application in Chrome at least,
you can visit the local storage,
you can view that,
and in here you will see a user ID and a token field,
and that's that data which I'd just stored.
And now we can use that to log the user in.
By the way, we can view that data, but it's also our data.
So that's no problem.
It belongs to us as a user.
So now we can add a new action
auto log in or try log in whatever you want to name it,
where we do just that.
We check whether that data exists
and if it does, we set a user, if it doesn't, we don't.
So here we also get context.
And then we can access local storage
and get an item, the token,
stored at in a token constant,
also gets the user ID,
and then check if we got a token and a user ID, let's say,
then I want to context commit,
set user and pass that data on.
So here past that payload to set user,
where I set the token to the token we extracted
from local storage and set the user ID
to the user ID we extracted from local storage
and set token expiration to null at the moment
because we're not using it yet.
That will change soon.
And if we don't have a token or we don't have a user ID,
this will not be committed and we will not set the user.
We will not log the user in automatically so to say.
With that, however, we now need to dispatch this action
whenever our app starts to check
whether we can log the user in automatically.
And the best place to do that is the App Vue file
because that is our root component.
This gets created first when the entire app starts up.
So here we can add the created lifecycle hook,
which has fired when this component is created.
And there we can then reach out to our store
and dispatch the try log in action.
And with that, if we save this,
you see if I now reload,
I actually end up in logged in mode.
And I can even reload on requests and we stay on that page.
So now logging the user in automatically works.
The only thing we now got to take care of
is that we cleared the data if we log out,
because at the moment if I then reload, I'm logged in again,
because I don't clear the data in local storage.
And we also should log the user out automatically
when the token expires,
because it turns out that the token has a limited lifetime
for security reasons.