So let's start with logging the user out
and clearing the data.
For that and the log out action besides committing this,
we should also reach out to local storage
and remove the token and all the remove the user ID.
Now that was the easy part.
The more tricky part is that we wanna log the user out
automatically if the token expired.
And for that got this token expiration,
which we aren't really using at the moment though.
Now when we do log in
here like this,
in the data which we get back from Firebase,
as you see in their docs, we also get the expires in field,
which is a text, but actually holds the number of seconds
in which the ID token expires.
I can tell you by default, that will be 3,600 seconds,
which is an hour.
Now we wanna store that expiration date,
not the duration because that doesn't help us,
but the expiration date
in the future when the token becomes invalid,
whenever we do log the user in.
So here in our off action, where we sent the request,
when we store that data in local storage,
we now also wanna derive the expiration date,
which has a date in the future, which is the current date,
plus the amount of seconds until the token expires.
So for that we can get the current date by calling new date
that gives us the current timestamp.
But now I wanna add something here and actually for that
I will call get time
to get the current timestamp in milliseconds
and I wanna add the expiration time,
the expiration duration in milliseconds.
So for that I'll add expires in
and get that from responseData.expiresIn times 1,000
and ensure that this is converted to a number
by adding a plus here.
So that is then converting the string to a number
then since this is in seconds, I multiplied with 1,000
to have it in milliseconds
and then I can add expires in here to expiration dates,
to have a new expiration timestamp in milliseconds,
which will be in the future.
Current time plus that duration.
And it's this expiration date,
which now also has to be stored in local storage.
So here I set a new item, which is the expiration,
which is called token expiration,
which is that expiration date.
And here we now also store data in UX the expiration date.
Actually, we don't even need it in UX
because local storage is enough.
It only matters to us when we reload the page.
So we don't need to commit it here and then in mutation,
we can actually also get rid of it here
And in try log in we also don't need to set this anymore.
Instead now we store it in local storage,
but I wanna do one other key thing.
I wanna set a timer whenever the user is logged in
so that we automatically log user out
if that timer expires.
And that's something that we'll also do here
in the auth actions.
I will set a new time out here where I have my expires in
so this time in milliseconds as a duration,
and after that duration, this function will execute.
And in this function,
I will simply dispatch the log out action,
because that's what I wanna do if the token expires.
I also wanna make sure that I only have one timer active
at a time so I will actually add a global variable here,
timer, which I use to hold my timer like this,
and then we can use this timer variable
from anywhere in this file to clear the timer.
And I wanna clear it whenever we log out.
When we log out, I wanna call clear timeout
and pass this timer variable to it,
to clear the ongoing timer.
For example, if we manually clicked the log out button,
then I also wanna clear the log out timer.
I also of course, wanna remove the token expiration item
from local storage if we do log out.
And also not commit to this anymore
because we don't store token expiration in Vuex anymore.
So now we've got this timer set whenever we logged in here,
we also need to set this timer when we automatically log in,
then we need to check how much expiration time is left
and set a new timer to that time.
So that's why I'm storing token expiration in local storage.
So here I can get my token expiration
by accessing local storage get item token expiration,
and that will now be a timestamp in the future.
So we now need to get to the difference
between that timestamp and the current time,
which I'll again store in a constant named expiresIn
which is that token expiration converted to a number
by adding a plus minus to current time
as a timestamp in milliseconds.
So that will then be the difference in milliseconds
between this time and a future when the token expires
and the current time.
And of course, if expires in, should be negative here,
then we don't even need to log the user in.
We could even argue that if it's smaller than let's say
10,000 so smaller than 10 seconds,
that even then logging the user in makes no sense.
But I will go with smaller zero here.
And if expires in a smaller than that,
then the token is definitely invalid
so then in that case, I will just return here
and not continue with logging the user in
because the timer expired,
there is no need to continue here.
Otherwise though, if the timer is positive,
if we have enough time left, if the token is still valid,
I again will set a timer here with expiresIn as a duration
and just as on my average timer in this function,
I'll call context dispatch log out
and store that timer in the timer variable.
Okay, so theoretically that should work.
In order to test it,
I will manually tweak this expiration time a bit
and when we log in,
I will not set it to the actual exploration duration
which we have.
But instead I'll duplicate this
and comment out to the correct one
and just set it to five seconds.
So now after five seconds, we should be logged out.
So if we give this a try and reload and log in here,
that works, but after five seconds
we shouldn't be logged in anymore.
And that looks good.
The UI switched to not logged in state.
That should also work if I reload the page in between.
So if I reload, I'm still logged in,
but still this should then update and it does.
Now one problem we have with this solution
can be seen if I visit a protected page like requests,
if I'm logged out, I now stay on this page.
So we should ensure that we redirect the user
if we automatically log the user out.
And to achieve this redirecting upon auto log out,
I will add a new action, which I name autoLogout
where I get my context
and where I will dispatch the regular log out,
but where in addition,
I will also commit and never a mutation,
which we have yet to add, which I'll name didLogout.
And in this mutation did log out, I'll set a new state
did log out to true,
and that's some state we first of all wanna add to our
main state here in the auth index JS fall
did log out initially is false,
maybe name it did auto log out to be clearer,
I will also name it did auto log out here when I update it
and named a mutation, did auto log out.
Maybe also the name it set auto log out to be in line
with the other mutation and then in actions dispatch
set auto log out.
Now what's my idea here with that auto log out thing,
which I now is set?
That should be set
when the auto log out action is dispatched.
So now in the timer, I wanna dispatch all the log out
here and also in the other place where I create the timer.
And the idea is that now in App View, we can add a watcher
and watch this all the log out.
For that, we just need to add a getter
did auto log out, we get our state
where return state.didAutoLogout.
So that state which I'm setting in this mutation
returned by this getter and in App View,
we can then add a compute property, did auto log out
where I returned this store.getters.didAutoLogout,
and then we can watch this, didAutoLogout computed property
received a new value or the current value and the old value.
And we can now check if current value is true.
So if we did auto log out
and current value is not the same as the previous value.
So it did change and it is now true,
then we can use the router
to redirect to slash coaches let's say.
With that when we automatically log the user out,
we redirect to coaches.
So if we now give us a try and we are on slash requests,
we are redirected to coaches.
So now with that,
that would be one way I can think of that
should help us redirect the user here.
Now with that auto log out approach and this mutation
where I changed did auto log out,
I also wanna make sure that I changed if we log in again.
So if we set a user again,
then did auto log out is set to false again
so that the next time it switches to true,
we also triggered as watcher again.
This watcher will then run if it's true and changed
and therefore we need to change it back.
Otherwise it would never change again.
I also noticed that, of course now here
in index.js of module,
we can get rid of the token expiration here
because we're not really using it in our Vuex state,
but that's just a side note.
With it we get the auto log out functionality added
and therefore in the auth actions,
I wanna switch back that expires in time to the real time,
which is of course longer than five seconds.
So that now if we log in,
we actually should stay logged in
and we can interact with this application.
And for example, send a message
to a number or a coach, or also send a message to ourselves,
hi there, which we now can also see under requests.
So that's now all auto log in
so that we can reload and stay logged in
and auto log out added to this application.
And therefore we now added all the key building blocks
which you need to add authentication to a View App.