So in this module,
we added authentication to this application.
With that, we can signup and login,
and you saw all the different pieces that you can add
to an application to, well, add authentication.
We used Vuex for the different actions
and for sending the HTTP requests,
and we also used it to manage the log in and log out status,
and to also log the user in and out automatically,
for example, when the token expired or after a page reload.
Now, these are some of the key features
which you will most likely need
in any application you're building.
Here, I'm using Firebase as a dummy backend,
but the general idea is always the same.
If it's your own backend, if it's an API,
which it typically will be,
it will definitely also send back some kind of token,
which you need to store and which you need to manage
and which you need to attach to outgoing requests.
So therefore, what we did in this module
does not just apply to Firebase, but with slight variations
of course, to any backend you might be connecting
to any Vue app.
Therefore, I hope it was helpful
and I hope all these core concepts
are clear and understandable.