We now know that components
can be very useful.
We know how to build them, how to make them reusable.
Also, with the help of props and custom events,
we learned how to combine components
and start building user interfaces with them.
In this module, we're going to dig a bit deeper.
We're going to dive deeper into components
to unlock their full potential and to turn you
into a component and today,
for most importantly, view master.
Now, specifically, we're going to have a look at
component registration and styling.
Of course, we already know how to register a component
with our Vue app, but it turns out
that there is more than one way of doing that,
and that every way has its purpose
and could be the right way of doing it
under certain circumstances.
We're also going to have a look
at how we can style components
and make sure that certain styling
only affects certain components.
We're then also going to explore a concept called slots,
what that is, and why it is useful,
and we're going to explore dynamic components
and where dynamic components could help us.
And last but not least,
we're going to have a look at component names
and possible folder structures we can use in our projects,
especially if our projects are getting bigger
and we wanna make sure that we are quickly able to find
all our different files.
So with that,
let's not waste any time, and let's dive right in.