I got a another starting project for you,
which you'll find attached to this lecture, of course.
In there run npm install.
Once you downloaded it to install all the dependencies
and then with npm run serv like always,
you can bring up that development server
and see this application on the screen.
And here is what you should see on the screen
once you load that, it's a very basic dummy application.
It has no real purpose and it also has no interactivity.
We can't do anything on this page as a user,
but it allows me to dive deeper into components
and show you some other core features.
And we're then going to build a complete application
from scratch and a more realistic application, of course,
in the next module once we covered those important features,
we're going to talk about in this module.
So let's dive into those features
and let me quickly walk you
through this dummy application here,
so that we're all on the same page.
In main.js I'm importing and registering
a couple of components, the components you find here.
In App.vue I'm using The-Header-Component,
there's Badge-List-Component,
and also the User-Info-Component.
To user-info, we're passing some data via props.
The data here is coming from inside the data object
we have in our App.vue files,
so in this configuration for our main app.
And then in the components, in UserInfo,
I'm getting those props
and then I'm just outputting them here.
I'm using the Base-Badge-Component here
and I'm passing more props to that.
The Base-Badge-Component also just has some basic markup.
It's responsible for displaying these badges here,
ADMIN and AUTHOR, which you can see on the screen.
And in the Base-Badge-Component,
I just got a computed property
for deriving this dynamic CSS class object,
which is bound to the class attribute here.
And I also got some styling.
Actually,
I got some styling in a couple of those components.
The Badge-List-Component just shows all available badges
in an onward of list.
So here we're using the base-badge again.
So we're not just using BaseBadge in the UserInfo,
but also in the Badge-List-Component.
And The-Header-Component is a very simple component
where I just render and style the header,
we're seeing on this page.
So let's now see what we can learn about components,
which we haven't learned already.