Let's start with Component Registration.
We are registering our components
with the component method on our App.
And that's how we did it in all the past modules.
Now, there is nothing wrong with this approach per se.
But it's also not always the best way
of registering components.
Because it turns out there is an alternative.
Now, when we register components like this
with the component method on our App,
then we are registering those components
as so called Global Components.
That means they're available globally
in this entire Vue App.
So we can use these components
as custom HTML elements anywhere in this App.
In the App.Vue file, but also in any of our components here.
So they're simply available anywhere in this Route App.
This is of course very useful,
because it means we can use these components
as custom elements anywhere.
And we don't have to think about where to use them.
But it also has one potential downside.
These components, of course, all contain some code.
Now, of course, here, they're all fairly simple components.
But still, it's a little bit of template code,
a little bit of scripting code.
Now, this code, of course grows,
the bigger our application becomes.
The more components we have, the more code packages
we have, you could say.
And if you're registering them all globally,
that in the end means Vue needs to load them all
when the application is loaded initially.
So the browser needs to download the code
for all those components initially.
This is absolutely no problem
for our basic application here,
but for bigger applications, that could be a problem.
In addition, if you register everything globally here,
this can be a very long list.
If you have a application with, let's say,
hundreds of components, this would be a super long list.
And it would not be obvious where
those components are getting used.
If all these components are meant
to be used in multiple places, or if maybe
some of these components are only used in a few places.
For example, TheHeader.
This component is really only used once.
It's used here in App.Vue, the same for UserInfo.
These are components which are just getting
used once and registering them globally, therefore works.
But there's a bit redundant, you could say.
We're just having these components
so that we can outsource our code
and keep our App.Vue file lean,
because that's the idea behind components.
We wanna build complex user interfaces
by combining multiple building blocks.
That's why we also have another way
of registering components.
Despite registering them globally
with this component method on our App,
we can also register them locally in the component
where we plan on using them.
So for example, with TheHeader,
we could remove this component registration in main.js,
and remove this import here.
And instead go to our App.Vue file,
which is where we plan on using this.
And then here in the script section,
we can import TheHeader from components TheHeader.Vue.
And now we can also register this component locally
in this App component or in this App object here
in this App options object.
We do this by adding a new property here
next to data methods computed
and all the other properties you learned about
and that would be the components property,
which we haven't seen before, but here it is.
And we can now tell Vue, which components
may be used in the template of this App here
or of this component.
And the components registered here
are then really only usable here,
not in any other child components,
not anywhere else in our application,
just here in this file, in this .Vue file.
Now components wants an object,
and then we need a key-value pair,
where the key is our custom HTML element.
So TheHeader for example, the tag we wanna use
for this element, so to say,
and then the value is the imported
component config object, we're pointing at.
And If I do that, and Save this, this still all works.
But now TheHeader is registered locally.
And you can actually also write this differently.
This is perfectly fine, but you can
also use TheHeader like this as a key here,
as a property name and you will still be able
to use it like this in your template.
Vue automatically translates this
so that you can use the-header in your template
or in case you prefer it, TheHeader like this.
And then you can also write it
as a self-closing element if you want to.
This self-closing tag is not supported
if you write it with a dash in between,
then this self-closing tag will not work
if you write it in this PascallCase it works.
So this is then up to you which style you prefer.
I will stick to the-header because
that's the style I've been using before
but you could now also use this PascalCase style.
When you register it like this both is possible.
And then you can shorten this even more,
you can remove this key here,
and just pass TheHeader like this,
because there is a modern JavaScript syntax feature
which is supported in this project setup,
where if you just provide a single value here
in an object, this is automatically expanded to this syntax.
So that's simply key and value variable
or value constant have the same name.
So you can then just write TheHeader
and this will register this TheHeader component
under the TheHeader identifier, and you can
then use the-header like this,
or as I explained before, use this PascalCase
if you prefer that.
That if we Save that would also work.
So this is how you can write your components
and use your components.
And this is local component registration.
And of course here in this demo application,
TheHeader is not the only component we can register locally.
If we have a look, the UserInfo
is also a component we simply use here in our App template.
The badge-list would be another candidate.
We also only use that here in our App.Vue file.
So we can actually grab the imports
to UserInfo and BadgeList from main.js
and cut them there.
And remove these global component registrations,
and only leave the BaseBadge here.
And then go to App.Vue and add those imports here.
And then add BadgeList and UserInfo
as local components in the components option here.
And this code should still work
because I didn't change those names here.
Now, this components option is available
in any config object, not just in App.View.
You Could also register local components
in one of your other components
if you had local components that would belong there.
But in this App, that's not the case.
We're now left with the BaseBadge component,
which I'm still configuring globally.
And this is a component I wanna keep
as a global component, because I'm actually
using it in multiple parts of this App.
I'm using it in the BadgeList component,
and also in the UserInfo component.
And whenever you have a general purpose component,
which you're using in a lot of different places,
whenever that's the case, you typically wanna
use a global component, at least you wanna consider it.
Of course, you could also add it
as a local component to multiple other components
if that makes more sense.
But using a global component also often
is correct in such cases.
On the other hand, if you do have components,
which you only use in one hour,
component let's say, then you might
wanna consider registering them as local components
simply to keep your main.js file short
and to not register everything globally.
With that, we got this working,
but now we know global and local registration
and when to use what.