We're going to stick to this global local theme.
Let's talk about styling.
We know how to add dynamic styling and so on,
but I don't want to talk about this,
I want to talk about component styling.
You can that you can add this style tag
to your '.vue' files,
and in here you can set up some styling.
Now maybe you remember that earlier in the course.
I mentioned that no matter where you added your styling,
it would always be treated as global styling
that affects the entire app.
So if I define a section h2 style
here in the Badgelist.vue file
This does not,
important, this does not mean
that this styling would only affect this template.
Instead, indeed, it affects all files.
And I can show this to you
in TheHeader.vue file
I am selecting the header element by its tag
and I'm applying a certain style here.
Now, in user info,
I'm wrapping this h3 tag and my BaseBadge
with a div and actually using a header element here,
makes more sense semantically in my opinion.
But if I switch to a header here,
you will see
that now I got the header styling being applied here
in my Userinfo component as well.
And that of course breaks my style there.
Now this is happening
because I do have my header styling set up
in header.vue,
and as I explained,
even though it's set up in that file
it affects the entire app.
Sometimes this is what you want.
For example in App.vue,
you typically do define
your global application wide styles,
like setting the body or some font family.
So styles that should affect everything in your app,
typically are defined in the style tags
of your App.vue file.
Since this is your entry point
of the entire application.
But if you have styles in individual components,
it often would be nice if you could scope
these styles to those components
to ensure that they really only affect the template
of the component in which you define them,
and vue supports this,
there is a scoped attribute which you can add to
that style tag.
And if you do add it,
that tells vue that the styles defined in here should
only affect the template that lives in the same file,
and no other component, no child component,
no sibling component,
nothing else in your app.
And we can do this in all those components therefore,
so in the header,
I add scoped,
in Userinfo I just added it
in BaseBadge I'm going to add it here
And in BadgeList, I'm also going to add it
to make all those styles scoped.
And if we do that,
you see now we no longer have this style
this header style being applied here.
We also see that some styles broke because I relied
on this global sharing,
but I actually rather fix those broken styles
than having this side effect
of being restricted which element I can use where
or of being forced that I have to ensure manually
that styles don't spill over
and destroy my layout.
So therefore here, in Userinfo,
I'm simply targeting the section header here
to fix the styling in my Userinfo header.
And regarding the available badges,
here in BadgeList.
The problem is that the section lost its styling,
because I did define that styling here in Userinfo.
Well, I'm simply going to copy that over
to BadgeList,
add it there, save everything,
and it's back.
So that's scoped styling,
a super useful feature to make sure that your styles,
really only affects the component
in which you're defining it.
Now in case you're wondering
how vue actually implements this.
If you inspect this with your developer tools
in the browser.
You will notice that vue achieves this
by giving your elements special attributes,
like this data-, V- something attribute.
Now this is added by vue,
and you've seen the styling
actually vue changes your selector behind the scenes
like this header selector here,
to actually now be header plus
this generated attribute.
And since every component's template
will receive its own attribute.
This ensures that styling is scoped
to that component's template markup.
That's how vue implements this behind the scenes
with this custom attribute,
and by adjusting your selectors.