There is another cool feature
when it comes to Vue Components
which once you know it,
will give you way more options
of structuring your code
and splitting your code into multiple components
and that would be the feature of slots.
Now what are slots about?
Let me show you an example.
In Userinfo,
we have this section with a header and a paragraph.
In BadgeList we also have a section with some content.
Now the content is different
but there is one important thing
which both components,
BadgeList and UserInfo have in common
and that's the section
but actually not just a section
but the section and the styling that's being applied
to that section.
You might remember in the last lecture,
I copied the styling
to ensure that the section has the same style
in both components.
Now of course,
an alternative would have been
to simply make section a global style
here in App.vue
where the style is not scoped
but another alternative would be
to create a standalone component
which simply contains the section
with the attached styling
and which then is flexible
regarding the content it receives.
That could be something like a BaseCard component.
Now the name is up to you
but I'm naming it like this
because I want to create a certain look
which is sometimes referred to as a Card Look in the web.
Basically this look of having a drop shadow
and rounded corners,
this is often referred to as a Card Look
and I'm going to create a component here
which encapsulates that look
so that we can easily reuse it wherever we want
and for that here in this template,
I will add a section like this,
or maybe also just use a div
to make it a bit more reusable semantically
but that's just a minor thing.
It doesn't really matter here
and then I add my styling
and important,
I'm going to scope this styling
by adding the scoped attribute.
Now I'm going to copy over this section styling here
to my BaseCard
and change it from section to div of course
because I'm now having a div here
and now I want to make sure
that the content in here
can be anything we want.
I basically just want
to use this component as a wrapper
with a certain style attached.
Now how could we receive content
from outside now though?
Well we learned about props,
we can add a script here,
like this
and then simply export our default JavaScript object
and now accept some props here.
But what would be our props?
Would it be content
and we then try to output content like this?
That actually will not work
because if we now wanna use our Card here,
we can't pass in our HTML content
with all those Vue features we're using.
Let me show you what the problem is.
Let's say we register this globally
because we're going to use this Card
in multiple places.
So here in main.js
we're going to register it like this
and then here,
with the app.component,
we have our BaseCard like that
and now in UserInfo
I wanna use it.
So I wanna in the end,
wrap my content here with BaseCard like this,
I'm not replacing the section with it
but I put my BaseCard into it
and then wrapping this content with BaseCard.
This is however not how props work do they?
If I save that,
I now lost all the content
because Vue doesn't know where to render this,
I added it between the text of a custom component
and well, how would you know what to do with that?
Where to output it?
After all our custom component has its own template.
Yes it has a content prop
but well Vue doesn't know what's in there.
Now we could of course
set content here equal to a string
and pass this content here as a string to content
but then this would no longer be able to use Vue features.
So that's all not the solution,
instead it's this slots feature which I mentioned.
Vue has a special syntax for this exact scenario
where you want to use your own component
as a wrapper around dynamic content.
So around different kinds of HTML content
and for that,
you simply go to your component
that should be the wrapper.
You don't use props in there
but instead you use a special element,
the slot element like this
and if you now save that,
you will see this works
and we got the look we want
and if I go to UserInfo,
please keep in mind
that I deleted the section styling here.
So this look is really coming from our Card component
and that's how slots work.
They allow us to receive HTML content
which also may be using Vue features
from outside of the component.
Basically just like props
but where props are meant to be used for data,
which a component needs,
slots are meant to be used for HTML code
for the template code a component needs.
So here we now just provide a shell with some styling.
We could also add some logic
if this component needed to
but we then allow the parent component
to provide the HTML code
that should be inside of that div
and that's the core idea behind slots.