So now that we learned about slots,
we can of course use our base-card slot
also here in the BadgeList.
There, I also got a section
which should have this card look.
So we can remove this section styling here,
not the h2 styling.
I wanna keep that exclusive to this component,
but the section styling
and then use our base-card component here to wrap this,
on all the list in the h2 tag in our case.
So use base-card as a wrapper around this content
and that will now ensure that again it looks like before,
but now we have this re-usable card component
and we can use it wherever we need that look.
But that's not even all, you can use slots for it.
It is nice that we're able to pass dynamic content
between the opening and closing tags of our own component.
But sometimes you also have the scenario
that your custom component should have multiple slots.
And actually, I can show this here
at the example of this BaseCard.
At the moment it has one slot,
but it would not be unrealistic
that it should have two slots,
let's say one slot for the header
and one slot for the main content.
So here in BaseCard, we could add a header component
to ensure that we always have the same structure
for every card, for example
and then here, we also want to add a slot like this.
But of course now we have two slots
and therefore Vue wouldn't really know
where the provided content should go.
So that's why if you use more than one slot,
you can add names to slots
with the name, attribute on the slot element.
And here we could give this a name of header,
but that name is up to you.
It can be anything,
doesn't have to be the wrapping elements' name.
You don't have to name all slots.
If you leave one unnamed slot,
that will be the default slot,
but you must only have one unnamed slot.
And now you can assign the content to the different slots,
for example in UserInfo,
we could now go to our header here
and now here I want to tell Vue that this content,
the h3 tag and the base tag
should go to the header slot
and for that you wrap it with a template tag,
which is a default HTML element
and on that template tag,
which holds the content that should go into your name slot,
you add a special directive, the v-slot directive.
The v-slot directive can be used to let Vue know
where certain content should go to.
Now, you will let Vue know where the content should go to
by adding an argument to this directive,
which you do by adding a colon,
and then the name of your slot.
Now I have a named slot with a name of header here
and therefore we can add header as an argument here.
And this tells Vue that the content inside of the template
will go to this named slot.
Now as a side note,
the template is a default HTML tag,
which doesn't render anything to the screen though,
which is why we use it as a container here.
Now, if you then have content left,
which is not in a template with the slot,
that content will automatically go to the default slot.
So if I save that,
it looks almost like before,
but we can tell that something changed
because now the label, the badge here
is no longer next to the name
and it is no longer next to the name
because we no longer have the header here in UserInfo,
instead, we have the template where we sent this content
into the header of BaseCard.
And since the header's styling,
which was responsible
for placing the badge next to the title
is still in UserInfo and is scoped to this component,
it does not affect the header in BaseCard.
We're going to take care about styling
in the next lecture though.
Before we do that, however,
let me go to BadgeList
and here I want to send this h2 tag into the header.
So again, we need a template,
wrap h2 with it, and then add v-slot:header.
You can also be more explicit about the fact that this here,
the rest will go into the default slot
by adding a template here,
adding a template around that
and then adding v-slot:default.
Default is a reserve name
and like the name implies,
it always targets the default slot.
So I'm going to do this here
and also in the UserInfo component
to be very clear about which content goes where
and to make it obvious that I did not forget
to assign this to any slot,
but that I want this to go to the default slot.
So that's why I add this default slot template
to both UserInfo and BadgeList here.
But with that, that's what we got.
Now let's explore the styling here
and let's see how we can fix this when working with slots.