Slots are a powerful feature,
but now we broke the styling.
We broke the styling of our user info component here
where the batch should be next to the title,
because we previously targeted this header here
to apply our styling.
Now we're sending this content into a header,
but into a header of a different component
of the BaseCard component.
Now you could think that the content that sent
into a header is to find in the component
where this styling is scoped to
and (murmurs) the component it's being sent
to the BaseCard component
should be affected by this styling as well.
But that's not how Vue works.
There is a very simple rule
when working with slots
and when sending content into other components slots,
nothing changes about what
you learned regarding scoped styles,
availability of data and props and so on.
For example, fullName, this prop here,
which we have available and UserInfo,
is also still only available here in UserInfo.
It's not a available in BaseCard,
even though we are sending this markup to BaseCard.
But Vue.js will analyze, compile
and evaluate this template before it sends to content
to the other component so to say.
So therefore, here we have access
to whatever is defined inside of UserInfo,
and to styling defined here
also affects this markup,
but not the markup of any component
we might be sending our content to.
That's how this works.
And that's why this header style here,
does not affect the header in base card.
So if you want to affect this header, of course
what we should do is grab this selector,
remove it in UserInfo and therefore,
since we have no styles left,
removed the entire style tag
and go to BaseCard instead,
and then in the scoped styling there,
we can add the header styling.
And with that, we got the look from before,
because now we moved the styling
to the appropriate place.