So, slots clearly are an important feature.
They give us way more flexibility
and allow us to do things,
which we can't really do
or which we can't really built without slots.
Now, I'm not done with slots still,
there's more we can cover about them.
For example, you can't provide default slot content.
So, with that I don't mean
that you have a default and unnamed slot
where content will go
that doesn't target a different name,
but I mean that if you have a slot,
which receives no content,
that this slot can then render some default content,
for example, here in the header,
we can add default content
by adding content
between our slots tags here.
Let's say h2 tag here
where I say The Default,
just to show how this works.
It does make a lot of sense
for this specific component,
but you definitely can have components
where some default content might make sense.
Now, if you add such an element,
if you add content
between your slots tags,
by default this will not be visible right now
because all the places
where I use the base card
do provide content for the header slot.
Both the badge list,
as well as the user info component,
both provide content for the header.
But let's say the badge list
wouldn't have it's v-slot header template here.
So, it doesn't provide any content
for the header slot.
If you remove that,
you see now The Default in that component,
because now the slot fallback content,
the default content of that slot is being shown.
And that of course can be useful for certain components.
Now we can argue
if it's useful for this specific component though.
Why should a card
which should just act as a wrapper
that gives us some visual styling,
why should that have a default title?
After all, you don't know what the content
that will be passed into the card will be about.
So, rendering some default title
probably does make a lot of sense.
I'll still leave it here for reference,
but of course it is just an example.
But you can in such cases
where you don't know if you really need
that slot element here,
you can also use another nice feature.
If we wouldn't render this default fallback content,
our badge list card doesn't have any title.
But if we inspect the HTML markup,
we of course see it has an empty header element.
And whilst we don't see it on the screen,
this is not ideal semantically
having an empty HTML element
lying around in the Dom.
I don't know, I don't want to have that.
You can utilize another cool feature here.
In the component where you define slots,
you get a special property provided by vue.
We can see it if I add the mounted lifecycle here.
Let's then console log,
this dollar sign slots.
Dollar sign slots
is a number built in property provided by vue.
And it holds information
about the slot data
this component receives for its different slots.
So, if I save that,
open the developer tool
and DARE to JavaScript console and reload,
we see queue console logs here.
Why do we see two?
Because we're using our component that has slots twice.
We're using it in user info
and we're using it in badge list.
So, every time this component
is getting used
mounted is getting called
because this base card component
gets created and mounted twice.
Obviously, since we use it twice
and therefore we get this console log twice.
Now, the interesting thing is,
in those objects,
we have access to the different slots we're providing.
So, we can actually access dot header here
because we have a slot named header here.
We could also access dot default
because we have a default slot.
Now, if I access dot header
we'll see something interesting.
If I reload again,
we also see two outputs in the end,
this one and this one
and we see two outputs
for the same reason as explained before.
But the interesting thing is that,
we see this strange output here once,
but that we see undefined the other time.
Now, undefined here
is coming from the usage
of the base card component
in the badge list component.
There we're not providing content
for the header slot.
And therefore in base card component
when I try to access this provided content, so to say,
I get undefined when this base card component
gets created for the badge list.
And now that's something we can utilize here.
On this header element,
we could add v-if
and check if slots header is truthy.
So, if it's undefined,
it will be falsy
and therefore this header element
will not be rendered.
So if I now save that and reload,
we get the same log.
But if I inspect this badge list component,
you now see the header is gone
and that's just of course, a minor improvement.
It's also definitely a bit more advanced,
but I hope you understand
what we're doing here.
With dollar signs slots,
we can check whether we do receive data
for a specific slot.
And if we don't,
we could use that information
to not render a certain element.
The headers still works fine
into the user info component.
DARE base card outputs to header
because DARE for the usage of base card and user info,
we do provide content for the header.
It's just the usage and badge list
where we also use base card,
where we don't provide header content
where therefore we remove the header.
That's how we could use
this dollar sign slots information.
And now there's one additional thing about slots,
which I also wanna mention.
In the places where you use the component
that offers slots.
So, in our case,
in badge list and user info,
we do provide slot content
with this template
and the v-slots directive,
just as for v-bind and v-on,
there's a shorthand for v-slot.
You can absolutely write it like this,
but you can also replace it with a hash symbol.
So, hash header also means the same
as v-slot colon header.
And that's simply a bit shorter.
We can do the same here
for the default slot.
And of course, we can also do the same
in the badge list
and target the default like that.
So, we can write this
in a bit of a shorter way.
And with that we get the same output as before
we got no error, everything works,
but now we're using this shorthand here.