Now slots are an important feature
and as you can tell by now,
all are quite powerful feature
and you can do a lot of things with them,
in Vue as you can tell.
Now there's one last thing about slots
which I also want to mention here.
It's definitely advanced
but it is worth knowing about it.
For that I'm going to create a new component
CourseGoals.vue and I'm going to add a template here
and in that template I wanna output a list.
And for the moment
I'll not care too much about the styling and so on.
I just wanna focus on this slots feature
which I wanna show to you.
So I have unordered list
and I have a script here
defining my config object for this component,
and in there let's say we have some data
and we have some goals in here
which of course could be dynamic,
but for the moment
I'll justify them like this,
Simple strings like finish the course and learn Vue.
So definitely nothing too fancy here.
Now of course,
we can render list items here with v-for
by looping through our goals as you learned it.
We can also add that key
and set that to our goal for example.
So to that string,
assuming that every string is unique in this array.
And then of course we can output our goal here
and now we could go to App.vue for example
there, import this newly created component.
So import CourseGoals from './components/CourseGoals.vue'
and there after, register it as a local component,
so that we can then use it in the template here.
So let's do that.
And that will simply add it here course-goals, like this.
So now I added my component here
and hence we see the goals here.
And as I mentioned, the styling is off
but that's not the focus here.
Now, what that does this have to do with slots?
Sometimes if you're building a component
which you might wanna share with our people
with our colleagues
or which gets used in different ways
in a bigger project,
you want to make
certain aspects of that component customizable.
For example here we could have this component
which has the CourseGoals data
which maybe also has more logic related to that
and which then takes care about
rendering those Course Goals to the screen.
But there's one thing which you might wanna make
customizable.
And that is the content of every list item.
With that I mean,
if you just have the text in the list item,
if you maybe have an h2 tag in there,
maybe multiple elements.
So maybe you want to make that customizable.
So that this core skills component
could be used in different parts of the app,
but the content of the list item
could be different every time it is getting used.
Now for that we could of course
think about using a slot here.
We could enter a slot here
and if we have a slot here,
the content the HTML markup
which is passed to a list item
can be defined from inside the place
where Course Goals gets used.
And that sounds exactly like what I'm trying to do here.
So in App.vue where I'm using Course Goal,
I could now pass in my content for a Course Goals.
And I could say that I want to have my goal text
instead of a h2 tech here.
But that's now where the problem start.
Yes I can pass in my markup,
but I have a big problem.
I don't have access to the individual goal
for which this list item is getting rendered.
This goal variable is only available here
inside of Course Goals,
but the markup which should be output in here
is getting passed in from App.vue here.
And here I don't have access to these goals
or goal variables, which I'm using in Course Goals.
And for this specific scenario
where you wanna to build something like that,
Vue has another feature.
It has scoped slots.
Now what are scoped slots about?
The concept of scoped slots is about
letting you pass data
from inside the component where you defined a slot
to the component
where you pass the markup for the slot.
And you do that by going to the component
where you have the data
and where you define the slot,
and then on the slot
you can add a prop. For example, goal.
This name is up to you.
And you can also bind it with v-bind
or with the shortened to a dynamic value,
In my case here, to goal.
And to avoid naming confusion here,
I'll name this item
though you could absolutely also use goal.
That would be okay
but to make it clearer,
I'll name my prop item here
and past this goal
which is created for every iteration, queue item.
Now these names are up to you,
but whatever you set as props on slot,
so on this slot element
will now be accessible in the place
where you pass data for that slot.
In this case here in App.vue,
where I'm passing this markup for my slot.
And here we can now get access to the data
by adding a template
around our slot markup.
So around the markup which we wanna to pass into that slot
and on that template, we use v-slot
or the shortened
for the default slot in this case,
but the same concept would apply to named slots of course.
And now here,
we can define any name of our choice like slotProps
but this name is also up to you.
This simply is the name of a variable,
which you can define which Vue will give you
and this variable
the value you get for this variable.
So the value you get for slotProps in this case
will always be an object
where all the props you define here on slot
are merged in.
So if you had another prop here with some data,
that would also be part of slot props
of this object
accessible under the another prop key.
And I'll actually leave that here
for demo purposes.
Here It's not bound, it's just set to a string.
So now here, we got this slotProps thing
and what can we do with it?
Well, you can now use that
inside of this template for example here,
to interpolate between the h2 tags
and now access slotProps.item.
.item, because I added a item prop here on my slot.
If you chose a different name here,
instead of item, it's a different name here as well.
And below that I'll also add a paragraph
where I output slotProps,
and now here using this square bracket notation
so that can access a property with a dash inside of it,
and then referring to another prop,
which I defined here.
Important here, Vue will not convert
this automatically to a CamelCase notation.
So if you have another prop with a dash here in CourseGoals,
you need to access it with exactly the same name here
in the place where you define the markup,
and that's why I need that square bracket notation here,
because with the dot notation
this would be invalid JavaScript code
with a square bracket notation this works.
So now with that if we saved that
we see our output here,
including the dots from the another prop
which I defined for demo purposes.
And this hopefully makes it clear
how scoped slots work.
It's definitely a niche and advanced feature
you will not need it all the time,
but there are specific scenarios
where it is impossible to build what you wanna build,
if this feature wouldn't exist.
And that's of course why I'm covering it here as well,
but be aware that it's definitely a niche feature.
Now there's one simplification, which we can make here
by the way, if you're only targeting one slot,
only the default slot here,
you can remove that template here
and let me first of all cut this,
remove this unnecessary template wrapper,
and instead add this hash default slotProps thing
directly on your component tag.
This is only allowed
if the markup between your opening and closing tags here
should entirely go into just one slot,
into the default slot here.
Then you can use this simplified code here,
as you can see it works.
And then this is the shortest way
of writing this in the end.
And that's now really it for
slots and all the first scoped slots.
I know it's a lot,
we'll see it in action
throughout this course in various projects,
and to scope slots feature
as mentioned is also a very advanced
and niche feature.