Time to finally leave slots.
In App.vue, I'm going to remove,
all those components I've been using this far,
except for TheHeader,
because I now wanna clean up the UI.
I will leave the files here though for reference.
But now let me quickly create two brand new components here,
which have nothing to do with
this dummy code we used before.
Let's say we have a ManageGoals.vue file
and ActiveGoals.vue file.
ManageGoals could be a component where
the user is able to add new course goals,
and ActiveGoals is a component
where all added and active goals are displayed.
We're not going to add all the logic for that though,
because I wanna show you something else.
Therefore, I'll keep it simple
and just say Active Goals here
in the template of the ActiveGoal component
so that we can recognize this component.
And in ManageGoals,
I'm going to add a template where I say Manage Goals.
I'll not even add script tags here.
I'll not export a default config object,
because if it is empty, you don't even need to export it.
It will so to say,
be exported and created for you automatically
behind the scenes.
You then don't need to define it
if it is empty anyways.
So you can have components with just templates like here
and now we can add them as local components in App.vue.
I'll import ActiveGoals from components
ActiveGoals.vue of course,
and import ManageGoals from
./components/ManageGoals.vue like this.
And then register both as
local components here in this case,
ActiveGoals and ManageGoals.
And now of course that shouldn't be a surprise.
We can use them here
active-goals can be used like this
and manage-goals can also be used like this.
And then now my build process here
is complaining about the fact
that I have components registered,
which I'm not using so let me actually remove
BadgeList, UserInfo, and CourseGoals from here,
and also comment out those imports then here.
So now it is rebuilds.
And now we can see Active Goals
and Manage Goals on the screen.
Now that's certainly not too exciting,
but here's the cool feature I wanna show you.
Vue has this concept of dynamic components
and here's where this could be handy.
Let's say we're building a component that has various tabs,
so various buttons in the end,
which we can press to show a different component
so that we either see Active Goals or Manage Goals,
but not both at the same time.
For that we could've our tab buttons here,
Active Goals, and then another button where I say
Manage Goals so I have these two buttons
like tabs here.
And when I press a button,
the respective components should be shown
and the other components shouldn't.
Now here's how we could implement this.
We can manage some extra data here,
selectedComponent, for example.
And initially let's say that is active-goals.
So the HTML tag name,
which we are also using here in the Dum.
active-goals.
And then we add a method here.
So we add the methods key
and in there add a method,
setSelectedComponent
where I get the component as an argument,
and then set this.selectedcomponent equal to the value
I'm getting here as an argument.
And now we can bind this method here to the buttons.
So here upon a click I wanna call
setSelectedComponent and pass in active-goals.
And on the Manage Goals button upon a click,
I will call setSelectedComponent and pass in manage-goals
as a value for the parameter.
So these are now the buttons,
and now that we can change to selected the component,
we can add v-if here on, these two components text
and check if selectedComponent is equal
to active-goals here or here on the second component,
if selectedComponent is equal to manage-goals.
And if I now save that
we can use this like tabs and we can switch
between these components.
but that's nothing new.
Here we're only using features
you already learned about.
Now, whilst you can build it like this,
if you have more and more components
between which you wanna circle
using v-if all the time
and repeating that v-if code all the time,
is pretty annoying.
That's why Vue has an alternative way of doing that.
So let's comment out this here
and let me introduce dynamic components to you.
Vue offers you a special HTML element which you can use.
The component element.
This is an element, a component provided by Vue.
And the interesting thing is that
this component won't work like this stand alone.
It doesn't show anything on the screen.
Instead, it needs one key property.
And that's the is property.
The is property tells component,
which component of all the components you defined
should be shown in place of this component.
So for example we could set this to active-goals,
but of course we don't wanna hard-code this
because if we did,
we could just use active-goals like that.
If we would always show just that component.
Instead, what we wanna do here
is we wanna bind is dynamically with v-bind
or with the shorthand.
And then in this case point at selectedComponent,
which holds our component HTML tags as values.
It's active-goals initially,
and in our method here,
in the end we switch between active-goals and manage-goals.
Which are our component tags.
And with that we're telling Vue,
that component should basically swap itself
for v-if active-goals or manage-goals.
Whatever is currently stored in selectedComponent.
So with that if I reload,
I got the same behavior as before,
but now with less code
without multiple v-if statements,
which of course makes our life as a developer easier.
And it means that we have less code to write.