Dynamic components are definitely an interesting feature
which can help you add certain features to your apps
in an easier way.
But here is an additional thing you should know
about dynamic components.
Let's say in Manage Goals, we had an input field.
Let's actually say we have a rapping div here, like this.
And then in here, we also have a input field
where the user is able to enter some goal name.
Now, this is just a dummy input field,
we're not doing anything with its value here.
But it would be realistic that we have one component
or multiple components
where the user is able to enter something
and that we then load this component dynamically
with component.
Now here's the problem we'll face with that.
In Manage Goals we have the input field,
but if I enter a goal here and then before I save it,
I decide to go back to Active Goals
and then I come back to Manage Goals.
You see what I entered is lost.
And the reason for that is
that when we switch our components,
the old component is really destroyed
and removed from the DOM.
And that of course means
that anything we entered here into this input field
is lost if we switch away
because the input field is removed from the DOM.
And when we go back to Manage Goals,
a brand new input field is added again.
Now this is maybe not what you want
and Vue has a solution for that as well.
It has another built in component, the keep-alive component.
And you can wrap that around your dynamic component.
So keep-alive works together with this component component,
with this dynamic component concept.
And it does what the name implies.
Keep-alive allows you to tell Vue
that components should not be removed and deleted entirely
but that instead their state should be saved.
That they should be cached behind the scenes.
So with keep-alive added here, if we go back and reload,
if I enter some goal here and I go back to Active Goals
and then back to Manage Goals, this text is still here
because behind the scenes, it was not entirely deleted
but Vue kept all the information around
ensuring that we're not losing this content here.
And it depends on what you're building,
whether you want keep-alive or not.
But it's good to know that it exists.