Are you ready
for more Vue component features?
We're slowly getting to an end
of this module though promised,
and you already know a lot of the core features
you got to know.
But here's another nice feature
which sometimes can be very nice to have.
Let me stick to this manage goals component,
even though it's not super beautiful.
And let's say here, we have a button.
Where I have a text of set goal,
and when this button is clicked, I wanna save my goal.
So for that I'm going to add a script here in managed goals
and add a method and I'll keep it very simple here,
I'll named as goal at this method setGoal.
And in here, I then want to check
what's inside of the input, and if it's empty,
I wanna show an error message to the user.
If it's a valid goal, will not do anything here
because I want to focus on that error part
and on the error message.
So here we point at setGoal, and instead of setGoal,
we can get our entered value with help of refs, for example,
or with V-model and two-way binding.
But here, I'll bring back that ref concept,
add my ref key to the input element
and give it an identifier of my choice, in this case goal.
And then here with dollar sign refs.goal,
we can get access to this input element
and therefore, with dot value,
we can get the value the user entered.
And now if entered value is an empty string, let's say,
then I want to show an error.
Now here in the browser,
we can use the alert function for that.
Input must not be empty.
That's a message we could output here,
and the alert function is availiable
in the browser like that.
So if we now save that, and go back here and manage goals,
we now have a button,
and if I enter nothing here and I press Set Goal,
I get my alert here.
This works, but in most applications,
you probably don't wanna show an alert like this.
This built in alert is not really nice to look at,
it probably doesn't fit the styling
of the rest of your application,
and therefore, this is maybe not what you wanna do.
Instead, maybe you want to build your own alert,
your own model.
So your own overlay dialogue, which you wanna show.
And that's exactly what I'll do here.
I'll build my ErrorAlert.vue component here.
And that will be a very simple component,
which uses to build in dialogue element,
which has a default HTML element, to output some content.
And actually here,
we could use some slot content to be flexible
regarding what's shown in that dialogue.
Now I will add some scoped styling here real quick,
targeting this dialogue,
giving it a position of fixed top 20vh
to move it 20% down from the top of your window,
left 30% here, whoops, like this,
and give it a width of, let's say 40%,
so that we have a centered dialogue here in the end,
and give it a background color of white and a box shadow
to have a light drop shadow here in the end.
But that's just some basic styling,
I'll always add a padding of one REM and that's it for now.
You can definitely style this in a more beautiful way,
but that should do the trick for now.
So now we have this dialog where the exact content
inside of it is flexible, thanks to our slot here.
So now in managed goals, I wanna show that dialogue,
if the user entered something invalid.
How could we do that?
Well, we could use v-if for that.
We could manage some data here,
in our managed goals component,
and have an InputIsInvalid data property,
which initially is false because initially,
the input is not invalid.
After all the user hasn't entered anything yet.
But we'll set this to true here,
if we see that what the user entered is invalid.
So we can then set this input is invalid to true.
And now we wanna show our error alert here,
if input is invalid is true.
So for that here in this template,
we could simply add error alert, this component,
and in order to use it here,
of course, here we should import ErrorAlert
from ./ErrorAlert.vue, not dot slash components,
but just dot slash error alert of Vue,
because it's in the same folder as managed goals,
which is where I'm adding this input.
And then we can register this as a local component here.
It's the first time we're registering a local component
outside of app.Vue, but as I mentioned earlier,
this is absolutely possible.
So error alert is now a local component,
here in managed goals.
And now I only wanna output error alert if with v-if,
if input is invalid is true.
And then in here we could have a title, for example,
input is invalid and a paragraph
where we provide more information,
please enter at least a few characters, anything like that.
This here is the markup that will be provided
for the slot in error alert.
So with that, we should hopefully show an error alert
if the user enters something invalid.
So if the user enters nothing,
then thanks to this data property and v-if,
we show this error alert.
Let's give it a try.
Let's save that, reload, go to manage goals
and enter nothing, click set goal,
and we see nothing,
that's my bad though the built in dialogue element
needs an open attribute to be displayed.
Therefore we could, of course, also display the visibility
of this dialogue by toggling the open attribute,
but I will always add open and instead just show or hide it
by adding or removing the entire component
to the dom with v-if.
But make sure you have that open attribute on the dialogue,
otherwise it won't work.
And, with that, if I reload and try to submit an empty goal,
and this is our error dialogue.
Now it looks like the styling was messed up a bit,
and we can fix that by adding a marginal zero here.
If we do that, we should have dead centered dialogue.
But it's not so much about the styling anyways,
I mean that can still be improved.
But we see that we can now open our custom overly like this.
And of course we could tweak it in more detail,
but this is already a useful pattern to be aware of.
We can also make it closable now by going to manage goals
where we do pass our markup to this component,
and for example, there we could add a button, okay,
which we can press to handle this error,
and upon a click on this button here,
instead of manage goals, we can trigger another method,
ConfirmError could be the name,
where we simply set input is invalid back to false
to give the user another chance.
So ConfirmError is now triggered
upon a click on this button.
This is also showing you as a side note,
why the concept of slots is so powerful.
We can add the content for a totally different component
in the component where we have all the logic
for showing the error alert component.
So we don't need to pass data around with custom events,
which the error alert emits here.
Instead, we can handle everything here in the component
where the error is generated and yet hand off the styling
and the markup off that dialogue
to a totally different component.
Which is a really nice way of splitting responsibility.
If you wanna look at it like that.
But with that, if I now reload again,
and I confirm an empty goal,
we now also got the button to close this dialog.
And that's very useful.
But this again is nothing new,
it's just a nice pattern to see, which also not bad,
but this is not showing any new feature.
Well, we're going to dive into a new feature next
because our current implementation has a slight problem.