So what's wrong with our current error dialogue here.
Well if I open it,
visually, everything is all right.
But if I inspect this here,
we can see a problem in the HTML mark-up.
Here's our dialogue right?
Its below the button input and h2 tag.
And its below there, because that's where we added it
in the template of Manage Goals.
Now visually as I said everything works but semantically,
and from HTML perspective,
having this,
element the dialogue,
which actually is treated as overlay to the entire page.
Having that nested here,
in our HTML code,
is not ideal.
It works but for accessibility this could be strange.
You could also run into some styling bugs here
and it might simply make more sense
if that dialogue wouldn't be down there.
But instead lets say it would be somewhere here.
It would be inserted at the root of our HTML tree.
And not deeply nested inside of it.
Really just for semantic,
and also partly accessibility reasons.
And this is something which is easy to achieve with view,
and a feature called Teleport.
Teleport, is a built in view component
just like component
and keep alive.
You can wrap your 2B teleported thing
so your 2B rendered somewhere else thing,
in this case the error alert,
with the built-in Teleport element.
Which again is a built-in component view provides to you.
Now how does Teleport work
or what do you with it.
Teleport wants one prop, one attribute.
The two prop.
And here you provide a CSS selector,
selecting an HTML element onto your entire page,
where this content should actually
be added to in the HTML mark-up.
So logically, it still belongs to this component
you can still interact with methods in that component
and so on.
But it will be rendered
somewhere else in the dome's structure.
And here for example
we could select the body element
by just referring to the body tag.
You could also refer to an element by an ID selector
like this.
You just pass in a regular CSS selector here.
And here I'll go for the body tag.
Which means, please render the content of this component
the actual HTML mark-up that should be added to the dome
please render it in the Body element,
directly in the body element
and not deeply nested in this HTML structure
as it was happening before.
So if I save that,
and reload
and generate this dialogue,
it looks like before.
But if we inspect this now, we see this dialogue
is now at the end of the body section.
And its no longer deeply nested in this
div or any other elements.
And semantically this can be better.
Its of course a small optimization
it might not matter to you
and you don't have to use teleport if you don't want to.
But as you can tell it's super easy to use.
And it may help you with
the overall HTML structure
and ensure that
you don't just create an application that looks nice
and works correctly
but it also uses a semantically correct HTML structure
under the wood.
And teleport makes that easy, as you can tell.