There's another feature
or aspect about components you should be aware of.
In some components, like the header here,
we have only one root HTML element,
like the header element here,
and all our elements, in this case,
the only other element, h1, are child elements of that.
In other components, like managed goals on the other hand,
we theoretically have multiple top-level HTML elements,
at least if I remove that div here.
And it is important to know,
to be aware of the fact that this is okay,
and I'm highlighting this because in Vue two,
this was actually not supported.
In Vue.js version two, you were required
to have one root level element per template,
and then, in there, you could have
as many sibling elements as you wanted to.
In Vue free, this changed,
and now, you can have as many
top-level elements as you want.
So if you don't need a wrapping element for semantic
or styling reasons, there is no reason to keep one around.
This is a feature called fragments.
You are allowed to have multiple top-level elements now.