Now let's move away from code for now.
And let's talk about our folder structure
and our file names here.
You probably just followed along and named your files
just like I did.
But the question is, why did I choose the names
I did choose?
And is this the most optimal folder structure?
There is an official Vue Style Guide.
On the Vue website, you can find it under Doc's Style Guide.
And here you will get recommendations on how your code
should look like, how you should name certain things.
There are essential rules which you basically
have to follow.
And then there are various levels of recommendations
like strongly recommended rules you might want to
consider following, and then just generally
recommended ones.
Now you can read through that to get an idea
for how you should name things.
For example, in data you'll learn that
components should be stored in files,
so one component per file.
You'll learn that you have base components, like the card
which you might use in different places,
which you then should name, BaseButton, BaseCard,
and so on, or AppButton AppCard,
whatever you prefer, here.
You will learn about single instance component names
like our header here, which I named TheHeader,
following the style guide here, where it's recommended
that if you have a component, which is only getting used
once in the entire app, the name should be
The, and then something that describes the component.
Now throughout the course, I will follow this style guide
as good as possible.
I will also say though, that from time to time,
I might deviate, to explain something in a better way
or to have an easier time explaining something,
but generally I follow that guide.
And you can go through it as well to get some ideas
on how you want to name your things.
And which kind of code you want to write
when you work with Vue on your own.
Be aware of though, that these are not technical rules,
but really just recommendations.
So if you don't want to follow a certain rule, that is fine.
It's your project, you don't have to adhere to those rules,
especially if you're working on your own.
If you are working in a bigger project with a team,
or if you are planning to share your code
with others though, you should consider following this guide
so that everyone is basically working with the same rules
in mind on the code base.
And that's all I want to say about the style guide
at this point, because this is a course where
I wanna teach you Vue and where I want to focus on Vue,
the framework and the features it offers.
And as I mentioned, I will follow this style guide anyways,
so by just following along with the lectures
and this course, you will automatically get a feeling
for how to name things, how to write code
and how to write good code.