Now the style guide is one thing.
It helps you write good code,
it helps you name your files.
But there's another aspect
that you should keep in mind
if you're working on bigger projects
and that is related to how you organize your files.
(indistinct), we have to source folder,
and in there we have a components folder
with all our review components.
This is a typical structure
and there's nothing wrong with it,
but in bigger projects,
this of course we'll reach certain limits.
If you have a project with hundreds of components,
having them all in one folder,
can be very hard to manage.
You might have a hard time finding the components
you are looking for.
Therefore,
you might want to consider creating sub folders.
For example,
we could create a sub folder named base or UI
for all those base components like the card here.
So I'm moving to BaseCard there.
I'm moving the BaseBadge here.
Of course, when you do that,
you want to make sure that you update
all the imports you're using.
So in main.js,
I'm now importing BaseBadge from components/UI/BaseBadge,
and the same for the BaseCard.
Otherwise Vue will not be able
to find these things
and your project will break.
Now that's the folder
for the general base components.
We could also create a subfolder
inside of the components folder named layout
where replace things like the header or the footer
if you have one.
So therefore of course,
make sure you also updates the import here
in app.vue in our case.
And then you might have various other components,
which you might want to organize by feature.
If you're building an online shop application,
for example,
you could have a subfolder named cart
where you have all the cart related components.
You could have a subfolder named checkout
for the checkout related components,
one named products for the components
that are dealing with outputting products and so on.
Now here I have various demo components
because this here in the end,
isn't a real app which we're building
and therefore I will just leave them here.
But in the next module,
we're going to use everything
we learned about components over the last modules,
and we're going to build a full application
from scratch.
And there you will see a proper folder structure
in place to manage all the components.
Because there will then have a real application
where this makes more sense.
For now, just be aware of the fact
that you might need to restructure
your folders here at some point
to keep your code manageable.