That was another long module
about components.
But we're never done with components.
We now know all the core features you need to know
and in the next module, we are going to practice
all the features we learned in this
and the previous modules by building a complete project.
A complete app.
Now in this module, we had a look at
component registration and styles.
And you learned that components
can be registered globally or locally.
Globally with the app component method,
locally by importing them and adding them
to the components option in the conflict object
of a component or app.
You should prefer local registration for most components.
But if you have components which you are using
in a lot of different places off your app,
then of course global registration makes a lot of sense.
We also had a look at styling
and styling can also be global or scoped.
Global styles affect all HTML elements,
no matter in which component they are.
And scoped styles only affect the HTML elements
in the template off the component where you are using them.
You should prefer scoped styles for most components.
But definitely set up global application wide styles,
like a font family in a unscoped style tag
in your app.Vue file.
We also had a look at slots, another key feature.
Slots can in the end be used as a placeholder
for dynamic HTML code
which can then be inserted from outside into a component.
You can have single slots.
You can have multiple slots
where you then also need names.
Only one slot may stay unnamed.
You can provide default content for slots,
which will be used as a fallback
if no content is provided for that slot from outside.
And we learned about scope slots
for some advanced use cases.
Slots are another key feature
which unlock rapper components like cards or dialogs,
and you will see them in action again in the next module.
We also have dynamic components.
Dynamic components is a feature built in
to view unlocked with the built-in component.
This can be used to dynamically swap it
for different components you defined.
And you can also control the caching of that component
with the built-in keep alive component
as you learned it in this module.
We will also use this feature in the next course module.
So, in the project we're going to build there.
Now last but not least, we have a look at teleport
and the official style guide.
Teleport is another built-in component which can be used to
manipulate the DOM structure and control
where something is added to the real DOM,
whilst keeping your component hierarchy.
So that will not be changed by teleport.
And last but not least,
I introduced you to the official style guide.
And you might want to consider following that
or at least have a look at it
to keep your code clean and understandable.
And that's it for this module.
In the next module we're going to practice
what we learned here and in the previous modules.