So that's it for the module, and this was a huge course section, of course, since we covered all
the important fundamentals, you need to know about the way you learned how interacting with the DOM
works and how View manages templates to allow you to use certain view features which are then reflected
on the actual page.
You learned that view has this core idea of letting you define the goal rather than the individual steps
so that it follows that declarative approach where you define how your page should look like and which
parts on the page might be dynamic and you let them view figure out how to get there.
Now, in order to let view do its job, you need to connect your view app, your view instance, the
actual HTML code with the mound method which you saw.
Then you can use a see us as selector to select a part ofthe page and turn that part into the template
of the View app in which you then can use all these new features, like, for example, the data and
event binding features you learned about.
You learned that data can be output in that template.
So in the controlled HTML code, by using the double curly brace syntax for this interpolation syntax
to just output some text which might change over time in a certain place off the page or with the V
directive to bind HTML attributes to some dynamic value.
You also learn about the is shorthand notation where instead of the bind colon, some attribute, you
just have colon, some attribute to then bind that attribute to a dynamic value.
And we of course cannot just output data.
We can also listen to events with the V on DirecTV or at shorthand notation.
Now these are the powerful core features view is all about.
But in order to make these features really powerful and to make them more useful, we rely on views
built in reactivity system.
That simply means that we will update the real DOM whenever some data which you're outputting with the
BINDE or double curly braces changes and you learned that you can register data which might change in
the data object of your view app, and that you can also work with computed properties and watchers
to calculate results dynamically or to run some code.
Whenever some data changes and view Worchester data for you, it automatically detects changes for you
and it will update the DOM and therefore what the user sees on the page whenever such changes are detected.
Now, that's the important foundation you need when working with view, but it's, of course, not just
about outputting text or data in Web apps.
We also, of course, want to make them look pretty and that involves styling.
And here you also can help us with achieving dynamic styling because we can, of course, also said
Sears's classes or inline styles dynamically with the bind.
And you also learned that view has special syntaxes for classes and inline styles to help you assign
dynamic styles to make that easier for you with that object or Arason text I covered over the last lectures.
Now that's the foundation.
It's of course not all you need to know, but it's the foundation for the rest of the course and you
will see the concepts taught in Discourse section throughout all our course sections.
So make sure you understand this.
Go through the lectures, which might not be clear to you at this point.
And due to challenges and exercises I offer to you in the section so that you really know what these
core concepts are all about.