In this module,
let's dive into another advanced concept,
and that would be mixins
and custom composition functions,
or to be precise, the general topic
and idea of reusing code, both with the options
as well as the composition API,
because the bigger your projects get,
the more components you have in your projects,
the more often you'll face scenarios
where there is some code duplication across components
and you would wish for a solution to reuse code,
to share code across components.
That will be the focus of this module.
To be precise, we'll dive into a general overview
of reusing things in Vue apps
and which different concepts we have when it comes to that.
And we'll then explore two main strategies
for reusing code across components,
and that will be mixins for the options API
and custom functions or custom composition functions
when using the composition API.
So let's dive in and let's explore our options here.