For this, I, again,
prepared a little starting project for you.
It is a simple project,
which you can start as always with NPM install
and NPM run surf.
And when you do so you will see this on the screen.
We've got two dummy components here for adding
and deleting a user, presumably.
And when we click add user, we open a,
an alert, a model with add a user
and the text asking us whether we want to add a user
and we can close this by clicking on the backdrop
or by clicking on the close button.
And when we click on delete user,
we see almost the same dialogue, the same alert,
but with a different content, a different text,
and therefore here in App Vue,
I'm adding add and delete user these two components.
And in these components,
I have my alert component added as a local component,
actually in both components,
we could add it as a global component as well,
but here I went for the same component,
added as a local component into different components.
And besides that add user and delete user are very similar.
They've got pretty much the same logic in them,
but they got a different template, of course,
because that is where these components differ.
And that already brings us to the core topic
of this module, reusing logic and code.
And for that, let's start simple.
What can we reuse in a Vue application
or in any web application, if we think about it?
Well, for one that's of course our HTML structure
and styling, this is something
which we often reuse on our page.
We often have different parts on our page,
which actually use the same HTML structure and styling.
Think about list items where every list item looks the same,
but we also often want to reuse logic and events,
which we might want to handle.
And that's exactly why we have this components concept with
this core concept built into Vue,
we have a powerful way of encapsulating structure,
styling and logic into a component,
and then using that component wherever we needed on
the page, and thanks to props and slots,
we can still customize this component to a certain extent.
And in the end,
that's what I'm doing in this mini app here as well.
The user alerts component is a reusable component,
which defines the structure and styling for a backdrop
and the overlay.
And then I'm using this component in both the delete user,
as well as the add user component.
And these components themselves, of course,
are also encapsulated pieces of HTML code
and logic attached to it.
And that is really the idea of components.
We have HTML structure, styling
and possibly also some logic like here
for emitting this close event in the user alert component,
which is all encapsulated into one reusable building block.
Now that's nothing new though.
We worked with components for hours and hours already at
this point in the course and they offered
that's nothing new,
but it is the core concept when it comes
to re usability in Vue.
But, it doesn't stop there.
That is something we learnt thus far.
Now here's the new part, even with components,
which are great for having an encapsulated template
and logic, customization options with props
and custom events and slots, even with those components.
And even with this powerful concept,
we sometimes are left with some code,
which we would want to reuse,
but which be conscientious as easily.
Because what if we have queue components
that have related or similar logic in them, for example,
the user list component with a search method,
data related to search and a Watcher related to search.
And then we have to same logic in another component
in such cases, creating a new component,
which has this combined logic might not always be possible
and therefore when using the options API,
you have a concept called mixins,
which basically allows you to share data, methods,
computed properties, Watchers, lifecycle hooks,
whichever configuration you might need across components.
So therefore let's explore mixins
and let's see how they can help us here
in this example project.