In this example, project, the logic,
which I would want to reuse can be found in the add and
delete user components.
There I basically have
the same data and methods and actually all
the components option, if you take a closer look.
Now you might be able to reuse these logic by creating some
wrapper component,
but another powerful tool for easily sharing this
configuration across both components are
the already mentioned mixins.
For that I'll create a new folder mixins,
the name is up to you,
but I guess this name makes sense since I'm going
to store one or more mixins in there,
and I will add the alert mixin file,
or just the alert js file.
The name is up to you though, how you wanna name this file.
And in this new js file,
so not a dot vue file,
but in this js file, I want to store my shared config logic.
And in this case here, it's actually an extreme case,
the entire config objects
for both components are exactly equal
they're exactly the same.
So therefore I will actually grab
this entire default export here,
copy it from one of the components and go to
the alert js file and paste it in there.
So now in alert js, I'm exporting this object
as a default object.
Now what's the advantage of this?
Well, now we can use this as a mixin, in those components.
So for example, an add user there, I can now import
the alert mixin this name is up to you
from, going up one level diving into
the mixins folder alert js,
and now we can remove all the code here so that we're left
with the empty config object and add a new option,
which we haven't used before, the mixins option.
And this takes an array where you add all the mixins,
so all the shared code you wanna apply to this component.
And here I add my alert mixin,
and I'm going to copy this now, go to delete user
and add the same code
there replacing the existing config object.
Now with that, there's just one more tweak we gotta do.
I get an error now regarding my user alert.
This import here is not required in delete user
and add user Vue anymore,
but we have to add it
in our mixin because here I'm referencing user alert.
So here I'm going to import user alert from going up one
level, going into components, user alert dot Vue.
With that, I can save this and reload.
And we get a warning failed to resolve component.
This mixin concept here will work,
but actually not for components.
If you've got components
that should be registered in a component,
this components option cannot be shared through a mixin.
So therefore we actually have to remove this and remove the
import we just added
and bring it back into our custom components
into our custom component options here.
So re-add components pointing
at user alert and re-add the import.
Yes, I know we just removed it,
but it is important to understand what you can and what you
cannot share through mixins and component configuration
can actually not be shared.
So let's quickly re-add it to both our add and delete user
components and save everything thereafter.
And with that though, if we reload,
this will just work and it works as before,
but there is one key difference.
Now we got way leaner add and delete user components where
the config objects simply contained the components option
and then the mixins option and all the logic we had in both
components before is now in our mixin,
and with these mixins,
you can share all the component options you typically have
with the exception of components as you saw here,
but you can share data, computed, methods, watchers,
whatever you need there, it can be shared through mixins.
And therefore mixins can be a powerful tool for
making your components leaner and sharing,
reused logic across components.