Mixins can be powerful
when working with the options API,
as you saw in the last lecture,
it's always important though,
to be aware of how mixins are merged
with the options you define in your components,
where you use them. Thus far, I only have one mixin,
in each component and I got no other options
besides the components option in those components.
Now you could add more mixins,
but you could also have more component options.
And let's say I also had a data option here
in the delete user component.
And in there I return a data object with some other data,
maybe with the alert title, let's say.
Delete user. That could be my title.
And now I wanna bind alert title to title prop
on my user alert component.
Of course we can do this with a colon
and then point at alert title,
which now is a data property of this component.
There's just one important question.
Will this work after all the mixin also provides some data?
So which data wins the one of the mixin,
or the one of the lead user. And if one of the two wins,
does that mean that the other functionality breaks?
Well, let's see. If I reload and I click delete user,
the alert opens, and we see that title,
which I just defined as a data property
of the delete user component.
So actually no data option wins
instead vue merges the data.
And that's important.
This is a built in mechanism when you have a mixin,
the options exposed by the mixin are merged
with the options you have in your component.
So for example, here in the alert mixin,
I have this alert is visible data property.
And by default, it's false.
Now this is merged with my component
and the data for,
in the end my component has this property as well
because I'm applying this mixin.
But I could also add the same data property here,
cue the data of delete user, and set it to true,
which is a different value than applied in the mixin.
And if I do that and save it,
we see when I reload my app,
this alert is opened by default.
So this means that my component option,
where I set this to true,
hence making sure that the alert is opened by default,
this component option overrides the option set by the mixin.
And that's indeed how vue merges mixins
with component options.
The component options win if there is a clash.
By default, data is simply combined, but if you have
like, we have it here, for example,
the same data property in your component,
as you have it in a mixin, the component option wins,
not the mixin.
This is how you merge the data
between component and mixin.