Now besides mixins as we added them thus far,
or as we added it thus far,
which has added locally to a component,
you can also define global mixins,
which affect all components and not just the components
where you explicitly add them.
Though to be honest global mixins probably have
a very limited use case.
Now, one use case could be some logging
or analytics functionality,
which you wanna add to every component.
For example, to know when a component was mounted,
anything like that.
For that we could create a logger.js, mixins file
in the Mixins folder,
and in the there, export our mixin object
and in this object now I don't wanna change any data,
but instead I'll add the mount that lifecycle hook.
Which of course can be added to any component
and you can also define it in a mixin.
As a side note,
if this mixins would be merged with a component,
which also has a mounted lifecycle hook,
both lifecycle hooks would execute the one in the component,
and the one in the mixins with the one
from the component being executed last
so that it is able to overwrite any changes made
by to mixin.
But that's just a side note.
Here I'm defining mounted in this mixin
which I wanna use as a global mixin
and for the moment I will just log mounted here.
So as simply some logging for me as a developer,
maybe you wanna store something in some database here,
some analytics data,
things like that could be done in a global mixin.
So here I'm just logging
and now we can register this as a global mixin
by going to our main.js file,
where we also defined global components and so on.
Here we can import the logger mixin
from /mixins/logger.js
and with that import that's simply added
by calling app.mixin and you probably see a pattern.
We had app component for global components,
we have app.mixin for global mixins.
And we simply point at our import here, LoggerMixins.
Now this registers it as a global mixin
and if we now save that,
I get my alerts here, of course still,
but we also now see mounted in the developer tools.
And we see that whenever a component is well mounted
to the screen.
So for example,
whenever we open a dialogue.
And these are global mixins, as I said,
probably a very limited use case
or a limited number of use cases where they can be useful,
but still something to be aware of in case
you have some functionality that should be added
to every component in your application.