Now that were mix ins,
a very useful mechanism for sharing data
and functionality across components,
either across all components with global mix ins
or across a few selected components
by manually adding mix ins to components.
But mix ins have some drawbacks
or at least one possibly bigger drawback.
If you build bigger applications,
far bigger than this demo here,
and you're maybe also working in a team,
mix ins can make it harder
to understand your code,
your component structure,
because it's not always obvious
where some value is coming from.
In our alert mix in, we got these show alert
and hide alert methods.
In our delete user component,
we don't have these methods.
Of course because they are in the mix in.
But we are calling them from inside our template.
Now, the problem with that
is that here in this simple demo for us,
since we're the only developer
who worked on this code,
it's obvious where this is coming from.
But think about bigger projects
where one component maybe is not just using one,
but let's say five or six mix ins.
And you're maybe also working in a team
with many developers working on the code base.
Then it's not always as obvious
where something is coming from.
If show alert is coming from the alert mix in,
or maybe from the error handling mix in,
which you also might have.
And that can be a problem.
With mix ins bigger projects,
bigger code bases can be harder to manage.
In addition, you have to take care
about this merging behavior.
And in case you have a scenario
where the default merging strategies don't fit you,
yes, you can override them,
but that's a lot of extra care
you have to take to ensure
that mix ins work correctly.
And even if they do, you still are left
with the problem of not immediately seeing
where some method or where some data piece
is coming from.
That might not be a problem for you,
especially in smaller projects
or if you're working on your own.
But as I said in bigger projects,
it could be a problem,
and that's why Vue.js has a solution for that,
and why Vue.js actually has
an entire alternative way for you
to write your components.
Instead of setting up data, methods,
computed and watches,
as you learn it throughout the course,
Vue offers an alternative way,
the composition API,
which I already covered
in the previous course module.
And you might remember that in that last module,
I already mentioned one possible downside
you might face in bigger Vue apps
when using the options API,
so the way of building components with data,
methods, computed and watch,
which we used in the majority of this course.
It's a great way, but re-using logic
can be tricky or cumbersome because we use mix ins
for re-using logic when using that options API
and for the reasons I just mentioned
that can be problematic in bigger apps.
And with the composition API,
we have a nicer way of re-using logic
across components.
Because whilst we have mix ins for sharing logic
in the options API,
we have custom composition functions
when working with the composition API.
So let's see how that would work.