So now let's explore reusing things,
reusing logic across components
with the composition API.
And for that you find the same starting project from before,
but now it's using the composition API.
So data and methods was replaced by my setup method
where I then use refs and so on.
Of course make sure you go through
the composition API module first,
before diving into these lectures.
So it's the same project as before
just using the composition API.
And therefore, of course, it also works as before.
And previously we used a mix in to share functionality.
Now, we can use a different approach.
But which approach?
Well in the end all this here
is just code in a setup method.
And if you leave Vue aside for a second,
how do you typically reuse code in Java script?
You might create a function.
A function that maybe receives some arguments
and then maybe returns a value.
That is how you typically outsource
and share functionality in JavaScript.
Well, this is just JavaScript
and the setup method is just one method
with a bunch of different steps.
So if you wanna outsource some of these steps,
we could create a separate function.
And that's just what we're going to do
with the composition API.
This wasn't a great alternative before,
because with the options API,
it was not just one method with a bunch of steps,
but it was an object with different properties.
And therefore the array using a function,
wasn't really an alternative, but here it is.
So I will create a new folder next to components.
And now it's up to you how you wanna call this.
I will name it hooks because sometimes
these composition API functions are called hooks.
And that's why I will follow this naming pattern.
Other names, which you might encounter
for these special functions,
which you use in conjunction with the composition API,
would be composables or custom composition functions.
So hooks, composables, custom composition functions.
That's the same thing.
It's a JavaScript function that very likely
uses some composition, API features
like refs or computed properties and so on,
which then is meant to be called
instead of the setup method.
And as a side note,
we already used such functions,
not built by us,
but by the Vue Router or the Vuex team
to use the route or router object
in the setup method, for example.
You saw that in the main composition API module already.
So in this hooks folder,
I'll add a new file again and alert.js file,
though of course the file name as before is up to you.
And in here I'm going to create a function.
And now here's a special naming,
which I wanna use.
Which you typically use
for these composition API reusable functions.
The function name should start with use
and then something that describes the function.
So here I'll name it useAlert.
Because this function will allow me
to use alert functionality instead of the setup method.
So your custom hooks, which you plan on using here
to share code across setup functions,
should start with use.
It's still a regular function though.
Now what should go into this function?
Well, in the end,
I wanna put all the code, DeleteUser
and AddUser have in common instead of
the set up method into this function.
So we could just grab this entire code
and move it in here.
Now, since I'm using a ref here,
I also have to add that import.
You always have to import the things you're using
in a file into that file.
So here, since I'm using ref in this file,
I also need to import ref in this file here.
It's not enough that we're already importing it
in another file.
This is not how this will work.
And with that, however,
we're creating a ref here,
thanks to the import that ref function.
And we've got all that logic in here
in this alert JS file
in this use alert function.
Now that's good,
but what's the advantage of this?
Well, now we can export this as a default, for example
this use alert function,
just as it is with all that code in it.
And with this return statement.
And we can now go back to AddUser let's say,
and instead of importing ref from view here,
I'll import use alert from going up
one level, hooks, alert JS.
And we can now call, useAlert here.
And what this will do
is it will execute the use alert function,
which has to code for creating a ref
and for creating these two functions that changed the ref.
We also return an object here in useAlert.
And that allows us to use these things
which are created in the function
outside of the function as well.
Because in AddUser, just calling,
this is not enough.
We still need to return an object in this setup method.
This is not replaced by our own function here.
And of course here, therefore,
I still wanna return what we're using
in the template.
So alertIsVisible, hideAlert, and showAlert.
And useAlert gives us all these things.
Inside of useAlert,
we by the way don't have to return an object.
It's our function,
so we can return whatever we want.
We could always return these three things in an array,
if we wanted to.
We could have an array with free elements
where the first element in this case is our data.
And the second and third elements are our functions.
This is up to you.
It's your function.
So to make this clear,
I will actually use an array here.
And now, since useAlert returns this array,
in AddUser,
we can store this alert array, in a constant.
And we know the first element will be,
our data and the other two elements will be the functions.
We can also use array destructuring here,
which is a modern JavaScript feature
to pull these free elements out of the array
and store them in new constants.
So here I will reuse the same names we have here,
though you could use different names
because it's the order that matters here.
But with that, we're saying,
pull out the first element of useAlert
and store it in a new alertIsVisible constant,
which is available in setup.
Pull the second element
and store it in a showAlert constant
and pull the third element
out of the array returned by useAlert
and store it in a hideAlert constant.
So now these free constants here
exist in this setup method
and therefore here.
We can, of course return them.
And the first element, alertIsVisible is our ref here.
This one.
And since it is a ref,
whenever does changes here.
Instead of the useAlert function,
the component where we use, useAlert
will always be notified by this.
Because it is a ref
and we're exposing this ref to the template.
And whenever you do that Vue is aware of it.
And whenever data ref changes,
these changes are reflected in the template.
So it's a different mental model,
but in the end,
it's just a function which we defined on our own,
which we're calling here.
And we can now copy that code
and do the same here in deleteUser.
Replace all of that with the copied code
and get rid of the ref import.
But instead import useAlert
from going up one level,
hooks/alert.js'.
And if you saved this,
this should all work as before.
But now,
with our own custom functioner.
Our own custom hook.