So this is how you can reuse functionality
across components when using the Composition API.
Now, we can do more than what we're doing thus far.
For example, we can of course still also
setup other things in setup.
We're not limited to just using our reuse logic here.
We could again import
ref here, from vue. If we had some other data
that should be changeable, and create our extra ref here,
like the alertTitle, which could be a ref
with a starting value of Delete User?
And here theoretically, I don't need a ref
because I won't add any logic to ever change this.
But I wanna show you that you could,
of course, have extra refs
as well as computed properties and watchers,
and anything else you can use in the setup function,
no matter if you are using a custom hook or not.
But with that I can for example,
also expose my alertTitle,
here, with the return statement to my template
and bind the title here, to alertTitle.
But we can absolutely do this.
And this is kind of a similar thing
to what I did before with the mixins.
There, the mixin was automatically
merged with your other options.
Here, we kind of manually merge it
by simply doing one thing with our custom hook
and doing other things in the rest of our setup function.
Now, our custom hook is also able
to receive arguments by the way,
here I got a custom hook function, which returns something
and your hooks will typically always return something
because you wanna do stuff into hook
which then can still be exposed to your template.
And for that, your hook needs to make these things available
to the setup method where it's getting called,
but your hooks can also take arguments.
For example, let's say for Delete User,
the default starting value
for alertIsVisible should be true.
So that by default, the alert is opened.
This might not make much sense from an app perspective,
but it's a great practice.
With mixins, this was kind of tricky.
With hooks, it's easy. It's your own function.
So of course, useAlert may accept
as many parameters as you need.
For example, startingVisibility.
The name of course is up to you.
You can even assign a default value here,
let's say false, so that you don't have
to pass in a value for this parameter when coding useAlert.
This is a modern JavaScript feature,
default parameter values.
But now we can use this and assign this here
to our ref as a starting value.
And now since we have a default value,
we can still code useAlert as before,
but we can also code it
and pass an extra argument in, for this parameter.
So pass in true as a value
for this parameter instead of Delete User.
And as a result, if I save that,
we start with the model opened
for the Delete User component,
because of that different argument I passed in here.
So your custom hooks are really flexible
you can accept any arguments you might need,
and you can use all the Composition API features in there,
do whatever that hook needs to do,
and then return to the component where you wanna
use the hook, what that hook should expose to the component.