So now that we saw hooks in action,
why could they be better or nicer than mixins?
Well, I see two main advantages.
For one, it's easy to make them configurable.
As you saw in the last lecture,
adding extra parameters is easy
and all of a sudden, your hook is very versatile
and can be used in different components
with different configurations, which is great.
In addition, they fixed one major flaw mixins have.
With mixins, I mentioned that in bigger apps with more
and more mixins, it's hard to see which data property
and which method is added by which mixin.
With custom hooks, that's easy.
I mean, the custom hook returns
the things it wants to expose to a component
and therefore, we have to accept these things
like here, where we get an array
and pull the things we need out of the array
and store them in constants.
It's super easy to see that alertIsVisible, showAlert,
and hideAlert are coming from the useAlert hook.
So even if we would be using 10 or 20 custom hooks,
it would always be easy to immediately see which feature
and which data piece is coming from which hook.
And that can be a major advantage
in bigger apps and bigger components.