Now maybe you remember that originally
I showed a little bit of a bigger project
as an example of why we might want
to consider using the Composition API.
I showed this example at the beginning
of the Composition API module,
and at the end of that module,
we migrated that project from the Options API
to the Composition API.
Now you find that latest snapshot attached to this lecture,
because I wanna pick up on that, I wanna start there
and now talk about reusing functionality
because that's something we haven't done in that project
up to that point.
We stopped when we migrated it to the Composition API,
but now I wanna reuse some functionality.
And there is one main functionality
which I would like to reuse.
In UserList.vue, I got my search functionality,
two pieces of data, a computed property,
and a watcher and this function here.
And we have pretty much the same in ProjectsList
we're dealing with different data there,
here we have a list of projects which we filter,
in UserList we have a list of users, but besides that,
it's the same functionality.
So let's see how we can now use a custom hook
to outsource this into a function
which we can then use in both UserList and ProjectsList.
For this, I'll add a new folder next two components,
and I will again, name it hooks.
And in there I will add a search.js file.
There I'll add a function, useSearch,
following that naming pattern which I recommended,
and I will already export it because I plan on using
and calling useSearch in UserList and ProjectsList.
Now, as I mentioned,
there is a lot of functionality we have in common.
So why don't we just go to UserList
and maybe grab all that code here?
So the two refs, the computed property, availableUsers,
the watcher, and this updateSearch function
and copy it into search.js
into our useSearch function like this.
Now we need to add a import
because I'm using a bunch of features
which are not available in that file yet.
The ref functions, the computed function,
the watch function, yeah, that should be it.
So we should add an import
and import from the view framework,
And there specifically,
I wanna import ref, computed and watch,
since these are the three functions
I'm using in this file now.
With that, that code showed almost work,
not entirely though.
One problem which we will face
is that we depend on props.users filter.
Now in this function, props is not available.
Even if we call it in our setup method later
inside of the scope of dysfunction props doesn't exist.
But of course we can work around that.
We can simply add a parameter and maybe name it items
to have a generic function that works on any kind of items,
no matter if that's people or projects.
That's why I'm just naming it items to make it clear
that this should work on any kind of array.
And then we could use items.filter here
and also replace props.users with items
in the other places here like this.
And I'll rename my user's helper variable here
to filteredItems and use that in all the places
where I used users to make this more generic.
I will also rename the entire computer property
to a availableItems,
because this is now no longer focused on users,
but on any items we wanna search.
Now, we will still have a problem though.
The function which has passed to filter here
has specific logic for filtering
that will only work on our users
because here I'm filtering on a full name.
In ProjectsList, for example, I'm filtering on a title.
Now there are two ways of making this work.
We could accept this filtering function
as a number parameter, a filter function,
which we then, for example, just pass here like this,
that would be one alternative.
Then we have to pass in the function
that should be used here from the place
where we call useSearch.
Or if we know that we will always operate on an item,
but the property which holds the text
we wanna use for filtering
has a different name all the time,
then we could also just accept a second argument,
which stores that specific property name
off the values we're trying to search in a given component.
So then for example here,
we could add a search prop or whatever you want to name it,
parameter, and simply access userSearchProp.
So dynamically access a property based on the value
we get on this parameter.
And maybe rename this from user to item.
So both works, but with that,
we have a more flexible filtering logic here.
Now we also have a watcher here
where we watch the enteredSearchTerm.
And whenever that search term changes,
we trigger this function and set this timer.
Now, here we can leave everything the way it is
because both enteredSearchTerm and activeSearchTerm
are refs defined in this function
and therefore will be available.
And updateSearch should also work.
So with that,
the only thing we gotta do
is we have to return a bunch of things
so that we can use them
in the components set up method,
where we're going to call, useSearch.
And as I mentioned, it's your function.
So it's up to you, how you return these things
if you bundle them together in an array or in an object.
And here I'll go for an object.
Before we saw an array, both is possible.
Here I'll go for an object.
And now let's think about what we wanna expose
to the component that calls useSearch.
For that let's maybe go back to UserList
because that will be a component
which will soon use this custom hook.
And there let's see what we're exposing
to the template here.
We're exposing the enteredSearch
and the updateSearch function.
We also rely on the availableUsers here
in our displayedUsers.
So therefore in our custom hook,
we should absolutely expose the enteredSearchTerm,
the availableItems and the updateSearch function.
So I'll expose the enteredSearchTerm,
That's what I'll return here in my search,
in my useSearch, sorry, in my useSearch function.
And now we can go to UserList.vue
and for the moment comment all of that out
and instead import useSearch from,
going up two levels, hooks/search.js.
I'm not removing this Vue import up here
because I'm still using a ref,
a computed property and no watcher,
but the ref and a computed property down there.
So we have to keep that around,
but we can remove, and we should remove the watch import
because I'm not using watch in this file anymore,
just ref and computed.
Those are still used in my setup method,
even with this code commented out.
But now here we can call useSearch,
so our own function here.
And this function now needs two parameters,
the items and our searchProp.
Now the items that was props.user, if you remember.
That is what we used here before.
So props.user is what I wanna feed into useSearch.
And for the property,
which we wanted to use for filtering on every user,
that was the fullName property,
which we should pass in as a string.
As a string because property names
in JavaScript objects are strings,
so we passed this in as a string.
And then we get back some values here.
In this case,
we get back an object because I returned an object
in my custom useSearch function.
And in there we'll have these three properties.
So we can again use object destructuring here
with this syntax to get the enteredSearchterm,
the availableItems and the updateSearch function.
EnteredSearchTerm will be a ref,
availableItems is a computed property,
and therefore our read only ref
and updateSearch is a function.
Now we can use these things here.
For example, in displayedUsers,
I'm relying on availableUsers.
This is now availableItems,
and of course we could rename this here
in this set up method,
if you wanted to stick to availableUsers,
but I will just go with availableItems.
The rest should be fine.
And then here I returned the enteredSearchTerm
and updateSearch queue the template
so that it's available there.
If we now save this, this reloads, but I see no users.
That is just a typo I have here though.
I should pass in props.users
since users is my prop name here.
So if I use that then I am feeding in users,
and now we see them here.
Now sorting works, and what about searching?
That is looking good as you can tell.
Here, we are able to search and sort
and select users just as we did it before,
but now we're doing this with our own custom hook
that supports us with that.
And we've got this useSearch hook now
and can therefore get rid of all that commented out code.
And now this line here,
or these three lines replace all the code
we had in there before.
And of course we can now use the same in ProjectsList
because that was our main idea.
We wanted to have reusable code.