So here in projects list we can also
comment out all this code here
and also this watcher which is related to searching,
and also remove this function here.
And instead import, use search from hooks, search JS.
And now copying that code which we used in user list.
So where we call use search,
but now I want to parse in a different value.
Here it's not props.users on which we wanna filter,
but instead it's props.user.projects.
So let's parse this in,
and we don't wanna filter on the full name property
on every user project but instead on the title property.
We can see this here in the original code
so we should feed this in.
With that we get the entered search term though
the available items and the update search function.
And we can now use this in the rest of the component.
For example, here we're using available project
that should now be available items.
Here we're using entered search term
and set a new value.
Well, since we're getting the ref here,
that should work.
Assigning a new value here should work.
It's a ref. We can update it from anywhere.
Here however, I now also want to return available items
or still available projects
so that I can keep using that name in the template.
Here for example, but I wanna store available items
in that available projects key.
So I will not use the shorthand here,
but instead store available items
in this available project property in this object
we return to our template.
And I'm with that, yeah I'm still importing
a bunch of things which we're not using anymore.
Let's maybe remove all the comments here
so that this is a bit easier to see and to fix.
Like this.
And we're not using ref anymore.
We got no other refs in here.
We still got another computed property and a watcher.
So we wanna keep those imports.
We also still use two refs,
but we're not using the ref function anymore.
So we can save that and get rid.
And if I now reload, I get an error.
Cannot read property projects off null.
What could be causing this problem?
Well, it's this line here.
I'm parsing in props.user.project to use search.
The problem with that is that
we don't have a user selected initially.
So initially user is null and I try to access projects
on a null value.
What could be workarounds here?
Well, one work around could simply be
to create a new helper, variable or constant.
Projects for example,
where I check if prop.user is a thing.
So if this is truthy and if it is,
I access props.user.projects and store data in projects.
Otherwise I store an empty array in projects.
And then here I just parse in projects,
which now is either an empty array if we have no user
or which is this value.
Now does this looking better.
However, now if I select different users,
we always get no projects found.
So it looks like there's something wrong with our code.
And what could be the problem here now?
Well it's still related to those user projects.
What did I say about props in the composition API module?
I said that the props object is reactive,
but the properties in there,
the values nested in there are not.
Now what I'm doing here is when set up is executed
for the first time, I'm pulling either the project
or this empty array.
And that's it.
Set up is not going to run again.
If we select a user there after,
this code is not going to run again.
So projects will always stay this empty array.
We need to react to user changing
and update projects and an easy way of doing that
would be that we use a computed property here.
Take this code,
and in the function inside of that computed property,
we now returned this code.
By doing that we ensure that computed
and therefore view watches out for props
since it detects props as a dependency
in that of that computed property
and whenever props change,
and therefore the user here changes,
whenever that happens, it will give us new projects.
We can actually shorten this a bit.
I'm already getting my user as a ref from props
with this line down there.
If we kept the line down there and actually move it up here,
we can now just refer to user,
which also ensures that this computed property
is not reevaluated whenever props change,
but only when the user prop changes.
Which is a bit more efficient,
though here it does not matter
because we only have to use our prop.
Though that's also not entirely it,
keep in mind user is a ref now
so we have to check user.value
and here also user.value.
With that however, it looks like it should work,
but we'll introduce a subtle new issue.
Projects now is a ref, right?
Because it's a computed property
and computed properties are read only refs.
So I'm parsing a ref to use search.
In user list we're doing something else.
Here I'm parsing in props.users
and as you know the values inside of properties
off your props object are not refs.
So here props.users, the array I'm passing in,
is not a ref.
In projects list, what I parse in is our ref though.
Now in search JS,
I therefore sometimes get items which are a ref
and sometimes items which are just an array.
Now I absolutely want the ref functionality here
because this computed property here
should be reevaluated when our items change.
But of course, items.filter will not work
if items is a ref.
That should be items.value filter,
and here it should be items.value
But now of course we'll face problems
when items is not a ref like here in user list.
There is a simple solution to this problem, though.
We can simply also use two refs here.
Like this.
And pull out our users from two refs props.
So the same approach I'm using in projects list
so that I can parse in users which now is a ref
to use search.
It's not required here technically but with that
we ensure that use search always receives a ref
as its items and therefore for will always work.
And now, you'll see we can switch
between different users and see their projects.
And searching here also seems to work.
And if I switched to user again,
that also looks good.
Like this.
So now we got this functionality working again.
Now however, with our own use search hook
and therefore with the reusable code.
Yes, there were certain things
we had to watch out for
related to this ref reactivity thing.
But after all, we were able to figure it out.
And now we got flexible reusability,
thanks to this custom hook,
which we're using in two components.