No, there are a couple of notes,
which I still wanna make about our solution here.
For one here enhance projects.
I'm also using props user projects.
Well, since we're already extracting user
into our ref here in this line.
We can, of course also utilize this here.
User dot value projects and access stat.
One other thing I wanna highlight is this watcher .
here, I'm changing the value of the entered search term.
Now keep in mind,
entered search term is exposed by our use search hook.
It's one of the values I'm extracting here.
It's originally defined inside of that hook.
Now changing things, changing a ref.
That's defined in that hook from inside,
the component where you use the hook,
is something you can do.
It will work as you can tell,
but maybe it's also something you wanna highlight.
for one simple reason,
to keep your code understandable and maintainable.
If I see this code.
I might think that entered search term,
should be a ref of this component,
and I'll not find it there.
Until eventually I see it's coming from this hook here.
In addition, changing it here.
outside of the hook
could interfere with our logic you have inside of the hook.
It doesn't here,
but it could in other apps and other scenarios.
So therefore a more elegant way of changing a value
that's defined and used inside of a hook,
could be to define a separate function
that is meant to be used,
If you wanna change a value.
And we get such a functional ready update search,
it takes a value.
And assigns this value'
as a new value to the entered search term.
And in the end, that's just what I'm doing here, right?
So therefore I can just call, update.
search and pass an empty string as a new value here,
because that's what I wanna do.
I want to set entered search term to an empty string.
There was this, I ensured.
That if I select a user and I'm filtering,
I still reset this when I select a different user.
So this watcher now still works.
and still resets my entered search ref.
But now it does this in a better way.
I would say.
Now with that,
I'm done with the search functionality though,
as a final practice task for you.
I want you
to now think about a way
of outsourcing this sorting functionality.
We're only using it in one component.
but theoretically, that could,
of course also be used in multiple components.
So try creating a custom hook for this.
We'll do it together in the next lecture.