We're you successful?
Let's try this together.
I'll add a new hook for this.
A new file.
sort dot js
And I'll export a function,
useSort.
Sounds like a fitting name.
Which in the end,
should later replace,
this sorting functionality.
So this sorting ref,
this computed property,
and this function.
Therefore, we can grab all of that,
cut it here, in userList,
and actually move it over
into this newly created useSort function.
Now, here I'm using a computed property and ref.
So, we should import ref and computed from vue.
So that these features are available.
I'm also relying on availableItems dot value,
and therefore, this should be an input,
a parameter in this function.
So, I will accept availableItems here,
as a parameter.
I'm also relying on fullName for the comparison,
which item should come first.
And that's, of course, very specific to users.
Now here, we're only using the sort functionality,
for the users.
So we could leave it like this.
But if you wanted a more generic sorting functionality,
a more generic useSort hook,
we might want to accept a dynamic value here.
So that the sortProperty,
is another parameter we get.
And here, we then access this dynamic value.
So that any property name,
can be passed in from outside.
Like this.
With that, however, we should be fine.
And now, we can again return,
our data and functions,
and so on,
from inside the useSort function,
to the places where we're going to call it.
So here, I want to return displayedUsers,
and sort,
displayedUsers and sort,
so that they can go back to UserList,
and use that data there.
I see in UserList,
I'm also exposing sorting to my template.
So therefore, in useSort,
we should also return this sorting ref.
So, that we have it available in the setup method,
of the UserList component.
And then here in the UserList component,
we can import,
useSort from
hooks,
sort.js.
And now,
call useSort here.
And to
useSort,
I want to forward my available items.
So the availableItems I'm getting here,
from useSearch.
This is a ref, a read only ref,
if you remember.
So I'm forwarding this
to useSort now.
And, I also pass in this property,
on which you want to sort.
Which here, is the fullName.
And we get back an object,
which we can destructure.
Where we will receive these three properties.
So, I'm copying them here,
putting them in here, reformatting this.
And now we have a sorting const,
a displayedUsers const,
and a sort const available here.
Sort will be this sort function.
It will point at this sort function,
which we defined here in useSort
and return in here.
And displayedUsers,
will be the displayedUsers computed property.
And therefore, a read only ref.
And sorting is our regular ref,
which we defined up here,
in useSort.
So now, we're forwarding sorting and sort,
to the template and displayedUsers as well.
If we now save this,
I'm getting an error,
that I'm still importing some things,
which I'm not needing anymore,
in the UserList dot vue file.
Because we're not defining any refs,
or computed properties anymore.
So, we can remove these two imports
and just continue importing toRefs,
because I'm still using that.
With that it,
compiled still,
and I can see the app here.
And sorting seems to work,
just as before.
So, if I give this a try,
yeah,
that seems to work.
And with that,
we now also would have,
our reusable useSort hook.
Now, the goal with decomposition API,
is not that you always,
need to outsource all your setup logic,
into separate hooks.
Here, we're just doing
this for practice purposes.
It would be absolutely fine,
if you have some refs,
and computed properties and so on,
left in this setup method.
Here, it just turns out,
that we just have these two main functionalities,
which are now outsourced,
and which should now be usable
in any component here,
which needs searching or sorting functionality.
And that's the great advantage
of decomposition API.
Especially, once you know about custom hooks.
Because now we have a lean component here.
We got reusable functionality.
And that really allows us,
to build super huge components,
which are still maintainable.