Up to this point in the course,
we always worked locally.
Our applications always ran in the browser
of the user using them,
so in this case, us, since we're the only one
who tested them thus far,
but in reality, of course,
you often need to persist some data on a backend,
on a service side, because at the moment,
we also already saw that we have the problem
that if the page is reloaded,
all the data that was generated by our Vue app is lost.
We are going to have a closer look at that in this module
because this module is about connecting our Vue app
to a backend.
It's about sending HTTP requests with Vue.
For that I'll first of all clarify
what exactly a backend is and why we need it.
I will, of course, also show you
how you can set up a dummy backend.
And then we're going to dive into how to send HTTP requests
from inside our Vue app to that backend,
with that let's dive right in.