Attached you find another starting
application downloaded, extracted.
Run, npm install followed by npm run serve
and this brings up another Vue app
which I prepared for you.
It's a basic view app.
This one, where you can
fill out this basic survey,
provide your opinion on this learning experience
and then your data will be saved
and output down there.
This application
uses features we already learned about.
We have
two main components in the App.vue file.
The survey component and the component
which outputs the submitted results in the end.
I'm managing my list of
submitted survey results here in App.vue.
Here I got a method for adding a new result
and the learning survey itself does component
holds this form with an input element,
which is bound with the model
and with a bunch of radio buttons
which are also bound with v-model.
And then this form is managed
just as you learned it in the forms module.
Got a submit method.
I'm validating the input,
showing an error message
here.
If one or more of the input fields are invalid,
a custom event is emitted,
the survey submit event
which holds the entered user name and rating
and that survey submit event
is then caught in
App.vue.
Here on the learning survey component
and that then triggers the store survey method
where this survey data is enriched with an Id
and then stored in (mumbles).
And then we have the user experience's component.
That's this component here,
which simply outputs all
submitted survey results with v-for.
I got another component in here,
the survey result component,
which is just responsible for outputting
the individual list items.
Got some conditional styles in there,
some conditional CSS classes.
And overall, this is nothing too fancy.
Now of course,
this application has one problem.
If I submit a bunch of data here,
we see all that data here,
but whenever we reload the page,
all the data is lost.
And this is not a bug,
this is, well, the only way it can behave
because thus far,
we always stored all the data just in Vue
and therefore just in the computer memory,
that is what happened here.
So all the data we create
with all those components
is just stored locally
in memory and therefore lost
whenever this website is reloaded
therefore the Vue app is dumped
and a new instance of the Vue app starts up
and therefore all the data attached
to the previously running Vue app is lost.
This is just how browsers work.
There's nothing you can do about that.
But of course, in reality,
you are often building applications
where data should be saved
and where it may be
should not just be saved locally
on the computer of your user
for example, in a file or anything like that
but instead where it should be stored
on a server, which you, as the developer own.
Think of Amazon.com.
All the products which are listed there,
they are of course,
stored on Amazon's servers
and shown to the users that visit Amazon.
So it is quite common that you
need a server that holds data
and then the Vue applications running
on the computers of your users,
running in the browsers of your users.
Those Vue applications should connect
to your servers and fetch data from there
or send data to them.
So here this survey application, for example,
should probably not just
output survey results down there,
but instead the data should also be submitted
to your server where it's saved.
In a reality, this year might even
be two separate Vue applications
where the survey form
is the application you show to your users
and this dashboard here
where you see the submitted surveys.
That might be a Vue application only you can visit.
But here it's merged into one so
that we can see both in action.
Nonetheless, we typically want a server
to which we can send our data.
And that's exactly what a back end is.
It's the other end.
It's the part that does not run
in the browser of your users
like your Vue app does
but instead it's about code running on a server,
you as a developer own.
It's about a database you
as a developer might own.
And that database would also be
on that server which you own.
So it's detached from the Vue app.
Nonetheless, we want to communicate,
and that's what this module is about.