So, obviously, we need a back end.
Now creating a back end,
that is something you could take an entire course on
because for writing server side code,
for writing code that runs on a server
and for connecting a database to that code.
There are dedicated programming languages
like Node.js or PHP.
And you can for example,
take my Node.js course if you want to learn all about that.
This course focuses on view
and therefore I want to keep that focus
so we're not going to write our own server side code here.
Instead we're going to use Firebase
which is a service that gives us a back end
where we don't have to write any code
to get started with storing data.
I will emphasize though that this is not
just a database which we're using.
It's a complete back end service.
It is like if you had your own server
with your own logic on it.
Just in this case, already pre-written
and pre-configured for you.
The good thing about Firebase, which is a service
offered by Google, is that you can get started
for free with it.
You can start for free and what we're going to do here
is possible for free.
And that's why I'm using this service.
All you need for this service is a Google account.
So make sure you create one
and then log in here into that console,
into the Firebase console.
Once you are logged in and in this Firebase console,
you can add a new project
and give it any name of your choice.
I'll name it vue-http-demo
but this name is up to you.
Click continue.
You can disable this,
you don't need that here, the analytics.
And then create this project.
Now Firebase is a service that has way more to offer
than what we are going to use.
Nonetheless it has all we need here to have a dummy back end
and that's why we're going to be using it.
We're also going to use this Firebase service
in a way that is typical for communicating with a back end.
So that what you learn here will also apply
to any other back end you might be using.
That's another reason why I chose Firebase.
So now, we're in the Firebase console
and here we want to go to database
because we are going to use the database part
of the Firebase service.
It's just one of the offerings they have
but here we need a database.
And we are not going to use the Cloud Firestore here
but instead this real time database.
It's bit easier to use and it has
a nice rest API which is a specific
interface we can use for sending our http request to it.
It's very easy to use and therefore a great choice here.
So let's create such a real time database
and make sure you start in test mode.
Click enable,
and here we go.
Now, you should see something like this on the screen
and for the moment that is all we need.
Now let's leave it at that
and let's go back to our view app.
And here, we are now going to see
how we can send http requests to this Firebase back end
and how we're not going to do it.