So with Firebase set up,
how do we communicate with it or with any backend
from inside our Vue App?
We actually, accidentally,
already saw a way of sending HTTP requests earlier.
In our form, the learning survey component here in the form,
there we have a submit button.
And I mentioned earlier in the course
that we wanna prevent the browser default
when that form is being submitted
because if we don't do this, a HTTP request would be sent.
If I remove the prevent modifier here, temporarily,
reload and click Submit, watch this reload icon here.
You see it briefly turned into a cross.
Every time I click this,
what happens is that the browser uses its default behavior
which is, to send a HTTP request.
The problem just is,
it's not sending that request to our backend,
to our Firebase servers,
but instead it sends the request to the same address
that was used for serving this page.
And with Vue applications that is typically not the page
that should handle this request.
In this case it's our local computer and our local computer
does not have any code expecting this request.
So therefore this default request goes into the white.
Now you could be building applications
where you also use Vue,
where your Vue App is served by the same server
that should be handling the request.
In that case this browser default might be fine.
But in the vast majority of cases,
you'll have a separate server for your Vue App,
which is just delivering this Vue App to your users,
then you have free handling of the user data.
And that's exactly the scenario
where you don't want this browser default,
but where instead you wanna prevent it
and handle the submitted data in JavaScript with Vue.
For example, also to validate it
and show such a client site error message.
So show this error paragraph, for example,
that is something you might wanna do.
And once you validate it you then wanna take the data
and send it to the server of your choice,
not necessarily to the same server
that is serving this application.
And that's exactly what we wanna do here.
So how do we send a request to Firebase then,
which is our chosen backend in this case?
Well, the nice thing about this Firebase servers
and they're the real time database
is that it has this HTTP address which you see here.
And if you send the request of a specific format
to this address, the data will automatically be picked up
by Firebase and will be written to a database.
Now, it might look like we're directly talking
to a database with that, but we actually aren't.
This is a HTTP address that leads to some server side code,
which we can't see, which was written by the Firebase team,
which passes the request that will be sent by us
and then extracts data and then writes it to a database.
So for us, it will look like we're directly talking
to a database, but we actually aren't.
But this is the address or part of the address
to which we wanna send the request.
And of course make sure you pick the address
you are seeing in your dashboard. Not mine.
This address will not be available anymore when you're
viewing this course.
So we wanna send a request to that.
But how do we now send the request
from inside our Vue code here?
Well, there are a couple of options.
We can use third party packages like axios,
which is a very popular JavaScript package for sending
HTTP requests from inside JavaScript.
It's very powerful and very easy to use
and definitely worth a look.
Alternatively, browsers also have built-in methods
for sending HTTP requests.
Precisely there is the fetch method,
which sounds like it's only there to fetch data
but it's actually a function that allows us to send data
to servers as well.
Fetch takes a URL as a first argument
and then we can configure it to get data from that URL
or to send data to that URL.
And I'm going to work with Fetch here
since it's built into the browser,
but you could absolutely also look into packages like axios.
Both axios and fetch will send so-called
behind the scenes HTTP requests.
That means that we won't reload the page,
our application will not be killed and restarted,
instead the Vue application will continue running
and the HTTP request is just sent well behind the scenes
to our backend.
And that's exactly the behavior we want here.
We want to ensure that our request is sent
without restarting the application.