So how does fetch work then?
As I mentioned, we wanna provide a fast argument,
which is the URL to which this request should be sent.
Now that's the URL I got from Firebase, but actually,
we need to tweak it a little bit.
You can add, after the slash here,
any identifier of your choice.
I'll name it surveys.
And then, important add .JSON after that.
This is not something Vue needs
or Backends in general need.
This .JSON at the end is just
a Firebase specific requirement.
When you're working with a different Backend,
there is a high chance that you don't need it.
But for Firebase we need to add it.
And this key here, surveys, that's up to you.
Firebase will then automatically create a note
in this database and store our data under that note.
So that is the first part.
Here we got this Fetch function.
Now, by default, this will try to get data from here.
Now here I don't wanna get data, instead, I wanna send data.
So, we can we can pass a second argument to Fetch.
And that is a (indistinct) object
where we can configure this request.
And here we have a method property which we can set.
By default, the value is a string get,
but we can set it to post.
And this influences which kind of http request we send.
There are get and post requests.
Get for getting data, post for posting so for sending data.
And there also are other words like delete
or patch for deleting and updating.
But here we need post to send a new piece of data,
and we also need to add some headers,
some metadata to this outgoing request.
To be precise, we should set the content type header
to application/JSON, telling the server
that we'll add some data to this request
which will be in the JSON format.
Which is basically just text,
but text for method in a specific way,
which is very easy for machines to pass and read.
And that's the next thing we gonna add.
We gotta add a body to this request.
Which is the data we wanna add.
And here of course, that should be my survey results here.
The name and the rating.
So here I'll add a new JavaScript object as a body,
where I set the name to this username,
and the rating to this rating,
sorry, chosen rating.
So the values which I emitted in the past,
are now added to this object.
And therefore of course here it should be entered name.
So, the values which are submitted before,
entered name and chosen rating,
these are the values which are now encoded in this object.
But that's a JavaScript object as I just said,
we wanna send JSON data,
and JavaScript has a convenient method we can use for that.
There is a JSON object
on which you can call the stringify method,
to which you can pass your object.
And this turns this JavaScript object into this JSON format
into a string that has this format we wanna send.
And now, that will send a http request to Firebase.
This also means that
we no longer need to emit our custom event here,
and hence it will comment out everything
that is related to that.
And of course it will also mean
that we no longer manage our data here in App.vue.
Now, we could do that,
you could have an application where
you wanna send a request,
and still also manage your data locally.
That could be a scenario you have.
Here, it's just not the scenario I have.
So I will comment out the data in Appvue,
and I will comment out these methods block here,
with the store survey method.
Because we'll no longer be doing this locally
in our Vue app, at least for this app.
We are not going to do it locally anymore,
and hence we don't need that data
and the methods here anymore.
And that also means that we no longer
will bind survey submit here, on the learning survey,
and we will no longer provide results for user experiences.
And that of course means that instead of user experiences,
for the moment,
we'll no longer get a value for results.
We'll take care about that later.
Back to our learning survey,
there we are now sending this http request.
Let's see (indistinct) that works.
Let's save everything, reload this application
and let's submit our survey result here.
Now, did it work?
Let's have a look at Firebase.
It should have worked,
and here you should see a surveys note,
where you see this random text
which is definitely different for you,
and in there, you should see your data.
Now this random text is just a unique ID
that was automatically generated by Firebase.
And that's great, we can later use that ID on the Frontend.
But now here, we got our data stored on Firebase.
So that's great.
How can we now get that data back to the Frontend
when we click this load submitted experience button,
which at the moment is not doing anything?