We now wanna get the data
that is stored on this server.
And for that I wanna connect this load
submitted experiences button.
So in the UserExperiences component,
we previously received results as a prop.
That will no longer be the case,
so we can remove that.
Instead now,
I wanna manage some data in here
and have my results as a data key.
And initially, it's an empty array.
Now, I also wanna add some methods here though,
or one method to be precise,
a method that should be triggered
when this button is clicked.
So here, I wanna add a click
listener to the space button
and trigger the LoadExperiences method.
Now that's a method we need to add now.
So make sure you add it under that same name
to methods,
and in here
we now wanna send another HTTP request
to the server we previously sent our data to.
But now to get data.
For that, we can of course copy this request
from Learning Survey.vue,
and bring it over to this new LoadExperiences method.
Now here, I wanna send a request to this same address,
which i used for storing the data.
But now it should be a GET request
instead of a POST request,
because you wanna get data.
The good thing is,
that would be the default,
so we don't even need to set this.
Now since we're getting data
we'll also not have any body.
So we can remove that as well,
because a GET request does not carry any data.
And now here for the headers,
since there is no body
we also don't need the headers.
So we have a empty conflict object
and therefore we are also allowed to delete it.
This will now send a request to get the data.
But we'll face a problem with that.
When we send this request,
how do we get access to the data
that will eventually be loaded?
Well, fetch returns a so called promise.
Now, what's a promise?
And why do we need that?
Well as I just said,
the data will be loaded eventually.
As you can imagine,
if you're sending an HTTP request,
that can take a couple of milliseconds or seconds.
Firebase is super fast
and my local internet is pretty fast
so it should be pretty quick.
But still, it might take 100 200 500 milliseconds
for the data to arrive.
And JavaScript is a language
that will not pause and wait with the other code execution
until that result is there.
That is good,
because it would mean if it would pause
that our web apps would freeze all the time
waiting for some behind the scenes HTTP requests
to finish.
So that's the idea behind promises.
Fetch returns an object
on which we can listen for the data
once it is there,
to then set up code
that will be executed when that data is there.
And we set up such a listener by adding a then method here
on the result of fetch.
The then method
takes a function
which will be executed once the result is there.
It will be executed automatically
by the browser once the data is there.
And in here,
we'll also get an argument automatically
and that will be the response of this request.
So the response sent back by the server to the browser.
Now here we can then work with that response
and try to parse it.
It can for example check if the response is okay.
This response object
which we get automatically by the browser
has an okay property
that indicates whether it was a successful request or not.
So for example,
if the server sends back a 404 code,
this would not be okay.
If it is okay however,
we can continue with the response
and try to read the data that's in there.
For that the response has various methods.
For example, it has a JSON method, which we can call,
which will parse the data
that's part of the response if it's in JSON format.
And JSON is the de facto standard for exchanging data.
And therefore, not only do we send data in JSON format,
when we send the request,
Firebase also replies with JSON data
when we get data from it.
So the JSON method
is the method we wanna use
for parsing the data that's part of the response.
Now, this also turns out to yield a promise.
And therefore what we can do here
inside of such a then block here,
is we can return this response JSON call here.
So we can return the promise yielded by that.
And we can add another then method
after the first then method.
And this then method will be triggered
when this return promise is done.
So here we have another function,
but here we'll get the actual data,
which response JSON yielded.
And that's now the place where we have access to the data.
And therefore here for the moment,
I will just log it.
We'll take care about error handling later,
for the moment let's just see if we can get that data.
So let's save everything.
Open up the developer tools,
reload,
and click Load submitted experiences.
And after half a second or a second,
you should see some data here.
And that indeed is the data that was stored on the server,
it has this Firebase id.
And then stored under that id,
we have a nested object with a name and a rating.
So fetching that data works.
Now, of course, we don't just wanna fetch it
and log it to the console,
but we wanna output it on the screen.
Now to do that,
all we gotta do here,
is we have to add it to the results we have here,
or set results to a new array,
which is full of that data.
Now setting this results equal to data
will not do the trick.
Because data is not an array.
It's a JavaScript object
with this id as a property name.
And then in there,
we have another nested object
with name and rating.
I actually wanna work with an array instead.
And therefore we need to transform the data.
I'll add a results array here,
an empty one,
and then I will go through all the id's in data.
Keep in mind that data is an object
full of such id properties.
So now I'm going through all those ids here.
And I will push a new object
to my results array here
to this temporary results array
for every id property I find in data.
And there I will set an id key
to this id,
which I'm getting here.
So to the property names used in data,
and set a name equal to data
for that id.
So this data object
and they're accessing this dynamic id property.
And then there
we have a name and a rating field.
So here, dot name
and set rating equal to data id rating.
That is how I'm generating a bunch of objects
with an id name and rating field
based on the data we're fetching from Firebase.
And I'm adding that all to my temporary results array.
And once we're done with this four loop here,
I will set these results.
So the results data property we're managing here,
I'll set these results equal to my temporary results.
And that should be all the code we need
to transform the incoming data
and load it onto our screen.
So if we now reload and load the Submitted Experiences,
I get an error.
Cannot set property results of undefined.
I'm getting this because this keyword in here
actually turns out to not refer
to my view instance object unfortunately.
The easiest way of working around that
is that we don't use this function syntax here,
but this arrow function syntax instead.
Arrow functions are another way of writing functions
in JavaScript.
They work like regular functions,
but they have one key difference,
that this keyword inside of them
does refer to the same context
as it does outside of them.
And therefore now this will refer
to the view instance object.
So if that, if I set this and reload,
and load the Submitted Experiences,
eventually we see the experience here.
And if I now would add more data,
more experiences,
and I load those,
we see all those experiences show up here.
And that of course is a great step forward.
Now we're able to save data on a server,
and we can also fetch it from there.
Now there are a couple of improvements and additions,
we can make