Well, another thing would be nice to have
when we reload or loading the data
and typically it loads extremely fast here
because Firebase is fast and my internet is fast.
But of course you might be talking
to a server which is a bit slower
or maybe the users of your view application
have a slower internet connection.
So loading the data could take a while.
Therefor you might wanna show a loading spinner
or a loading message.
And that's something we can do here as well.
In our user experience component,
where we are loading and displaying the data,
we might only want to show this list of data
if we really did load data
and we wanna show a loading message and stat
if we are still loading data,
that's something we can easily implement
by adding a new data property is loading for example,
and let's set it to false initially.
Now, whenever load experiences is triggered
right at the beginning before we start fetching,
I wanna set this is loading to true
because we're now sending a HTTP request
and hence we're loading new data.
And then I wanna set it back to false
once we're done loading that in the end means
that here once we got our data,
I want to set this is loading back to false
because we're not loading anymore we got our data.
We gotta do it here
and not here at the end of the method after fetch,
because keep in mind,
JavaScript does not wait for fetch to finish
so the next line after fetch will execute immediately,
JavaScript will not wait for that to finish
it's just the code in these then functions
that will execute at a later point of time.
That's why we need to reset loading here.
And now we've got this is loading property which we can use.
We can check if we're not loading
that's when I wanna show my data.
And if I am loading,
I wanna show my loading spinner or in this case
if his loading is true
I will just show a loading text at least
like this.
Of course therefore here we can also use V-else.
And if we do that you really have to watch closely
because it will be super fast here,
but you briefly see a loading here, right?
You can see it for the fraction of a second.
So that's working we're showing a loading spinner
or a loading message whilst we are waiting
for the data to arrive.
Now, what about not having any data or getting an error?
How can we handle that?