At the moment we assume, that everything is going to work,
that we never getting any error here.
But of course in reality, we could be getting an error.
So therefore beside checking this loading state,
I also wanna check whether we get data,
and because we might not get an error and still
not get any data, for example if we got no data here on
Firebase, if I delete all of that,
then we can send a successful request.
But it will get an empty response, because there is no data
to be loaded so we wanna handle that.
And thereafter I also wanna handle real errors,
where the server times out, we have server site error
or anything like that.
But let's start with the no data case.
We are setting our data here, to the results
and in the end handling the no data case is easy.
Will simply not be able to loop through any data here,
and therefore results will stay an empty array.
So in this case, we should check not just if
we loading or not.
But here,
with "else-if" maybe I wanna check if we not
loading...
but that we do have data,
were the length is greater than zero.
If length is equal to zero its an
empty array and that simply means we have no data.
And of course its not data but results.
So if results length is greater than zero we could also
add an extra check, and check if we have a true feed
results value before we try diving into the length.
Here we always have results, but in other apps
that might not even be set if you fail to load data.
Hence checking this as well could make sense.
Then here we could add another paragraph,
where we say: "No stored experiences found.
Start adding
some survey results,
first."
And I wanna show this paragraph
"if" or "v-else-if"
where not loading,
but we don't have results,
or and therefore that should go
between brackets so that these two statements are
evaluated together, or we do have results but the length is
equal to zero.
So for not loading, but we don't have results
or our results length is equal to zero,
then I wanna show this "No stored experiences found" text.
Otherwise, I will check this and show my actual results.
If we save that and reload, we see loading and then
our no data message.
If I start submitting data though,
and then load the submitted experiences we see that works.
So now we handling the no data case.
But what about real errors?