For that, let me show you how a real error
could occur here.
We can simply manipulate this URL.
Of course, that is an error
you typically would be able to avoid
because you as a developer add that URL.
But since I have no influence on the server side code here,
I can't fake a server side error.
Hence sending a request to an invalid URL
is the best thing I can do right now.
Let's remove dot .json at the end.
This is something Firebase doesn't like,
and if you then send the request to this invalid URL,
Firebase will respond with an error message.
So let's save that and reload and everything is red.
We see a bunch of red, so clearly this failed.
We can handle such errors,
which in this case actually is thrown by the browser here.
We can handle such errors by adding another block
in our then chain.
After all those then blocks, we can add a catch method.
So .catch on this long chain of thens and thens.
Catch all the works on promises and it takes a function.
I'll also use an arrow function here,
which will be triggered whenever any error occurs
related to the previous, then blocks.
So related to the original request
or thrown in a later then block.
Here, we'll get the error and here we can handle it.
So here for example,
we can console log the error to get started.
If I do that and reload, here that's my console log.
Of course, I'm not here to just log it.
So instead, I wanna show something to the user
on the screen,
because typically your users are not going to open
the developer tools.
So they just see loading and they are wondering
whether they will eventually see some data or not.
So I wanna improve this experience and show an actual
error message to the user,
either a dialogue or in my case here,
simply a message down there.
And for that, we can simply manage another data property
in the component where we are sending the request.
The error property for example,
the name is up to you though, doesn't have to be error.
Like for all those properties.
Initially, I'll set it to null
because initially we have no error,
but down here we do have an error.
So here I'll set this error equal to
"Failed to fetch data - please try again later."
Of course you could also analyze this error object,
which we're getting and see if you got more detailed steer
and show a more specific error message to your users.
That really depends on your application,
which kind of errors you wanna handle and so on.
But this at least is a generic error message
that tells the user that something went wrong.
So here I now wanna use error to show an error message.
For that I'll add another paragraph here
with v-else-if in that long block of v-else statements
and check if we're not loading,
because of course if we're loading,
I definitely don't wanna show the error message,
and if I have an error.
And if I do, I simply output the error here
because error is simply set to a string here,
so of course we can't just output it in our template.
And now we can also use v-else here in the end,
because we know if we reach that block here,
we will have results which we can output,
because we're handling all our cases
before we handle this case here.
Of course, I also wanna reset error
whenever we send a new request.
So when we start sending a new request here,
when we set isLoading to true,
I'll also set error back to null,
to reset the error at this point.
And now with that,
my project here complains that this error argument
is never getting used so we'll console log it here
like this,
alternatively, we simply leave that blank,
but I wanna show you that you would get this error object
that was thrown as an error here.
And therefore with that, if I reload,
we still see a loading.
Let me check why?
Oh yeah, because of course here,
I'm just checking if we're loading, and if we are,
I'm always setting loading.
Now the problem is we are loading if we get an error,
because we only set isLoading to false
if we're able to read some data,
which is not happening here, if we catch an error.
So of course we should set this isLoading to false here
in the error case as well,
because we are not loading anymore.
We were unsuccessful, but we're not loading anymore.
So we need to reset this here as well.
But I also noticed another issue, the order here.
We're checking if we're loading,
but they're afterward checking if we're not loading,
but then if we maybe got no result data,
and if that's the case, we'll show our no data message.
Actually I wanna switch the order
and first check if we have an error,
so that this overrides the no data case,
and we show the error message
instead of the no data message if we have an error.
So with all that, let's save that,
and now if a reload,
we see this "Failed to fetch data" message here.
On the other hand, if we do fix this URL here,
if I add .json,
then you see if I reload,
the data gets loaded and displayed correctly again.
And if I delete my data here, let's check this case as well.
If I now load the data, we see the no data message.
And if I add data again
and then load it, that works.
So now this is also how we can handle errors.