Now, there's one more thing
you gotta know related to that though.
The fetch method works such that technically, errors,
like the one I generated with the invalid URL
are in the end handled with this catch method like that.
You also could be errors that are stemming
from the server site, so that are stemming from Firebase,
which are not technically errors.
So where you do get a regular response,
but the response simply tells you that something went wrong.
And that would by default not be handled
with this catch block.
And I can show this to you as well.
Let me show you a server site error.
And that's something I can do
in the LearningSurvey.vue file.
Here, we're sending the data and there,
we are actually not using then or a catch at all.
I'm not using then because I don't care
about the response here, but I actually should care
about whether everything worked or not.
So I also wanna show the user an error message
if sending the data failed.
For that, of course, we can add an error property
to data here as well.
And then simply add a catch method here
to wait for a potential error.
And if we do get an error,
we can set this.error equal to something went wrong.
Try again later or anything like that.
And I wanna reset it right before we start fetching.
Here, I'll set error to null again.
So now we also handle errors here in the send data case,
and we can use the error property now,
for example, here to show an error message.
Of course, you could also instead show an alert,
whatever you wanna do, but here I'll check
if error is truthy, if it is an error string,
and in that case, I output the error.
And now, of course, I can generate the same error as before,
if I remove the .json here.
Now in the case for sending data.
If I do that and I try to send data,
I eventually get this error output.
But that's just technically error I was talking about.
But now let me show you another kind of error,
an error which will not be a technical error
thrown by the browser but instead,
an error generated by the server,
which is then still resulting in a regular response
being sent back, but a response which is not okay,
but which instead has a status code
that indicates that something went wrong on the server.
And we can force Firebase to do that
by removing .json stringify.
With that, we're telling Firebase
that we're sending .json data
and that is what we should send and what Firebase expects.
But then we're actually sending a JavaScript object,
which is not .json data.
If we do that, reload and try to submit a new rating,
we'll see nothing.
Here, we see no error message,
but if I load my submitted experiences,
the new rating, which I just submitted is not there.
I can do this as often as I want.
It's not there.
And it's all done out here in Firebase.
The error, we just have the old rating from before.
We can see the problem if I open the developer tools,
we got an error here, failed to load request.
The server responded with a status of 400.
And that's the important part.
Now it's not a technically error thrown by the browser
which we had before, but it's a regular response,
which just has a status code of 400.
Success responses always have status codes of 200 or 201.
If you have 400-ish or a 500-ish responses,
that means something went wrong.
And that can happen but the problem is catch
is not picking it up.
Well, that's just how this fetch methods works.
We need to add then and have a look at our response.
This then function here will always be triggered
if we have a regular response,
so if we don't have a technical error.
And here we can check if the response is okay,
and then do something, but if it's not okay,
which it will not be if we have a 400 or 500 status code,
then I wanna also set my error.
We could this by setting this.error,
but we could also do this by throwing
a new error object here.
Could not save data, could be the message
which I pass to that.
The argument you pass to the error constructor
is the message that will be set for the error.
And this error constructor here is built into JavaScript.
This throws a new error,
and this will then automatically reach this catch block.
And here I can then actually set this.error equal
to error.message to use my message here.
The message property will be present on this error object
because this error constructor creates such an object
where what you pass here will be stored
on a message property.
And if we do that and save this,
if I now reload and try doing this again,
now we see Could not save data here.
And now we're showing the users some message
that allows the user to, well,
at least try again later or anything like that.
Now here, of course, the problem is a problem,
we, as a developer, should avoid.
I should stringify this but in reality,
you could have circumstances where the server generates
such an error response without you, as developer,
the front end, the Vue developer being responsible for it.
That's why this still was a great example,
even though that, of course, in reality would not occur,
but it shows you how you can handle
such service site error responses.
And with that, we really handle everything.
We handle success cases.
We can load data.
We can show messages if we have no data
and we can also handle errors.