So this is it for this module.
You'll learn how to send HTTP requests,
both to send data as well as to get data.
You'll learn how to work with their response data,
how to extract it, and how to show it.
You'll learn how to show a loading text
or a loading spinner.
You'll learn how to handle errors
in case something goes wrong.
And in general, you hopefully now have
an understanding why we might want such a backend,
at least for some applications which we're building,
and how you can communicate with the backend
behind the scenes from inside your Vue app.
Using the fetch function,
which is built into browsers, is just one way of doing it.
I also did mention the axios package before,
which is a third-party package
you could add to your project,
which also allows you to send such requests.
It just works a bit differently.
For example, there, catch will automatically also trigger
if you get back error responses,
so that extra handling we needed with the fetch function
would not be required with axios, but that's it.
We're going to see this in action in a course project
as well, but this hopefully gets you started
and now gives you everything you need
for you to start sending HTTP requests in your applications.