In this module, I will dive into view free and explain what changed with View Free and which new features
we have now.
I want to start with one important note view version.
Free is the latest version of a view, but there is a but if you visit the official GitHub repository
of View version free, which at the moment is the view next repository, not view the view next repository,
you'll find the release notes there.
You also find them linked below the video.
And the interesting thing here is that they follow a phased release process.
Now, what that means is that view core, the core framework is finished.
It's stable, it's out there.
But some other parts of the framework, for example, the router and Buick's integration in the def
tools.
So some other packages and things that belong to the framework and to the Vuko system are not final
yet.
That's why The View team decided to go with this phased release process where for the moment, if you,
for example, visit Viejas dot org, you'll still end up in the view to docs there.
So you still start with view to their.
Also, if you install view via NPM, so if you run NPM install, you also see that at the moment you
get viewers in queue on that latest tag you need to run NPM install you at next to get dead.
Real latest version.
And you need to visit the free dog Viejas Dog to get to the view free version of the official website
and documentation.
Nonetheless, viewership of free is final.
And the word and you should learn right now, do the work and you should dive into right now.
You just should be aware of this phased release process and that all parts like the Web page and and
install latest version will only be switched to view free at the end of the year.
That's the plan, at least as you can see here.
So that's something to be aware of nonetheless.
Now is the time to learn you free.
And if you're just starting with you, I would recommend that you do that with viewers and free because
it is stable and it is the future of view.
And the parts which still get some work might not matter to you.
You can find the next steps on which to view team focuses here, and none of these parts should have
a strong impact on you if you're just getting started with the view at the moment.
So with that, let's now explore what changed with View Free and what's new now.
The good news is that not a lot of things changed.
And what you learned for of you two generally still applies.
There aren't any major breaking changes that would force you to relearn everything.
That is not the case.
But there are a couple of changes and a couple of new features you should be aware of.
I will highlight all important changes you should be aware of in this module, though.
So let's start with the changes here.
I will just highlight the most important changes which will likely affect everyone, or at least a lot
of people for an exhaustive list of all changes, no matter how big or small they are and all new features,
definitely check out the official migration guide, which you also find attached to this video.
Now, the changes I'm going to list here will also all be shown in detail throughout this video.
One change that will affect everyone is that you now create your view instances, your view apps differently
than before the syntax changed and therefore you will need to change this in your apps as well.
But changing it as simple as you will see.
In addition, the data option now must always be a method.
It's no longer allowed to be just an object.
And another change that will affect everyone is related to how you register components, directives
and third party modules.
This will now also work a bit differently, as you will see.
But updating this and changing this will also be simple.
If you're using transitions in your app, the transition component, see us as class name changed the
dash enter class is now dash enter from and I'll show this in an example as well.
And that's almost it when it comes to just view.
As I mentioned, check the official migration guide for all minor changes as well.
But these are the most important changes you should definitely know now if you're using the view router
there, we now also create De Ruyter differently and transitions with the router.
So if you have animations for switching pages, that also works differently.
Now, for a viewer, it generally works as you learned it, but we now create our store differently.
So these are the changes, and I'll cover them with concrete examples from the video.
We also got a couple of new features, which I'll cover.
We got two minor, but nice to have changes, a teleport component and support for fragments.
And I'll explain both what it is and why and how we use it in this video.
Of course, the biggest new feature, which was added with View Free, is the new composition API,
which and this is important, is 100 percent optional.
You can use it to replace the options API so you can use it to build your components differently.
Instead of using data, watch methods and computers, you can use something else, but it is optional.
It will not replace the options API.
You can use it, but you don't have to.
And all also dive into that in detail, of course.
And then kind of a new feature.
We got better typescript support.
You could always use typescript with view.
But since View Free was internally rewritten from scratch and uses TypeScript internally, it now has
better support.
Now using typescript is still optional and at the moment at least, I'm not using it for most view projects.
But if you want to use it, you got better support.
So that's the overview.
With that, let's dive into the concrete examples.