I prepared a little project.
You find a link to the GitHub repository
with all those examples attached to the video.
And here we can walk through all those important changes.
And let's start with the basic-app.
With basic-app-v2.
Here, I'm creating a basic Vue app with Vue version 2.
Creating my Vue instance,
having some data,
having a method to change that data
and having a component with a template,
which basically has a button where I emit a custom event.
That's what I'm doing here.
And if we view this application
by simply opening this HTML file in the browser,
this is what we see
and when we click the button, this works.
Now, this is Vue 2 and this is probably what you know.
With Vue 3, a couple of things change here.
To be precise, I'll now cover these first three changes,
which are outlined here
because all these changes affect what we see here.
So let's go to basic-app-v3.
There, we first of all have to make sure
we import the latest version of Vue.
And for that, I currently have to add @next here
since at the time I'm recording this,
Vue 3 is in release candidate phase
and not really finally released yet.
In the future, of course,
this default CDN link
will automatically pull in Vue 3.
And I will update this repository as such
that all the CDN links are correct all the time.
So here I'm now importing Vue 3 by adding this.
And with that added here,
we'll see that if I now open this index.html file
in the browser, this fails.
Now we clearly don't see the message anymore
because this base syntax here changed a little bit
with Vue 3.
Here in app.js, in the v3 folder,
I got the Vue 2 syntax
but this will not work anymore.
Instead, to create a Vue app,
we now no longer instantiate
the Vue constructor function here.
Instead on Vue, we calculate createApp.
That's a new method
that was added with Vue 3.
Now, to this createApp method,
we now need to pass our app config object
and here we can pretty much copy the object we used
in Vue 2 as well.
But there are two other changes you should be aware of.
The el property doesn't work anymore.
Instead, we now mount our app to the DOM
by calling mount on the created app object.
So on the result of createApp.
And to mount, we pass that CSS selector,
which we previously had in el.
And we can get rid of new Vue now.
That's the first change.
In addition, well, I mentioned
that the data option also changed
and now always needs to be a method.
Now, in Vue 2, both was allowed.
You could have just an object
and you could have a method,
though a method was recommended in Vue 2 as well,
especially if you worked with multiple components and so on,
then you needed a method.
Well, now, with Vue 3,
data always needs to be a method.
So we simply should turn data into a method,
which then returns our data object.
So that's the only change we need to make here.
Besides that, it works as before.
And for example, methods computed in watch,
those things all work as you learned.
Nothing needs to change there.
And with that, we already covered
the first two changes here.
Now, the third change,
which we should be aware of,
also affects this demo app I prepared.
Components, directive, their-party modules,
all those things are now registered on the app
instead of the global Vue object.
So calling Vue.component, that's not how this works anymore.
Instead createApp creates an app
and we can store this in a constant
and then on this app, we can call mount, for example.
Now, it's also on this app
that we have to call component, directive
and use to use third-party modules,
which we'll see in action later
with the router and Vuex.
So here, we can call component
and then pass this component code,
which we also passed to the component method before,
so these two arguments,
to this component method here.
So it works as before
but now it's on the app instead of the global Vue object.
So with that, we get rid of this line here as well.
With that, however, if I save all of that,
and I reload, we got our message back,
we got the button and it works.
Now, one minor change,
which I didn't highlight on the slide,
if you have a component
that emits a custom method,
like here, this component.
It emits update,
there also is a new option you can pass
to this Vue instance config object here
and that's the emits options.
It's basically the counterpart to props you could say.
With props, you could specify all the props
a component receives,
and that was already the case with Vue 2.
With emits, you now can
and should also specify the custom events a component emits.
It's technically not required
but it makes your component easier to understand.
Now I can immediately see which custom event
will be emitted somewhere in this component.
It's a minor change but also something to be aware of.
And with that,
we covered these first three changes you should know.
Now, the fourth change is related to transitions.
There a CSS class name changed.
I also prepared an example for that.
The transitions folders here.
Let's start with transitions-v2.
If we open that in the browser,
we get this button and with that,
we can toggle the box here,
which has a transition attached to it.
This transition works simply because I'm wrapping the box
with the built-in transition component
and then adding my transition CSS classes down there
in the CSS file.
And this all worked with Vue 2.
Of course, because that's a Vue 2 example here.
Now, with Vue 3, this changes.
If I make sure that I import Vue 3 here
in the v3 folder, this example,
if I load the v3 example breaks.
Now, it breaks because we need
to create the app differently.
So let's quickly do that.
Vue.createApp.
Instead of el, call mount here.
And then also make sure data is a method.
That's what we just learned.
I just wanted to practice it here again.
But that's a simple change of course.
With that, we create the app properly.
And hence if we reload, now this works.
But you'll notice that the remove animation works
but the enter animation does not work.
Because a CSS class name changed,
the -enter class is now -enter-from.
Basically, to be in line with the other class names
because we had -enter-active
and -enter-to already.
Now we also have -enter-from
for the starting class instead of just -enter.
And it's the same for leaving.
This here should be -leave-from
instead of just -leave.
So a simple renaming of the class names is enough here
and once we do that, save everything.
Now we've got the animations back in Vue 3 as well.
So that were transitions.
We also got changes when we're using the Vue Router.
So let's see what changed there.
For that, I also prepared two projects.
Here's the Vue 2 version, here's the Vue 3 version.
And here I used the Vue CLI to create projects,
so it's no longer just an index.html file.
Therefore, I'll navigate in router-v2.
Run npm install
and then npm run serve
and this will install all the dependencies
and then also bring up the development server
for the Vue 2 version of this app here.
Once you load the app,
this is what you should see on the screen.
You've got two routes
and you can switch between them
and we've got a nice animation.
Now, how was this built?
I simply have my router set up in main.js
by using VueRouter,
which is imported from vue-router
and by adding the router here to the global Vue instance.
Registering all the routes,
setting mode to history
and we have the animation because the router-view
is wrapped with this transition.
This is how it works in Vue 2.
That's what you also learned in my course.
If we go to the v3 version
and also install everything there
and start the development server,
we'll see a difference.
To be precise, initially,
we'll not see anything
because I haven't added routing there yet.
In the router-v3 folder, in main.js,
we still have to add the router for good reason
because we now added differently than before.
Instead of importing VueRouter from vue-router,
I already installed the vue-router package here.
That's why it's available.
But instead of importing it like this,
you import createRouter from vue-router.
So you might see a theme here.
We have createApp from vue to create our app.
We have createRouter from the router
to create a router.
This is the new way of creating things in Vue 3.
Now, once this is imported,
we can create our router by calling createRouter.
And we then use this router on our Vue app.
So we can store the app in a constant
and then call use on the app
instead of on the global object.
I mentioned before that we no longer do that.
Instead we call app.use and use the router.
This is how we add the router.
But now we also need to configure the router.
For that, we still pass a config object to createRouter
and now we can generally grab the configuration
from Vue 2.
So here, I will grab the object,
which was previously passed to VueRouter
and paste this here into my createRouter function call.
The routes configuration works
just as you learned it.
That's the good news.
The mode, however, is set up differently.
Instead of setting mode to History,
you now need to set a history property
in this config object
and then create a history with another function.
And here you typically import createWebHistory
and then simply execute this here.
And the result of that is provided as a value to history.
This is how you set up a default router
using the HTML5 history mode for routing.
With that, we just have to add the imports
to WelcomeScreen and UsersList.
Copy that from the v2 example
into main.js in the v3 example like this
and now if you reload, our routes work again.
But you will notice that the transition is missing.
We've got no animation.
I also have another small addition or note,
which I wanna bring up first.
In TheHeader component, in the v3 project,
there is the exact prop on router-link.
This prop was needed with Vue 2
and the router for Vue 2
to make sure that the home link wasn't marked as active
when we were on Users
because Users also starts with a slash.
With Vue 3 and the router for Vue 3,
the router works differently internally
and you no longer need this.
It will automatically detect that home isn't active
if you are on Users.
That's just a minor thing but also worth noting.
More important than that,
as I just mentioned, the transitions don't work anymore.
The reason for that is that with Vue 3
and the router for Vue 3,
you no longer may wrap router-view with transition.
Instead, it needs to be the other way around.
Now you need to pass transition into the router-view,
so the router-view should wrap transition.
This is related to changes made internally
in the view-router package.
So router-view in the end has a slot internally
and needs this transition.
The problem just is transition, of course,
should wrap the component that is swapped.
And for that, you can use another feature built into Vue.
It's the dynamic component feature.
You can use the built-in component component.
This tells Vue which component to render.
Now, the router determines which component
should be rendered.
And you can get access here in this slot in the end
by using a feature called scoped slots.
This feature already existed in Vue 2.
And in my latest course update,
the Vue 3 course update,
which I added to my existing Vue course,
I cover it in detail as well.
You simply have a directive, the v-slot directive,
which you add to router-view.
And there you can then get access to special props,
which the router-view exposes to you.
You can now use these props here
between the router-view tags
and bind the is prop on component,
which component needs,
to slotProps.Component with a capital C.
This prop here is exposed to you by the router
and it holds the component that should be loaded
for the selected route.
This syntax certainly looks strange
but you only need it if you plan on using transitions
with the router,
otherwise you don't need it.
With that, however, if I save this,
now the transitions are back.
Well, at least almost.
We also need to adjust the transition names.
As you learned a second ago,
it's now enter-from and leave-from.
And once we do that, now the transitions are fully fixed
and now we've got nice animations for entering and leaving.
You might notice that if you load the app,
you've also got an initial transition here
and that's also related
to how the Vue router works internally.
If you wanna avoid this,
you need to mount your app only once the router
is fully initialized
and you can do this by going to main.js
and calling router.isReady,
which gives you a promise,
which resolves once the router is ready.
So if you mount your app in the function you pass
to this then block,
then you make sure that the app is only mounted
once the router is fully initialized.
And this will ensure
that you don't get this initial transition.
So with this change made to main.js,
now we can load without the initial transition
and we still got the transition for route changes.
So as you can tell, we have a couple of changes
to the Vue router, not to its core logic
but how you set it up
and how you add transitions
and now I guess you are aware of these changes.
Great.
Now, the last change I wanna cover here
is a change to Vuex.
The store is now created with createStore there.
I also got an example for that.
You find it in the Vuex folders
and if we have a look at the Vue 2 version here
with npm install and npm run serve,
you will see that it works just as you learned it.
We create our Vuex store
by instantiating new Vuex.Store
and passing our store config to it
and then we add the store to the Vue app, like this.
With that, this is what we get
and here we've got a basic store,
which is managing this list of users here.
Now, with Vue 3, this works differently.
If I dive into the v3 version of this,
and start this all,
we first of all, have to add Vuex again,
just as we had to add the router before
because now we added differently as you might guess.
Now we import createStore from vuex,
again to be in line with how we create things in Vue 3.
Then we create our store by calling createStore
and now the good news is to createStore,
we pass exactly the same store config object
as we did with Vue 2
and Vuex for Vue 2.
So we can grab this object here,
which holds the state and mutations and actions and getters
and we use that same object here for Vue 3.
And that's important.
How you work with Vuex
and which features it has,
that has all not changed.
You still have actions, getters, mutations, state.
You can use modules.
That's the same.
But now we create the store like this.
And we then add it to our app
by you might also be guessing it already,
by using it.
So on our app, we simply use the store.
And if we also had a router here,
we would simply use the router as well.
We don't have it here but this is how you would use it.
And with that, if you reload the Vue 3 version,
this also works without any other changes.