Now that's it for the changes that you should be aware of.
Now let's dive into the new features.
Here we got a teleport component
and a feature called fragments.
Now what's that all about.
Again, I prepared something for you.
The teleport fragments folder.
Let's dive into that.
And NPM install and NPM run serve.
Once this is up and running. If I reload,
that is what I got. And if I click on a button here,
I get this modal where I can confirm
that I want to deactivate this or cancel.
And if I confirm it's gone,
so a very simple dummy app here, using Vue 3.
Now, here we can use two new features,
teleport and fragments. Let's start with teleport.
If I opened this modal,
we can inspect this in the dev tools.
And here in the elements tab,
we actually see that this dialogue and the backdrop
is rendered somewhere nested in our element tree, right?
So this is the real DOM and our backdrop
and dialogue is deeply nested in the DOM.
Now, visually that's no problem,
but it's actually not perfect for semantics
for accessibility, maybe.
And it could even break your styling
if you don't work with set index, for example.
In general, this of course should be an overlay to the app.
So logically it should not be deeply nested in the DOM tree.
Instead, it should be directly inside of the body,
for example.
Now this is not something you technically need,
but it's simply would be a bit better logically,
semantically, from accessibility perspectives.
And hence, it would be great if we could move this div
and the dialogue to a different place in the DOM.
With Vue 2 this wasn't really possible,
with Vue 3 it is.
We now got a feature called teleport.
If you know, react there, it's called portal.
Now, how does it work?
In the component where you want to move things,
for example, here in the confirmed dialogue component,
you can simply wrap your entire component here,
your entire template with a new built in teleport component,
just like this.
And then on teleport, you need the to prop
where you pass in a CSS selector, for example,
selecting the body element to make it clear
that everything in here should actually be rendered
directly in the body.
Now you still use this component as you did before.
So I can still use it in the template
of another nested component.
As I'm doing here in admin mode, this is still possible.
We can still pass props to this component, listen to events.
This all works as you learned it.
But now the actual DOM, which has rendered
will be rendered in a different place.
If we save that and reload, I can still view this modal,
but if we now inspect it, we see this div, the backdrop,
the dialogue and the div which holds both
that's now directly in the body.
It's not deeply nested in our arbor component tree
in our arbor node tree, I should say.
So that's teleport a nice new feature,
which allows you to write semantically
more correct HTML code, I guess.
Another nice feature is the fragment feature.
Here in admin mode, I got this confirmed dialogue
inside of this list item.
Now, technically I can place it anywhere
because we just learned
that the HTML code will be rendered somewhere else.
But still to make it clear that
this is not really in the list item.
It just belongs to this component.
We might want to move it out of there.
And with Vue 2 this was not allowed.
My IDE still gives me an error here,
but I can tell you with Vue 3, this is allowed.
With Vue 3 you may have multiple root elements
inside of your component template.
You're not restricted to have just one.
You can have multiple sibling elements
directly in your template.
This is new.
This was not supported with Vue 2, now with Vue 3,
this works, as you can tell, we got no error here.
And that's teleport and fragments.
Now the biggest new feature,
which is 100% optional is the composition API.
The composition API can replace the existing options API.
And I actually want to take a closer look
at this composition API, therefore I have this
in a separate lecture right after this lecture.
Before we go to that separate video though,
here's the last new feature I wanna touch on.
It's kind of new TypeScript support.
You always could use TypeScript with Vue,
with Vue 3, it's now easier because Vue 3 internally
is built with TypeScript.
Now, if you wanna learn more about that,
I recommend the official docs.
There, you can learn all about TypeScript support
and how to use TypeScript in your Vue 3 projects,
and how to write TypeScript code there.
It's an alternative. You don't have to use TypeScript.
I'm using Java script in most of my projects,
but you can use TypeScript if you prefer that.