Now that we spent so much time
on dummy projects and all those important basics,
it's time for our first, a little bit bigger project.
We're going to build this Monster Slayer game
in this module.
It's a little game where we got various options
for fighting against a monster.
We got a battle log where we can see what happened,
for example, how much damage we dealt.
And most importantly, in this game,
we'll practice all those core basics we learned about
throughout the last modules and lectures.
We'll practice data binding, interpolation, V-bind,
event binding with V-on.
We'll practice how to output lists of data with V-for.
We'll have conditional content with V-if,
like this Game Over screen, and so much more.
It's all in there, and therefore,
that's the game we're now going to explore in this module
to really strengthen all that core knowledge,
we gained over the last module
and to ensure that we're all on the same page
and well-prepared to venture deeper into Vue JS
after this module.