So let's get started.
Attached to this lecture, you find this starting project,
which is this index HTML file with a basic skeleton
for our application.
No Vue logic is in there yet, it's really just HTML.
You got to style CSS file with some basic styles
we're going to use throughout this module
so throughout this app.
And you've got an empty app JS file because we're going to
write all the Vue logic together step by step.
Now, as I said in the last lecture,
we're going to build a simple monster slayer game
where we have a monster health and our health.
We've got various options for attacking,
launching a special attack,
healing ourselves or surrendering
and we wanna implement all of that with Vue
so that we have this browser based game here,
which we can fully control with JavaScript
but of course not with just JavaScript,
but instead with Vue and JavaScript.
And for that, obviously we're going to start
by controlling this with Vue.
So by taking over control over some HTML code with Vue
so that we can use Vue features here.
And you might notice I already prepared this div
with an ID game here and well, that looks very tempting.
And indeed this is the div
we're going to control with the Vue,
because it turns out that inside of that div,
we got the entire game HTML code.
The header is outside of the div
but the header is nothing we need to control with Vue.
We're not going to use any Vue features in there.
Therefore in app JS, like we did many times before
we can create a Vue app by calling Vue.createApp
and we can store it as a constant
and then mount our app here to this game div.
So to this div with an ID game and therefore,
we use the ID game selector here.
So now we got a Vue app connected to this div
and now the question is with which parts do we wanna start?
There certainly is not just one possible route
you could take, there are multiple routes,
like always in programming,
but I would suggest that we simply start
with the attack button.
So we basically implement features top to bottom.
So the attack button here when pressed should of course
reduce the Monster's health, but at the same time,
the monster should then also strike back
so that our health is also reduced.
And we probably don't want to use a single hard-coded value
by which we reduce healths,
but we wanna use some randomness
so that our game isn't too predictable.
And therefore in app JS,
I'm going to start by managing some data.
And you already saw it by now in the last lectures
and modules,
data of course is a core concept, a core thing in Vue apps
because pretty much any app you're going to build
needs some data,
no matter what you're managing in there,
but you're going to need some data.
Think of data as the variables you need
in your regular JavaScript codes
and it makes a lot of sense that we need data.
For example, here in this game,
which kind of data do we need to manage here
to make anything really work?
Well, how about the healths of the player and the monster?
We need to manage that data,
we need to manage that health data
because we're going to change it and changes in the health
of course, should later be reflected back on the UI
so that these health bars are reduced.
So therefore we need data, we need this data option
in our Vue app configuration object.
And as you learnt in this data method which it should be,
we returned the object that holds our actual data.
And here as I just explained, I have two main data points
and that would be the player health.
And let's say we start at a value of 100 here,
though of course you can pick any values you want
and we'll need a monster health.
Now we could say to monster has more or less health,
but I'm always going to set the monster health to 100.
So now we got these two health values which allow us to well
manage the health of our two game participants.
But the health alone is not enough.
Of course, we also need ways of changing the health,
for example, when an attack is launched.
So that screams for methods because methods are essentially
the actions we support in our Vue application.
For example, when the attack button is clicked,
we want to trigger a method that reduces the monster health.
And therefore I'm going to name that method attackMonster,
because that's what we're doing.
We're attacking the monster.
Now, what should we do inside of this method then?
What should happen instead of attackMonster?
Well, we wanna calculate the damage we're dealing
and we then want to reduce the monster health
by that damage.
And as I said before, I wanna use a random value here.
You could, of course always deduct the same amount
from the monster health
but your game would be pretty predictable then.
So to calculate a random value,
we can use the math random function,
which gives us a random number between zero and one.
Now, I don't want a value between zero and one.
Instead, since we're working with a health of 100,
we probably want a higher number.
So for example, we could say that we want to
get a random number between a minimum and the maximum value.
Let's say between five and 12,
we wanna deal at least five points of damage
but no more than 12 points of damage.
And the formula for calculating this
is to multiply math random
with the difference of max, which is 12 as I just explained
minus the min value, which should be five, for example.
And then we take the floor of that to round it down
so that we don't have a number with a decimal place
but we have an integer number instead,
and we add the minimum again.
This is a formula for calculating a random number
between five and 12.
So this will give me my attack value let's say
by which I wanna reduce to monster health.
So therefore here,
I want to reach out to this monster health
and I explained that we can access all data properties
in your methods through the this keyword because
Vue will merge all your data properties in this object
into a global behind the scenes managed object
and that's why we can use this here in a method
and get access to this monster health
and we want access to monster health
so that we can set monster health
equal to this monster health
minus the attack value we just derived.
We can also write this in a bit of a shorter way.
We can use a JavaScript shortcut here,
a shorthand notation and use minus equal attack value.
That's exactly doing the same thing
with that we're reducing the monster health
by the attack value we derived here.
Now that's one part of the equation.
We want to be able to attack the monster,
but of course the monster should also be able
to attack us as a player.
And let's say, whenever we attacked the monster
as a consequence there after,
the monster should attack back.
So we can add a second method,
a second action to our game so to say,
which is attack player.
So that is the monster attacking us as a player.
And here we wanna do essentially the same.
We wanna get an attack value calculated randomly,
but let's say the monster actually hits a bit harder
so the max damage is 15
and the min damage let's say is eight instead of five.
so that by just spamming attack all the time,
we probably won't win because the monster hits us harder.
And then we take this calculated attack value
and deduct it from the player health like this.
Now since I have the same formula
for calculating a random number,
I will actually outsource this into a separate function
and here I'll use our regular JavaScript function
and not a Vue method because this will be a function
which I only call from inside my JavaScript code,
which will not use any Vue controlled data properties
or anything like that
and which will not be called from inside our template
so from inside our HTML code.
And if all of that is the case,
if you don't need access to Vue controlled properties,
if you're not calling the function from inside HTML
and you only use it from inside the JavaScript code,
then you can write a regular JavaScript function
and I'll name it getRandomValue.
And I want to get a min and a max boundary here
and then just wrap that formula, cut it and return it here
and replace 12 with max and five with min.
And the advantage of this is that we can now simply call,
getRandomValue here and pass in five and 12
and do the same down there and pass in eight and 15.
And with that we save some code
and we simply outsourced this into a separate function.
So with that, we got our two actions.
One thing is missing here in those methods
and then of course
we also need to connect this to the HTML code.
But the missing thing here of course is that attack player
should be triggered whenever we attacked the monster.
So here after attackMonster,
I'll reach out to attackPlayer and call this method here.
And that's something we haven't done thus far
in the previous modules.
But just as we can access data properties
through the this key word,
we can also access methods through the this keyword
inside of the Vue instance config object here.
And the reason for that
is the same as with the data properties.
I mentioned that this data would be merged
into a behind the scenes managed global object
and it's the same for methods and for computed properties.
All of that is getting merged
into that behind the scenes controlled global object.
And therefore just as we can access data properties
through the this keyword inside of methods,
we can also access our methods in there and call them.
So we can call attackPlayer here
from inside attackMonster to make sure that
this method executes right after this method executed.
And with that we're done with the JavaScript code for now.
But of course we also
need to connect this to our HTML content now.
We need to make sure that in our HTML code,
we now also trigger attackMonster
when the attack button is clicked
and that we update those health bars
so let's work on that next.
Of course, feel free to try this on your own first
before we then continue together in the next lecture.