So let's do this together now.
Let's make sure attackMonster is triggered,
when the attack button is clicked.
And for that of course,
we need to go to the index HTML file,
here we have the attack button,
and we simply wanna add a click listener to it.
We can do this with v-on click,
or as you learned, we can use the short end
with just @click.
And that's the style I'm going to use throughout the course.
So I'm using it here as well.
Now here as a value,
we wanna make sure that attackMonster gets executed.
And therefore we can call attackMonster like this,
or as you learned, alternatively, we just point edit.
We just provide the name of the to be executed function,
to view here and view will execute attackMonster for us,
when a click occurs.
Both is supported by view,
I'm going to use this point at the function approach.
So now a attackMonster should be executed,
when we click the attack button.
But in order to see something,
I also wanna make sure that those health bars are updated
when the player and monster healths change.
And how could we now achieve this?
Well, this div year, these two divs,
the healthbar value divs,
in the end these are the divs that control
by how much the health bars are filled.
So if we change their width
we'll reduce the healthbar on the screen.
And here I will actually use inline styles
with the style attribute to set that width
and override any width set through a class.
This is one of the scenarios
where such an inline style approach makes sense,
because we want to be able to set the width to any value.
So predefining CSS classes with all possible widths,
we might need is pretty cumbersome and almost impossible.
Therefore here I wanna set the inline style,
but of course I wanna set it dynamically.
And we can do this with the bind
or just a short end of colon style.
And then you learned that you can pass an object here
to your style binding, and in that object,
you can define which CSS property you wanna change,
and then give that property a potentially dynamic value.
And here I wanna change the width property off to stiff,
and set it to a value which indeed will be dynamic.
I want to set it basically to my player
or to my monsterHealth,
depending on which healthbar I'm working on.
Here this the first healthbar,
which is the monster's healthbar.
So here I want to use the monsterHealth.
So this data property.
And as you learned throughout the last lectures and modules
here in your HTML code in the template
of your review app so to say,
it's not this monsterHealth, it's not data monsterHealth,
it's just monsterHealth.
You have direct access to all your data properties,
and to all your methods
without using this or anything like that.
Now the monsterHealth will be a value between zero and 100.
At least once we're done at the moment,
it could also become negative, but will prevent this soon,
but it will definitely be not higher than 100.
And that's pretty good.
That means we can use a percentage width here.
Where initially it's 100% and it can go down to 0%.
So in the end we set this to monsterHealth plus
percentage sign as a string,
because width is a CSS property,
and it wants a value like 10 pixels,
one RAM or 50% or anything like that.
So you need to add a unit.
Hence the number alone is not enough.
Instead we combined a number with a string
to turn it over all in a string,
which is what width once here if we set it fruit JavaScript,
and that string contains the unit off this value,
so that we set this to 100% to 80% and so on.
And of course we don't just wanna do that here
on the monsterHealth, but also here on the second div
on the player healthbar.
But of course here we therefore refer to playerHealth.
And now if we save all files and reload here,
if we press attack,
you see the healthbars become lower and lower.
They are reduced and that proves that both our data,
as well as methods, logic here works,
and that our dynamic style bindings also work.
Now there's one thing I wanna improve,
it's optional, but something I would recommend.
As I also mentioned already,
a couple of times throughout this course,
you shouldn't put too much logic into your HTML code.
You wanna keep that HTML code relatively lean.
And therefore I will actually cut this here,
and add computed properties as a side note.
This is a nice practice.
So here I'll add computed properties
with the computed option in our view instance config object
next to data and methods
though the exact position does not matter,
you could add it after methods or before it doesn't matter.
And in here I'll have my monsterBarStyles,
where I wanna return this object I just cut.
But here of course, we should now use this monsterHealth
since we're now having code inside
of our view instance object.
And we'll need playerBarStyles,
where I want to return this object here,
which I had on the playerHealth bar.
So returned is here this JavaScript object
of course referenced this playerHealth here
as just explained.
And now we can use these two computed properties here,
to set our styles dynamically.
So here it's the monsterBarStyles
and down there on the second bar,
it's the playerBarStyles.
Now let me reform it that and save that.
If I reload, it still works,
but now we got the logic out of the HTML code
and we are also using computed properties.
So that is our first important step.
The attack function works.
Now let's make sure the special attack function also works.