Now that the attack button
and the attack action is working,
let's implement the next action
we wanna support in this game.
And that is the special attack action
and therefore the special attack button that should work.
The idea here is relatively simple.
I want to do the same as an attack monster,
but we should deal more damage.
On the other hand and to not make this too powerful,
the special attack should therefore
not be available all the time
but only every three rounds.
So let's start by adding this method though.
I'll name it specialAttackMonster.
And in here I want to calculate an attack value
but let's say between 10 and 25 damage points.
So we have the potential to do quite a lot of damage.
Of course, just as before,
we then reach out to the monsterHealth
and deduct the attack value from it.
And also just as before,
the monster should still attack us back thereafter.
It does not just attack back if we launched a normal attack,
it also attacks back if we use a special attack.
So here we call attackPlayer, thereafter,
to make sure that we as a player
are attacked after we launched a special attack.
Now, with that,
we can connect this special attack button here.
Again, by adding a click listener
and then by pointing at the specialAttackMonster method
we just added.
And if we saved that
and save the JavaScript file and reload.
If I click special attack, I'm doing a lot of damage
to the monster, as you can tell by its quickly shrinking
monster health bar.
But the problem is, that right now we can spam this attack.
So winning would not be too hard
because we can press the same button over and over again.
And therefore I wanna restrict this powerful attack.
It should only be available every three rounds.
And when it's not available,
this button therefore should be disabled.
So how could we implement that?
How could we make sure that this is the way it works?
Well, we could keep track
of the number of rounds the game is already lasting.
For that we can add a new data property
because we got a new piece of data
we wanna change and update and be aware of
and I'll name this, currentRound.
I'll add it here to the data property
and not add it as a regular JavaScript variable,
for example, because we'll need access to it
from inside the view instance
and view needs to be aware of when it changes.
And that is all the case
if something is a data property in the view app.
So now we got the current round,
we start at zero and I wanna increment that round,
of course, whenever we do anything.
So whenever we attack and so on.
Whenever that happens, the round should change.
So therefore, for example, when we attack the monster,
I'll set this current round, plus plus,
to increment it by one.
When the monster attacks us,
I'll not do it,
because that will still be the same round, right?
The monster attacks us whenever we did something,
so we don't need to change the round again
when that happens.
But we need to change it
when we launch a special attack, of course.
So now we got this current round,
how can we now use it to control the special attack button?
Well, we can go back to index.html
and disable the button if the current round
is not dividable by three.
That makes sure that we can only use it every three rounds.
To achieve this, we can set the disabled attribute
of a button, but of course not like that
but instead to a dynamic value
and we can do that on attributes as you learned
with v-bind or again, this short hand of just :disabled.
And I want to set this to true or false.
And true or false should be derived
based on the current round.
So here we can access current round,
so this current round data property we added.
And use the modulus operator,
which we have in JavaScript,
to divide it by three and find out
what the remainder of this division is.
And we know if the remainder is not zero,
then this was not dividable by three
and therefore we know we're certainly not
in the third or sixth or ninth round.
And we only want to enable the button in those rounds.
So we'll disable it if the division of three
does not leave a remainder of zero.
If we saved it and reload,
the special attack's available
but once I clicked it, you'll see it's become gray.
And now I need to do two more normal attacks
before it's enabled again.
So this is now working the way it should.
But as so often, I don't necessarily wanna have that logic
in my HTML code and therefore I'll cut it here,
go back to app.js and add a new computed property
which we could name mayUseSpecialAttack
and in here we simply return this calculation
now using the this keyword though,
since we're in the view instance.
And with that, we can use the mayUseSpecialAttack
computed property here, just like that,
to make sure that the button is disabled
when it should be disabled.
So that's working now
and with that we ensure
that we only have access to the special attack
every three rounds.
And that's the special attack functionality implemented.