So we can attack,
we can launch a special attack every three rounds
and we're already using some nice view features
that make building such a game very very easy.
Now let's move on to the next button,
to the heal button.
Maybe we as a player took too much damage
and we wanna heal ourselves.
So we should implement a functionality for that as well.
So in the methods of my view app,
I'm going to add a heal player method
because the heal functionality, the heal button
of course should heal the player not the monster.
For that I'll calculate a heal value
and we can use the same get random value function
to get a random value between two boundaries,
and it's up to you which values you wanna use here.
Since the monster hits us between eight and 15,
I want to get a heal value of let's say eight and 20,
so between eight and 20.
And now of course we'll just reach out to the player health
and simply add that calculated heal value.
But we should be careful here.
Always adding this heal value like this
would introduce a bug in our game
because we could heal ourselves above 100 health.
We start with 100 health
and we shouldn't be able to heal ourselves
for more than that.
So to prevent that this happens,
we can add an if check here in heal player
and check if our player health
plus the calculated heal value would exceed 100.
And if that's the case,
if we would heal ourselves above 100,
then I instead want to set the player health to 100
so that we can't go higher than that.
And only in the else case
if our current health plus the calculated heal value
does not exceed 100,
only then I wanna add the full heal value
to the player health
simply to ensure that we can't go above 100.
So, with that we got the heal player method,
now we can connect it to the button
by adding a click listener as we did many times before,
and by calling heal player just like that.
And if we now save that and reload,
if I press heal initially, nothing happens
but if I launch a special attack,
this works, I can attack
and now let's heal ourselves, that worked.
Heal ourselves, that worked.
So that's looking good.
But we're not fully done.
For one, healing ourselves
should also count as a round in the game.
So of course here I also wanna increment the current round.
In addition the monster should attack us thereafter
because just because we heal ourselves
does not mean that the monster does nothing.
So once we're done healing ourselves,
the monster will attack the player,
and we do that by calling the attack player function.
And now with that, if I reload,
you see if I heal myself initially,
my health still goes down
because healing myself initially makes no sense,
I already have a health of 100, so we heal by nothing.
But the monster attacks us thereafter
and hence we take damage.
But of course we can still heal ourselves thereafter
and eventually well try to win that game.
Yeah, like that.
So, that should work,
but of course we're still not done with the game at least
because we now have all those actions here
and the health bars change appropriately,
but how does the game end?
We want to ensure that either the monster
or the player wins or for the unlikely scenario
that we both go below zero health, that we have a draw.
And that could happen by the way
since we attack and the monster always attacks back,
we could launch an attack that takes the monster below zero
and then with its last blow,
the monster also takes us below zero health.
So a draw would be possible.
Well, let's work on those win and lose conditions next,
of course feel free to try implementing this
on your own first
before we then implement it together
because that of course is a great practice.