So, how do we now check who won
and who lost?
Well for that, we need to basically check the health values,
the player and the monster health.
That is what matters to us here.
And hence we could add if checks here after we attacked
the player, so after both the monster
and the player got attacked.
Here, we could check if this player health
is smaller than zero, in which case the player lost.
And we could check if maybe all the Monster health
is below zero and so on.
But we would have to repeat this check.
We would have to repeat this check
in the special attack monster function,
and also in the heal player function,
because maybe we healed ourselves,
but the monster still dealt too much damage
and we still died.
So repeating the same code in all those places.
That's not what I wanna do because repeating code
is never good.
If we ever decide to change something,
we need to change it in a lot of different places.
And therefore we wanna avoid that.
Instead with view, we have a nicer way of keeping track
of something than doing something in reaction to that.
We could add a watcher.
So I'm going to add watchers here by adding the watch option
to the configuration object.
And here, I wanna watch two properties, the player health
and the monster health.
So we add a watcher for the player health property.
And as you learned, this name is now not up to you,
instead that has to be the name of a property
you wanna watch and you wanna watch
this player health property.
And hence I'll add a second watcher,
where I watch the monster health like this.
You all learned that we get the values then
of those watched values whenever to watch your triggers.
And therefore let's now start in the player health watcher.
There, we need a regular if check where we check
if the value, so the player health is smaller
or equal than zero.
And if let's say the monster health also is smaller
In that case, we would have a draw
because both participants are below zero.
Now, another case would be if just the value
is smaller or equal than zero.
So the first condition is not met, but the value.
So the player health is below zero or equal to zero.
Then we know the player lost.
We don't need to check the monster health being smaller
than zero here, because we're going to do this
in the monster health watcher.
There, indeed, I wanna check if the value.
So now the monster health is smaller or equal than zero.
And if the player health is smaller or equal than zero.
In this case, as mentioned, we have a draw,
or else, if just the value of the monster
is smaller than zero, then the monster lost.
Now of course, I am aware that
if we take the monster below zero and then hits us
and takes us below zero, both watchers fire,
because both healths changed
and therefore the if checks run twice.
And we'll find out that we have a draw twice.
This won't be a problem however, because you will see
what we do with this information.
We're just going to show something on the screen
and it will only show up once there.
So finding out that we have a draw twice
will not be a problem.
What do we want to do if we have a draw then,
or when the player lost or the monster lost?
Well, we probably shut this place message on the screen.
And for that, let's go to the index HTML file.
And here above the controls,
but below the health bar sections,
I'll add a new section null.
Give that section, a class of container,
which will just give it some default styling.
And now inside of that section, I wanna say game over
and then either say you lost or you won, or it's a draw
and also present a button to start a new game.
And that screams for what?
For v if, because now we have conditional content.
First of all, this entire container
with the game over message should only be shown
if the game really is over.
So if we either have a winner or a draw.
And then the message below that, something like
you lost in a h3 tag, or you won, or it's a draw.
Those h3 tags should also be shown conditionally
depending on who won or who lost.
And therefore we need to not only check those values,
but also change something which we can then reflect
in the HTML code.
And that against screams for a data property.
Here, we could store the winner
and initially set this to null because initially
when the game starts, we have no winner, of course,
But then here, if we have a draw,
I want to set this winner equal to draw, let's say.
So to a string that says draw.
If the player lost,
I want to set this winner equal to monster.
Because the player lost, the monster won.
Here, it's this winner, which is a draw again.
And if the monster lost this winner,
of course is equal to the player.
So now we have the winner data property,
which is either null or if it's not null,
holds a string of draw monster or a player.
And we can use that in conjunction with v if
to conditionally show this entire game over container,
but then also to different messages.
The entire container can be shown with v if
if indeed winner is truthy.
By default at the beginning, it's null,
and that is treated as a falsy see value in JavaScript.
So if I said v if winner and winner is null,
this section will not show up because null
is interpreted as false.
If it is a string like draw or a monster or player,
the concrete value does not matter, then this is truthy
and they for this section does show up.
Now inside of the section, we also need v if
here on the h3 elements.
I wanna show you lost if winner is equal to monster.
Else if, and for that we can use v else if directive,
I wanna show the second h3 tag if winner is equal to player
because if the player won, I wanna show you won.
And last but not least with v else, we can show it's a draw.
We could also use v else if to check a winner
is equal to draw, but since we know that
we only have those three options,
I can always just use v else.
With that added, if we now reload,
you see initially we have nothing here.
By the way, when the game loads, you briefly see
that our content show up until the view framework
is downloaded.
That is something we'll always tackle later
in the course.
Later, we'll have a different setup
where this initial flickering is not visible
just as a side note.
But here that is our starting setup now.
And now let's try to end the game.
And let's see who's going to win.
Okay, looks like we lost.
The health bars are not reflecting this
because they basically don't go into that negative.
They don't reach zero,
but we see that you lost message.
Now let's reload and let's try to win.
So for that, we need to use the special attack
and also heal ourselves a little bit here.
Special attack, attack, heal ourselves maybe,
special attack, and we won.
And let's see if we can achieve a draw here.
I'm not sure, I won again, here it is.
I was able to achieve a draw as well.
So this seems to work,
we're showing the proper message here.
Now let's make sure we also do a restart the game thereafter
if we do have such a draw and let's maybe also update
the health bar correctly, to really have
an empty health bar if the game is over.