I wanna start with the empty health bars
and for that we have our computed properties
with the Barstyles, right?
Well, we could change those a little bit
and tweak them to make sure that we set
our bar widths to exactly Zero percent if the game is over,
that should be fairly easy to do here because we can check
if this monsterHealth in the monsterBarstyles,
if monsterHealth is smaller than zero.
If that's the case I want to return an object
where the width is set to zero percent
so that we set it exactly to zero,
a negative value can't be displayed,
So we need to set it to exactly zero
and only otherwise I returned
the dynamically calculated health,
and we can do the same here.
Check the playerHealth,
whoops step playerHealth, if it's smaller than zero,
then I wanna return width of zero percent
and otherwise return the actual value.
With that If I reload and I quickly try to end the game,
you see now my health bar is empty now that I lost
and if I try to win here real quick,
You'll see now to Monster Health is zero.
So that seems to work.
Now for restarting the Game.
We could add a button in our Game Over box
below the h3 text.
A simple button like this,
where we say "Start New Game".
Now this button should do what the name implies.
It should start a new game, when clicked.
for that of course, we need a method,
because we need a new action which we can trigger
from inside our HTML code.
Hence, I'll add a new method here.
The position of the method does not matter by the way,
you can add it the end, in between or at the beginning.
And I'll just add it here because Start Game
sounds like it should be at the beginning.
And in here, I now essentially
wanna reset all those parameters,
so playerHealth, monsterHealth, currentRound, and winner,
this should all be reset when we start a new game.
So therefore we can set the playerHealth back to 100,
set the monsterHealth back to 100,
set the winner back to null because we have no winner.
And of course all those set the currentRound back to zero
because we start a new game again.
And now it's starts game,
that should be triggered when this button here is clicked.
So we simply add a click listener as we did it many times
before and point at start game.
And if we now save that and reload, let's give it a try.
Let's try to end this game here and see who wins.
It's a draw, but we have start new game.
And if I click this,
you see the health bars update and a new game begins.
So this is working here.
Let's also see if we can lose.
Yes, and this all works.
So now we got this Start New Game functionality as well.
We got the game working therefore,
but the surrender button is missing,
when we want to well, surrender.
And the battle log is missing.
A log which I wanna have at the bottom of the page,
which simply shows every action that happened.
So every damage dealt, every health point healed,
that should show up here
and I'll implement the surrender button right away
in this lecture already because it will be super easy.
If we add a new surrender method,
which we of course need to be able to do anything,
when that button is pressed.
I want to set the winner equal to monster,
because if the player surrenders the monster won.
Alternatively, we could also set the playerHealth
to a negative value, but I don't want to do that here.
I don't want to kill the player with, well,
by setting the health to zero or something like that,
the player simply surrenders.
So we just set the winter to monster and we're good.
And now we can go back to index HTML
and on the surrender button.
We bind it with a click listener,
to the newly added surrender method, just like that.
If we now save that and reload, if I click surrender,
I can start a new game.
One thing, however is not ideal.
Even if I surrender,
I can still press attack and the health bar still update.
So we might want to disable all those game action buttons.
If the game is over or remove the controls entirely,
if the game is over and that's actually something I will do
here to finish this lecture,
we do show this Game Over container.
If we do have a winner with V-if.
Now this section is a direct neighbor of this section.
So here we could make sure that this only shows up
if we don't have a winner with, not winner.
So if winner is falsely or since it is a direct neighbor
by using V-else so that we only have those game controls,
if we don't have a winner yet.
And if we do have a winner will not have the game controls.
So if I save that again and I surrender,
now the game controls are gone
and I have to start a new game
to bring them back and the same happens
If we lose the game naturally.
The game controls are gone
and we have to start a new game.
And with that I think the Core Game functionality
is finished now.
And next we can work on that battle log,
again as always feel free to implement something
on your own there,
we'll do it together in the next lecture.