So let's move on to the battle log.
And there are certainly many ways
of implementing such a log.
I want to have a log where we can add messages
that basically keep track of which action occurred?
And who started this action?
And which value was connected to this action?
For example, how much damage was dealt.
For that we should go back to app.js
and add a new method here,
which could be called addLogMessage,
because that's what we're going to do.
This method should take three parameters.
It should take the information, who did something.
So I'm going to name it who.
Then I want to know what happened.
Did we attack? Did we heal?
So I'm going to add a what here
and I need to know the value, how much damage was dealt.
How much did we heal for?
So these are the free parameters we need here.
Who, what and value.
And with this information,
I want to add a new log message
to a growing list of logMessages,
which then can be output here
in this battle log on the screen.
Hence, what we need a data property
an array of logMessages,
which can change and which Vue tracks
to be aware of changes
so that it updates the UI when it changed?
So therefore here, I'm going to add a logMessages array,
which is empty initially.
And whilst we're at it,
we can also already reset it to an empty array
when we start a new game.
So set logMessages back to an empty array here,
but now that we got logMessages in addLogMessage
I want to add a new log message to this array
whenever this method is called.
And I want to add it at the beginning of the array,
so that the latest message is always right on top.
So it's the first one in the array,
and we can do it as by reaching out to logMessages
and using unshift.
Unshift is basically like push,
but where push adds something at the end of the array
unshift adds something at the beginning of the array.
And now it's up to you how a log message should look like.
Thus far in the course in the other lectures and modules.
When we worked with lists and arrays and v-for,
we always had arrays full of strings full of text.
Here since we have free pieces of information that matter,
I will actually add an object to this array.
So a log message is an object,
and you will see how we can output does on the screen
in just a second.
So here I will now add different pieces of information
to this object to who, what and value to be precise
and I'll name the key actionBy: who
actionType: what
and actionValue the value we got.
So we add an object to our logMessages,
which has three keys action by action type and action value.
So that we know who did the action,
which kind of action it was
and what the value of the action was.
That's how we add logMessages.
And now a new log message should be added
when we for example, attack the monster.
So here in attackMonster, before the monster attacks us,
I want to call addLogMessage, so this newly added method
and set to who to player
because the player attacked the monster
wants to set the action to attack
and pass in the attackValue like this.
Now, when the monster attacks us here in attackPlayer,
I also want to add a log message,
but now it's the monster who attacked us
for this given attack value, which you derive here as well.
Of course, we do the same for the special attack.
Here the player attacks the monster.
We could also name this special-attack,
but that's really up to you
how you wanna handle those different types later.
I will not differentiate
between special attack and regular attack.
So I will just name it, attack here as well.
If you would want to add such a differentiation,
you could use a different identifier here,
but I'll stick to attack.
Last but not least for healing here,
the player heals himself for the heel value.
So that is the log message I wanna add here.
So now we've got these different logMessages being added
with that our logMessages array will grow.
And now the question is how we output those messages.
In index.html we got this unordered list here
in our battle log
and this unordered list should render
a bunch of lists items.
As I mentioned before,
you don't need to use a list item to use v-for.
V-for can be used on any element,
but since we're outputting lists of data
and we want to write semantically correct code
often you will use v-for on list items,
because that is the semantically correct HTML element
well for list items.
That's just a side note.
The more important thing of course here is
that we use v-for though
a nice Vue directive we learned about
which can help us with outputting a list content.
It allows us to repeat this list item element,
and create it as often as needed
to have one list item HTML element on the screen
per item in our logMessages array.
So therefore here we need to refer to logMessages
and go through it with the in key word
and then get access to every single log message
which we now can use on an inside
of this repeated list item.
And now here.
The content we want to output
of course is fully up to you.
We could use interpolation here
to output the action by field,
which is one of the free fields we add as a log message,
which basically indicates who did something.
Then we could add a dash
and a new piece of interpolation here
to output logMessage.actionType
so that we know what happened.
And then another dash
and another piece of interpolation here
to output our action value.
That's something we could do
with that we would output
who did something, what happened
and which value was associated.
And if we saved it and reload,
indeed you will see if I click attack here.
We have these two logMessages
where we see that the player attack for six
and there after the monster attack for eight.
And that's a nice start,
but actually I prepared some styles
to output this in a nicer way.
So let's actually use those.
And therefore I'm going to get rid of that.
And instead, add a span here, a span element,
which actually should hold the initiator of the action.
So this action by field.
So here I wanna access logMessage
and check if actionBy is equal to player.
In which case I want to print player here with a capital P
otherwise it'll be the monster, so I'll then output that.
So a little ternary expression here.
I also want to have a second span thereafter
which holds the type of action that happened,
and here we either dealt damage or we healed ourselves.
So with v-if, I'm going to check if logMessage.actionType
is equal to heal.
In which case here,
I wanna say heals himself
so that we say something like player heals himself,
for, and then of course,
the amount of healing done,
which I'll wrap in another span
simply so that I can later add some styling
to highlight the value
and into this second span here,
I'll add the log message action value,
which is the amount for which be healed here.
And I'll give this span here
a CSS class of log--heal,
which is one of the prepared CSS classes here
to simply color the amount by which we healed green.
That's the only reason why I have this extra span here
so that I can add an extra CSS class
just to this heel value text.
Now this is one option.
I need a number of span
next to this general healed himself span.
And that is for the scenario
that we actually dealt damaged
that we did not heal ourselves.
Here we can use v-else
because dealing damage is the only other option
we have in this game.
And therefore here I'll say attacks
so that we say something like player attacks and deals.
And now again, I would put the damage in a span
so that we can add an extra CSS class
in this case the log--damage class,
which is our prepared CSS class to give it a red color.
And output the damage value again, in that special span.
So that we take advantage of this highlighting,
of this special CSS style?
So here we have logMessage.actionValue again.
So this is now how we could structure this.
I also wanna add a CSS class here to this first class
to highlight who did something.
And for that I'll dynamically add a class here
because I want to add different classes
depending on whatever we have the player
or the monster doing something here.
So I'll add this object syntax here
and add a class of log--player,
which is another prepared class here this one,
if action by is the player
and add log--monster
if the action was started by the monster,
you need single quotes around those keys here by the way,
since we're in a JavaScript object here
and dashes in property names are not allowed
without wrapping the whole property name into quotes
with quotes though, they are allowed.
So that's why you need single quotes
around your property names here.
And the values off these properties here,
as you learned needs to be values that indicate
whether or not those classes should be added to that span.
So you'll need true or false here in the end.
And therefore we can simply check if logMessage.actionBy
is equal to player here.
If that is true,
I want to add the log--player class.
If that's false, I don't wanna add it.
And for adding log--monster,
I want to check if logMessage.actionBy
is equal to monster.
And of course only one of the two
will be true at a given time.
And that's my logic here.
Now, this is quite long,
but outsourcing this into a computed property
would actually not really be possible
because this does not depend
on some general data property,
but on a concrete value we get for this exact list item,
which is being rendered.
So if you would want to outsource this into JavaScript code,
you would indeed need to use a method
to which you pass logMessage.actionBy for example,
because that is not a single value managed application wide,
but that depends on which list item is being rendered.
That's just a side note.
With that however,
if we save that and reload, if we now attack,
we see something like monster attacks and deals 12,
player attacks and deal six.
If we heal, we see player heals himself for nine
and there after the monster,
attacked us for a 13,
so that didn't help too much.
This now looks better and so on.
So this all seems to work.
Now we got a log
and if the game is over,
we can inspect the whole log.
If we start a new game,
it's of course reset as it should be.
Because in start game,
we set the logMessages to an empty array again.
And that is the finished game here.
That actually is a nice first project,
which shows all the core features we learned about
like interpolation, v-bind, v-on different events,
methods, computed, watch, v-if, v-for
it's all in here.
And therefore I hope that this project
helps you get a better understanding of Vue,
the different pieces that make up Vue
and how they all work together.
Now we're really well prepared to dive deeper into Vue.