As you build bigger and bigger
Vue applications,
managing your application state,
your application data
can become more and more challenging.
This module is about a better state management solution
called Vuex.
Which can be used to replace, provide and inject
for data which you wanna share across multiple components
possibly across your entire app.
Now to understand Vuex in detail,
in this module,
we'll first of all dive into what exactly Vuex is
and why exactly we need or use it.
And then of course we'll explore it from the ground up
so that you understand how Vuex works
and how you can use it in your Vue applications
to manage your application data
in a better way.