So, exactly is Vuex?
Vuex is a library for managing global state.
Okay, that's a nice sentence.
What does it mean?
What's state?
State could simply be translated with data,
data your application needs and data that affects
what the user sees on the screen.
So, you can think of state as reactive data,
data which may change and where such changes
then should trigger something on the screen.
And Vue.js is all about this reactivity, of course,
as you learn throughout the course.
But managing data, state, that affects
different components of your app can be tricky.
For that it's important though,
to differentiate between two main kinds of state,
local state and global state.
Local state is the state the data
you manage inside of one component,
which only affects this one component and possibly,
indirectly through props, also a child component.
Here examples could be user input
that was entered into input elements, or for example,
a button that shows or hides some container.
And I got an example for you.
This is a course project we built a little bit earlier
in the course after the main component sections.
It's this learning resource manager
and in there in the AddResource.Vue file
in the AddResource component, we, for example,
have a form where we fetch user input.
And that user input, as well as the overall form validity
only matters to this component.
Here for example we have this inputisInvalid data
and therefore that would be the state of that component
which influences whether or not we show this dialogue.
So, this inputisInvalid data piece is state
because it affects what the user sees on the screen.
We show or don't show this dialogue.
And it really only matters to this component.
We manage it internally in this component.
So, that would be an example for a local state.
On the other hand, global state is state data
that affects multiple components, possibly the entire app.
So, data which you need in a lot of different places.
Examples here could be the user authentication status,
whether a user is logged in or not,
shopping card items which might be presented
in different parts of the app, and similar examples.
Again, in this app I just showed you
an example for a global state could be found
in the TheResources.vue file.
In there I got these stored resources
and those stored resources are changed
through the addResource method, for example,
but this method is triggered
from inside another component and the StoredResources
are also used in other components of this app.
So, this is an app wide, or at least a multicomponent state.
It's data that's used across multiple components.
And it's the global state where Vuex can help us.
Because thus far, for example,
in this app I just showed you,
we managed this state through provide and inject.
And this works, and this is not necessarily bad,
but it has a couple of drawbacks
which might or might not matter to you.
One potential disadvantage for example,
is that you end up with all the data
and all the methods to change the data in one component.
In this case, the TheResources component,
which therefore gets rather big
and which has a lot of data and a lot of methods
inside of it, which isn't really needed
for the template of that component,
but which is simply needed in other components.
So, getting such a big component,
which manages cross components state,
that can be hard to maintain as your application grows
and as you maybe have more and more
global state to manage.
In addition, provide and inject
can have some tricky problems regarding reactivity.
It depends on which data you provide and inject.
And whilst there are solutions
for all possible problems you could face,
a solution like Vuex in the end might be the best solution.
Now, why exactly is Vuex a good solution though?
Why might it be worth a look?
As I just outlined, managing app wide
or global state can be difficult.
You end up with such fat components,
which have a lot of logic in them,
which isn't needed for the component's template,
but in other components of the app.
You also might have unpredictable behavior
in your application because it's not always
immediately obvious where state gets changed
or maybe it's possible to change state
in ways that you don't want it to be changed.
It also could be error prone because accidental
or missed state updates could happen.
Coming back to this example in the component
where we inject the resources, we get the resources array,
which we also manage in TheResources.vue.
Now, theoretically, we could edit this array
in the place where it is injected,
and we would be editing the exact same array in memory.
We're not doing this here, but you could do it accidentally,
or maybe because a colleague is working on the code
who isn't paying close attention.
And that is exactly what I mean with
it being unpredictable or error prone.
You can edit data in places
where it shouldn't really be edited.
Of course, if you're working on your own,
this might not be a problem,
but in bigger projects and in bigger teams,
it could become a problem.
And that's exactly where Vuex helps us
because with Vuex, we outsource the state management.
It's no longer in such fat components,
instead it's in a separate place,
detached from the components.
It's also a more predictable because Vuex has
some clear rules on where state should be managed
and how it should be updated and shared.
And therefore it's also less error prone
because we have that clearly defined data flow,
which we have to adhere.
So, that's the what and why.
Now let's install Vuex and let's get started using it.