Now for this module.
As many times before you find a starting project attached,
which you can download, extract,
run npm install,
and they're all after you can run npm run serve though,
before you run npm run serve,
let's already installed the vuex
and you can do it as with npm install dash dash save vuex.
This now installs the vuex package into the project.
Just like we installed the router earlier in this course.
And now we can get started using vuex.
And for that I got a very simple application here.
Definitely not an application where we would need vuex,
but a great application to understand the core concepts
of vuex introduces.
So let's start the development server with npm run serve,
and let's see what we got on the screen.
We got this simple container here.
We're at just say Vuex,
now to get started with vuex,
let's say here inside of this base container
in the app view template here,
I want to have a button
where I say Add one
and above the button.
I actually want to have a counter.
Let's say  tag where I output to current value
is starting at zero and then incremented by one,
every time the button is pressed.
Now we could of course implement this behavior
just with data and methods and what you learned.
And for a simple app like this,
we normally would do that,
but this module is about vuex
and understanding vuex.
So let's not do it with these tools.
Instead, let's manage this counter state with vuex
as if it would be some global state,
which we need in other parts of the app as well.
And for that,
we started main.js And we start by creating a vuex store,
which stores our application state.
And there is one store per app.
So we create the store by importing, from vuex.
And what we import is to createStore function.
And you might see a pattern here,
createApp for domain vue app,
createRouter for the router,
createStore for the store.
Then we can store the store in a constant named store.
(chuckles)
And these are a lot of stores,
I guess, or storage's
and we can do so by calling createStore().
Now it createStore() takes an object
where we configured a store
and the most important thing
with which we start in our store is the state,
state() is a method
and it then should return your state object.
So it's a bit like data in a component.
Now this is the state of your application.
So this object will hold the application-wide data
and you only have one store for the entire application.
You might have multiple states though,
but I'll come back to that later
now to get started with our counter here,
we could have a counter here in our state object
and initialize it to a value of zero.
Now we need to connect our app to the store,
which we do by calling app.use and passing the store to it
just as we used the router in the routing module.
And now we can use that state in our component,
in any component of this entire app,
we don't need to add inject here or anything like that.
We can just use this state
and how do we do that?
Well, there now is a new property,
which we can access in every component.
And that's the dollar sign store property,
which points at the vuex store.
This then has a state property,
which points at the state managed by the store.
And that state of course,
is this state object.
Therefore, we now have a counter property in there
to access our counter.
And if I do that and save this,
we see zero here.
Now clicking the button.
Of course doesn't do anything yet
because we haven't wired this up.
Let's do this next.