[Maximilian Schwarzmüller]To wire up the button,
we can add a method here.
Add one could be the method name.
And it's the method I want to trigger
upon click on this button,
just as we learned it before in this course.
Now in here we can access this stores and store,
access the state and there to counter
and increment it like this.
We can, by the way, also outsource this here
into a computed property, If we want to.
We can add a computed property name it
counter or whatever you want,
doesn't have to be counter and in their return
this dollar sign store state counter.
And now we can use this counter here.
Save everything.
If we now go back,
we can click Add one,
and this now updates with help of Vuex.
Now Vuex has way more to offer than just that.
But this already shows us how it works
in a nutshell how you work with Vuex state in a nutshell.
And the great thing is
that you now can really add any component you want,
like the counter.Vue.
And in there, we can
add this h free tag.
So let's add it in the template of the counter.
And in there, I then add this computed property.
So this computed property dot calculates the counter
counted from app Vue and added in the counter Vue.
And if we now register the counter here in app Vue,
like this, and like this,
we can add it here above the button
just like that.
Save everything
and it will still work as before, if I reload.
This still works,
because it's really a global store a global state
that can be accessed from any component
without injection without passing props around.
Now, this doesn't replace props in general,
to a direct child, you typically want to pass props
if you would parent component, half the data.
But for application wide state,
like here for our counter Vuex is great
because without any extra setup,
we can tap into the state and use it.