Remember this slide?
There I mentioned this predictable state management,
this predictable flow, the clearly defined data flow,
which makes sure that we have to use a certain approach
of updating our data
and of getting our data
and this would be less error prone.
Well, actually, the way we're using Vuex at the moment works
but it's not fully following the Vuex philosophy.
We're directly tapping into our store.state
to change something from inside a component
and whilst this works technically here,
this is not ideal.
We can change the state from anywhere in the application
and it's up to us if we add one
or if we set it equal to state.counter + 10
or we have a typo and accidentally type one twice
and hence add 11 every time we increment this.
So what I wanna say is that here,
we still can introduce errors
because we're not having
a clearly defined state-changing mechanism.
We can change the state from anywhere.
That is why we should use Vuex a bit differently.
We have this app-wide, central Data Store,
this State Store,
and we communicate with it
from inside our components.
Now, I have a dashed arrow here
because yes, we want to communicate
but not directly.
What we're doing at the moment is not ideal.
Instead, Vuex has a built-in concept called mutations.
Mutations are clearly defined methods,
which have the logic to update the state.
And from inside our components,
we should, in the end, just trigger those mutations
instead of directly manipulating the state.
By triggering mutations,
all components that want to edit a state do it
in the same way.
And it's guaranteed that they do it in the same way.
And to give you an example,
I will actually add another component here.
ChangeCounter.vue.
And this will be a very simple component,
which also just has a button
where I also say Add 1
and where we're gonna click,
I want a trigger addOne.
And then I have my script in here.
And in there, my methods
where I have the addOne method.
And every component is able to use Vuex as you learned it.
So here I can access store.state.counter
and increment this by one.
Now, in App.vue, we can import ChangeCounter
and register it as a component
and use it in addition to the button,
which we already have here.
So I got two buttons now.
One here in the app component
and one in change-counter.
Both should add one but here I'm adding 11
because I mistyped or I changed my logic
and forgot to rename the method
and the text on the button.
Whatever.
But now we have two buttons.
One button adds 11 and one really adds one.
Now, why am I doing this?
I want to show you that now we have different places
in the app where we update our state.
And even if we wouldn't have that stupid mistake
of having 11 here,
even if we would have one,
if we ever decide that we want to add two,
we have to change that in two components.
We have to go to two components
and change our logic in two places
and in bigger applications,
we might have even more places
where we need to change the logic.
Now, that's a lot of code duplication
and that's exactly why we have this mutations concept.
Back in main.js where we create our store,
we don't just have the state here,
we also have mutations.
Mutations takes an object
and in this object, you can define methods.
For example, I addOne method or increment.
Whatever you wanna call it.
And this method should contain the logic
to change this state.
Now, this method will automatically get the current state
as a argument.
This is guaranteed by Vuex.
Vuex will give us the current state
whenever this method is triggered
and I will show you how to trigger such a method
in a second.
And since we get the current state here,
the guaranteed latest state,
we can access state.counter in here
and increment this by one.
Also, of course, with this code.
Or if we ever change our logic,
we simply change it here.
And now we want to trigger this mutation
from all the places
that should change our state.
And of course, it should be needless to say
that you can have multiple mutations.
You can have as many as you need for your application.
So here I've got one
and I wanna trigger it for the button in App.vue
and for the button in ChangeCounter.
Now, let's start with the button in ChangeCounter.
Here, to trigger a mutation,
we access this.$store
but now there we've got a commit method.
It's a built-in method,
which Vuex gives you on its store.
And commit takes the name
of the mutation you want to perform.
In this case, that's increment
and the name should be provided as a string.
It's increment because I named my mutation increment.
If you used a different name here,
you also need to commit a different name.
But now we can commit this here in ChangeCounter
and also in App.vue.
And now we moved the logic,
the concrete logic on how the state is updated out
of the components into our store,
into this mutation.
And we just commit this mutation
from inside our components.
So now, if we save that,
this still works
but now with help of mutations,
which is the more elegant
and more predictable way of updating our state.