Now some mutations might require arguments.
Here, we got the increment mutation
and the value by which we increment this
is hard coded into this code.
We could add and increase mutation,
which also gets to state and say that in here,
we also want to change the counter,
but we actually want to increase it by a value
which can be defined when this mutation is committed.
And you also allow for this scenario,
your mutations actually also take a second argument,
a payload, so a data package that can be a pendant.
And I'm going to name the argument payload here,
though of course, these names are up to you ultimately.
Now payload can be anything.
It can be a number, it can be a string, it can be an object.
And let's say here, we assume it will be an object
where we have a value property.
But this is entirely up to you
it's your store, your application,
you can expect any kind of data on committed mutations.
But how could we now call this?
Well let's and ChangeCounter, we say add two,
because that's more appropriate to what happens here,
but in App.vue, I don't want to commit increment,
but the new increase mutation
and I want to increase TheCounter by 10.
Now, I still don't want to manipulate the state
from insight this component.
I still want to use a mutation,
but I want to pass this data package
to this mutation so that we have some flexibility.
For that commit, takes a second argument,
which will be the payload,
which then later is received in your mutation.
So the second argument here,
indeed is also the second argument you can pass to commit.
And this can be anything as I mentioned,
a number, a string, but here it should be an object
with a value property because
that is what I'm expecting here.
I'm accessing dot value on the payload in my mutation here.
So here I provide a value and in this case,
let's say the value is a number and it's the number 10.
If we now save this and reload, add two adds two,
because it commits the increment mutation.
But add 10 adds 10 because it calls to increase mutation
with a payload that contains this value of 10.
So payloads extra data can be passed to your mutations.
You also got an alternative way of committing by the way,
there is nothing wrong with this approach,
but you can also call commit and pass an object to commit.
Now this object now needs to have a type property
which holds the name of the mutation
that should be committed.
But in addition, it can hold as many properties as you want.
For example here, this value property,
and then it's this object without the type so to say,
which will be provided as a payload to this mutation.
So that's simply an alternative way of committing
and it's up to you, which approach you prefer.
This will also work as you see here.
Now these are mutations, and the clear advantages
that you move the concrete logic
that changes your state into your store.
And here of course, it's very simple logic,
but this could be way more complex in the end.
And you just commit mutations from inside your components,
so you never, and that's really important.
You never directly add the state from inside components.
This is not considered a good practice.
You should instead use mutations.