So we use mutations to edit our data
in the state,
in the store.
Now just as we shouldn't directly edit the state,
from inside components,
we could also argue that directly reading the state,
might not be ideal.
Why could this be sub-optimal?
Well in this app we got the,
TheCounter component,
where I output to counter.
Now lets say for whatever reason
we also have another component.
Favoritevalue.vue
And in their we do the same thing as in the counter.
But maybe we do more.
That's why we have separate component.
So we do more here.
Now of course we can use this
component here,
in AppVue,
we can import FavoriteValue from components
FavoriteValue.vue
and register it here,
and also add this here below the counter maybe.
FavoriteValue like this.
Now of course this will work.
We got the counter twice now,
and it updates in both components.
Now lets say we decide
that actually we always want our output to counter
times two.
So we update it here in FavoriteValue
and we update it in the counter.
Do you see the problem?
We are again replicating logic here.
We do have duplicate code.
And again in bigger more realistic applications,
this might absolutely happen.
That we need the same kind of data in different components,
and then we decide that we want to format
or calculate the data differently.
And therefore we suddenly need to change it
in all the different places.
This is why we might not want to directly talk to the state.
Instead we can use a concept called Getters.
Which in the end are,
you could say computer properties
defined directly in the store,
which we then can use from inside any component
of our choice.
So here is how we add a getter to our Vuex store.
Next to mutations,
doesn't matter where exactly but in the same place as
State and Mutations,
you add getters.
This takes an object,
and every getter is a method in this object now.
So basically just like computer properties are methods
in the computed option of components.
Here we could have the final counter getter
lets say.
And the final Counter Getter method
like all getter method in Vuex,
gets two arguments.
The current State,
which we need to get a value out of it,
and other getters.
Getting other getters in a getter
can be helpful if the value you wanna calculate here,
depends on the result of an another getter.
But lets ignore that for now,
lets just work with the state argument.
We wanna return a value here,
a getter has to return a value.
And the value here is our counter
which is manged in the state,
times two lets say.
And we can now use this getter
from any component of our choice.
For example,
from inside the counter.
Here in this computed property,
which we keep,
we now access this $store,
but no longer the state but instead
store.getters.
And then the name of your getter.
Which in this case was FinalCounter.
So here it's also FinalCounter.
And you don't call it,
you don't execute it,
you just point at it.
Like this.
Like a property.
And Vuex will execute this getter method for you then,
passing into current state into the getter.
So we do this here,
in the counter,
and also in FavoriteValue.
And with that if we ever decide that the counter should be
lets say the Value times three,
we just need to do this in one place,
instead of in two places.
So with that,
if we go back,
you see this works now.
And this is the concept of getters.
Now I mentioned that you can't have multiple getters,
and that getters can also depend on each other.
Lets say,
besides our FinalCounter getter,
we have another getter
which is called normalizedCounter.
And the idea here is simple,
I wanna use my counter value,
to be precise the FinalCounter value,
but I want to make sure it's greater than zero
and smaller than 100.
And I either output zero or 100 if one of this boundaries
is crossed.
Now one way of building this,
would be,
that we recalculate our counter times three here,
and then we have our FinalCounter here.
We check if FinalCounter is smaller than zero,
which can't happen here but lets say we still check it.
In which case we return zero,
we check if FinalCounter is greater than 100,
in which case we return 100.
And only if neither of the two things is the case,
we return the FinalCounter.
As a side note,
this also shows us that you of course
can have more than one line of code in a getter.
That's another advantage of using getters.
You can move such code
out of components into your Vuex Store.
So that your components stay lead.
But now with that we got the normalizedCounter.
And we could use the normalizedCounter
in the FavoriteValue component.
Simply by referring to normalizedCounter here.
That is the name of this getter.
And with that you would see
that as soon as we exceed 100,
the bottom counters stays at 100.
Because of the logic we just added.
Now this works but it's not great.
We are calculating something,
which we've already calculate in another getter.
And that's why we get this getters second argument here.
With that we can refer to our getters,
and get our FinalCounter,
simply by calling getters.FinalCounter
and imagine we had more code in there.
Replicating that all in another getter,
is just unnecessary if we already do have a getter for that.
So that's how we can use finalCounter like this here.
And in this case,
I don't even need to state them,
but if we would need it we could still use it as well.
In this second getter.
Here I will replace the state argument with an under score,
which is a convection signaling my setup,
my project setup here that I do have to take this argument
in order to get to the second one,
but then I don't wanna work with it.
Otherwise this specific project setup,
won't complain about an unused argument,
following this naming convection.
It won't complain.
With that if we reload if we get the same behavior
as before,
but now in a slightly more elegant way.