Now we got "Mutations and Getters,"
what could be missing?
There is another important concept,
another important feature Vuex exposes.
But in order to understand it,
let's go back to our code.
Let's say, in the increment mutation,
we don't wanna increment immediately.
Instead, we wanna wait two seconds
and then increment.
Now this might be a dumb example,
but a better example could be an app
where you send an HTTP request
and you wait for the response.
And only once the response is there,
you wanna change your state.
Put in other words, you sometimes have code,
which runs asynchronously,
which doesn't finish immediately,
but sometimes in the future.
The problem is that Mutations must be synchronous.
You're not allowed to have any asynchronous code in there.
So if you run a Mutation,
it needs to execute step-by-step-by-step without any pause
and immediately change the state.
It's not allowed to do anything that may take a bit longer.
The reason for that simply is that if multiple
Mutations execute,
every mutation should get the latest state.
And if another mutation was committed,
but didn't finish yet,
that is unexpected and will lead to errors in your program.
That's why a key requirement of Mutations
is that they have to be synchronous.
But what if I do want to wait for two seconds?
We could do it as we've set timeout.
There, we could wait two seconds,
and then the function here,
which then executes after two seconds,
we update our state.
But this is actually not allowed.
It will work if you try it,
but it is a very bad practice and nothing you should do.
Instead Vuex has a better concept in place
for working with asynchronous code.
Besides Mutations and Getters, it also has Actions.
And Components should trigger Actions,
which then in turn commit Mutations.
Because Actions can now use asynchronous code.
And because of that,
it's actually considered a good practice in general,
to always put Actions between Components and Mutations,
even though Components could commit Mutations themselves.
And that wouldn't be a problem
if you only had synchronous code.
But even with that fact that directly committing Mutations
from inside Components often would not be a problem.
Even with that, it is considered a good practice
to always put Actions in between
to ensure that you never accidentally put asynchronous code
into Mutations.
So how do Actions work then?
How do we add them to our store?
In main js,
besides Mutations and Getters and State,
we can add Actions.
And I'm doing this here, I'll add Actions here.
And Action also takes an object
just like Getters and Mutations did.
An action again is just a method.
For example, increment: You can use the same name here
as you do in your Mutations.
So here I've got an increment mutation.
I'm also using an increment action.
You don't have to use the same name,
but often you will because often you just have an action
in between a component and a mutation.
So using the same name makes sense.
Now, this action will get an object as a argument,
a context object.
And this context object is full of interesting things.
The actual get this argument automatically by Vuex,
like all these Veux features do.
Now context, for example, has a commit method,
which you can call.
And it's does what you think, it commits a mutation,
just like you could commit it from inside a component.
You can pass a second argument as a payload
and you can pass an object alternatively
to the two argument way of using it.
But here I only need one argument
and that will be the name of the mutation
that should be committed.
Now we'll have a look at the other things
inside of context in a second,
but for the moment, let's leave it like this.
And now we got an action which commits increment.
The interesting thing is that Actions,
unlike Mutations are allowed to run asynchronous code.
So we can take our timeout here
and wrap context commit with it.
With that, the mutation is synchronous again,
but the action is asynchronous,
which is allowed by Veux.
It simply commits the mutation only
once the two seconds have passed.
And now we need to change our component code
and make sure that we don't commit
from inside the component,
but that we use the action instead.
And how do we use an action then?
How is that meant to happen in Veux?
Well, inside of the component
where we previously committed,
we can now dispatch an action.
And the cool thing is the syntax for dispatching
is pretty much the same as for committing.
You can either dispatch with two arguments
where the first argument is the action name.
So in my case increments here.
And the second argument is a potential payload you want,
or you use the one argument syntax.
Here however, I'm dispatching increase,
which doesn't exist as an action yet.
So I will quickly also add an increase action
so that this will work.
Simply add a new action named Increase,
and context commit Increase here.
Your action will receive the payload
that was added to the dispatch function
like value here, or like this second object
as an extra argument.
So here we will automatically get payload,
which we then can forward to the committed mutation.
So this is how we can set up an action
that also has a payload
and forwards that payload to the mutation.
Of course, you could also change the payload
before you commit this mutation.
You can do whatever you wanna do in this action.
Whatever needs to be done for your application
to work correctly.
But let's get back to the Components.
We dispatch Actions just as we committed Mutations
with the difference that we now run Actions
instead of Mutations.
And therefore we can also do this and change counter
and simply dispatch the increment action here.
And with all those changes in place,
if you go back, this still works.
And only after two seconds
do you add two button click is having an effect.
But now we're doing this in the proper way using Actions.