So actions are important
for asynchronous code, and in general,
it is a good practice to use actions.
Now, I did mention that we have this context, object
which we get as an argument automatically,
and that it's full of interesting things.
Thus far we're only using the commit method though.
So what's inside of context as well?
Well, we can simply console log context
to have a look into it.
So now I log it in increase so if I run, Add 10,
here is the log.
And we see we got this commit method, which we already saw,
but we see a couple of other interesting things.
Let's ignore route getters and route state for now,
but let's have a look at dispatch.
You can also dispatch a number action from inside an action.
This can be helpful if you're sending an HTTP request,
and if it succeeds, you wanna trigger a success action,
if you get an error,
you wanna trigger an error handling action.
Then you could have one action
that dispatches multiple other actions
in reaction to different results of HTTP request.
You can also access getters
in case your action needs some calculated value,
which would arrive in some getter.
And you can also directly tap into the state,
in case getting access to the getters might not be enough.
You should not manipulate
the state from inside the action though.
Always use a mutation for that.
So that's context and these are actions
and with state,
mutations,
actions and getters,
we get the core concepts vuex uses
to manage state application wide
which you can then use conveniently
from inside any component.