Now we know the core Vuex features,
we'll see it in a more realistic app in a second.
Before we go there though,
let's talk about a couple of utility features,
which make our life as a developer a bit easier.
And let's start with mappers.
In the counter, for example,
we have this counter computed property,
where we in the end,
just access our final counter getter.
So we have this code here just to get access to our getter.
Now, this is obviously not a lot of code,
but we're not doing anything besides
drilling into our store.
This is not horrible.
But in case you're not happy with that
Vuex has a helper which you can use.
You can import something from Vuex,
and that something is a mapGetters function.
You can use it inside of this computed object.
Instead of defining a computed property on your own,
you can call mapGetters here.
And this will return an object which you can then spread
with the free.spread operator
into your computed property object.
So mapGetters gives you an object, which we now merge
into the computed properties object.
Because the object mapGetters will give you
is an object full of computed properties,
which are defined automatically for you.
Well, now,
which computed properties do we get here?
Well, mapGetters takes an array as an argument.
And in here, you list all getter names as strings,
which you want to have
as computed properties in this component.
So in this case, for example, the final counter,
but of course, we could have multiple getters here.
And now this will give us a final counter
computed property in this component,
which automatically points at the finalCounter getter.
And with that,
we just need to change this here to finalCounter,
because that will be the computed property name.
And then if we reload,
it still works as before.
But now with mapGetters,
especially when you use multiple getters
in a given component,
you might be able to save some code
and not drill unnecessarily into the store all the time.
Now, we have something similar for state and mutations,
but you don't really use those in your components anyways.
So let's have a look at mapActions then,
which also exists to mapActions into your components.
How does this look like?
Let's say in change counter,
we don't manually want to define methods,
which in the end also just drill into the store
to dispatch some action here.
Instead, we could just as with getters,
import something from Vuex,
and that something here is mapActions.
Now, just as with mapGetters we call mapActions.
Now inside of methods though,
not inside of computed,
but inside of methods.
We call mapActions, like this.
And again get back an object which we merge
with the methods object by using the spread operator.
MapActions now also takes an array.
And now here we define all the action names,
which we wanna have as methods in this component.
So in this case, increment.
But of course, we could also add the increase action here
to map both actions to methods in this component.
And these methods will be created for you by mapActions.
That's the idea behind using it.
Now with that, we could add a second button
and on the first button, call increment.
That's the name of the method
which will be created for the increment action
and point at increase on the second button.
Now, of course here we need a payload.
And you can simply pass your payload as an argument then.
So in this case, an object with a value of 10.
Because we expect a payload in our store,
which will be an object,
which has a value property.
So that's why we pass an object with a value property here
simply as an argument to this automatically created method.
With that, we can change this button caption
maybe to 11 to tell it apart from the other button,
also change the value.
And with that,
now we got this new button, which also works.
So now we're also mapping actions
and this saves us the time to
add to those methods on our own.
There also is an alternative way of mapping actions,
in case you're not happy with the default names,
you can also call mapActions
and not pass an array to it but an object instead.
And then you can define the method names
you want to have in your component as keys.
For example, inc,
and then hold the action
which should be mapped to this method as a value.
So with that, we could go with inc and increase like this.
And with that, the increment action
would be mapped to an inc method,
increase would be mapped to an increased method.
And therefore we would have to call
increment by calling inc now,
increase stays increase,
because that's how I'm mapping it.
And with data of course,
that would still work if we try this.
So mapActions and mapGetters can be very, very useful.