Now let's say our application is growing
and besides this awesome counter feature,
we now also got a user auth component,
which deals with user authentication.
So in there we have a button where we say log in
and a button where we say log out
and it's depends on the off state,
which button we're going to show.
Now, of course we could manage this locally into component,
but again, authentication might matter
to a lot of parts of zap.
So we wanna manage it with UX and stat.
here I just got this template with the two buttons
and app view, I'm now going to import user off
from components user off dot view
and register this as a new component user off.
And therefore we can now use this
and I will create a new container here
to show it visually
that does this a different part of the app user off,
give this container a title prop off.
and make sure I only show the first container.
If we are authenticated.
Now at the moment we see those buttons,
but of course they don't do anything.
Well, that's something we can fix with UX.
And before I dive into the utility features
we have for managing bigger applications
with different kinds of state.
Here's a quick pause,
which you can use to add the functionality in UX,
to react to a log in and a log out click
to manage some is locked in state
to show just one of the two buttons
and to show or hide this base container
based on the off state.
So add a new state and all the getters mutations and actions
you might need to manage this is locked in state,
which can be true or false in the end.
Here's a chance for you to pause the video thereafter
we'll implement it together.
Where are your successful?
Let's do it together now.
So I wanna manage an off state.
So in my state and my story here, I will have-
is locked in state.
Of course, the name is up to you,
which initially is false let's say
now in order to change it, I want one or two mutations,
depending on how you decide the mutation,
I will add one mutation and name it set off
where I expect to get the state, of course, and the payload
and the payload will be important here
because it will tell me wherever I wanna set the off state
to authenticated or to not authenticated.
So here I said, state is locked in,
equal to payload is all let's say,
and that can be true or false.
Now this is just my approach.
You probably have a different one
and that might be fine as well.
It's just one way of doing it.
Now that's my mutation,
but we shouldn't necessarily call mutations
directly from inside components as you learned.
So I will add actions.
Now we could add a set of action,
which basically works like the mutation,
or we add two actions to mix things up a log in action
and a log out action.
Again, it's just my way of implementing this.
We get this context object and in log in,
I want to commit, set off.
That's the name of my mutation, this one,
and the payload will be an object here
where I said is off to true because it's the log in action
I want to set the user to logged in.
So dis is off property,
which I'm reading here in the mutation is true now.
And in log out, it's almost the same.
It's the same mutation which I commit, but it's false.
Now of course, these actions could be asynchronous
In reality, we are probably sending
some HTTP requests around,
but here I will not care about that.
I will keep it simple and keep it synchronous.
But in actions, of course,
we could also use asynchronous code as you learned.
So now we've got actions, mutations,
and a state what's missing a getter.
So I will add a new getter name is up to you.
I will name it user is authenticated.
And here we get our state and I will return.
State is logged in, which is true or false.
Now I have everything in the store
which you'll want to have there.
With that back and user off.
I want to wire up these buttons.
So I'll add my script part and now add my methods
for the actions that should be dispatched.
We could use map actions here,
or we add the manually totally up to you
to show all approaches, I will add the manually here,
add a log in and a log out method here.
And in log in, I will call this store dispatch log in
because log in was the action name I defined
and for log out it's the same,
but of course, with the log out action.
And now we can set up the click listeners,
trigger our log in method on the first button
and trigger log out on the second button.
With that we should be manipulating the state
now to reflect it i also want to listen to changes.
For example, here,
I only wanted to show one of the two buttons
at the same time.
For dav we can use computers to get access to the getters
either with map getters or by setting up
our own computed properties.
And here I'll add the is off computed property
where I returned this store getters
and I named together user is authenticated.
So that's the getter
I wanna access here and now is off,
is a computed property, which is true or false.
And with VF, all showed a login button is off,
is false because of the user is not authenticated.
I want to show the log in button
and I want to show the log out button
if we are authenticated.
And we can copy the computer property
into the app view file now here like this,
because I also need is off here to show
or hide this first base container.
So here with VF, I wanna show it if is off,
is true and hide it if it's false.
With that initially, we don't see it
because initially we're not logged in,
but if it click log in, we see it.
We can change everything, but if I click log out,
we hide it.
So that works.
And that's an extra piece of state managed.
Now that wasn't nice practice,
but I started this lecture mentioning
that our app could be getting bigger
and that we had more and more States to manage.
So here in this demo,
we now added at least a little bit of extra info
to our store.
View UX also gives us utility methods
and features when it comes to managing bigger stores
with different kinds of state inside of it.