A pretty nice feature provided by Vuex
as your store and your state and zone grows
is the possibility to set up modules.
To split your store into multiple modules.
You may only have one store per application,
but this store can be made up of multiple modules
To keep your code more manageable.
You automatically, if you don't set up any modules,
have one module, you could say,
the root module, the root state,
but you can then add as many other modules as you want.
For example one module for the counter
and another module for authentication.
Or you leave authentication in the root state,
in the root module and outsource the counter
into an extra module.
That would also be possible.
And that's what we're going to do here.
So here in main.js still,
I'm going to create a new counterModule,
which is an object, not a store,
just a regular JavaScript object.
But now it's an object with exactly the same features
as the object you pass to create store.
So it may have a state method.
It may have mutations, which is an object.
It may have actions, which is an object and getters.
So exactly the same features.
And in state, we of course also return an object.
But now we can move our counter state here
out of this global store, into this counterModule.
The same for the mutations related to our counter,
grab them and moved them here into mutations.
The same for the actions of course,
grab the counter related actions,
remove them from our global store,
and add them to actions here.
And you guessed it the same for our getters,
grab the counter getters,
remove them from the global store,
and add them to getters here.
With that, our global store, our main store, is way leaner.
It now has only the Authlogic left.
And we could put this logic into a separate module as well,
if we wanted to.
But how do we now get the module back into the store?
Well, createStore, this object here
also takes a modules option.
And modules is an object.
And here you now add all the modules
you wanna merge together into one store.
You give every module an identifier of your choice,
for example, counter or numbers
or whatever the name should be, this is up to you.
Here I'll go with numbers
and then point at the module object that should be merged.
In this case, the counter module.
Like this.
And now this will be merged into this store.
If you save this now, everything will work as before,
because by default, modules merged into a store
are all merged on the same level, so to say.
So if you merge a module into this store,
it is as if you would have to find
all the getters and so on
directly in the store,
as we had it before a couple of minutes ago.
That's why we can still dispatch all the actions
and use all the getters as before
even though we're now using a module.
And as mentioned
you can of course have as many modules as you want to.
But the idea of modules doesn't end here,
there's more we can do with that.