I mentioned that modules
are merged into your main store
on the same level as all the other things in the store.
You can change this behavior
and there is one place where
it actually already did change.
Let's say inside of a mutation,
inside of the increased mutation let's say ,
we console.log, our state.
So that's inside of the counter module now. .
Inside of the increased mutation.
Well, let's have a look what happens
if we click add 10.
This is the log here for our state.
And if we have a look at this,
we see something interesting.
Do you notice it?
We see the counter in there.
But there's one thing we don't see in here.
Our authentication state,
we don't see is locked in there,
this state.
Now I just said it would all be merged into one store.
So why don't we see,
is locked in here, in the state,
of our counter module then.
Because the state inside of a module,
is actually treated as a local state,
inside of the module.
Mutations actions and getters are global,
you can access them as before on the main store.
But the state is local to this module.
So anything you do on this state inside
of this module refers just
to this state module.
So for example, in a getter,
I would not be able to get the off status.
If I add new getter,
in the counter module,
getters object, TestAuth
and I try to return state is locked in,
this will not work.
If I now try to access TestAuth,
let's say in the UserAuth component,
we had a number of computed property is TestAuth,
where I returned is newly
added getter, TestAuth,
which I just added to the counter module.
If I access this here,
and I then simply output the value,
let's say in a paragraph, like this.
So if I output this newly added computed property,
which uses the new getter here,
this will not work.
First of all, though,
I have to fix an error,
in main.js in the new TestAuth getter.
Of course, I should accept state
as a argument in order to use it.
But even with that,
you notice there's nothing below the button.
And if we change it, there's still nothing
because it doesn't find is locked
in the getter here.
In the state of this getter.
Because this getter is in the counter module.
And as As I mentioned, the state is local.
So here we only have access
to the state that belongs to this module.
So that's important to keep in mind.
And it's similar for actions
and mutations there in context,
for example, where you learned earlier,
that you all have access to the state,
in case you needed it,
you also only have access
to the state of this module.
Now in case you need to work around that,
there are ways though.
For example, in getters inside of a module,
you now don't just get state
and getters as before,
but you can now also get access
to a root state and root getters.
And you might remember,
that we saw similar properties
on this context object earlier in the module.
This is your way of getting access
to the main state,
the main getters of the entire store instead
of just the state of this specific module.
So this is your fallback way
of getting access to state that's not part
of this module, in case you needed.
Typically, though, of course,
inside of a module,
you tend to just work with the state
that belongs to the module.
So you probably don't need this too often,
but there can definitely be situations
where you do need it.