Now besides this local state,
you can also make the entire module local.
You can make it name spaced, as it's called,
to make sure that multiple modules
are clearly separated from each other.
Now why might you wanna do that?
Well, as you're application grows,
you could of course have name clashes.
You might be using the same getter or the same action name
in different modules of the same store.
It's not the case here,
but if for whatever reason
we had a login action here, in the counter module,
that would be clashing with the login action
we got in our main store.
Because at the moment, besides the state,
everything is merged together into one object basically.
So in bigger apps, you could have such clashes
and to avoid that you can name space modules.
You do that by adding an extra option,
inside of your object here,
and that's the name spaced option
which you can set to true.
If you add name spaced true,
you tell vuex that now the entire module
and not just the state should be kinda detached
from the rest of the store.
If you do that though, you will now notice
that our getters and our action dispatchers no longer work.
Because now these actions and getters
are no longer available on the main store.
Instead now we have to access them
by specifying the correct name space.
And how does it work and what is the name space?
Well, the name space is this key you assigned
for adding the module in this modules object to your store.
So in my case, numbers.
That's the name space off the counter module.
And we now need to use this name space
to work with actions, getters and so on
inside of this module.
Now here's how that will work.
In favorite value, I access my normalized counter getter.
Now you don't access dot normalized counter
but instead a special property name,
which contains a special character,
in which you hence have to access
with this square bracket notation.
You pass in a string here, your property name as a string,
and this property name is now made up of
the old property name, so normalized counter,
but prior to that, in front of that,
you have your name space.
So in my case, numbers.
So you have numbers and then a slash in between.
Might look strange
but this is now the property name of the normalized counter,
name space, slash and then your getter name,
action name, whatever it is.
In this case, it's a getter.
And that's when we now see at least one counter here,
it's this normalized counter,
which I'm outputting like this.
Now if you are using map getters,
you pass a first argument to map getters,
which is your name space, in this case numbers,
and then there after you still add your array
with the getter names as before.
So with that if we save this,
the second counter is back as well.
So name space as a first argument,
second argument is then still your array of getters
inside of that name space.
And the same of course for the other parts.
Map actions takes name space as a first argument
and then your action names as before.
And in app vue, here we're at dispatch,
where I dispatch manually actually,
the type is now numbers slash increase.
So again, name space slash and then the action name.
With that, all the buttons work again now
and now we're using this name space in the future
to detach our module and to make sure
that we don't have any name clashes,
which we of course don't have here,
but which you in bigger apps definitely could have.
And with that, we're merging a module with our main store,
we still have some global state in there,
the authentication state,
but we can absolutely combine it like this
and we're even name spacing our module
to make sure that we don't accidentally
trigger an action inside of this module
when we actually wanted to trigger a global action,
for example.