With that, we are almost done
with the basics, but there is one, maybe obvious problem,
the main JS file is huge.
It has the entire store and even an extra module in there,
and it might work for this app,
but even here, it's a lot of code.
In bigger apps,
I definitely don't want to have that all in main JS.
Instead, just as with rooting,
you typically create extra files for that.
You could start with a store JS file
and outsource your entire store into that.
That might be a good start.
So let's grab the module and this store,
cut it all from main JS and instead, add it in store JS.
And then also, of course,
cut the create store import,
go to store JS
and add the import here
because we use create store in his file,
and then in the end, export the store as a default
so that we can import it in main JS.
Import store from store JS
and with that, everything should be working again.
Yes. But this is just a start.
Store JS is still huge and in bigger apps with many modules,
this quickly becomes a super large file.
Therefore, typically, we go even further than that.
Often, you add a separate folder named store,
and in there, you then have your index JS file,
which holds your main store creation logic,
then you have separate files for actions and mutations,
possibly all the for getters, if you want to.
And then we create separate sub folders
for all the modules we might have,
like the counter module.
And then there again, you could have a index JS file,
actions JS ends on to merge things together.
Now I'm going to split it like this
to show you how this could work,
I will also be honest for this demo,
of course, that's all overkill.
But with Deb, we have a bunch of files
and now let's see how we split the code into those files.
In store JS here,
I will grab from my main store,
this whole logic to create a store, including the export.
And I will cut that and add it to index JS in store.
So not index inside of counter, but index inside of store.
I'll also grab the import here of create store
and add that to index JS in the store folder.
Now, I grab my mutations,
in this case, the one root mutation I have here,
grab this object here and in the mutations JS file,
I will simply export this object now.
Again, this is overkill.
Just having one object in a file,
there would be nothing wrong with having that in index JS.
I'll just show you the ultimate solution
for very big apps here.
So with that, I'm exporting my mutation object
and re-import that in index JS then.
Import mutations from mutations JS.
Maybe also named as root mutations
to make it clear that these are the mutations
that influence our root state here.
And I assign root mutations to mutations then.
Same for actions.
You can grab the actions, object actually,
go to the actions JS file in the store folder,
export it as a default, like this,
and back in index JS,
we then import the root actions from actions JS.
And then assign root actions here to actions.
At the same, if you want,
for getters, grab the getters,
export them into getters JS file, like that.
And back at index JS,
I import my root getters from ./gettersjs
and assigned root getters to getters.
And now, this is a very lean file.
The state stays in here by the way.
Now for the modules.
In store JS, I still have the counter module.
I now grab this code,
so that store JS is empty
and hence we can delete the file, of course,
and go to the counter folder in the store folder,
and there, in index JS, I paste it in.
And I export this entire object
as a default simply like this.
I leave namespaced here, I'll leave state here,
but I grabbed the mutations object
and move that to the mutations JS folder
in this counter sub folder
and exports that in here.
And then again, in index JS,
but now in index JS inside of the counter,
I import counter mutations from ./mutationsjs
and assign those here to mutations.
Same thing for actions.
Grab the object, go to actions JS,
export them here as a default,
like this, and in index JS, import them.
Import counter actions from actions JS
and assign them here to actions.
And last but not least,
we can do the same thing here for getters.
Grab the getters object,
add a getters JS file inside of the counter,
export our getters object like this,
and then import it.
Of course, you can tweak the file names, by the way,
you don't have to use these exact file names,
I'm just following some convention here,
but you could also use a different file name here.
So here I then have to counter getters from getters JS.
So I'll assign them here.
And now, this all split up,
I'm exporting my module here,
so now in index JS here, in the store folder,
I can import my counter module
from counter index JS.
And now assign my counter module to numbers.
And now in main JS, we no longer import store from store JS,
but from the store folder enter there the index JS file.
And with all that out of the way, it works as before,
but now with a different folder structure.
Now, if you want that structure, know that it's up to you,
but it is one option.
You can also change this a bit more.
If you had multiple modules,
you could also add a modules folder here
and move counter into modules
and then have other modules like a products module folder,
if you had some, in the modules folder as well.
To make it clearer that you manage your modules in here,
you then just need to adjust the import
and import counter module from modules counter index.
And as I mentioned before,
you can also tweak the file names
so that they make sense to you.
You could also split action, getters,
mutations and so on, for the root state,
but not for the modules.
It's up to you, which structure you want,
I'm just showing you one possible approach
to make sure that you have small maintainable files
instead of one super big file,
where you then have to search for things all the time.
And therefore, this here,
is one possible way of building this.
It is overkill for this demo,
but of course it shows you what you can do in bigger apps.