So now that we've learned
the basics about Vuex, I want you to practice it
in at least a little bit of a bigger application.
You'll find this application attached,
as always, NPM install, and NPM run serve, are your friends.
And we've got this very simple demo online shop there.
Got a few products, we can add them to a cart,
and you see this cart counter increases
every time I add a product.
We can then view our cart, see the cart's total here,
see our items here.
And we can remove items from the cart,
and everything updates.
We also got this login button,
which doesn't do anything at the moment, actually,
even though it should,
but here we're facing some limitations
by a provide and inject.
If you update something which is not an array,
or not an object, like in this case,
where I'm in the end updating, is logged in,
which is a bullion,
the changes to that will not be reflected
back to the components that inject that status.
We don't have to worry too much about this though,
because your goal is a different one anyways.
I want you to try to migrate this entire state,
which is managed application-wide, to Vuex.
So, the products
and the, is locked, in state, also the cart.
Set up Vuex in whichever way you want
using modules, or not using modules,
using namespaces, or not using them.
And try this on your own as a practice.
From the next lecture on,
we'll migrate this together
so that you see my possible solution.
This will be a great practice,
and hopefully helps you understand
how you really use Vuex in projects.