So did you succeed?
Let's try this together.
For this, I will add a store folder here
and in there add an index JS file.
I will also already add a modules folder
because I will definitely use some modules.
Looking at our state here in App.vue,
I think we have three main kinds of state,
we have the products,
we have the cart,
we could also treat products and cart as one state
to shop state so to say.
And we then have isLoggedIn
which is the authentication state.
Now there will be different ways of solving this.
But I will put isLoggedIn into my root state so to say,
so not into a module,
but then I'll work with a product
and with a cart module.
And therefore in modules we can create two sub folders,
products and cart and there is nothing wrong with it
but I will use a different approach,
all instead at a cart.js and a products.js file.
That is not what I showed you in the last lectures.
I am aware of this,
but that's also an alternative.
I don't want to split my mutations and so on
in separate files here,
instead, I wanna have them in one file,
but still separate files for different modules.
So that's an alternative to having multiple module folders,
where in every module folder,
you then have separate actions and mutations files,
which you could also do though,
just to make this clear.
But with all of that,
I'm going to npm install vuex,
so that we have this available here in this project
and bring up the development server thereafter.
And in index.js,
in the store folder.
I will then import create,
store from vuex.
And then call create store here to create a store,
which I then export as a default.
This store text and object
and we're going to configure the store here soon.
Since I'm exporting the store,
we can already import it in main.js though,
here import store from store.js.
And besides using the router,
we will now also use the store.
But now back to the store.
I mentioned that I want to have some global state
the authentication status and then module state
for my different modules for products and for the cart.
Let's maybe start with products.
For that we're exporting an object in here,
which will be our module object
and set up state which is a method
it returns an object which defines our state.
And in here,
I want to have my products array,
which currently is in App.vue.
So we can grab this entire array from App.vue,
cut it,
and go to products.js.
And add it here products is now this array.
In App.vue,
we therefore no longer provide products.
And we remove products from the data property.
Now for products I actually have no mutations
and actions because we never change products
in this example app.
They offer of course,
this is not really state which we need to manage.
It's just some static data,
which we also could export and import like this.
But to practice vuex,
I'll put it into some state
even though that is state which will never change.
There is at least one thing which we need though.
And that's a getter.
Because we shouldn't directly access state,
we should use getters for that.
So here I'll add a getter,
also named products maybe,
which gets the local state of this module.
And we're at then simply returns state products like this.
So it's not a super fancy getter,
it's not doing a lot of things,
but hey, it's better than nothing.
That's it for the product module already.
So in index.js,
where I create the main store,
I can import my products module
from modules/products.js,
and then add the modules key here.
And add let's say,
prods as a namespace if we want to use namespaces later,
otherwise this is just required,
technically but has no effect.
And register products module under the name space.
Now currently it is not name spaced.
Currently it will be merged globally.
So together will be available just like that.
But I wanna make it name spaced
so that we all to practices.
Therefore, we can add name spaced as an option
in the exported module object and set this to true.
And now prods will be the namespace for this module.
Let's continue with the cart.
Here in the cart.
I of course want to have my carts data.
So we can cut this from App.vue,
but also later to methods that's changed the cart.
So in cart.js in the store modules folder,
we export our module object,
add our state,
and here I return an object which has this cart.
And actually,
since this is an entire module for just the cart,
we can also flatten this and just add items total
and quantity as separate keys in this overall module state.
Now here, we will need mutations as well,
because in App.vue I have two methods for changing the cart,
add product to cart,
and remove product from cart.
So I can grab these methods,
cut them from App.vue,
and add them to cart.js here
in mutations,
but we of course have to tweak those mutations now,
because now they don't just get an argument
and do something.
Instead, they now need two arguments,
the current state which they should change,
and the payload.
The payload can then hold all the extra data
that might be needed.
Here for example,
I expect to get some product data describing the product
that should be added to the cart.
So to make sure that the rest of the code works,
I will add a constant named product data
because that's what's getting used down there.
And expect to get that on my payload.
Let's say payload.product.
We have to provide this payload later.
So we can of course expect any data we want.
We just have to make sure that this data exists later.
And then we have to update the state.
So here for example,
it's not this cart items find something.
It's state items,
because items is now a property in our local state
of this module.
Here it's also State.items.quantity.
Assuming that items in the cart do have a quantity field,
and they do because this is how we add items to a cart,
we set up products ID, title, image price
and quantity for that product in the cart.
And this should all continue to work
because this doesn't use the state or anything like that.
But then here in the end,
we access state items and push our new item.
And we access state.quantity and state.total.
So the other state properties which we added here.
And that's the add product to cart mutation.
Now for remove product from cart,
we also get a state and a payload.
And again,
prodId was received previously as an argument.
So I will add a constant prodId,
and extract this productId let's say
from the payload object.
And then again,
we search state.items here.
And here, it's all those state.items
and we manipulate state items, state quantity
and state total.
Now we get the mutations in place.
Now we learned that we shouldn't directly commit mutations
from inside components.
So I'm going to add some actions as well.
And here I'll add an add to cart action
and remove from cart action.
And add to cart receives this context
and maybe also a payload.
And the same here for removed from cart.
And in here I then simply commit,
add product to cart
and forwards the payload to the mutation.
And for the other action we commit remove product from cart.
So that would be context commit,
remove product from cart and forward to payload
And with that we just have to add some getters now.
Getters that allow us to get access to various pieces
of information about the cart.
And here, we can get creative.
Previously we shared the overall cart.
And then in different components,
we extracted different features.
For example in the user card page,
I extracted the cart total like this.
In the header,
I'm extracting
the card quantity here.
Now we can define some getters for that in our module,
we can have a cart item scatter,
which gives us the overall cart items.
A cart total getter,
which gives us the total sum and a cart quantity getter,
or since this is all in the cart module already
just name this items or products or whatever you want,
total sum maybe and quantity.
And then here return state which we get
in a getter automatically state items
here in total sum return state,
total.
And here return
state quantity.
And now we can go to index.js in the store folder,
import the cart module from ./modules/cart.js
and add this to our modules here as well.
And I'm going to namespace this cart
and save to cart module in there.
Now with that we're not done
but we made an important first step.
Now let's continue with cleaning up
and with using the store in the next lectures.