So let's continue now.
For one, I get an error
that store.js wasn't found in main.js.
Yes, because I'm importing from store/index.js.
That would be correct.
So make sure you have this import set up correctly.
But besides that, we now also need
to wire up our store with the different components
and clean up the App.vue component.
In there, I don't want to provide anything anymore
because I don't want to manage any data in there anymore.
We still have isLoggedIn in there
but we're going to remove this soon as well,
just as these methods.
For the moment, let's ignore them though.
But let's now start using our modules.
Now, one thing I forgot
is in cart.js in this cart module,
I also want to namespace this.
So set namespaced to true in here.
And now let's use it in different parts of this app.
For that, we can start in ProductsList.
Here, I previously injected products.
We're no longer going to do that.
Instead, I now want to get access to Vuex.
So we can add a computed property.
And either use the map gathers helper
or add our own computed property,
which is what I will do.
Maybe name it products
and return this.$store
and now let's see.
In the products module, I have the products getter
but keep in mind that this module
is namespaced and the namespace is prods.
So what we should access here in ProductsList.vue
in the pages folder
is .getters and then it's prods/products.
And this gives us a products computed property now,
which we can use to look for all the products.
Now, we currently can't preview this
because we've still got errors on the page
but this should work.
Now, let's fix the other errors.
Let's make sure we also get the cart data
and the header correctly.
It's no longer cart.qty
but let's say cartQuantity as this like this
as a computed property in the future with this name.
And we no longer inject anything here
but instead, we add computed,
add this cartQuantity computed property,
which I just referred to in the template.
And in there, return this.$store
and now here, we also namespaced cart.
So we access this store.getters
and then use the cart namespace, which is cart
in the index.js file in the store folder.
So access cart/
and then the getter I'm interested in
in my case is the quantity here.
So that's /quantity.
Let's save that.
And if you now reload,
you should see products again
and at least see cart.
You can't go to cart or you'll not see anything there
and the app breaks
but at least the first pieces are working now.
So let's now work on the other parts.
In UserCart, I'm interested in the cart.items.
So here I'll change this and expect cartItems,
which I soon will add as a computed property.
And I also use the cartTotal here.
We no longer inject the cart here.
Instead, the computed property for cartTotal
will now refer to this.$store.getters
and then cart/,
what was it?
It was totalSum,
so refer to totalSum here.
And add another computed property called cartItems,
or whatever you are using here in the v-for loop.
And here, return this.$store.getters cart/
and then it was products I think.
Yes, products was the getter name.
With that, if we go to cart,
this also works again.
Now let's make sure we can also add things
to the cart and remove them.
So for that, we need to dispatch actions.
So for the actions,
in the components folder, products, ProductItem,
I got the button to add something to the cart.
Previously, I injected addProductToCart for that.
Now we can delete this
and instead, call this.$store.dispatch
and then dispatch a function,
which is named addProductToCart.
No, sorry, that's the mutation,
which is named addToCart, that's the action.
So dispatch this
but it's namespaced, so it's cart/addToCart.
And now, of course, this object here is the payload,
which I want to transmit.
And actually here, we have to be careful.
In the module, the Vuex module,
we forward that payload to the mutation
and in the addProductToCart mutation,
I expect to get a product key on my payload,
which then has all the fields I tried to extract.
Now, if I just pass the entire object like this
as a payload, there is no product in there.
So we either nest this data here
into another object under the key product
in this payload object
or we pass the payload like this
and adjust our logic in the mutation
to simply set payload as we get it equal
to productData from which we then extract id and so on.
And that's what I'm going to do
because it means less code changes.
Now, in a CartItem, components, cart, CartItem,
we got the logic for removing an item.
Previously, I injected this.
No longer needed.
So let's get rid of it.
And instead here, I want to simply call this.$store.dispatch
cart/ and then the action name is removeFromCart
and on the payload,
which we want in the mutation,
I expect to get a productId field in the object
which I get.
So in CartItem, I dispatch cart/removeFromCart
and pass an object as a payload,
which has a productId field,
which points at this prodId,
which is this prop which holds the productId.
With that, theoretically, hopefully,
we should be able to add and remove items.
And you'll see, the badge here updates
as I add items to the cart.
If I go to the cart,
the total looks good.
We see the cart items
and if I remove them,
the total and dispatch updates.
So that seems to work.
Now, I get a warning regarding isLoggedIn
but we'll fix this soon.
The main thing here is that we now migrated the products
and the cart functionality.
Now, to score some bonus points here,
we could actually also change our addToCart logic.
In ProductItem, I'm current passing the entire product data.
We could argue that all the product data
is already in our store right here in products.js.
Here we've got all the products.
So the only thing which we really have to pass here
to addToCart should be the ID of the product.
So let's do that.
Let's get rid of the image and title and price here.
Let's delete it
and just forward the ID on the id field.
And now in the cart, in addProductToCart,
I get my payload,
which no longer holds all the product data.
Instead, now here I just get my prodId
by accessing the id field
on the payload.
That's all I get here.
And this is, of course, not enough.
Now, the problem is because everything is namespaced
and the state inside of a module is local anyways,
the state we're getting here is just this state.
It has no information about the products.
Therefore, we should actually get this product ID
in the action,
in the addToCart action
because in here in this context,
we actually also do get access
to other parts of the Vuex store,
not just to this module.
Here, on context, we will have our rootState object,
which has access to the root state
but even more important than that,
we've got access to rootGetters.
And on the rootGetters, we can get access
to other namespaced getters as well.
Namely here to my products getter
in the products module.
How?
Simply by accessing square brackets,
then the namespace name, which in this case is prods.
For the products
and then the getter name, which is products here
in the products module.
With that, we actually get our products
and now we can filter out the product with this ID.
So now we can get our product
by searching products with the find method
for the product where the prod.id
is equal to the prodId we got here.
This is a built-in method
for searching all items in an array
and when this function returns true,
we got the item we wanna have
and it then returns this item.
And then it's this product,
which we can pass as a second argument
as a payload to our commit method here.
So now we receive the entire product in this mutation
and payload therefore again
is the entire product data.
If we now save this,
hopefully adding to cart still works.
And this does look good
and we still see our data here
but now we are getting it differently,
a bit leaner, leveraging actions
and not passing all the data around as a payload,
at least not when we dispatch it inside of our component.
It's up to you which approach you prefer
but this is a common scenario.
Therefore, I also wanted to show this to you here.
With that, the only thing that's left is the login state.