Now lets finish this up
by migrating is logged in.
Currently we're managing it in App Vue
and that's of course not the goal.
Instead, I'll manage this as a route state,
which is not in a module,
but which is managed ind the store itself
though, of course you could put it
into a module if you want it to.
But with that we return an object here
and then there we got is logged in,
which initially is false in our main store.
With that in App Vue,
we can entirely get rid of data.
Now I got these two methods,
which I will now also cut
and hence, we can remove methods here
and add them as mutations instead.
So here we got the mutations
and in login we get to the state
and we change state is logged in
and set it to true.
In logout we do the opposite.
Now we also need actions as you learned.
So here I will also add login and logout actions
and we get our context here
and then context commit login here.
And in logout, we do the same with the log out mutation.
And then we can add a getter
is authenticated could be together name,
the name is up to you of course.
Here we also get our state
and then we return state is logged in,
which is true or false.
Now we can wire up the rest of the app.
In App Vue we're not using authentication,
but in the header we are.
Here I got login and logout buttons
and I'm using the is logged in instead
to show our height and extra menu item.
So to make that all work,
I'll add methods here
to wire up those buttons
and add a login method,
which will trigger this store,
this patch, and then log in.
We got no namespace here
because this is a route action directly in the store.
Now save the thing for log out
of course with a different action being dispatched.
And in computed I will add is logged in computed property,
which points at the this store
is authenticated getter we just added.
So that is this gather.
It's a global getter, not namespace,
which is why we access it like this.
This year should be at click of course not at logout.
This was a mistake on my side.
It was fixed in your attachment already though,
but make sure you have click listers on those buttons.
And then this works.
The admin page doesn't allow us to do much,
but we can go there.
Now we stay there if you log out,
but it's not about that at the moment.
Instead, this is about Vue.js
and you now hopefully have a good understanding
of how it works
and how you may add it to your projects.