So that's it for this module.
You learned what Vuex is,
why you might want to use it, and how it works.
It's all about having that central state,
which you manipulate through actions
and mutations and which you get through getters.
You learned how to set all of it up,
and how to manage more complex states
with multiple modules and different folder structures.
You also learned about the map getters
and map actions helpers.
Now Vuex in a nutshell isn't too complex.
Yes, you need to write some extra code to manage state,
but their after you have a clearly defined flow,
a clear structure for managing state.
And as you can absolutely see in this demo
and the demo before,
sharing state and manipulating it from anywhere
in your app in a clearly defined way is super easy
with Vuex in the end.
And that's why Vuex can be very helpful in bigger projects
and why it can make managing state a breeze.
It's much nicer then provide and eject
at least in my opinion, in bigger projects,
and can therefore definitely help you write any application
of any size you want.