We got those important basics now.
We learned how Vue generally works
and how we can output content on the screen,
how we can react to user input.
Now, with the knowledge we got thus far,
we'll be able to build a lot,
but there are important missing pieces.
And in this module,
we're basically going to dive into those pieces.
We'll learn how to render content conditionally.
So how to render some parts on the page
only if certain conditions are met,
and how to output lists of content.
For example, a list of course goals, a list of products,
which should be rendered dynamically
and new items should be rendered when the list grows.
Items should be removed if the list shrinks.
This is what we'll dive into it in this module.
Specifically we'll therefore dive into
how to render content conditionally.
So which tools Vue gives us to make sure
that certain text is only shown,
if we got no products to be rendered, for example.
We'll then learn how to output lists of data.
So how to output a list of goals
or a list of products, for example.
And we'll have a first look behind the scenes of Vue
and learn about one important optimization
or one important feature
when it comes to outputting lists of data.
But let's get there step by step
and let's get started with conditional content.