There are a couple of things that are worth knowing
about v-if. For one, you can have any expression in here
that deals a truthy or falsy value,
just as in a regular if statement.
In here, you can also check whatever you want,
and it will be interpreted as truthy or falsy
by JavaScript. You can, of course,
also combine conditions here with end, or or, that works.
You can also point at a computed property,
you can point at a data property,
you can execute a method here
as long as that method returns a truthy or falsy value.
That is all possible.
But besides that, which should be fairly obvious,
since it's really just like if in your HTML code,
so it works like if in JavaScript just in HTML.
But besides that, there also is another directive
you can use in conjunction with v-if. Because, of course,
we don't just want to show this paragraph conditionally,
we also want to show the list conditionally.
And, we only want to show this list if we do have goals.
That means we can add v-if if on that too,
and we can check if goals length is greater than zero.
Because only if it's greater than zero,
only then we want to show this list.
If we save and reload,
we therefore only see the paragraph initially.
But if I then add a goal,
the paragraph disappears. And instead,
we see the list with that dummy goal initially.
This works and there's nothing wrong with it.
But, essentially, this is a little bit like the else case
in a JavaScript if statement, right?
And, there you can also have else and even else if.
That's all supported in JavaScript.
And, Vue also supports this in HTML with its directives.
Instead of repeating v-if here, which you can do.
But instead of doing that, you can also specify v-else.
The only important thing is that v-else has to be used
on an element that comes directly after
an element with v-if on it.
You can't have another element in between.
If we have a paragraph in between,
that would not work.
V-else needs to be used on a direct neighbor element
of the element which has v-if.
This works, an element in between breaks it.
But with that I can reload
and get the same behavior as before.
Now, sometimes you also have scenarios
where you have multiple possible conditions.
And, that's why you'll also have a v-else-if condition,
where you can check if goals length is, let's say,
greater than zero. And, then you could have another element
with v-else in case that's not met,
and that's not met with your fallback content.
In this case, that would kick in for a negative length,
which, of course, can't occur,
but I'm just showing this as an example.
So, v-if, v-else-if and v-else can be used to control
which parts of your HTML code
are really showing up on the final page.
And, I want to emphasize
that it's not just about showing and hiding stuff.
It's really about including those elements in the DOM
or not including them.
It's really about attaching and detaching.
If you inspect this paragraph,
you, of course, see that this paragraph is there,
but there is no list below it.
Now, if I add a goal, like finish the course,
watch what happens when I press the button.
Watch here on the right side.
You see, now the unread list was added,
and the paragraph completely disappeared.
Now, because of v-if and v-else combined,
by the way, Vue also doesn't need the place holder anymore.
But that's just a side note.
So, that's v-if,
and it's very, very, very useful
for showing content conditionally,
which turns out is something you'll need
in a lot of applications you're going to build.
And, this is how easy it is to implement it with Vue.