Now there is an alternative to v-if.
There is nothing wrong with v-if,
but there also is v-show,
v-show does not work together with v-else or v-else-if.
It only works stand-alone
and therefore if you have multiple alternatives,
you really need to use multiple v-shows.
That's one difference.
But what does v-show do then?
It seems to be more complicated.
It doesn't have to simplifications with v-else
and v-else-if.
So, why would we use v-show?
There's one important difference regarding its behavior.
If I reload, we don't see a huge difference.
It works in the same way,
but let me reload again and let's inspect this.
And then you'll notice a difference.
The paragraph is there,
but so is the unordered list.
And the only difference is that the unordered list is hidden
because its display style is set to none
and that's the difference.
V-if really removes and adds elements from and to the DOM.
So it really impacts which elements are part of the DOM.
v-show on the other hand,
just hides and show items with CSS.
Now, which approach is better?
Showing and hiding with CSS means
that you don't have to add and remove elements all the time,
which can cost performance,
adding and removing elements can cost performance.
On the other hand,
it also means that you have a bunch of elements in your DOM,
which you don't really need at the moment,
which also is not ideal.
Therefore, as a rule of thumb,
you should typically use v-if and only fall back to v-show
if you have an element,
which visibility status changes a lot.
So, if you have like a button that toggles an element
and it's switching between visibility
and being hidden all the time,
that is when you might want to consider v-show
in other cases use v-if.
And that's why I'm going to switch back to it.
But I wanna show you, v-show as an alternative
because of course it is important to know that as well
for situations where you have content
that switches a lot between being visible and being hidden.