So we learned about v-if,
which is great for showing content conditionally,
but we all have an array of content here,
potentially we have multiple goals,
and it would be nice if we could output those actual goals
which we store in our view app,
instead of this dummy goal goal.
Well, of course view has us covered for that, as well.
We now need to output a list of content,
and that's also something you commonly have to do in apps,
consider lists of products, users' to do's,
lists are everywhere in web apps.
And therefore, of course, view gives us a tool
for working with lists of data
and outputting repeated content.
Here we wanna repeat this list item
with different content for all the goals we have.
And view has another directive for that.
The v-for directive.
And you might see a pattern here.
We have v-if, just as we have if statements in JavaScript.
And we have v-for just as we have for loops in JavaScript
for dealing with repeated code.
And it's the same logic here.
V-for is there to help us output content that's repeated.
So for example here, we wanna output the same list item
over and over again for every goal which we have.
And we can do this by setting up value to v-for,
and between those double quotes,
as always, with those view features,
we can execute a JavaScript expression.
And here we can point at goals,
which is our data property that holds the goal's array.
But not just like this,
instead in a for loop in JavaScript,
we have something like const goal of goals.
This is how a for loop could look like in JavaScript.
It looks quite similar in view.
Here, we wanna go through all goals,
but of course we also wanna get hold of each goal,
so that we can take that goal's text for example,
and output it between the list item text.
That's why the v-for syntax looks a bit different,
we have goal in goals.
Goal of goals also is supported but you should use
goal in goals.
Which is a bit different
than the standard for loop in JavaScript
but you just have to memorize it like this,
v loop, through an array, with the in keyword
when using v-for and now this name here,
goal in this case,
is totally up to you.
You can name it G or GO or hello, whatever you want.
I'm going to go for goal,
because this will hold every goal in goals,
for every iteration v-for does for us.
And v-for will go through all the goals
and give us access to every goal here.
And why is that useful?
Well, our goals are just strings, in the end.
We just add whatever the user entered,
which is a string, to goals.
So goals is an array full of strings.
So every goal here is also just a string,
enhanced here between
the opening of the closing list item tack
we can use double curly braces
to output goal like this.
And this now has to be goal here,
if you used goal here.
If you used hello here, for whatever reason,
it has to be hello here, as well.
But I'm using goal so let's revert to that.
Now what this does, is, it tells view
that it should repeat this list item
for all the goals in goals,
so render as many list items as we have goals
in the goals array,
and give us access to every goal,
and then inside, and that's really important,
inside of the v-for controlled element,
so between the opening and closing tags of that element,
and also on the element itself,
we have access to that goal.
We don't have access to goal
outside of the list item element here.
So if I tried to output goal here,
in another paragraph,
which is not inside of the list item here,
that would not work.
And I guess that makes a lot of sense.
In regular JavaScript,
if you have a for loop,
even though it looks a bit different,
if you have for loop here, you also can't use this
constant outside of the for loop.
And it's the same with v-for.
So now just we'll repeat as many list items
as we need for all our goals,
and output the goal text in our case
between the list item tags.
So for now I've saved it, and reload this page,
we can add finish the course,
click add goal, and here is our goal.
We can also add master view,
click add goal, and here's the second goal.
And you see that this list grows with every new item we add.
And this is v for and why it matters
because now we can really build a dynamic application
where we render lists of content and also update that list
when the content changes.
And view does that updating for us,
and it also does it in a smart way.
If you inspect the list item here with the depth tools,
I mentioned before that the parts
which are updated in the DOM, will flash.
So if I add a new goal,
watch what happens here on the right to those first
two existing list items.
You see?
They did not flash.
Only the third one, the new one did.
And that is how view updates the DOM,
it does it in a very efficient way,
leaving the unchanged list items alone,
and only adding a new list item,
which, of course, is great for performance.
It would be bad if view would re-render the entire list
with every new item that we add.
This would not be good for performance
and thankfully view doesn't do it.
It's just important to be aware of such things
because that helps you understand a bit more
how view works under the hood.
Now let's dig a bit deeper into v-for.