We're using v-for with an array like this.
And that is honestly also probably
the most common way of using it.
But v-for has a couple of interesting variations.
For one, you can, for example,
pull out more than just the array item.
You can also get the index off the item in the array.
And doing so is simple, you just wrap your item,
which you're pulling out off the array,
with every iteration between parentheses,
and then add a comma.
And now you can add a second item here,
give it any name you want,
like index or idx and going forward.
Index here, and this will be the index off this item.
So that's another syntex supported by Vue,
getting not just the item itself,
but also its index with this notation.
And now here we could, for example, add a dash
and that's not special Vue syntex, that's just a dash.
And then again add interpolation to all the output index,
if we want to.
I'll quickly reformat that.
And if I saved it and reload,
if I start adding goals, you see here,
this has the index zero because it was
the first goal I added, master Vue has index one and so on.
So that can also be useful in cases
where you need the index.
Now you can also loop through more than just arrays.
You can also loop through objects.
Now here, goals, is an array, and you will probably most
often loop through arrays,
but in case you had a different scenario,
you can also loop through objects.
I'll quickly add a second onward list here
with a second list item with a second v-for.
And here I wanna loop for an object,
where I have my name and my age.
You could of course create that
in your data property in the Vue app,
I'm doing it here in HTML, quick and dirty.
But of course, if this would be a real app
and a real example, you might wanna move that
into your JavaScript code.
But now we have this object here,
and I wanna to loop through it and it's properties.
v-for supports that as well.
Again, with the in keyword, and here
I had to reload by the way, that's why it's empty
on the right again,
but here you can now get your different values stored
in the different properties and output those between
the list text with interpolation again.
And if you saved it and reload, you'll see Max and 31,
because these are the values of those properties.
Now, just how you can get the
index for looping through arrays,
you can also get the key name
when looping through objects,
by wrapping this into parentheses,
and then the second element you can pull out of
this loop is the key.
So that here, you could also output
the key with interpolation, then maybe a colon,
which has just plain text and then the value.
And now you would see name, colon, Max, age, colon, 31.
And if you needed it,
you could also get the index here,
though of course, that will probably rarely be the case,
but that is also supported here.
So you can also get the index just by adding it
as a third element here, if you're looping through objects.
We don't really need it here for this demo app,
but of course it is important for you
to be aware of what v-for can do.
And well, looping through objects
is one of the things it that can do.
I'm nonetheless going to comment this out
because we don't need it here,
but you should be aware of it.
You should be aware of the fact
that v-for can be used with object as well,
and that you can retrieve the value or the value
and the key or value, key and index if you needed that.
One other thing you can do with v-for,
is you can loop through a range of numbers.
You can also use it like this,
and then output the numbers one to 10, for example.
So whenever you need something like this,
looping through a range of numbers
by simply using v-for with in,
and then some number, that also works.
Again, not something we need here,
but something you should be aware of, since well,
that is also something you can do with v-for,
And who knows, maybe you need exactly
this behavior in your next application.
With that however, I'm going to comment this out
and I'm going back to our demo application
with the course goals here, we're now able to add goals
and to output them here in our list, and that's great.
Now let's also make sure that we can remove items
from the list to make this truly dynamic.