So, how could we remove items,
from this list here?
Well, we have our list item,
which is repeated for every new Goal.
It's still our regular HTML element though,
even though we're using before on it.
And that means we can still add event listeners to it.
For example, a click listener here,
to react, to clicks on the list item.
And now let's say when a list item is clicked,
we wanna remove that respect of Goal from the Goal's array.
Now for that, of course, in our JavaScript code,
we can add a method,
removeGoal, sounds like a name that makes sense.
Now, we definitely need some identifier off to Goal,
we wanna remove.
And I would say since we have the index anyways,
we can't just use that.
So here in this removeGoal method,
we could expect to get the index as an argument,
and then, use the splice method,
which is also a built in method in JavaScript,
to splice this one element at this index,
in case you don't know this method yet,
this method use like this,
we'll find the element at this index, and simply remove it
from the Goals array.
So this removedGoal method,
should remove a Goal at this index.
Now we just need to make sure we pass in that index.
And how do we do that?
Well, let's go back to HTML,
here on this click listener, on this list item,
we wanna point at removeGoal,
but we also wanna ensure that the index
is forwarded to that method.
So for that we can call it explicitly by adding parentheses,
and we got the index here,
and both Goal and index
can only be used inside of this element,
which has v-for on it.
So that means between the opening and closing tags,
in any child elements, but also,
and that is what helps us here, on the element itself.
So, we can simply forward index,
which is the index we're retrieving with v-for,
to removeGoal.
And that will be the index zero one and so on,
off the goal, on which be clicked.
So if I reformat that and save that and reload,
we can add finished the course,
and
Master Vue,
and learn all about Vue.
If I now click on Master Vue,
you see that disappears, and we only have two elements.
We can do that with all the elements until they're all gone.
And then, thanks to v-if, we see our paragraph again.
So that is how we could remove items,
by leveraging this index,
and by connecting it with a click listener,
to a method that updates the array,
and since we told Vue to output this array with v-for,
it has this built in reactivity,
which by now you can certainly tell Vue is all about,
that, automatically goes to the page and updates the list,
whenever the array changes, it adds more items
if we added more items to the array, and it updates the list
to remove Dom elements, if we removed items from the array.
That's all Vue does behind the scenes.
And again, I'm really saying that a lot, I know,
but that is why Vue is great.
That is so much work we don't have to do in JavaScript.
I mean, look how simple our JavaScript code is,
it's barely any code at all.
And yet we got a full dynamic list,
to which we can add items,
and from where we can remove items.
And writing that with just vanilla JavaScript,
in the same efficient way, without re-rendering
the whole list all the time,
that would definitely be a bit more difficult.