We're almost done with VF and V-for,
but here's one important addition related to V-for
which you have to be aware of since...
Well, you can see strange bucks if you're not aware of it.
Let's say our goal and index here
is actually in a paragraph, inside of the list items.
So it looks like this.
Hence if I, Master Vue here, we see it like this.
Now let's say besides that, we also have input here
where we can enter some text.
And let's also make sure
we can actually enter something here,
because right now, if I reload and add this,
you'll see whenever I click in there,
I also click on the list item and therefore it's removed.
We can avoid this by adding a click listener here,
where we add the stop modifier.
You learned about event modifiers before,
and this stops propagation.
So it makes sure that when we click on the input,
the click is only processed there
and the disc click event on the list item is not triggered.
We don't have to specify any code that should be executed
if all we wanna do is stop the event.
So now if I reload, we can Master View,
click in there and type.
But I didn't do that to just show you the stop modifier,
even though it's good to know.
Instead of let me show you a strange bug
that you can experience with that.
I will also add, Finish the course as another goal,
and now I will actually type in here something.
So in the first goal.
And now click on it so that this goal gets deleted.
And isn't that strange?
Something is still there on the second goal.
The first one was deleted.
So the new first one is the old second one
and it kept something around.
Might look like a cool feature, but it's actually a buck.
This might become more obvious
if I reload and try this again.
Master Vue, Finish the course
and now let's do it the other way round.
Let's enter something here in the second goal
and remove the first one.
Now Finish the course,
had something in this input field a few seconds ago
until we deleted the first goal.
Now the old second goal,
Finish the course, is the new first goal,
but it lost the input which we had in these input field.
And this is definitely not what you want.
You could argue that this is a niche scenario,
but the problem that causes this is actually a bigger one,
which can also lead to performance issues
if you don't fix it properly.
The problem here is simple,
Vue updates the list when you add and remove items,
it renders the list in the real Dom
and updates it as required.
And it tries to do that such that it optimizes performance.
That also means that it reuses Dom elements.
So if we have two goals here, two Dom elements
and I delete the first one,
Vue will actually not re-render the entire list.
It will also not delete the first Dom element
and move to the second one around.
Instead it basically takes the content of the second element
and moves it into the first Dom element.
And that explains why if I enter some text here,
that text is lost if I delete the first element.
Because the first Dom element is not actually removed
instead the content of the second one.
And with content, I mean the dynamic content.
So this part with the curly braces,
is moved into the old first Dom element.
The input element in the first Dom element
is still the old one
because the entire list item is still the old first element.
Just the dynamic content was moved around
and that's why we lose the input
we had on the second element
when the content of the second element
moves to the old first element's, Dom element.
I hope I could make it clear what the problem here is.
Now this occurs because Vue reuse this elements,
which generally is good.
But sometimes it needs to be able to tell elements apart.
Now the problem is since they all have the same element,
the same Dom element, they are all LI elements.
There is no unique identification criteria
for every rendered Dom element.
Yes, the content is different,
but thankfully Vue is not going ahead
and comparing all the content with each other.
That would be super performance intensive.
Instead, long story short,
there is a simple extra attribute,
which is a non default HTML attribute,
which you can add on elements on which you also use V-for.
And that's the key attribute.
The key attribute,
I'm going to say it again is not a default HTML attribute,
instead it is an attribute understood and detected by Vue.
It's optional, but it is a good idea to add it
whenever you're using V-for.
And actually you will also later in the course
see that there are many scenarios where you must use it.
So it's already a good habit to start using it on all items
where you're using V-for.
And key, once a unique identification criteria
for every item it's outputting here.
Therefore, we wanna bind it to a dynamic value with V-bind
or the short end, just a colon.
And now in here, we need something
that uniquely identifies every goal.
You might be inclined to say the index does that
because every goal has its own index.
But well, keep in mind that if I have two goals
and I delete the first one,
the old second one now has index zero.
The index doesn't really belong to the goal content.
The index is always the same.
The first item always has index zero, for example.
So the index isn't strictly attached to the element value
in the array.
So the index is not really a good thing to use here.
Instead in this case, we could use the goal text itself.
Of course we could enter the same goal text
more than once here, but let's assume that's not the case.
Then goal is good.
More realistic examples, would be IDs
that you might, for example, already have in your database.
And you will see later in the course,
once we also talk to a backend and to a database,
that in most cases you do have a unique ID.
So getting such a unique key per list item,
in reality isn't too difficult.
But here I'll simply use the goal text.
And if I now reload and enter, Finish the course
and Master Vue,
you will see that if I type something here
in the second goal, and I then delete the first one,
now the input moved together with the second one.
Because now Vue was able to tell
the different Dom elements apart
and detect that the first Dom element
now needs to be removed in order to not lose any data
attached to the second element.
And that was a very thorough and long explanation
with a lot of behind the scenes stuff.
If there's one key takeaway,
again, no pun intended, it is that you should add such a key
with a unique identification criteria
when you're using V-for.
You should add it to help Vue
tell the different elements apart
and make sure that state like such entered value
is not getting lost.
And also to help you behind the scenes,
do more performance optimizations.