So that's it for this module.
And now we're a key module,
which together with that module before it forms
the foundation of view.
Now you really already know a lot,
all the core basics you need to build view applications.
And in this module, we of course learned
about conditional content and lists.
Conditional content is all about the v-if
and v- show directives.
Where v-if is the more important one as I mentioned.
V-if allows you to render content only
for certain condition is met,
and with v-if the element is really added,
and removed to and from the DOM with the show,
and it's just shown where hidden with CSS.
We, if can also be combined with v-else,
and v-else-if to render.
Abra elements as alternatives,
only on direct sibling elements though.
So v-else and v-else-if need to be used
on elements directly after v-if not inside v-if,
but after v-if.
We all learned about lists and outputting lists of data.
For dad, we have to v-for directive,
which can be used to render multiple elements dynamically.
And you'll learn that before it can be used
with a raise with objects and all the,
with ranges, so with numbers,
we always had a couple of variations steer,
for example, you can extract values,
and indexes, or even values, keys, and indexes.
If you're working with objects and before.
And if you need before v-for and v-if together,
as we had it in the assignment,
don't use them on the same element.
use a wrapper with v-if instead,
for example, use it on a template,
a diff, a UL element or whatever makes sense,
in your application.
Don't use them on the same element.
In addition, v-for has this concept of keys,
that you might consider using,
you needed whenever you have state in your list items,
because of view reuse this DOM elements
to optimize performance,
but this can lead to bugs.
If your list item elements contain some state
that should move to gabber with the content.
For dad you can use keys,
and you should bind them to unique values,
so that view has a clear way of identifying every element,
in a unique way.