Knowing the basics about Vue,
which we do by now, is of course important.
It's the most important part,
but in my opinion, it's also important
that you understand what Vue does behind the scenes,
how it works behind the scenes.
And that is exactly what we're going to explore
in this module.
Now, I will say this module is optional.
At least the majority of it.
There are free lectures, which you should not skip.
The lecture about Refs
and the two lectures about the Vue app lifecycle.
You can skip the rest of the module for now,
if you're not interested,
though I strongly recommend that you don't skip it,
or you at least come back later,
but you will definitely get the most out of this course
if you go through this module right now.
I mean, after all, that is why I did add it
at this point of time in the course,
because having that extra behind the scenes knowledge
will help you overall as a Vue developer.
Because if you understand the tool you're working with,
you're able to work with it better.
Specifically in this module, we will explore
how Vue works under the hood,
how it's reactivity system works under the hood,
and we'll also understand
how it uses a concept called the Virtual DOM,
to efficiently update what you see on the screen.