Now for this module,
I prepared another very simple project for you.
You find it attached.
And there I already have a simple Vue app
created with create app
where we have two pieces of data,
the current user input and the message
where we have two methods.
One to change the current user input
to the event target value.
And one to set the current message
to the current user input.
And all of that is connected to some HTML code.
That is the section we're controlling with Vue.
This is what triggers to save input method.
Here we triggered a set text method
and here we output the message.
And then we've got some styles,
which we of course can ignore though.
These are largely the styles you already know anyways.
Now this app here is very simple,
Vue is awesome is something I can enter here.
And if I click set text, that's the message showing up here.
And that is achieved with a combination of data methods
and then of course, event bindings
that triggered the methods
and interpolation to output the message data.
Now, that's all something you'll learn about in this course,
and I'm not going to bore you by repeating this again here.
If that is still unclear, you should go through
the previous lectures and modules again.
Now, what I wanna explore here
is how Vue does this behind the scenes.
This automatic updating here.
If we changed the text here and set it,
this part of the page, we as a user see, is updated by Vue.
And that's this built in reactivity, which Vue has,
which is one of its core features.
Essentially viewed as one important thing.
The data you define here is something Vue keeps track of.
I mentioned before that it would take this data object here
and merge all your properties in here into a global
behind the scenes managed object,
the same object where your methods
are merged into by the way.
And indeed, this is what is happening
behind the scenes by Vue.
It also does other things like ensuring
that this points at this global object,
but when it comes to the data,
the important and key thing which Vue does
is it turns your data object into a reactive data object
by essentially wrapping your properties
with a JavaScript feature called Proxies.
in JavaScript there's a built in feature,
which is called Proxy,
which Vue leverages under the hood
to wrap your properties here and to be notified
whenever you assign a new value,
like here with message.
When I set a new value to message,
no matter if data is another data property
or a hard coded string like this,
no matter what it is, when you assign a new value to message
Vue is made aware of that.
And that's important.
If Vue would not be notified about this new assignment,
it could not go ahead and update what you see on the screen.
It needs to be notified by changes like this
so that it recognizes that it should scan
the controlled HTML code for a use
such as ofted changed property
like here, messages being used here.
And then when it sees those usages
and it knows that message changed,
it goes out to the rendered page
to the screen the user sees,
it goes to that screen
and finds the appropriate place there
where this dynamic content is displayed
and updated there on the screen as well.
And that's this built in reactivity,
which Vue does and uses behind the scenes.
Now, how does that work though?
I mentioned that a feature called Proxies would be used.
Let's explore data in greater detail.