For a second, I will leave Vue
to dive into that proxy thing,
which is built into JavaScript,
which Vue uses.
And let's leave the Vue world here
and write some vanilla JavaScript.
We have a variable message
where I say Hello!
So this is a regular JavaScript variable.
It has nothing to do with Vue.
Now, the interesting thing about JavaScript
is that if I now have a new longMessage,
which is my old message
plus let's say World,
I can, of course, console.log that here
and we would see Hello! World!
If I save that, open the console,
and reload, we see Hello! World! here.
Now that shouldn't be too surprising.
But now if we change message thereafter
to Hello and a couple of exclamation marks,
if I console.log longMessage again
and I reload, I still get Hello, World!
I don't get all these exclamation marks here.
Instead, I just have one exclamation mark after Hello!
Because JavaScript by default is not reactive.
That is really just something
which Vue adds for us.
JavaScript by default is not reactive.
If we have a calculation, like we have it here,
where we use a variable
and we change that variable thereafter,
that calculation here
is not re-executed.
JavaScript doesn't note that message changed
and that it was used here.
So that is how JavaScript works
and Vue works differently.
Vue has a built-in mechanism
to be aware when message changed
so that parts of the app
that rely on message can be updated.
And as mentioned for that, it uses proxies.
So let's see how proxies could work.
For that, let me remove that
and let's create an object, data,
which is just an empty JavaScript object,
again not related to Vue.
And let's put the message in here, Hello!
Now we can wrap this object with a proxy in JavaScript
by creating a new Proxy.
And that is a constructor function built
into modern JavaScript.
Therefore, make sure you're testing this code
in a modern browser like Chrome.
Now, we can store that proxy in a constant
and this proxy wants the object it should wrap.
In this case, data.
But it does not just want this.
Instead, it wants a second object as a second argument
and that will be an object full of handlers
for that wrapped object.
Now, I'll come back to what that is in a second.
Let's first of all create such a handler object here.
This handler object can now use certain features.
It can set up so-called traps,
which proxies support.
For example, set traps.
You do this by adding a set function here
in the handler and as a argument,
you will automatically receive a target,
a key and a value.
Now, to understand what this does,
let's console.log target,
key and value here.
And let's now pass this handler object
as a second argument to our proxy.
Now, it's said that the proxy would wrap this object,
this data object, the first argument,
and indeed it does.
So on the proxy, we can indeed access message
just as if we would have a message property
on the created proxy object
because actually, we will.
It wraps this data object.
This object has a message.
So the proxy also has one.
And we can set this to Hello
with a couple of exclamation marks.
Now, let's save and reload
and what you should see here
is that you get three console.log messages
because we have three console.logs here.
The first one, the target is essentially the object
that was wrapped here.
That's just your object that was wrapped.
The second one, the key,
is the property that you just set a new value to.
And the third one, the value,
is the value that was set.
And that hopefully shows you
what a handler does.
With that, we can define a setter function,
which is triggered whenever a property is set
to a new value on this proxy
and then we can find out which property that is,
what the new value is
and which original object we wrapped.
And we could then use this if we had another property here.
Let's say a longMessage,
which initially is Hello! World!
But we want to ensure that longMessage changes
if message changed.
Let's say that's our goal.
Now, by using a proxy,
and setting up such a handler with a so-called set trap,
we can implement this.
We can check if the key we're setting
is message, so if we're setting the message property,
and if we do,
we want to set
target.longMessage
equal to the new value we assigned for message, plus World!
And thereafter, we also wanna make sure
that the message property itself is set,
so we set target.message equal to value.
And the interesting thing can now be seen
if we console.log proxy.longMessage thereafter here
at the end after setting the message to Hello
with multiple exclamation marks
and after updating our handler here.
If we now reload,
we see that down there from line 40,
we're outputting the longMessage,
which now picks up all those extra exclamation marks.
So longMessage was updated when we set message.
So here we built our own reactive system
for tracking one property
and updating another property
when that one property, the message property here, changed.
And in a nutshell, and of course,
with a couple of simplifications,
that is what Vue does under the hood.
It keeps track of all your data properties here
and whenever such a property changes,
it updates the part of your app
where that property was used.
For example, it knows that it needs to update this paragraph
where you're using the message.
And it does that by wrapping your properties with proxies
so that it has a chance of finding out
when you're setting a new value.
That is how Vue works.
And of course, it has a way more complex way
of doing that than I did I down there.
And of course, it also has computed properties
and watchers which are triggered when a property changes.
But that's just the in-a-nutshell approach,
which hopefully gives you an idea
of how Vue works under the hood
so that this magic, which Vue adds
and which is amazing is a bit less magic
in a positive way.