Now that we explored reactivity.
I already want to leave it.
I already want to leave this example
because that really is all I think we should know for now
of how View's reactivity works under the hood.
It's not all we should know about View in general, though;
for example, you might have wondered
if you can only have one view app per page,
and maybe you already tried out working with multiple apps
because yes, you can have multiple apps. Here,
and thus far in all the lectures and modules,
we just haven't had one app
and we mounted that to one part of our HTML code,
which would then be controlled by that app.
But you can absolutely have more than one app
if you wanted to.
So if we add a second section here with an idea
of app two, we can absolutely create a second app,
maybe name it app two here with View Create App,
which we mount to this app two ID section.
And in here, we can do the exact same thing
as we did in our first app.
We can also return the data object here.
We can have a data property here, like a favorite meal,
pizza and, we can then of course, output this here,
in our second app, the favorite meal.
If we do all of that and saved it and reload,
here is our second app.
Now it's missing the styling
because I actually set the styling up to target the app ID.
But if we would target the app two ID as well,
we would get the exact same styling as before.
So, if you quickly find all the places into styled CSS file,
where we target the app ID selector,
simply add the two ID selector with a comma as well.
Also, here and here. And of course all the 40 input.
If you plan on using one in your second app
and all the other styles.
Now, since I don't use a buttons on in my second app,
I'll omit this. And with that,
if I reload, we see this in a nicer style.
Now, of course, you can't use data from another app.
So, here in my app, two, in this section,
which is controlled by the second app,
I can't output the message,
which is part of the data of the first app.
This does not work. If I do that, you see nothing here,
because the message is not a data property
of the second app.
It's one of the first app.
And these two apps have no connection,
which is important, by the way.
Each view app works stand alone.
There is no connection between them.
These are really two different parts
of your HTML code, controlled
by two different apps with no connection between the apps.
So this here does not work,
because this is the data from another app.
And therefore, multiple View apps
are definitely something you might want to use.
If you have different independent parts on your screen,
that should be controlled by View.
If you have a part that needs to work together,
though, for example, an input,
which is connected to the button,
which ultimately influences what's in the paragraph.
If you that, then this all should be controlled
by the same app. Of course.