So we can have multiple apps,
and I already mentioned that we control different parts
of the HTML code.
Now, of course, it should be needless to say
that you shouldn't control the same HTML part
with different apps.
And you also can't use one app
to control multiple HTML parts.
It's one HTML part per app.
And also, the term HTML part
or controlled HTML is not entirely correct though I used it,
because I think it's easy to understand.
The official term is template by mounting your app,
your Vue app to a certain place in the DOM in the HTML code,
you make that part of the HTML code
the template of that Vue app.
So this section is the template of our first Vue app
which is mounted with this selector to this section,
and that other section is the template
of our second Vue app.
And I'm emphasizing this because we're also going to hear
about the term template later again.
There also are different ways of defining your template
of an app.
This here is definitely the most common,
and most convenient one, writing HTML code,
and then mounting your application to it,
this makes a lot of sense,
but actually, it's not the only way of adding a template,
and I wanna show this here as the example of app two.
You can also add a template to a Vue app
by adding the template option
to your app configuration object.
This template option wants a string,
and to write multi-line strings
with these I will use backticks here.
Really just so that I can write multi-line code.
So these are not single quotes,
that's a backtick which is a different character
on your keyboard.
And now we could, for example, grab this paragraph here,
and cut it from the HTML file,
and instead add it in this string here.
This now is the template of the second app,
and actually, this was the template before as well.
We controlled this section so anything inside
of the section was our template.
Now I'm just defining this differently.
Now we still need to mount this app
because Vue still needs to know
where to display this template with the actual value
for a favorite meal when it is rendered on the screen.
So we still need to mount it otherwise Vue wouldn't know
where to add this paragraph on the page.
But with that if I save it and reload,
you'll see the same output as before.
The template is just defined differently.
Now in reality you will most
often use the approach we used this far.
We get nicer syntax highlighting there,
it's easier to understand,
and there is no great reason
for using this string based template.
We will however, learn about a different way
of defining a template and of writing Vue code in general,
in a couple of modules,
not a drastic change,
but a nicer way of doing that.
So that's also why I'm emphasizing
this template part right now already.
For the moment, just be aware of this template concept,
and that of course, there's nothing wrong
with the approach we used before,
but that with that approach we
in the end made all the content
of the Vue controlled HTML part the template of that app
that controlled that part.