Now here's a lecture
which I recommend that you do not skip in this module
because I'm going to show you a different way
of getting a value out of such a input element.
Thus far, we're listening to the input event,
and therefore, with every keystroke, saveInput is fired,
and in the saveInput method,
INDN just saved the current value of the input
to the current user input data property,
so that we can eventually use that property later
to assign the entered value to our message.
Alternatively, as you learned before,
we could also use v-model and bind that
to our current user input property like this.
That is also something you learned about
in the course before,
then we can omit this input binding here.
But whatever approach we use,
we basically log what the user enters with every keystroke.
Sometimes that is what you need, for example,
because you want to validate the user input
with every keystroke,
but sometimes that's all just overkill,
and in such cases, Vue has a feature
that allows you to retrieve values from DOM elements
when you need them, instead of all the time.
And that feature is called, refs.
Here's how you add it.
Instead of adding this event listener,
which you still could add in addition,
but which we simply won't need any more now,
instead of having that,
you add a special attribute to this element,
the ref attribute.
Just like the key attribute,
which we used with V4 before,
the ref attribute is a non-default HTML attribute.
So the browser doesn't know it,
but Vue understands it.
You assign a value here,
which is any string identifier of your choice,
for example, userText.
But again, this is totally up to you.
And you can also not just add refs to input elements,
you can add them to any HTML element,
to paragraphs, headers, sections,
inputs, text areas, whatever you need.
Now, why am I doing that?
Because Vue detects such refs and stores them internally.
It basically memorizes
that you want access to the input element.
And in the JavaScript code, you can then get this access.
Here, in this case,
inside of the set text method,
because that's where I need the entered value.
Instead of using this approach,
I can now set this message equal to this,
and now a special property, which is provided by Vue,
the dollar sign refs property.
Dollar sign refs is a property provided by Vue.
All Vue provided properties start with dollar signs
to make it clear that this is a built-in property.
This is an object full of key value pairs
where the keys are the ref identifiers
you set up in your template,
for example, userText.
So here we can access dot userText.
And this now simply points at the DOM object
for this input element.
So the JavaScript object,
we can use in vanilla JavaScript as well,
when we got access to a DOM element.
So now here, we can get access to the full input element,
and to show you what this means,
I'll comment this out and log it to the console for now.
If we now open this console and reload,
and then click, set text,
you see the whole input element is locked here.
And if we use console.dir, instead of console.log,
and click, set text, again, after reloading,
here is the inspectable object,
and this is really the JavaScript object representation
of this input element, with all the properties that has.
So this is not Vue specific,
that is the vanilla JavaScript object
we could use and work with in any JavaScript code.
And for example, here, we've got this value property.
Essentially, the object we're logging here
is the same one we get access to with event target,
which is why we can access value there as well.
But now we're not doing this with every keystroke,
but instead only when setText is emitted,
which happens when this button,
the set text button, is clicked.
So now we can access value here.
And with that, if we reload,
and I set detects to, Vue is awesome,
and click, set text, this works as before,
but now we're not logging the input with every keystroke,
but we only extract it with help of that refs feature
when we need it.
And that's why refs is a feature worth knowing,
and why you shouldn't skip this lecture.