Now we already learned about
a couple of nice behind the scenes and core features of Vue.
Let's now understand how it actually updates
what we see on the screen.
Of course we learned about it's built in reactivity,
but this is basically just how Vue detects
that an update is needed and where the update is needed.
But performing that update in a performance optimized way
is yet another thing.
And I mentioned this before,
and I'm going to show it to you again.
If I inspect an element here in the browser developer tools,
you will notice that if I type here,
and I click set text, only the paragraph
with the text inside of it flashed here on the right.
So Vue only updated this paragraph,
and nothing else on the screen.
And Vue does that with a concept called the virtual DOM.
So how does that work?
And why does view update to DOM like this?
We got our Vue Instance, our view app,
and we got the DOM, the Browser DOM.
So the HTML content rendered by the browser,
and therefore essentially
what the user is able to see on the screen.
Our Vue app, our Vue Instance, stores data,
computed properties, and methods.
And the Browser DOM is then influenced
with help of the view controlled template.
That template content is rendered to the DOM.
And during that rendering process, which Vue controls,
the dynamic parts and placeholders, the interpolations,
and bindings, are removed,
and the actual values are inserted.
I mean, that is what you can see here as well.
We got the paragraph tag,
with the test text being rendered here.
We don't have the curly braces here,
yet we of course do have them here in our template.
On the button, we got this @click thing,
which is an instruction to Vue,
and that's why we don't see it
in the actual DOM that's rendered in the browser.
Because those Vue instructions are removed by Vue
when it renders its template to the DOM.
So when it basically converts its template,
to the actual HTML elements
that should be shown on the screen.
That's what Vue does here.
And therefore, if we have data like this,
we see something like this on the screen instead,
if we use interpolation for outputting the data for example.
Now of course our data,
and our computed properties might change.
For example, because the user entered something
or clicked a button and those updates
should of course be reflected,
but Vue should not re-render the entire page,
every time something changes,
but only the parts that did change.
Because if Vue would reevaluate
and re-render the entire page,
well that would not be great for performance
if just one piece of text changed.
For example, if just the title changed,
but not the text property here,
then only the h2 tag, which outputs the title
should be updated and not the paragraph.
Now, how could Vue ensure that this is the case
that it does not re-render the entire screen?
Well, one possible solution would be
that it basically compares the old DOM values
with the new ones.
So it basically goes through the entire rendered DOM,
sees which content is in there,
and compares that to the content it has stored
in the data properties of the Vue app.
And if there's a difference, it updates it.
Well it could do that.
And at least it would not update the entire screen then,
but actually it's not what it does
because reading the entire real DOM,
which is rendered by the browser all the time,
whenever something changes
is also pretty performance intensive.
Maybe not as bad as re rendering the entire page
all the time, but definitely not great.
Instead, as mentioned before,
Vue uses a concept called the Virtual DOM.
It basically has a virtual copy of the real DOM,
which is managed entirely in JavaScript,
and therefore in memory.
It could look something like this,
a bunch of JavaScript objects where Vue memorizes
which HTML tag is needed,
and what the content of that tag is.
And when data changes, it basically just creates
a new Virtual DOM you could say,
and compares the new Virtual DOM to the old Virtual DOM,
and only differences between those Virtual DOMS
are written to the real DOM.
And that is way more efficient
because doing such comparisons and updates in a Virtual DOM
and therefore entirely in memory,
is way more efficient than doing it in the real DOM,
which was rendered to the screen.
And that's how Vue does that behind the scenes.
Whenever we change something,
whenever I changed this text here,
and I click set text, Vue detects this change,
thanks to the reactivity we discussed earlier
in this module, and then it creates a new Virtual DOM,
compares it to the old Virtual DOM,
and detects the differences, and then updates the part
in the real DOM where the differences were detected.
That is what Vue does in a nutshell.
Now it should be needless to say
that Vue has a bunch of optimizations in place
that actually make this way more performant.
In reality, it does not recreate
entire virtual DOM's all the time.
It has a bunch of optimizations for that,
but this is beyond the scope of this course.
And really also not something
you'd need to know necessarily.
You should just know how it generally works
to be aware of what Vue does, that it's not all magic,
but that it's pretty, pretty performant.