Now to concludes this module,
we'll have our second lecture, which you should not skip.
The first one was the refs lecture.
Now we're going to talk about the Vue Instance Lifecycle,
which is also important.
We learned how Vue works under the hood,
we learned about the virtual DOM,
and that there are various steps
for bringing something onto the screen.
Sometimes you need to run code during those steps.
And that's why Vue has a quite elaborate life cycle,
where you can step in at any time
to execute code you need to execute.
And you will see some of those lifecycle hooks
we're going to discuss now in action
throughout this course, by the way.
It all starts with us creating a new app.
And of course, mounting it with the mount method
to the HTML code, to the DOM,
so that Vue knows where to render the app.
Then, when it starts creating the app,
and starts bringing something on to the screen,
it reaches a couple of points, a couple of lifecycle phases,
which are also reflected in methods
you can add to your Vue app configuration object
to run code you might need to run at this point of time.
For example, the first lifecycle phase,
the first so called lifecycle hook
that is reached is the beforeCreate phase.
It's followed by a created phase.
The difference is that beforeCreate
is basically called before the app
has been fully initialized,
whereas created is called thereafter.
At this point of time,
we still have nothing on the screen though.
After created Vue just knows its data properties,
and it's aware of the general app configuration.
But now's the time where the template is compiled.
So where all the dynamic placeholders,
all the interpolations and so on are removed
and replaced with the concrete values
that should be shown to the user.
Thereafter the before mount hook is reached
Before mount means that this is right before Vue
is actually going to bring something to the screen.
So right before we can see something on the screen.
So now after created and beforeMount, we reach mounted.
So that in the end just means that now
we see something on the screen.
Now the Vue app was initialized
the template was compiled,
Vue knows what to show on the screen.
And it handed those instructions off to the browser,
so that the browser really adds all the HTML elements
with all the content we need, as defined by our Vue app.
So now we have our mounted Vue app,
our Mountain Vue Instance.
Now of course, in most Vue apps data changes
at some point of time.
And that then triggers a new life cycle.
Now we reach the beforeUpdate hook
and there after the updated hook.
This is a bit like beforeCreate and created.
BeforeUpdate is reached before the update
has been fully processed internally by Vue in its app,
updated is reached, once that has been processed.
This by the way, also means that at this point of time,
the update is visible on the screen.
So we don't reach mounted again,
because the template was never unmounted,
so it always was visible.
After updated, the changes just have been processed
and have been rendered to the screen.
Whereas in beforeUpdate, they haven't.
Now sometimes, an instance can also be unmounted.
A Vue app can be unmounted.
We haven't had this scenario yet,
it will become more important later, as you will see.
But I can also show you
how we could unmount an app in the next lecture.
When an app is unmounted all its content is removed
from the screen and the app is dead.
And we have two lifecycle hooks here as well.
BeforeUnmount, which runs right before
it's about to be removed,
and unmounted, which runs after it has been removed.
You can for example, use these hooks
to execute any cleanup code you might wanna do,
send a HTTP request to your server
to keep track of that app being unmounted
or whatever you need to do.
Now let's see all those hooks in action
to make it a bit clearer how they work.