To see it in action, I'm back in app.js,
and I'll go back to my main Vue app,
which is the one with this input field.
Now I mentioned all those lifecycle hooks,
and I mentioned that these would be methods
you can add to your Vue app.
And with that, I don't mean methods you add
in your methods option.
Because in there, you really only add
the methods you plan on calling yourself
or which you want to call upon events, like clicks.
Instead, you add them right next to data and methods.
Anywhere you want in this app.
So for example here,
towards the end of this app configuration object.
Here, we could add the beforeCreate method,
which I showed on the slide.
You just add it as a method like this,
and here we can console.log beforeCreate
so that we get an idea for when this runs.
And of course you could do more than just logging here.
You could send an HTTP request to a server.
You could set a timer, you could do whatever you need to do.
If I now expand this again,
open the console and reload,
you see beforeCreate being logged here.
And actually, I'll comment out his log message here
at the very bottom so that we're not confused by that.
So let's go back to our Vue app again then,
reload, and we see beforeCreate.
If we do something else and go to the Sources tab here
in the Chrome developer tools,
we actually can also inspect our source code there.
And I'm showing this to you here
because there's something neat we can do with that.
We can actually find the beforeCreate method here
in the app.js file and click here to set a break point.
As a consequence, code execution will pause
when this is reached.
And if you now reload the page, you will see it pauses here,
and you can always continue
by clicking the blue play button.
But the interesting thing,
and the reason for why I'm doing this
is that you see there's nothing on the screen yet.
As I mentioned,
in beforeCreate you won't see anything on the screen.
At this point, actually not even the Vue app
will have been fully initialized.
So let me click the blue button here to continue
and remove the break point by clicking on it again.
Let's now add the second hook, which is the created hook.
At this point of time,
the Vue app was initialized internally,
but it was not mounted yet.
So visually, we'll still not see anything.
If I reload, in the console we see created.
And if we go back to Sources
and I add a break point in the created hook now,
if I reload, you see again at this point,
there's nothing on the screen, just as I explained.
So let me remove the break point and continue,
and let's add more lifecycle hooks.
The next hook in place is beforeMount.
This triggers right before this app really is mounted.
So right before we see something on the screen.
So we'll still not see anything here,
but we will see something in the next hook thereafter,
which is mounted.
So here, let me console.log mounted.
And let's then save this,
go back to the JavaScript console and reload.
And we see beforeCreate, created, beforeMount and mounted.
But again, it's more interesting if we go to Sources
and now add a break point in before mount and in mounted,
and now reload.
And we first pause in beforeMount
because that hook runs first.
And you see nothing on the screen.
If you now click resume, so this blue play button here,
we pause on the next break point, which is in mounted.
And now you see something on the screen.
As I explained, because at this point of time
this Vue app was mounted to the screen.
It was initialized internally, all the data was processed,
the template was compiled
and it's showing its output on the screen.
So, with that, we can also remove those break points
and resume again.
Now with that, the creation life cycle here is finished,
but I mentioned that we would have data changes,
which also triggered their own lifecycle hooks.
So let's see those in action as well.
After mounted here, though,
as mentioned before, the exact position does not matter,
but after Mount that I'll add beforeUpdate
and console.log beforeUpdate here.
And I will also add updated.
The difference will be that in beforeUpdate,
we'll not see the changes on the screen yet.
In updated, we will.
So if you go to the JavaScript console in the DevTools
and reload, we don't see those hooks being executed
because nothing was updated in this app.
It was created, but nothing was updated.
So now let's enter a new text here.
And if I click Set Text now,
you see beforeUpdate and updated.
And if you go to the Source tab again
and add some break points in beforeUpdate and in updated,
we can also see that if I changed is again, for example,
to add more exclamation marks, we now pause.
And we first pause in beforeUpdate.
And you notice that the text output here on the screen
is still the old one.
Because, as mentioned,
in beforeUpdate the update was not fully processed yet.
It's not visible on the screen.
If I resume, we pause in updated.
And indeed at this point of time,
the output has been processed and is visible on the screen.
So again, I'm removing those break points and resuming,
and that hopefully shows the updating process.
Now, as mentioned before, we also can unmount a Vue app,
even though we haven't done this thus far.
We then trigger the beforeUnmount and the unmounted hooks.
And as also mentioned before,
this unmounting process will become more relevant later.
Nonetheless, let's see it in action now already.
And for that back in code here,
I'm going to add deep beforeUnmount hook
and console.log beforeUnmount.
And I'm also going to add the unmounted hook
and hence console.log unmounted here
so that both those hooks are implemented
and we log a message for them.
But at the moment, this app will never get unmounted.
We have no way of killing or removing it.
But just as we have an app mount method,
we also have a app unmount method to remove a Vue app.
Now you will rarely call this method
in a real application though.
Instead, you will later see a way more realistic scenario
of unmounting apps.
But at the moment we're missing a key prerequisite for that,
so we're going to work with that unmount method instead.
We could set a timer here
and set it to three seconds, let's say,
and then have a function in which we call unmount.
So that three seconds after the app was created and mounted,
we destroy it, we unmount it.
And if we now save that and reload,
you will see that after three seconds,
the app has gone on the screen
and we see beforeUnmount and unmounted.
And of course, again, we could also go to the sources
and simply add break points here in beforeUnmount
and in unmounted.
And reload and see how this pauses after three seconds.
First in beforeUnmount, at which point of time
we still see the app.
So that's the last chance to work with it.
But then if I resume, it's removed in unmounted.
And that is the Vue lifecycle with all its hooks.
In reality, you will only need a few of those hooks.
Nonetheless, of course, I wanted to show them to you
because this is the complete guide after all
and not the I show you some things guide.
Nonetheless, we'll especially see hooks like created,
mounted or unmounted in action throughout this course,
as well as updated.
And with that, we can also leave this module.
We now have a solid understanding of the basic features
and not just of how to use them,
but also how they work under the hood.
And with that, you already made a huge step
in the right direction to becoming a Vue developer.