We now gained a lot of knowledge
about important concepts
and features which you need in Vue applications.
There is one thing which is missing,
which you don't need in any application,
but which helps in a lot of applications.
And that would be transitions and animations,
moving things around and doing so in an animated way
to help users understand your user interface,
to provide a better user experience.
Technically, transitions
and animations are totally optional,
but they often make your UI and UX much, much better.
And therefore in this module,
we'll start by understanding transitions and animations,
how they work and how you can make them work with CSS.
We'll then learn how Vue.js can help us with animations
and where exactly we need its help.
And then we'll also see that animating lists is
a bit different than animating other things,
which we'll dive into first in this module,
and therefore we'll cover this as well.