Now, you know the game.
Attached you find a starting project,
run npm install to install all dependencies we got in there.
And once that is done and out of the way,
you can run npn run serve
to bring up that development server
which hosts this demo app.
Now here's the app we'll be starting with.
And to be honest, it's more of a playground than a real app.
We've got a modal here which can open and close.
But it's really just there
so that we can practice animations,
but will not start with the modal.
We'll start with this square.
With this dark purple square here.
And we'll see how we can animate that with CSS
and also Vue.
And then we'll also see where we need more support
from Vue side and how we get that support.
So how can we animate things? Let's start simple.
Let's say we want to click this animate button.
And well, then this square here,
this block should be animated.
And for that, we can go back to our code.
To App.vue which is where I have this block.
This div with the class block.
And we'll start by adding a click listener to animate.
Sort of we can write some Vue code
that should do something with that div.
And I wanna start very, very simple.
I wanna start by simply moving that block
a little bit to the left, let's say.
To achieve this we can add a new method.
Animate block, sounds like a fitting name for that.
And that's the method which should be triggered
upon a click. So let's wire this up.
And I wanna manage some data here,
which basically controls
wherever we wanna animate the block or not.
So whether we clicked the button or not.
Animated block is the data property I will add for that.
And it's a simple Boolean and starts with a false value.
Now that's just one way of implementing this,
but this is a very simple demo
which we can build like this.
So we get the animated block data property here
in the App.vue file.
And we can now utilize this data property
to add a CSS class to this div conditionally.
Because we can animate things in web development
with just CSS. We don't technically need JavaScript for it.
We might just need JavaScript to start the animation,
to add certain CSS code.
But thereafter, CSS can do that on its own.
So here we could add a dynamic class binding
to bind the animate class let's say.
This class name is up to you.
Whenever animated block.
So this newly added data property is true.
When that's true, the animate class will be added.
And we can now define this animate class here in our styles.
I'll add a brand new class animate.
And to move the block around,
we can for example use the transform CSS property
which is a built in CSS property.
Has nothing to do with Vue.js
and there we can add translate X
to move an element around on the X axis.
And the transform property is perfect for that
because it moves elements in an optimized way.
It gives us great performance essentially.
So here we could move it by, let's say, 50 pixels.
So now to finish this up,
we just need to go to this method we added before
and set this animated block equal to true here.
And with all of that, with that property,
which be used to add the animate class dynamically
and that animate class to find down there.
With all of that set up.
If we save that we can click animate
and we see that block move a little bit.
We can actually also move it a bit further by for example,
deducting 150 instead of 50 pixels.
But what you'll see of course is that
this is an instant jump. It's not an animation at all.
It's just a instant jump to its new position.
Now this is not what I want here.
I want a smooth animation.
And implementing that is super easy with CSS.
We can simply go to this block class,
which is the base CSS class this div has.
And on that block class here,
we can add the transition CSS property.
Which is another built in property CSS offers.
It has nothing to do with Vue.
The transition property takes a couple of values.
It first of all wants to know
which other CSS property we wanna transition.
For example,
we could say that we want to animate the opacity.
But here on this block, we're never changing the opacity
so this makes no sense.
We can say all, to animate any changes
in any animatable CSS properties.
Or we target transform specifically since we know
that we're going to change the transform property.
Initially on this base class,
we're not saying anything about transform.
And then later we set it to translate X -150 pixels.
So when that kicks in,
transition with the transform value here
tells CSS that any changes applied to the transform property
or with help of the transform property, should be animated.
And therefore
besides the name of the property we wanna animate,
we also have to provide a duration
over which this animation should be done.
For example, 0.3 seconds.
Now, as a side note.
If you wanna learn more about that,
the potential values you can set up here
and how CSS animations work.
You might wanna check out a dedicated CSS course
or some free CSS animation resources
which you'll find out there.
I'll not dive too deeply into that here
since it's still a Vue course in the end
and not primarily as CSS or CSS animations course.
Nonetheless here, we now animate changes
and transform over 0.3 seconds.
And we kind of find that easing function
which basically determines how this animation accelerates
and then throttles at the end.
If we now save that. You'll see if I click animate,
now this animates.
And this moves in the duration we specified.
And we are using Vue here to start this animation
by setting animated block to true.
Initially it's false but we set it to true here.
And that adds the animate class.
So that's the part where we use Vue.
But thereafter it's just CSS.
And it's just the transform property combined
with the transition property.
And that's important. This is a perfectly fine way.
It's not just fine.
It's actually the recommended way
for adding animation like this.
Now there is an alternative for cases where
a simple transition like that is not enough though.
Let me show you that alternative as well.