Besides the transition property,
which we can use to tell CSS
to well provide a transition between two changes,
we can also set up a more detailed animation.
For that we first of all have to define an animation in CSS.
And we do this by writing @keyframes,
and then any name of our choice,
for example, slide-fade
but again, this name is up to you.
Now, in here you can define in detail
how the animation should behave,
and which different states it should have
and you express this with percentages.
You for example say that at 0% of animation completion
so at the start you for example,
want to have transformation along the X axis of zero
so it hasn't been moved.
And in addition, you set the scale to one.
Scale is a number transform function which you can add
to change the size of a block.
Then let's say after
70% of the animation time,
you want to change this,
to move it to 120 pixels to the left
and scale it up a little bit,
make it 10% bigger by setting the scale to one dot one
one is the original scale,
one dot one is 10% bigger.
And then here at 100%,
we want to translate X to
the full minus 150 pixels.
So move it the entire way to the left
and set scale back to one.
So that we just bump up the size
in the middle or a little bit after the middle
of the animation and move it almost
to the end here at this point and entirely
to the end here and bring it back to its normal size.
And these are different states we have in our animation now
that's now our defined animation
and the different states the so called keyframes
wanna reach during that animation.
And we now apply this by going
to our block first of all,
and removing transition there.
We can move transition and animation together if we want to,
but often you'll use just one of the two.
So here I want to use an animation
hence I comment out transition.
And in the class which we add eventually,
I'll comment out transform,
and instead add the animation CSS property.
That property now allows us to add an animation when
that CSS class is added to an element.
Here, we now refer to one of our keyframe sets,
which we defined so in this case at slide-fade.
So using this name here,
then we still specify a duration
which will be split up across these key frames.
So here, let's say dot three seconds.
And also easing function,
which controls how fast these different states
are reached if we start fast and end slow,
or if we start slow and end fast.
If we save all of that, and reload,
if I click animate,
you see it animates,
but then it snaps back to the original state.
That's not a bug
that's how CSS animations behave by default,
we need to add four words here to tell CSS
that we want to keep the final keyframe the final state
as the new look the new state of the animated element.
So by adding four words here, if we save that and reload,
if I click animate,
it now moves over there with our custom animation
and keeps that final state.
And that's how we can implement animations
with CSS transitions or CSS animations.
And all we're doing with view here
is we're adding this animate class dynamically
two to two be animated element,
which of course also doesn't have to be a div
but could be anything.
And often that is all you need.
But there also is a scenario where this is not enough.
So let's explore that, next.