So what would be a scenario where these
basic CSS transitions and animations might not be enough?
Well, first of all, and that's really important.
CSS animations and transitions will very often be enough,
but adding them like we're currently doing it,
that might not be enough, and here's an example.
In our running application, if I take show dialog,
this model dialog pops up immediately,
it's just there and it's gone when we close it.
This might be fine.
This might be absolutely the behavior you want,
but sometimes you might wanna animate it in.
You want to have a little animation
when it appears and the same for removing it.
And that is the part that will be tricky
with just CSS animations and with just adding CSS classes
with Vue as we did before,
especially when you also want to animate the disappearance.
Let me show you why it's tricky.
We can go to the base modal,
which holds to code for this dialog
and there on the dialog selector here,
we can add a little animation.
We can for this again, to find some key frames here
and give it any name of our choice and I'll name it modal.
But again this name is up to you and I'll start at 0%
and I wanna go to 100%.
And if you just define two styles, two states,
as I'm doing it here,
you can also use the from and to shorthands basically.
And now here we define the starting state
and there let's say the modal should initially be invisible
by setting the opacity to zero with transform translate Y,
I will move it up on the Y axis by 50 pixels.
And I will actually also scale it from zero dot nine
to its final size.
And speaking of final, in to, I now add the final states.
Opacity one, translate Y of zero
to reach the real position this element should have
and scale one to reach the real size
this element should have.
And now we could this modal animation
to our dialog selector to basically make sure
that every dialog we're selecting with that.
So the only dialog we have here receives that animation.
And by default,
the animation will be played when the element
is then first being part of the page.
So the animation starts instantly.
We can utilize this here, with animation I can point at my
modal animation here, give it a duration, ease out
and important, add forwards to tell CSS
that the final state should be kept.
And if we now save everything, when I click show dialog,
we have this little animation here, as you can tell,
and we have this animation because the animation is part
of the dialog selector.
So whenever this selector finds something on the page
and it will find something when the dialogue is added
to the page, which I do in app Vue in the end
with v-if on my custom component, the whole component
is only added if dialog is visible as true
and therefore the dialogue element in the component
is only added under that circumstances.
And therefore whenever that is the case.
This here, this animation will be played thanks to that key,
but the problems start if we all do want to animate
the removal of the element,
if I wanna do that, currently it disappears instantly.
The problem we'll have is that the element
is detached from the DOM.
And that means there is no way to animate it with CSS.
It's removed instantly.
You can't play an animation and then tell the browser
to only remove it once that animation is finished,
but that is what you would need to do
in order to animate the disappearance.
And that's exactly what Vue is able to help us with.
Vue can help us with animating the appearance
and also the disappearance of elements by for example,
delaying the disappearance
until a certain animation has finished.