And I will show this to you
by going to App.vue, and there I'll add a new div.
I'll come back to the modal later,
but I wanna start with that.
Give it a class of container,
and in there, let's just add a regular button.
"Toggle Paragraph" could be the text we have on the button.
And then I'll add a little a paragraph above that button.
"This is only sometimes visible..."
and this paragraph should be toggled
whenever this button is clicked.
Now, you know how that works.
We can add a new data property, paraIsVisible,
which initially is false, for example.
We can add a new method anywhere in the methods key.
toggleParagraph, could be the name,
and in that method we now control this
newly added data property.
So we set, paraIsVisible, to what it's currently not
to invert its value.
And then we can use paraIsVisible with, v if,
to only sometimes show that paragraph.
And the only remaining step now is to wire up this button
with a click listener pointing at, toggleParagraph.
And if we do that, well, we have that paragraph,
which instantly appears and instantly disappears.
Now let's animate both and let's see
how Vue helps us there.
There is a built in component,
which you can wrap around the elements
where you wanna control the appearance
and removal animation with Vue.
And that's the transition component.
You can wrap the element, which should be animated,
with transition, and of course,
you can wrap multiple elements
per Vue app and per Vue component,
and transition, this built in component,
will then manipulate this wrapped element.
Important, transition must only contain one element,
one direct child.
There is an exception about which I'll talk later,
but for the moment, keep in mind
that you must only have one direct child in transition.
And what does transition do with that wrapped element now?
Well, it's this wrapped element,
which at some point of time is mounted,
but which of course in this case also
is not mounted initially.
It's not always visible on the screen.
Transition now adds a couple of
CSS utility classes to that element.
It adds a enter-from class,
an enter-active class, and a enter-to class.
And it adds enter-from first, enter-active at the same time,
then it removes from, but enter-active stays on the element
and enter-to is added, right when the animation finishes.
And Vue finds out how long that process should take
by analyzing these special CSS classes
and looking for transitions and animations inside of them
to then read the duration from them.
So Vue will analyze your CSS code
for these special CSS class names.
Find out the duration,
then actually add those CSS classes over the duration.
And that in turn will allow you
to set different styles during that appear,
during that entering phase of the element.
And of course you have
a similar concept for removing elements.
So when an element is mounted
and now is not mounted anymore,
because with v if, the condition turns false,
then Vue adds a leave-from class,
and at the same time, a leave-active class,
then it removes the leave-from class
and adds a leave-to class,
and this allows you to animate the removal of elements.
And the important thing again is that
Vue will analyze the CSS code you write for these classes,
it will read the duration of the transitions
and animations you define in those classes,
and then, and that's the key thing,
it will only really remove the element from the dom
once that duration is over.
And that's the key difference to the non-Vue behavior,
their elements are instantly added and removed
with the transition component,
and these special CSS classes Vue will add and look for,
Vue is able to tell that an animation has taken place
and how long that animation takes,
and it then only removes the element
once that animation is done.
Now that's the theory.
Let's see it in practice.