So back in code,
we've got this wrapped paragraph
and I mentioned that Vue would add certain utility classes.
Well, it does.
So let's define styles for them in the CSS code.
You could do this anywhere, I'll do it here.
And the default class names Vue will add are v-enter-from,
v-enter-active and v-enter-to.
Vue, by default, will add these three CSS classes
at different times as explained
when the element is first added to the DOM.
So in this case, when the paragraph
is appearing on the DOM for the first time.
Now we can define different class styles here.
We can define different properties.
And we should include at least one transition
or animation so that Vue is able to read the duration time
from these classes because I mentioned
that this would be another key thing it does
behind the scenes.
Now, in v-enter-from, you define your starting state.
And for this paragraph,
that could be that it initially is invisible
by setting opacity to zero.
And maybe that it's moved up a little bit
by setting transform to translateY -30 pixels.
This moves it up a little bit above its real position.
In v-enter-to, we have the end state,
so the final state we wanna have at the end.
And there, we can have an opacity of one
and set transform: translateY to zero
to take the real position
of the element it should have on the page.
And v-enter-active is now the place
where you, for example,
add the transition CSS property
to tell Vue to watch for all CSS properties
that might be animated.
So in this case, opacity and transform,
which are the two properties changing here,
then you define a duration.
That is what Vue will read.
So what Vue will take to find out
how long these classes should be added to the element.
And then your easing function.
And if you do that, and you reload,
you can click Toggle Paragraph
and you have this animation for adding the paragraph.
For removing, we don't have any yet
but for adding, we do.
Well, and I already showed it on the slide.
You have similar classes for removing.
There we have the v-leave-from class.
We have the v-leave-active class
and we have the v-leave-to class.
And it's the same concept as for entering.
We define our starting state,
which for me here is the same state
as the end state for entering
but it doesn't have to be the same.
You can define a totally different state here,
totally different CSS properties as well.
That is fine.
You don't have to use the same CSS properties
as for adding.
But here I'm doing it.
In v-leave-to, I use the same state
as I had for entering in my from state.
Now it's the to state for leaving,
making this invisible and moving it up a bit.
Or actually, let's move it down a bit
by setting this to +30 pixels,
also to emphasize that you don't have
to use the same styles as before.
And for v-leave-active,
I have the same transition set in here
but instead of ease-out, I'll use ease-in
for a different easing function,
which just controls how that duration
is split across the different steps.
And now if you save that and reload,
we have animation for entering
and also for removing like this.
Now, that is how you can use the transition component
to animate the appearance and removal
of HTML elements.
And especially the removal is something
which was harder without transition.
But also for entering,
you gain more flexibility with that transition component,
which you wrap around the element,
which does use v-if or v-show
and which then should be animated.
You don't need it if you're not having this v-if
or v-show case
because if you just have something like the block
in the first example,
in the last lectures,
you can just conditionally add and remove CSS classes
as you learned it.
It's just this added to the DOM
or removed to the DOM case
where you can't do that
because the element is just not there
and that's where transition then helps you.