Now transition cannot just be used
with the transition CSS property
just to make this clear,
you can also use it to apply an animation.
Now we already have an animation here,
slide and fade, it's actually not really fading,
I guess it's more of a slide and scale animation.
So maybe let's use this as a name.
And let me show you how we could add this
with this transition wrapper component.
So on this paragraph,
I mentioned that view would add these special
CSS classes v-enter-from and so on.
Now, if you don't want to use this transition way,
because maybe you have a more
complex animation with different steps,
you can do this as well.
Now we don't need all classes in that case though,
we don't need v-enter-from
because we have no starting state
and we have no end state.
Instead, it's all defined in the animation.
So in the end, we just have animation in v-enter-active.
Then I point at the slide-scale animation
to find the duration
which you will read as you learned and ease-out.
You don't even need four words here,
because you need to keep in mind
that all those special classes are being removed
once the animation is over.
So once this duration which Vue reads is over,
and therefore the final end state
you will see on the screen is just a regular styling
you defined for this element
with the other CSS rules you have.
So here we don't need four words
because this class is also getting removed
once the animation is over
so it can't jump back because it doesn't even know
the animation anymore once it is, well, over.
Now we can do the same for a leaving though.
Don't need a from state, don't need a to state
but for v-leave-active of instead of transition.
We can use animations slide-scale .3 seconds ease-out.
If we now save that and reload.
Now we got this other style here.
Now it's the style from the square from before.
That's why it looks a bit strange here,
but you can tell that it works.
So using CSS animations with the wrapper
with this transition wrapper component is also supported.