Now what if you had
multiple transition components
on your page though?
Because maybe you don't just want to animate the removal
and addition of this paragraph,
but also off this div or of any other element.
Theoretically, that works, but you will face a problem.
Vue always adds the same CSS classes to all elements,
which basically means you will use the same animations
and transitions for all elements.
Maybe that is your requirement.
Maybe that is what you want,
but maybe you want different transitions
for different transition components on your page.
And that's why you can customize those names here.
We could, for example name this para-enter-from
para-enter-active, para-enter-two,
and the same for the leave classes
instead of the v- thing at the beginning.
But with that Vue of course wouldn't know
that these are the CSS classes it should add and analyze
instead with just the names changed here,
we have no animation because Vue will stick to its default
v-enter-from, v-enter-to and so on class names.
We need to tell Vue that for this transition component here,
it should add the para-classes
and we do so by adding a special name prop
to the transition component.
Here you add your custom prefix, which in my case is para,
but which can be anything you want.
And if you do that
now these para-enter-from, enter-active, enter-to.
And so on classes will be added and managed
and analyzed by Vue.
So now with that, if you reload the animation is back.
So this name can be set and customized
so that you can have multiple different transitions
and transition component usages most importantly,
in the same component.
Now, one more word about the naming here.
You can define your own custom prefix,
as I explained here with the name prop
in cases where you wanna replace the entire class names.
So you don't wanna work with para-enter-from,
para-enter-active, para-enter-to and so on,
but you wanna use totally custom CSS class names here,
for example, because you're using some third parties,
CSS animation library,
which gives you certain classes you need to add
where you can't change the names.
For such cases, you can add more props here instead of name
you can add, enter-to-class prop
and define your enter-to-class name,
enter-active-class prop and so on.
So here you can, then define your CSS class names
that should be added during the enter-to phase
the enter-active phase and so on.
So instead of v-enter-to or para-enter-to,
you would then add some class and so on.
Now that's not what I'm doing here.
I'll revert this to name equal para,
but I want to make you aware of that,
so that you know that you have full flexibility
when it comes to these names.
And when it comes to which CSS classes
are added at which point of time.