So let's now apply what we learned about transition,
about this transition component, to our modal.
Because that was the thing where I explained
that we might need more help from vue's side.
Especially for having a transition and animation,
when we close it.
Now we can wrap transition around our own custom components,
just as we can wrap it around built-in elements.
So we can use transition here,
around our base-model, just like that.
Now we can, of course also set the name prop
to define our own prefix for all
those special classes you will add.
And I will add modal here.
But again, you can pick any name you want.
And then we can dig into our CSS code
and start to finding those CSS classes.
And here I'll add a modal-enter-from class,
a modal-enter-active class and a modal-enter-to class.
And I will actually go to BaseModal.vue
and make sure that I removed the animation
from the modal there.
So that we don't see this animation anymore.
So make sure you comment as out or remove this line.
And then let's go back to App.vue,
which is where we're using the base-model
and where we are wrapping it with transition.
And now we can define our different styles here.
And it's now of course, totally up to you,
how you want to animate this modal.
I will actually bring over my modal keyframes here.
So the keyframes from the BaseModal.vue file,
add them here, to App.vue.
You can have multiple sets of keyframes
in the same style tax,
as long as you're using different names.
And I actually don't even need to enter
from an enter-to now.
We just need enter-active to play at animation
and this will be the modal animation,
which i just copied over,
give it a duration and a ease-in function.
And if we do that, we'll notice a problem.
If we reload, this modal has no animation.
Now, this transition component
does work on custom components.
But we have a problem here.
The classes vue wants to add are added
to the root element of your custom component.
This is ,this attribute fall through behavior
I talked about earlier.
So these classes transition wants to add
fall through to the root element
in the template of base-model.
But base-model happens to have two root elements.
There's div and there's dialogue.
If we comment out the div for a second,
if we remove that div, the backdrop for a second,
and then reload, you see, it works.
Now we have this animation for showing the modal.
But if we have both root elements here,
which you of course want, then this does not work.
And it doesn't work because as I mentioned before,
this transition component wants one direct child element.
Yes, it has just one child element here,
just one base-model.
But of course the base-model here,
is really just a wrapper around its template,
where we have two root elements.
So these two root elements, this div and this dialogue,
these are the actual direct child elements
inside of this transition component.
Well, and two elements are more than one.
That's why this set-up here does not work.
What can we do about that?
How can we work around that?
Well, there are various ways of solving this.
We can, for example, split this into two components
and manage the backdrop separately.
But we could also bring this transition component
over to base-model and try using it in there
to transition to style log.
And that's the route I will take here.
I'll remove the transition wrapper
around my custom component.
Though it theoretically would work,
if our custom component had just one root element,
but here it doesn't, so it doesn't work.
And I will bring it over to base-model
and wrap this dialogue with transition, like this.
Now I can give this a name of, modal
and go back to App.vue,
and grab my modal specific CSS classes,
to be precise to modal-enter-active class here,
we can remove them from App.vue,
remove the modal keyframes from App.vue
and bring all of that over to BaseModal.vue.
There, we already got the modal keyframes,
and now I'm also adding the modal-enter-active class,
which points at the modal keyframes
to play it as an animation.
Now, however, we need to change the logic,
how this base-model opens.
At the moment, I'm adding the base-model component
in App.vue with v-if.
And this won't work, if I want to use transition
inside of the base-model template
to animate the addition and remove of dialogue.
If transition is part of that template,
which has added and removed with v-if,
it won't have any effect.
Therefore I'll now open and close the modal differently.
I'll add a new open prop, to my base-model component
and point at dialogue is visible there.
So forward, the dialogue is visible property
through the open prop to the base-model component.
And now in the base-model component,
we can accept this prop here.
So expect the open prop here.
And now that we're getting it,
we can simply add it here with v-if.
We can check open, so does open prop,
which is true or false, to control whether or not
the dialogue is visible or not.
So now the base-model component is always added
to the App.vue template,
but inside of that base-model template,
the dialogue is still controlled with v-if.
But now it's wrapped in a transition,
and now this transition has only one direct child.
And of course, we also want to add v-if here to the div,
and pass the open prop to v-if as well,
to control the visibility of the backdrop.
And now finally, if we reload, we got this animation
and everything works properly.
And we can, of course now also work on a closing animation.
We can add modal-leave-active here,
and play the same animation.
Let's say with an ease-in function,
just to keep things simple.
Of course, we could also play
a totally different animation here,
or a set-up a transition
by also using the from and to classes.
But if I do it like that, if I now reload,
we got a animation for opening, and also for closing.
Now the closing animation, certainly is a bit off
because I'm just re-using the opening animation,
but we can add the reverse value here to this animation
on modal-leave-active, to tell CSS,
to actually play this animation in reverse,
for this case here, for this CSS class selector.
So that it will start at, to and go to, from,
if you add reverse.
And with that, if I save that and reload,
we've got a nice animation for opening and also for closing.
And now, that is enabled with help of transition.
Keeping in mind, that transition
must only have one direct child element.
And therefore, we had to restructure this a bit,
and I hope it's clear why we had to do it.
But with that, we now got a nice transition
for opening and for closing.
So for adding and for removing,
this element to the done.
Now I'll dive into some cases,
where we actually are allowed to have
more than one element inside of transition.