So, I always emphasized that transition
must only have one direct child element,
and because of that,
we had to change our Base Modal a little bit here,
to ensure that transition
has only one direct child element.
Well, actually there are exceptions to that rule,
there is a scenario where you might
have more than one direct child element,
and here it is.
In App Vue, I'm going to add a new Div
with a class of container,
simply to show you a new example
inside of that Div.
And here, I'll add a good, old button,
but now we'll animate the button itself,
and I'll have a button here,
where I say, "Show Users.", and below that,
a second button, where I say, "Hide Users.".
Well, at the moment we got no users,
but for the moment, I simply want to switch
between these two buttons when we click them,
so that we simply animate the switch
from show to hide, and back,
because we worked with buttons
that change their text before,
but whenever we had such a button,
the text on the button changed instantly,
and we had no animation for that.
You might not need that,
but if you do, you can build this
with the transition component.
So first of all,
let's make sure we switch between these buttons,
for that we can add click listeners here,
point at Show Users, on the first button,
and then here at Hide Users.
So, Show Users and Hide Users,
these are 2 methods we now need to add,
and we also need a new data property here,
which controls in which mode we are at the moment,
users are visible, could be the name of that property,
initially it's false let's say,
and then we have a method, Show Users,
where I simply set these users are visible to true,
and Hide Users, which is that other method
we're pointing at from the other button,
and here we can set users are visible to false.
So, this is just some dummy code,
but with that, we are controlling the users
are visible property here, the data property,
and we can now control which button should be visible
based on that property.
The first button here should be visible
if users are visible,
is false,
because if they are not visible,
I want to show the Show Users button,
so that we show them.
The other button there for
is shown if users are visible, is true.
If we see the users at the moment,
I want to show a Hide Users button.
With that, if we save this,
we got this new button,
we can click it to switch between these buttons.
In reality, that of course would do something else
on the page as well, show a list of users for example,
but here I just want to focus on the transition
between these 2 buttons,
and I already said it on the transition.
At the moment, it's an instant change,
which might or might not be what you want,
but if you don't want it,
if you want to animate this,
you can use the transition component for that,
and wrap it around these 2 buttons,
and you heard that right,
around these 2 buttons.
There is one exception,
where you are allowed to have more than one
direct child element inside of your transition component,
and that is the exception here.
The exception is,
if of the child elements you have in your transition,
you're guaranteed that at most one
is added to the real dom at the same time,
and that's the case here.
We got 2 alternatives If statements,
and therefore we guarantee
that only one of these 2 buttons
will be added to the real dom at a time.
So, if you use transition around elements
where only one is added,
then this is okay.
If there is a chance of both buttons being added
to the page at the same,
then this is not okay.
So, if we had the same If condition here,
then this would not be okay,
because now both buttons would be part of the page,
but if we have the opposite If conditions here,
then this is okay.
Now, let's add a nice, little transition here.
Fade-button is the prefix I will use here,
but as always, this is totally up to you,
and now down there in the style code,
maybe here,
I'll add fade-button-enter-from,
and then copy this to all
the active,
and two classes,
and let's say we want to start
with an invisible button,
then we want to go to a visible button,
and we want to animate this
with the transition property
where we watch the opacity property,
and whenever that changes, because it does here.
Whenever that changes,
let's see us animate that change over 0.3 seconds,
and now we can also add the classes
for removing a button,
and now for the first time,
I will reuse some code,
because my Enter-From state
is also my Leave-To state.
My Enter-To state
is also my Leave-From state,
and I will have a separate active state though,
because I want to use a different easing function,
so Fade-Button-Leave-Active,
there I set up a transition
watching the opacity over 0.3 seconds
with an ease-in function.
If I would use ease-out here,
we could of course also have merged it
with this CSS rule,
but I want to use ease-in here.
So now, here I am reusing a little bit of code,
instead of writing everything twice,
I did it before to be more explicit,
but now I think we got the idea,
so we can write less code here,
and now if I now save that,
we got an error.
Transition expects exactly one child element
or an component.
Now, I just emphasized that it would be fine
to have multiple elements,
if we guarantee that only one
is shown at the same time.
Well, the problem is,
Vue doesn't understand that these If conditions here
guarantee us that only one button is added.
It doesn't analyze the If conditions.
So, in order to give Vue a clear signal
that it's either that or that component,
we should use V-Else here,
because V-Else is pretty clear.
With V-Else, we guarantee
that only this or this component is shown,
that we'll never have both on the screen
at the same time.
So, now with that added,
this works,
and now you see we have this smooth transition here
when a button is removed, it fades out,
when it's added, it fades in,
but of course, it's also ugly,
because it jumps, and during the transition,
we actually have both buttons on the screen,
which by the way, is okay here,
because this is now controlled by Vue.
So, this is certainly not what we want.
We want this fade transition,
but we don't want both buttons at the same time
on the screen.
Instead, one button should fade out,
and then the other button should fade in,
that's the idea,
and that's also something that you can control.
You can add the mode prop here
to the transition component,
and mode knows two values,
in-out, and out-in,
and this controls whether first,
the leaving element should be animated,
or the new element.
So if I set this to in-out,
and reload,
we got the same behavior as before,
or a similar behavior.
Now, the addition of the button
is animated first,
and then the button is removed.
We can switch this to out-in,
and now we will have a better behavior,
without in, if we reload,
Vue will first animate the removal of the button,
and then animate the addition
of the new button.
So, this allows you to control
which element should be animated first,
instead of animating both at the same time,
which gave us this undesirable output.
Now, we're having a smooth animation
with help of transition,
and multiple child elements,
which is okay as you'll learn,
if you know that only one of them
will be active at the same time,
and you can give a clear signal
with V-If, V-Else, to Vue
that this will be the case.