So by now, we already learned a lot
about transitions, to transition component, what it does
and how you may use it.
Sometimes you'll also want to run some JavaScript code,
either as part of the transition,
maybe to even control the entire transition
and the style changes Fruit JavaScript,
or maybe because you want to do something
when an animation starts or when it ends.
And vue gives you an opportunity to do that as well.
It gives you various events,
which are emitted by this transition component
during a transition.
So when the transition starts,
when an element is added or when an element is removed
from the Dom
and I will show it here on this transition wrapping,
this paragraph.
We can listen to various events here
with v-on or the short and, the @ symbol
and the first event to which we can list here
is before-enter.
Here, we can run a code which will be executed
when the element which is wrapped, this paragraph,
in this case is about to enter.
So when the enter animation starts,
so in the end, you could say,
this runs whenever this enter from CSS class is being added.
So right at the beginning, when the element is added
and the animation starts.
Now, I'll add a couple of methods here,
which allow us to print something to the console,
so that we can see this all in action in the console.
And here I have beforeEnter,
now this method name is up to you.
It doesn't have to be beforeEnter.
Here, adjust once to console.log beforeEnter.
So that we see that we uh, reached this event.
Now we can point at beforeEnter here
at this newly added method on the beforeEnter event.
Again, the method name is up to you.
The event name isn't beforeEnter,
it's one of the built in events transition emits
and if we saved that and we opened the developer tools
with the JavaScript console here in the browser,
if I click toggle paragraph,
we see beforeEnter being printed.
So that works.
Now, if I remove the paragraph,
we don't see beforeEnter again,
because it's only firing when the element enters.
So when the enter animation is played.
Of course, we can also listen to the leaving though
with @before-leave just as we have beforeEnter,
we can also listen to that event or the point of time
when that element that is wrapped is leaving the Dom.
So here we can also add a before-Leave method
where we then console.log beforeLeave.
Well, and of course we can now point at this method here
on our @before-leave event handler.
If we saved this, reload,
if I click toggle paragraph, we've got beforeEnter,
if I click it again, we got beforeLeave.
Now you actually also get an argument in those methods
automatically by vue.
And that is the element hence we'll name it  here,
on which this animation runs.
If I console.log here and also here in beforeLeave
and save that and reload,
you will notice the difficulty toggle paragraph.
It's printing the paragraph,
which was added at the same for removing it.
So if you need to do something with that element,
for example, change its styling In case you want to control
the Animation Fruit JavaScript,
something we're going to do in the next lecture,
by the way, then you can do this with help of the element,
which you get automatically as argument
when listening to beforeEnter and beforeLeave.
But beforeEnter and beforeLeave is not everything we have.
We also have an @enter event to which we can listen.
This is basically the equivalent to the Active CSS Class.
The enter event is triggered as a next step
then beforeEnter is done, you could say.
Now here, I want to trigger an enter method,
which doesn't exist yet, but which I'll of course add now.
Here, let's say I add, enter()
and I console.log(enter) here.
We also get the element here,
So it would be also we could interact with it here
If we wanted to enable console.log(el).
If we now saved it and reload,
if I toggle the paragraph we see beforeEnter first
and the paragraph, and then we see enter and the paragraph.
And of course we can also listen
to when the animation finishes with @after-enter.
And here, I want to trigger an afterEnter method,
which we have yet to add.
This will fire whenever the animation is done,
the entering animation.
So here, I will add an afterEnter method,
console.log (afterEnter)
and here we also get the element.
So if I print that here, saved it and reload,
click toggle paragraph,
you see, we got beforeEnter first, then enter
and then afterEnter.
Now we have a quick animation here,
So it looked like afterEnter was basically called directly
after enter
but actually it waits for the animation to finish
until afterEnter gets called.
And I can show this by going to .para-enter-active
and ramping this up to two seconds, let's say.
Keep in mind that vue will read this duration.
Vue analyzes this duration
and it knows how long the animation will take.
It will add the CSS classes appropriately,
and it will also trigger those events appropriately.
And now afterEnter will only be called after two seconds
when the animation completed.
So now if I reload here and click toggle paragraph,
we only see enter here
and only after two seconds,
we see after enter being printed
because that only is called when the animation finishes.
And of course we have the equivalence for removing.
I'll restructure this to make it a bit easier to read.
We already added beforeLeave
but of course we now also have "leave"
where I want to call @leave method and @after-leave
which is called when the "leave" transition finished,
here, I want to call an afterLeave method.
So now we can add those methods as well.
Here, I'll add a leave method where we also get the element
where we can console.log
and then console.log[el]
and we've got the afterLeave method
where we also get the element
and then we can console.log[afterLeave] here
and also if you want to console.log[el].
With all of that, if we saved this and reload,
if I toggle the paragraph we got beforeEnter and enter
and after Enter.
And if I clear to console now and toggle it again,
we got beforeLeave, leave and afterLeave.
So this is how we can listen to that
and that allows you to run any code you want
in reaction to your animation.
This can be useful for a lot of things
but you can specifically also use it
to control the entire animation with JavaScript
instead of CSS if you want to do that.
And that's something we'll explore in the next lecture.