So let's now build an entire animation with JavaScript
instead of CSS.
And it will do that for this paragraph.
Therefore, I will actually remove all
those para dash classes.
I will simply delete them here
so that we no longer use those CSS classes
to control how this is being animated.
Instead, I now want to use JavaScript for that.
And that is something which is also supported by
the transition component.
Now typically, you will most often use CSS,
but using JavaScript instead can be useful
if you, for example, wanna use
a third party JavaScript based animation library
like GreenSock.
GreenSock has nothing to do with Vue,
but it is a powerful JavaScript library for orchestrating
and building animations, complex animations with JavaScript.
And that then would be a use case
where you might wanna build
your entire transition with JavaScript,
because you might want to leverage a library like this.
But even without such a library, you can use JavaScript
to animate this paragraph here, for example.
And that's exactly what we'll do now.
For that, we already added all those hooks
and you will need those hooks here.
You will need them because building an animation
with JavaScript requires those hooks here.
Because to some extent, they will still be called
even if you have no CSS code.
Even if you have no CSS Animation.
If I reload here, for example, and keep in mind
that I removed the CSS classes which were added previously.
We still see beforeEnter and afterEnter being called.
We have no actual transition.
Everything is instant, but those hooks are still called.
So those events on the transition component
are always emitted when the wrapped element is added
or removed to the DOM.
But without any CSS code that controls the animation,
they just execute instantly after each other.
Because of course, there is nothing to wait for.
But that's something we can change with JavaScript now.
For that and before enter, we could set up our
initial animation state.
For example, here, we could reach out to this element,
which is the element on
which we want to perform the animation.
And we could set a style here.
We could set the style property here
and give it an opacity of zero.
This is a way of programmatically setting the opacity off
this element to zero initially.
This is Vanilla JavaScript,
which we also can use here in Vue.
Now that's my initial style.
In enter, I now want to change this to one,
but not instantly, but over a certain duration.
And that's something we can build
by calling setInterval here.
SetInterval is a built-in JavaScript function,
which allows us to execute code every few milliseconds.
The second argument here is the amount of milliseconds
we wanna wait until the next code execution.
And here we could use 20.
At the first argument is a function
which will now be executed every 20 milliseconds.
And here we could gradually change the opacity.
We can do this by using our element
and setting its opacity,
but now not to a hard coded value,
but to a dynamically derived value.
And to dynamically derive a value based on
the number of intervals we already completed
or the number of function executions we already completed,
we can keep track of the current round, you could say.
Add a little helper variable named around here.
Start at one and set the opacity equal to round times
0.1, for example.
So in round one, we set it to 10% opacity.
In the next round, we'll set it to 20%.
Now we just need to increment the round
every time interval is called every time
this function is called by setInterval.
And we need an exit condition
and check if round is greater than 10,
at which point we already reached 100% opacity.
And if that's the case,
I want to call clearInterval and clear this interval.
We can do this by storing the interval,
or a unique ID pointing at that interval you could say,
in a constant and passing this to clearInterval.
So now the interval will be cleared,
will be stopped if we exceeded 10 rounds.
And now we should animate this over time.
But with that alone, we'll have a small problem.
It will work I will say that.
If I reload, we can see that the paragraph fades in, right?
That is something you can see.
And if it's too fast, you can slow it down
by only increasing this by 1%, let's say
and waiting for 100 rounds.
Now we'll wait two seconds in the end
until this is fully visible.
So if you save that and reload.
Now this fades in slowly here.
But you'll notice a problem here on the right.
If I reload, clear to console and click Toggle Paragraph,
it fades in over two seconds, but afterEnter
is actually called right at the start.
Watch again.
I click Toggle Paragraph
and afterEnter is called right away.
This might or might not matter to you.
Maybe it does not matter to you.
Maybe you don't care about this.
But actually the order is wrong as you can tell;
it's called too early.
And in some cases this might matter.
And this is not a bug.
But instead Vue has no chance of knowing
when it should call afterEnter.
To us it's obvious.
I mean, we're done with enter, once we in the end
make it into this if condition.
But that's something view doesn't really understand.
That's way too logical.
It doesn't parse and try to understand our code
and our reasons behind writing that code.
Instead, we have to tell you when we're done here.
And for that, enter,
actually receives a second argument automatically.
And that's a done function, which you can call whenever
you want to signal to Vue that you are done in this hook.
You don't need to call it
if you're having CSS-based animations
because then Vue is able to read the duration
in the CSS code.
But if you're not using CSS, if you have your own logic
and the duration is simply just made up
by incrementing round and checking this condition
and having a certain interval time here,
then you need to call done explicitly
to let Vue know when you're done.
So here after clearInterval, we call done.
We call this done argument as a function
to let you know when we're done.
If I reload here.
Now we can toggle the paragraph and you see afterEnter
is now really only called at a later point of time
once we are indeed done.
And this is now how you can control animations
with JavaScript.
And of course, we're not limited to controlling
the enter animation with JavaScript.
We can also write something similar for leaving.
And definitely feel free to write the equivalent for
this enter animation for the leave case.
So basically the opposite going from one to zero.
Here is a quick pause for you to pause the video
and try this on your own.
And there often will do it together.
So were are you successful?
Let's try to gather now.
And for that here in leave, I will basically use
the same logic as I had here for entering.
I'll copy this entire code and bring it over to leave.
But I'll do the opposite here.
I will basically
set my opacity to one minus this calculation,
so that we start at one and I reduce it
and they're all after we can leave
the rest of the code as it is.
However, in before leave, I of course also want to set
the initial opacity to one, though that is a bit redundant
because that is our end state and our initial state of
the rendered and attached element anyways.
Nonetheless, we can set it here to be very clear about
the fact that this is our starting state
for the leave animation.
And of course, we all need to accept this done argument here
in the leave method, so that we can call it here
when we are done.
Now, we can also of course,
work with different timings here,
a different amount of rounds if we wanted to.
But I'll leave everything as it is.
And with that, if I reload,
I can toggle the paragraph to animate it in.
And then I can also animate it out.
And that is how you can control animations with JavaScript.
Now, by the way, if this is animating in
and I then click toggle paragraph,
again, this automatically cancel and reverses it.
However, you'll also see it flickers a little bit.
And it's flickering, because in the end
it's playing two animations at the same time.
If we cancel the first animation that effectively just means
that the leave animation starts before
the entering animation finished or the other way around.
So then both animations are playing at the same time
resulting in that flickering which you saw here.
And that's also something we can prevent.
Because there is another useful event which is emitted by
the transition component.
And that is the enter dash canceled event
and the leave canceled event.
And here we can execute methods which are called whenever
the animation is canceled.
And by the way, those events are always emitted
when it's canceled, no matter if you are writing your logic
with JavaScript as we're doing it here.
Or if you would be using CSS as we did before.
Whenever one transition isn't finished,
when you start a new a transition,
the respective canceled event will be emitted.
So here we can have an enterCanceled method
and a leaveCanceled method that should be called.
Now let's add those two methods therefore.
EnterCanceled
and leaveCanceled.
And of course here we can also log
something to the console.
We also get the element here and we could change it.
But I want to do one important thing here.
If the enter animation gets canceled,
I want to cancel my enter interval here,
this interval, immediately before it completes.
So that it's not just cleared if the rounds reach 100
but that I also clear it if enterCanceled is triggered.
So that the enter animation is immediately canceled
when the leaf animation starts.
And I want to do the same in leaveCanceled.
The problem is that we store our interval in constants,
which are part of the enter and the leave methods.
So these constants are only available
inside of these methods and not available
inside of enter and leave canceled.
But the solution is simple.
These are regular methods in the methods property, right?
So, in the end, we can just use data property
to store those intervals.
And we can have our enterInterval here,
which initially is null.
And our leaveInterval, which initially is null.
And now we store the interval we create here
in the Enter method
in this enterInterval.
And we cleared this enterInterval here
and we do the same in the leave method.
There we store the interval in this leaveInterval.
And we cancel this leaveInterval.
We'll face a little problem here
because here we're accessing this leaveInterval
and this enterInterval inside of a nested function.
And in there to this keyword will unfortunately not refer to
the same thing to the Vue app object
as it does outside of this nested function.
The workaround is simple, we use an arrow function.
There to this keyword is not overwritten
and will therefore keep its context.
So make sure that in both setInterval calls
you use an arrow function.
And with that, we can now use leave and enter interval
those new data properties, also in the canceled methods.
And we can call clearInterval on this
enterInterval.
And in leaveCanceled, clearInterval on this
leaveInterval.
And if we save this,
yeah, my setup complains
that I'm never using the L property.
Well therefore for completeness sake, I will log it here.
Alternatively you omit it if you don't need it.
But I will just leave it here so that it is clear
that we would be getting it.
Log it here, save it, everything it saves now.
And now if I click Toggle Paragraph and click again,
now we have no flickering
because now we're canceling this.
We're clearing the interval and we're going back
to removing this therefore.
So this is now enter and leave canceled
that these events exist and what you can do with them.