Now, we saw JavaScript based animations in action
with help of these special events,
and I just want to emphasize again
that these events are always emitted,
no matter if you control your animation
with JavaScript or not.
If you control it with CSS, as we did before,
those events are also emitted,
so that you can run any code you want.
But you can also leverage those events,
as you saw in the last lecture,
to control the entire animation through JavaScript,
either through your own JavaScript code, as we did it,
or by using another third party,
JavaScript animation library, for example.
Now, if you control your entire animation
through JavaScript,
as we're doing it here on this paragraph now,
you can add another property on this transition.
Instead of setting a name, which we don't need now,
you can add the CSS prop
and bind it to false.
Now, what does this do?
This tells vue that this transition
controlled by this transition component
on this paragraph will not use CSS.
It will not use a CSS transition
or a CSS animation defined in CSS code.
Instead, the entire transition will be controlled
through JavaScript.
And why is this a helpful piece of information
we can pass to you?
It's technically not required, as you saw it worked.
But now by passing this prop,
we tell vue that it doesn't even need to search
for the respective CSS classes
in our CSS code for this transition.
It doesn't even need to try to read the duration
from our CSS code, because it won't find it,
because we're not using CSS code.
Therefore, it skips this CSS analysis step,
it skips searching for the respect of CSS classes
and the duration of this animation in CSS.
And that simply improves performance a little bit,
because it doesn't need to do this unnecessary step.
Hence, you should of course only add CSS false,
if you really don't use CSS code for this transition.
And for example,
on the other transition user that we have here,
like on these two alternative buttons,
we absolutely must not set CSS to false,
because there we are relying on
CSS transitions and animations.
But if you don't do that,
if you just control your animation through JavaScript only,
then you can set CSS to false, to optimize performance.
With that, we reload.
This still works as before,
but now even a bit more performant.
Will not notice the difference here,
but it is there, and tiny things like that
can make your app faster in the end.