Now up to this point, we always added
the addition or removal off just one element.
I mean, even with the two buttons here,
it was about having just one button active
on the page at the same time.
But sometimes you also have the lists of data,
which you want to animate.
So you have multiple list items
and you might wanna animate this
and thankfully Vue got you covered for that as well.
I'll add a new component ListData.vue
the name of course is up to you
and I'm just using the new component
to keep the code split up and keep it manageable,
since App.vue is already a large component
with a lot of code in there.
So ListData.vue is a simple component.
We'll have an unordered list in there
and we'll have a little bit of dummy list data
in our component object here.
Now it's up to you, which data you want here.
I will have a users key
and have 'Max', 'Manu', 'Julie'
'Angela' and 'Michael' here as names,
but you can of course add as many names as you want.
Now, my goal is of course,
to output those items here in a list
so we can use v-for to loop through to users
so "user in users"
also add a key and point at user,
since we have unique values in there
and output the user name here then.
So it's a very simple list.
It also doesn't have any fancy styling at the moment.
Now we can go to App.vue
and import it here as a local component, for example,
so let's quickly import.
ListData or actually let's name it UsersList
makes a bit more sense, I guess.
So let's import UsersList
from './components/UsersList.vue'
and then as you learned it
and did it multiple times in the course,
we can register it as a local component here, UsersList.
And now that it is imported and registered,
maybe here at the very top,
we can add a new div with class container
and then render our UsersList component here,
the newly added component.
With that we got our user's list up here.
Now let's add a little bit of styling
to make it look a little bit nicer
in the UsersList.vue file.
We can add a scoped style tag here
and on the unordered list I'll set list-style to none
to remove the bullet point,
set the margin: 0 and to padding: 0
And every individual list item
is then style by giving it a border of 1px solid
and a light gray color
and a padding off 1rem
and I'll set the text-align here
to center to center, to text.
And now that is the list we have here.
Now, this is a very simple list and at the moment
it's not animated at all.
Let's make sure we can now add and remove items to it,
and then let's make sure that we can animate this
because that's something that's missing
in all the examples we solve throughout this course.
So to make sure new items can be added
in UsersList.vue in the template
below my unordered list.
I'll add another div here simply as a rapper
and then have an input element here of type text.
And a button where it say Add User.
And the ideal of course is that we take
whatever was entered here and added as a user to users.
And on the other end of a list item is click
that users should be removed.
So add a click listener to a list item
and say, removeUser here and pass the user
as argument to removeUser.
And on this button on the other end,
I'll add a click listener and say, addUser.
We could also use a form here if we wanted to,
but I'll just add a good old click listener on this button.
So now we can add methods
and addUser method and removeUser method
and on removeUser we'll get the user name,
we're passing it here as an argument.
So we get it here as a parameter
and we can then set this.users = this.users.filter,
searching for the user that is equal
to the user we're getting here.
So if we got a user that's equal to the user,
we're currently looking at,
we want to filter it out,
actually by inverting this so that we keep all users
where the names are not equal
to the user we're getting here.
And if the name is equal, we return false.
Hence we filter it out
and therefore our new users is the old array minus
the user with the username we got here.
In addUser, we wanna get what the user entered here
and I'll use that ref for that userNameInput
is my ref, which I'll use here.
And then addUser.
We got the enteredUserName by reaching out
to this.$refs.userNameInput.value;
we could add validation but I wanna keep it simple.
And therefore a simply push my enteredUserName to users.
And actually I'll not push it.
I'll unshift it to add it at the top.
Now with that, if we reload,
if I click Julie, she's removed.
If I add Julie again, she's back at the beginning.
And we can always add some spacing here
by going back to the unordered list
and actually adding a margin of 1rem top
and bottom zero left and right by adding this rule here.
So now we got this in place.
You can of course optimize the styling,
but I rather wanna focus on animating now.
I wanna ensure that we animate
when an item is removed or added.
And that is something we can do with the Vue.