In the end,
what we want to do here is
we want to wrap this list item
with transition,
because we wanna animate
the addition and removal of list items,
but it will have a problem.
It's not just one list item
because of before,
we'll have multiple list items here.
And therefore, transition won't work
because transition is steered
to work with one element.
But Vue has got us covered.
It has the transition group component.
In addition to transition,
transition group,
as the name suggests,
is there to work with multiple elements
and it can also animate multiple elements
at the same time.
So it's great for lists
where in this case,
we only add or remove one user at the same time,
but of course you could have other lists
where multiple items
are added or removed at the same time.
And that is why transition group is great for lists.
It is capable of animating individual lists items,
but also multiple items at the same time.
There's one important thing you gotta know
about transition group, though.
Transition to components used before in the end,
renders no element to the Dom.
It's just here in the template
to give Vue some instructions,
but you don't see it in the actual Dom.
If we inspect show users,
which is the button we're animating,
there is no transition component here in the Dom.
Now that will be different for this list
and transition group, though.
Transition group will render
an element to the Dom in the end,
and you can control which element it is
by giving it detect prop.
And here we want to unordered list.
So we, in the end replace our wrapper here,
the unordered list
with transition group,
giving it a tag off UL,
and you can use any valid HTML element here.
You can also use a custom component here.
Now besides that
it works pretty much like transition, though.
It also adds those CSS classes
to the elements which are added
or removed.
It dives into the CSS code to see how long
an animation takes.
So here I'll add name prop
and give it a name of user list.
And that is then the prefix
in front of the enter-from,
enter-active,
enter-to clauses,
everything you already learned about.
So here in my styling,
I will now add user lists,
enter-from,
copy that,
and then also add
enter-active
and enter-to.
And now as so often,
it's totally up to you
what you want to add here.
I will add an opacity of zero here
and transform my items
to translate them along the X-axis
and move it a little bit further
to the left.
And that's my starting position
when an item is added.
In enter-to,
I will then set this to zero
and the opacity to one of course.
And in enter-active,
we can add the transition property
and watch for changes in all
CSS properties,
which might change.
And in this case only opacity
and transform will change
and then add a duration.
And I'll go for one second here
and then also an easing function
and I'll go for ease-out.
And if we do that,
you will see
if I reload and I add
Praveen, for click add user,
this is a smooth animation
for adding this element.
Now, of course,
we also get animation for removing elements
for that all,
in the end,
just copy my enter classes
and add my leave classes here.
So leave-from,
leave-to,
leave-active.
And I want to leave-from opacity one
and no change on the X-axis
and therefore,
We can also merge this with
the enter-to clause because
it's the same.
On leave-active.
I want to have an ease-in,
easing function instead of ease-out
and on leave-to,
I want to go to an opacity of zero,
but then move it 30 pixels to the right.
So it's not the same as the enter-from state.
There we had minus 30 pixels.
Here I have plus 30 pixels.
And if I do that and saved us,
if I click an item,
you see it's animated out like this,
which is nice,
but you might notice that the list jumps,
when an item is removed,
the other elements,
snap in place there after,
and thankfully,
Vue actually has a solution
for that as well.
It helps us avoid such snapping.