Now, how can vue help us
with this snapping behavior we got here,
which is not too nice to look at?
It adds a never special clause
when you're using transition group.
So when it's actually controlling multiple elements,
instead of just one.
Because you might not notice it actually,
whilst we're only adding and removing one element
at a time here,
we are animating multiple elements simultaneously
because the other elements also need
to switch their position when a new item is added.
And that's why we use transition group.
It is capable of animating multiple elements.
And it gives us a special clause therefore
which allows us to control the animation
of the other elements,
which are not getting added or removed,
but which also might need to move around
to make place for the new element
or to fill up the space of the leaving element.
And the special clause we add here is our prefix.
So user list in this case,
since that's the prefix we defined here
with the name property,
and then
dash move.
That's another special CSS clause,
which vue will add to all the other elements,
which are not entering or leaving.
And even better than that,
vue will automatically move them
to their new place under the hood,
by using the transform CSS property.
That's just something you have to know.
Vue will use transform under the hood
for moving the elements,
which are not added or removed around to their new position.
And therefore, here in the move class,
we can actually transition the transform property
on those elements.
Let's say over dot eight seconds with a ease function.
So just ease to distribute the time evenly.
Now, if we save that and go back,
we'll be able to see that if we reload and add a new user.
Praveen, for example.
You see the upper elements move smoothly
to their new position.
Now, if you reload and try this for removing though,
we still have this snapping behavior.
There's one thing we got to fix for that to work
on the leave active clause.
So, which is added to the leaving element.
We need to add a position of absolute.
Once we add that to the leaving element, and I reload,
now you'll see the other elements move as well.
And they move to their new position.
Now, the rest of the page jumps
but that's something we can't avoid here.
But inside of that list,
we have a smooth animation for entering items.
But also for leaving items
and for the rest of the list for all the items
that need to move to a new position.
And that is how transition group can help us here.
It allows us to animate items in a list,
multiple items at the same time,
it allows us to move items smoothly,
even if they're not directly affected.
So even if they're not the added or removed item.
And therefore, it is the component you should use
if you want to add multiple items.
If you have one item or two alternating items you want
to animate, transition
is the component you should use.
Because that component is optimized
for animating single items
or alternating items like these two buttons.