By now we get a pretty good understanding
about how Vue helps us with animating things.
There's one specific kind of thing
which you might want to navigate,
which we haven't seen thus far though.
And that would be changes between two routes.
For that, I'll quickly add routing here,
simply by adding a new pages folder.
And then in here we could have AllUsers page, let's say,
and also a CourseGoals page.
I will not really populate those components with life
or with real values,
I just want to dive into how we can animate
between these pages.
For that, here I'll simply add a div
with a class of container in the template off AllUsers.
And add a h2 tag where I say All Users.
And I'll then copy that
and add the same here to CourseGoals,
but of course here I will say CourseGoals
so that we can tell these two pages apart.
So these are very simple dummy components
which just have templates.
Now we can quit the development server with Control + C,
and npm install, dash, dash, save the vue-router.
This package, which we already installed
in the routing module.
Once it is installed, we can restart the development server
and then add routing as you learned it
in the routing module.
So here in main.js or in a separate router.js file.
But since we'll only have two routes, I'll go with main.js.
You can import createRouter from vue-router
and also already import createWebHistory
and then set up the router here.
So here we have the router we created with createRouter
and pass a config object to createRouter.
Set the history two to result of createWebHistory.
And then add our routes.
And I gonna have two routes here.
The first route should be applied if we have slash, nothing.
In this case, I want to load the AllUsers component.
Therefore, we should import it,
AllUsers from dot, slash, pages/AllUsers.vue.
And we can also already import CourseGoals
from dot, slash, pages/CourseGoals.vue.
Then load AllUsers here on this first route.
And then add a second route
with a path of slash, goals, let's say,
where we want to load the CourseGoals component.
So these are the two routes I have here.
Now we can call app.use to register this router
with our Vue app.
And with that, Vue is aware of these routes.
Now, as you learned that in order to load a route
and to display it, we need to go to our App.vue file,
and in there I will actually remove all the content
we had in there and just add router-view
so that we just switched between these two components
based on which route we selected.
In order to move back and forth between these components
from inside the running app,
I will actually also go to AllUsers
and add a router link to my CourseGoals.
So therefore, the two prop points at slash, goals,
because that was the path I'm handling here.
And I will copy that.
And in CourseGoals I'll add the same link,
but I'll go to just slash here,
which therefore goes to AllUsers.
If we save that, I got some complaints here
that I'm not using
the users list component anymore in App.vue.
And that's correct, I'm registering it here,
but I'm not doing anything with it in my template.
So we can comment this out and remove this import
or remove the components option entirely here.
And now with that saved, we see All Users
and we can switch between those routes.
That's all nice, but it has nothing to do with animations.
Well, I want to animate the transition
between these two routes.
And thankfully we can do this.
Now, one thought you could have
is that you wrap your router-view with transition.
I mean, it's a regular component.
And if we want to animate with Vue's help
between two components, like the button we saw earlier,
then we wrap the element with transition, right?
That's what we did previously in this course
when we wanted to animate components.
And we could then defines a new CSS classes here.
Route-enter-from.
Route-enter-active.
And route-enter-to.
And I want to use that animation,
so I will actually only use route-enter-active
and use my slide scale animation,
the key frames which are set here,
over .4 seconds and with an ease function
or ease out, let's say.
And then also define route-leave-active.
Of course, depending on which animation you want to build,
you could also add route-leave-from and route-leave-to.
But here I again, just want to apply an animation.
And that will be a slide scale
over the same duration with ease in.
And now, since I named these CSS classes
like this with route,
we could apply this name to this transition like that.
But since I always say could, and so on,
this probably is not how it's going to work.
And indeed, we do have some strange behavior here,
but we actually see that router-view can no longer be used
directly inside of transition.
Now, it says no longer,
because previously with older versions of Vue,
that did work.
So maybe if you learned that,
you are still used to this old way of doing it.
With Vue 3 this is no longer possible.
And we actually get the solution
here in the warning as well.
We need to restructure our code.
Transition now needs to go inside of our router-view.
So we should move transition inside there.
But this alone now all the won't do it
because while router-view supports getting content
that will be rendered inside of it,
now we also need to tell it
where to actually render the actual page,
the actual component that should be rendered
based on the route that is active.
And for that, we can use the scoped slots syntax
router-view uses under the hood.
Normally we don't need it,
but for transitions with routes, you do need it.
You can use this v-slot directive,
which I introduced earlier in the course
when we talked about slots,
to extract the slotProps you're getting here.
You get those by the router-view component,
which is built in.
And you can then use the dynamic component component
to bind it to slotProps.Component.
So slotProps have a property named Component
with a capital C, which holds the component
that should be loaded for the currently selected route.
And this strange looking syntax is what you need
to animate switches between these components.
If you now save this, you no longer get the warning.
And now this kind of works,
but of course this looks really stupid here, right?
I mean, it's just moving around
and we got two components on the page at the same time.
So this is not fully what we want,
but technically this is correct at least.
But one thing we want to change here
is something we already saw earlier
when we switched between two buttons.
We want to make sure that only one component
is shown on the page at the same time.
And you might remember that we can achieve this
by adding the mode prop to the transition component.
And there we add out-in and in-out.
And if we use out-in, we ensure that first,
the leaving component is animated
before then the entering component is animated.
So with that, if I reload,
now this leaves and then we have the new component.
I will admit it still looks strange,
but that's just because of the animation CSS code we set up.
If we use a different animation,
like the fade button classes we have here,
if I use this as a name here, fade button,
this will look nicer.
With that we've got a nice fade animation
between these routes.
So that is how you can animate route transitions.
Now, one thing you might have noticed before
is that when you used that other animation
which looked a bit strange, the route animation here,
we even saw that animation when we loaded the page
for the first time.
So you have this initial animation.
The reason for data's that with the vue-router,
technically the first act of route is an empty route.
And then when your page starts,
when your page is loaded for the first time,
it immediately switches to the route that should be used
for the given path in your URL.
That means that technically when the app starts,
the vue-router goes from no route
to the chosen route for to given path.
And hence it plays an animation
because we go from one component, nothing,
to the to be loaded component.
To avoid this behavior, you can go to main.js
where you register the router
and there you can actually use the router
to call the is ready method on it.
This method will let you know
when the router successfully evaluated
which page should be loaded.
This gives you a promise and hence you can call then on it.
And in the function you pass to this then block,
in this function the router will now not go
from the empty to the to be selected page.
But instead, at this point of time,
it is aware of the page that should be loaded
and it will therefore not make this initial transition.
So you can then mount your app inside of this function
to only mount and therefore render your app
once the router is fully set up and aware of the page
that should be loaded.
And if you do that and reload,
you don't have this initial animation.
Now you just have it if you switch routes.
And now I'm going back to the other animation
since that looked nicer,
so to the fade button animation here.
But that is it.
That is how you can animate the transition
between different routes.
It's a strange looking syntax maybe,
but you really only needed for this transition scenario.
But with that, you're now able to also animate changes
between different pages.