In this course module,
we are going to explore the biggest
addition Vue 3 introduced.
So the biggest change from Vue version two to three,
in case you're interested in that
we're going to explore the Composition API.
The Composition API gives us a different way of building
our components of writing our component code.
But I will already say not a totally different way.
The template, the styling that stays the way it is,
the props and custom events concepts
that stays the way it is.
the JavaScript code you write that,
however, changes if you use the Composition API,
and I will also already say
the Composition API is 100% optional.
You don't have to use it.
I'm not teaching you everything I taught you thus far
in the course, just to now tell you that it's obsolete.
No, what you'll learn thus far
is the basis of Vue and absolutely fine,
but you can move to this new Composition API,
or even mix it with what you learned thus far,
if you like to.
But with that, let's get there step by step.
In this module,
I will start by explaining
what exactly the Composition API is
and why it exists.
Why we have these two different ways of building components.
We'll then understand the Composition API.
We will learn how to work with it
and how to write code with it.
And of course,
I will show you how you could move from the Options API,
which is the name of the approach we used thus far
in the course to the Composition API, if you want it to.
So let's dive in.