So let's now dive into the Composition API.
I already mentioned that we're talking about data,
methods, computed and watch,
that we're talking about these four options,
from the Options API,
which will now be handled differently
in the Composition API.
These four options are in the end,
going to be replaced with code
we're going to write in the new setup option.
A new setup method, we can add to our object
our component or Vue app configuration object.
On the other hand,
that means that all the other options we also learned about.
Props emits, components,
those remain untouched by the Composition API.
So there, nothing changes
what you learn about these options does not change.
The only other part which will also change,
which is not on this slide,
will be the lifecycle methods,
but I'll come back to those later.
Now let's start with data,
and let's see how we replace data
with the Composition API and this setup method.
For this attached you find a very simple project.
It just has one app, a Vue file at the moment.
Which is also very simple.
I'm just out putting a userName here,
which for the moment is hard-coded into my data option.
But it's still the date of option,
so we're not using the Composition API yet.
Got some styling here
and if you install all the dependencies
and then start your development server with npm run serve,
you see this here on the screen.
Now let's see what the equivalent
to this data option would be, if we used a Composition API
And therefore I'll comment data out and instead,
the first thing I'll do is I will add this setup method.
This is this new method we can add since Vue version three,
in our component config objects.
And again, if we had something like
local components registered in the components option,
or if we had props here, that would remain untouched,
that would stay here.
But we now added setup
and now the goal is to replace the data we managed here,
so userName, with something new,
so that we still can output it in the template.
And there we got two new features offered by Vue,
that help us with managing data.
We need to import them from Vue,
so we need to add the import statement
to import something from Vue
and the something would be put between a curly braces here
is ref.
Now, this is a import sin tax,
which imports one of many things exported by Vue
and here were importing ref.
Now what's ref?
We learned about refs earlier in the course.
For the moment, let's ignore that,
ref is slightly related to what we learned about refs
in the past,
but still on the other hand, it's something new.
So let's ignore would be know about refs thus far.
It's a different concept here,
because red is a function which we now can call
inside of setup.
And ref creates a so-called reference
but now not just a reference to some DOM element
but instead, a value which we can reference,
which we can use in our template for example.
So ref creates a value, but not any kind of value.
Instead a reactive value,
where Vue will find out when we change it.
Where Vue is able to watch it
and where Vue then is able to update the template
at the DOM, when that value changes
and is being used in the template.
But ref like this actually does nothing.
It creates a value as I mentioned,
so we should store it in some variable or constant.
And we are not going to use the this keyword here,
because whilst it technically would be available,
in the setup method,
since this is still a method in this object,
this here is actually
not referring to the Vue config object
as it does in methods, for example.
Because setup is a method executed by Vue very early
during the component initialization process.
At a point of time,
where this component hasn't been initialized yet
and therefore this actually won't give us access
to all the things we're used to.
It doesn't give us access to props if we had any and so on.
So we don't use this here in the setup method.
And we're not going to store this value in a property
of this overall config object.
Instead were just going to store it
in a plain vanilla variable or constant
and here and going for a constant
and I will name it userName
so now the ref thing here is stored in this constant.
Now I said ref creates a reactive value
but what is the actual value here?
We might wanna store a number or in this case a string,
our name.
Well you can pass the actual value which you wanna store,
as our argument to this ref function.
So here I'll pass Maximilian
and this now creates a reactive string you could say,
under the hood, it creates an object.
This string is stored in that object
and Vue will watch this object,
so that whenever we assign a new value
instead of that original string.
Vue will be aware of it and is able to update the DOM.
But step-by-step, at the moment this code simply won't work.
If we try to save this we get an error.
That userName is created, but never used.
And it's true, we have that userName constant,
but we're not doing anything with it.
You might think that we're using it here in the template
but actually that's not how it works.
It was the case with the options API
that you had access to all your data properties,
your computed properties and your methods,
in the DOM just like that.
This is not the case for some constants
you might have in you're setup method.
If you have a constant here,
it's not available in your DOM, in your template.
Instead you need to do one extra step.
You need to return what you want to expose
to the template of this component
this config object belongs to.
And you always return an object here.
So in setup, you return an object
and into this object we'll put all the things
we wanna expose to the template.
So here we want to access a userName thing
and therefore in this returned object
we should add a userName key
and the value we wanna store under that key,
is the value stored in this constant.
Which is all the names, userName
but we could have chose a different name here.
And to avoid confusion, let's maybe name this uName
and therefore all the name are uName here.
So here I'm referring to this constant.
Here I'm naming this userName
because I'm accessing userName in my template.
And what I expose in this returned object
is now available in this template
and if I save this now, and reload,
everything works and we see Maximilian here, on our page.
So that's how we create and store a value
with the Composition API.
We use this ref method.
Now, actually you wouldn't even need the ref method,
if I remove it and I store a normal string here.
If I save that, I get an error that I'm importing ref
and I'm not using it,
so let's com it out the import real quick,
but then if I saved that it, then all the words.
So why do I need ref then?
Well because I already said that this,
if we created with ref, would be a reactive value
and that's the next thing I want to show you here.
Let's say we have a timer here.
We use set timeout, which is built into the browser
and after two seconds, we execute a function here.
And in this function I wanna assign a new value
to my uName constant.
Now here's how we're not going to do it.
We're not going to say uName equal your new value.
For one, that's not allowed because this is a constant.
Of course we could turn it into a variable
and now we could assign a new value,
but now we would overwrite the old ref
with a simple new string, so we would lose the ref.
And you want a ref
because the ref has some built-in mechanisms
to let Vue know about changes to that value
because if we do it like this,
you will notice that if I saved this
and I reload, after two seconds,
nothing happens on the screen.
We always see Maximilian here.
Never Max, now I do assign a new value to uName
after two seconds,
but this new value is never picked up by Vue.
The setup method only runs once,
so we never return a new object
with the new value to the template.
And that's exactly why we need a ref
and that's what we can use a const
because I'm never going to assign a new value
to uName like this.
Instead, we can use uName which holds this ref
and acts as a value property.
I mentioned that the ref function creates an object
and under the hood, that's an object with a value property.
The value, you pass to the ref function here.
Is stored under that value property.
And you can assign the new value,
queue this value property, in this uName object.
For example, Max.
And if you do that, then Vue will pick it up
and will update the DOM and the template.
You see this changes to Max after two seconds
and that's why we use a ref here.
it's a reactive value and we can manage any value here.
A string, a number, a bullion, whatever you want.
Vue will watch it and will pick up changes
to reflect them in the DOM as it does here.
Now one word about the template here by the way.
You don't access dot value here,
because Vue will automatically drill into that value prop
if you expose a ref in your return object
in the setup method.
So here userName points at a ref
and we need to use the value property,
if we wanna set a new value.
But if we pass our ref to the template,
Vue will automatically read the value property,
so in the template you don't use dot value
but just the ref as a whole and Vue will do the rest.