So now we introduced the ref,
which creates reactive values.
Which are values watched by Vue where changes are picked up
to be reflected in the template.
Now, let's add a second value.
Let's say, besides the username,
we also wanna output the age year.
So for that, we can simply create a uAge constant,
for example, and a second ref, with a number, for example.
And now here, I also expose age here in my object
and I'm using age as a key
because I'm using age here in the template.
And the value for age is uAge.
And if we do that, we also see the age here.
And of course we could now also change the age year
in our timer if we want to.
We can assign a new value after two seconds
so that if we reload after two seconds
both the name and the age change.
Now since we have two pieces of data,
name and age, which kind of belong together,
we could also consider grouping them together.
So here, instead of creating two refs
with two individual values, we could create a user,
constant, and create a ref here which holds an object.
And in an object we have a name, Maximilian
and we have a age, 31.
So now we still have a reactive value,
but now it's a object where we grouped the data together
instead of having two separate values.
Now we could expose the username
by getting it from user.value.name.
Keep in mind, user is a ref therefore
it has a value property
and the value holds the actual value we stored here
so the object with the name property.
And here we have user.dot.value.age
and here in setTimeout,
instead of changing these two individual values,
we now set user.value.name equal to Max
and set user.value.age equal to 32.
And if we save that and reload, we see Maximilian and 31,
but after two seconds, nothing happens.
The data doesn't update here.
Well, there is a reason for that.
When you create a ref with the ref function,
you get an object, Vue gives you an object.
We can see this if we console.log it here with console log,
if I reload, that's our ref object
and there we got this value property
in which we actually got such a proxy.
You might note this proxy from the behind the scenes module
we had earlier in the course.
We also have a getter and a setter
on this entire ref object.
With those, Vue keeps track of read and write access
to the value property so that if you, for example,
access user.value and you assign a brand new object
Vue is able to pick up this change.
But in addition, if you pass an object as a value to ref
that object is also wrapped by a proxy so that Vue is
even able to keep track of internal changes in that object.
So for example here, when you drill into the object
and you assign a new name and age, as we're doing it here.
Nonetheless, as you also could see
Vue was not able to update the screen,
even though I'm just telling you
that it would pick up those changes.
The problem is, how we pass that to our template.
Here we also drill deeply into this object
with user dot value, we access the object stored in our ref
and then the name and the age properties.
And that's the problem we'll have here
name and age, these properties in there,
the values of name and age so all of those properties
are just regular strings and numbers.
These are not reactive values.
So therefore, whilst Vue will indeed theoretically
be possible to tell that something changed about user,
it does not understand that we're in the end exposing user
to our template because we're drilling into user like this.
So all it sees is that we expose a string and a number.
And since it doesn't track those specific values,
it's not detecting any changes there.
Now one thing we could do here, is we could provide
the entire user object here.
So our user ref under a user key to the template
and output that there.
If I for example add a paragraph here temporarily,
I can output user now because we're exposing
this user key here and if I do so,
indeed you will see my object here and you'll see
it also changed after two seconds.
Here you go.
And therefore, we could of course also output user.name
or user.age here.
So drill into this object here in the template
and now it would work if I reload,
after two seconds it updates.
Because now I still drill into this,
but only in the template, I pass the raw object,
the raw ref object to the template here
in my return statement of the setup function.
And that is what matters to Vue.
With that it gets this raw ref object.
It has all the reactivity that's in this object and it knows
when we assign a new value and it knows
that we're using this in a template
so then it goes ahead, finds the places in the template
where we use this object and updates that code.
And that is how we would use ref correctly
with an object instead of separate values.
But if you are working with an object,
there actually is a better alternative to ref.
Instead of using ref, which you could use like this.
And of course, by the way, you could now delete all of that.
Exposing just the user would be enough,
but instead of using ref, you can now also import
the reactive function, which is all provided by Vue.
Reactive is a bit like ref,
but it's explicitly made for objects.
So now instead of ref, we call reactive
and you still pass your object to reactive.
But where ref worked with any kind of value, strings,
numbers and objects, reactive only works with objects here.
So you must pass an object to reactive.
And now reactive does one important thing.
It doesn't wrap this with an extra object
which has a value prop, which then points at your value.
Instead it makes this object which you passed to reactive,
reactive by wrapping it into a proxy
so that you can still work with this object
as if you would have just that object without any wrapper.
We can also see this soon when we see this console log,
but that means that instead of accessing
user dot value dot name and user dot value dot age,
you now access just user dot name and user dot age.
So we can skip this dot value step
because there is no wrapping object with a value property.
Since we already have an object here
and we're using reactive.
Now when it comes to exposing, we still expose it
as we did it with the ref though,
we expose the entire object, we don't drill into it
to give Vue the entire reactive object.
And we can now delete those other properties
we're sharing here, and then we can use user dot name
and user dot age.
So just as before, the key difference is
that we now don't have this extra wrapper object
with the dot value property.
So just to bring this back as a comparison
before with those individual value refs,
we had uName.value equal Max
and we had uAge.value equal 32.
Now we directly work with our object as if it would be
a regular JavaScript object, but it's actually reactive.
So if you save that and reload,
we still see that it changes after two seconds.
Now one note about our console log here,
where I'm logging user, before it was this ref object
with the value property
and the getters and setters for value.
Now it's this proxy object here instead,
which wraps our object and which simply has
these internal listeners to changes to our properties.
Basically what I already covered
in the behind the scenes module.
And with that, I'll delete this console log
and leave that code because that's it for now,
when we talk about managing reactive data.
You got refs and reactive, reactive is there for objects,
refs are there for all kinds of values, including objects
if you're fine with this extra dot value access.
It's up to you which one you prefer.
If you're dealing with an object you have the choice
between reactive and refs, if you have anything
but an object, like a string or a number, it's always a ref.
It's always up to you whether you wanna group data
together into an object or manage data stand alone
as we did it before.
There is no wrong or right way here,
it depends on your preferences, the kind of data,
what the rest of your team says
and in general, your application of course.
Now you know these two important
data management concepts though,
for reactive data, ref and reactive.
And with that, let's dig deeper
and let's see what else we can do with the Composition API.