Now before we dig deeper
into the composition API,
here is an optional lecture
and I really want to emphasize this, it's optional.
You can skip this lecture for now,
proceed with the rest
and come back to it later.
I wanna explore this reactivity concept a bit more
to make sure we're all on the same page
and there are no unanswered questions here.
I hope I could make it clear,
how ref and reactive works,
that they're very similar
but that I could also make it clear
what the difference is.
I locked both to the console
and I'll do it again here
with the age here as an example
so that we can again see the difference.
So I'm logging uAge
which is a ref
and user which is a reactive object
and I need to import ref again for that
and if I do that,
if I save this
and I reload,
here our log.
The first one here,
that is our ref,
you'll see it's an object with the value prop
and in that value prop
the number is stored
and we have the getters and setters.
The object, the reactive object
is a proxy wrapped around our object
and it has those extra handlers
for dealing with data changes
so that vue is aware of them.
Now a common mistake
or something which can be hard to understand,
is that these objects,
the ref object
and the reactive object are reactive
but not the values stored in them
which is why we have to pass
the entire user object here
and not the name and age separated.
Just to make this clear again,
if I would pass user, name
and age like this to the template,
so if I drill into the user object here
and I provide that on a name and age key,
if we do this
and then try outputting name and age here,
that would work,
as you can tell
but after two seconds
it wouldn't update.
It always stays at Maximilian 31
and those changes made here
aren't picked up
and the reason for that
is that the entire object is reactive
but the values in those properties are not
and if we expose those values to the template
vue thinks that only the values matter
and not the entire object
hence it's just interested in changes to those values
and since those values are not reactive objects
and not refs,
it will never know about these changes.
That's why we had to do it differently
hence I'm reversing this to go back to the old code
where I expose the entire user
and access it in the template
but now back to this console log statement.
Here we can basically see the problem.
If I console log uAge.value
and I also console log user.name
and user.age.
If I log these three things here,
if I reload,
you see 31 Maximilian
and 31 here in the console
and these are ordinary JavaScript values.
These are not special objects
hence they have no watch mechanism attached to them.
This is what would arrive in the template
if we just return user.name
or user.age in this object down here,
what I did a second ago
and then it hopefully is clear that,
this will never change to vue.
It's just a string,
just a number.
It never changes.
Yes the object from which I extracted those values,
that object changes
but I took a snapshot of those values
before the change happened,
that's basically what I'm doing here
and that's the problem.
Now vue has helper methods here
which can help us with understanding
what's reactive and not.
It has isReactive
and that is ref function
and whenever something is reactive
or is a ref
when you expose it to the template
updates will be picked up.
Whenever that's not the case,
updates will not be picked up.
So here we can check if uAge.value is a ref
and we can check if username,
user.name I mean is reactive
and if I do that,
save this and reload,
I get false twice
and that's just what I've been talking about
over the last minutes or so.
On the other hand,
if I check the entire uAge
and the entire user object,
instead of the nested properties,
I get true twice.
So whenever we expose the entire ref
or the entire reactive object
to the template by returning it here
changes will be picked up
and reflected in the template.
It's as easy as that.
Now I'll remove this here
but it can be helpful to be aware of these helper methods
in case you wanna find out
whether something is reactive or not.
Now there actually also would be a way
of making the nested values
inside of a reactive object
reactive as well
or turn them into refs to be precise.
There is a toRefs function
which you can import from vue
and toRefs is a very simple function,
you give it an object
and it will then automatically
turn all property values into refs.
So with that,
we could get our user refs
by calling toRefs
and passing user,
so our reactive object to it,
you can pass in any object by the way
and with that,
you get back an object
which now has a name
and age property
but now the values in there will be refs.
So now I could expose userName
by accessing userRefs.name
and age by accessing userRefs.age
and we could use username
and age in the template now,
like this username and age
and if I save this
I get an error related to uAge
which I'm not using anymore
so if a comment out uAge here real quick
and ref is also on use now
and I get rid of the ref import,
it now compiles
and now if I reload
and wait for two seconds,
the update is reflected
because now not just the object is reactive
but with toRefs
we also wrapped the nested properties into refs
so that now we can also pass those properties,
those property values directly to the template
because now they are refs
and as I mentioned
if you pass a reactive object
or a ref to the template,
then changes to that value will be picked up
and reflected in the template,
otherwise they won't.
Now that was a lot of extra deep dive stuff.
As I said,
it's an optional lecture
you can come back to that later again
in case it's not entirely clear,
you won't need all of that all the time.
I'm just a fan of teaching something thoroughly
and diving deep into a topic
to give you a chance of fully understanding
what's happening behind the scenes
and why we are doing something in a certain way.
With that however,
I'm going to revert all that code here
because it's not important
for the next lectures
and I don't want to confuse you with it
so let me get rid of all of that.
Get rid of the toRefs import
and go back to user.name
and user.age here in the template
and now with that,
let's leave this deep dive
and instead see what we can do
beyond data management.