So we had to look at ref for single values
and reactive for objects if we wanna group values together
and want to ensure that we can edit properties
just like this, and still maintain reactivity.
Now, enough about ref and reactive.
We're going to see more of that
as we write more code with the Composition API.
But now let's actually come back to this simple slide here.
We learned that the data that's managed with the data option
can be replaced with ref and reactive.
Now we also have methods computed
and watch which I mentioned would be replaced.
So Let's now move on to methods here.
For that, let's say, we have a button here on this page,
and it will be a simple button with no particular styling.
And there I'll say change age.
And when we click it, I wanna change my age here.
So for that, of course, we can add a click listener.
And now, normally with the Options API,
we would point at a method here.
We would add our methods option, to this config object,
and then have something like set new age,
or any name like this.
And if we then had, age data property here,
like 31, initially,
we would set this age equal to 32, for example.
that is how we would do it with the Options API,
with data and methods combined.
Now we're using the Composition API,
and therefore we don't have data,
and we won't have methods.
But how can we then, call a function,
call some code to be executed, when an event occurs?
How do we bind click here?
Well, of course,
we could access user age,
and set a new value here.
You might remember that simple JavaScript expressions
like this, are allowed, and therefore we could do that.
So if I keep this code, and actually remove this timer,
because I no longer wanna update name and age with that,
so let's remove the timer.
So if I save that now,
we have the button, and it works.
But running all the code that should run
upon button clicks and form submissions,
in the template like this,
is definitely not what we wanna do.
It's a good practice to not put too much logic
into the template.
And if you consider more complex examples
like form submissions,
where you also wanna validate user input,
and maybe show alerts and so on,
then this absolutely would not be an option.
Instead, the solution is actually very simple,
though it might look strange when you see it the first time.
The setup method here,
is called when Vue sets up this component.
It's called only once.
And in this setup method, you basically define the data,
which should be available in your template.
Well, you cannot just define your data here,
you can also define the functions
that should be available to your template.
We can add a function here,
set new data could be the name,
and we can expose that to the template as well.
It might look strange that we define a function
(indistinct) of a method,
but this is regular JavaScript code.
We can create functions inside of functions.
This is absolutely fine.
And actually, we've set timeout before,
we did nothing different.
There we also had a function,
which we created on the fly here,
that's also just a function
to find (indistinct) of the setup method.
So defining a function here is fine,
and then this function, we could set user age equal to 32.
And now the question is, how do we expose this function,
to the template so that we can bind it to this click event?
Well, just as we expose data,
we can add a new key value pair,
to this object which we return here in the setup method
and, for example, have a set H key,
and point at set new data.
Or set new age maybe, and change the name up here as well.
And I'm not executing the function here,
I'm just pointing at it.
So I'm storing a pointer at this function,
in the set age property in this returned object.
And this returned object
simply holds all the things you can use in your template.
That may be data, like our user object,
but it may also be a pointer at a function.
So now we'll set H as the key here,
so therefore, we can bind, or click event here to set age.
And this will then trigger, the set new age function
at which we point in set age.
And therefore if I save that, and reload,
we can still change the age,
but now with this exposed function.
And that's really simple,
but this is how you expose functions
which you typically bind to click events,
but which you also can execute, just like that,
between interpolation for example.
That's how you expose them to your template.
You define them in setup and return them in your object.
And that's your replacement for methods in the end,
simple as that.
And of course, it does not just work with a reactive object,
but instead if we would go back to using refs,
so if I reverse this all,
and I go back to U name and U age
and having two refs instead of one object,
then of course we can also update our data here.
With U age value equal to 33 for example.
Now we just need to change
the code we exposed to the template,
because I went back to using two individual values.
So now we could again expose,
let's say a username and a age, like that.
Exposing these two refs, which are defined here,
where one of them has changed here,
through the value property,
which is watched by Vue as you learned.
And then in the template, we can use username,
and age to output both.
So username,
and age here.
And with that in place,
if we save this, this still works,
and updating also still works.
So that's how we can replace methods.
Of course you can define and return as many functions
as your component might need in the template.