So now we get started with ReFS
reactive and with functions which replace methods.
What about computed properties?
How can we replace those?
Again, let's expand our example here a little bit.
Let's say we actually don't just have to change Age button,
but we have a div below that below the Change Age button.
and in there we have two inputs.
The first input here,
is for the First Name.
The second input is for the Last Name.
And I want to use the values entered here
to output my userName.
Which should be combined
from first and Last Name.
Now let's see how we can implement this.
First of all, I will add two ReFS here.
I will add a firstName, ref,
which initially is an empty string.
And a lastName ref, which also is empty initially.
Of course you could have different default values,
but I will start with empty strings.
Now I want to update the firstName
whenever we type into this input,
and the lastName, whenever we type into this input.
We'll have a look at two-Way binding
and V model in a second,
for the moment I'll do it manually
by listening to, at input.
So by listening to the input event.
Now I want to trigger some code whenever this event occurs
and therefore I'll actually add a new function
setFirstName where I get the default event object.
And where I then want to setFirstName dot value,
so the value of the firstName ref
equal to event target value.
And do the same for the lastName
setLastName getting the event
and setting lastName dot value
equal to event target value.
Now we can expose these two functions
through this object to the template.
SetFirstName points at setFirstName.
And here I use the same name for the key
as I do for the variable that holds the function.
And hence we can use the modern JavaScript Shorthand,
to just use this name once,
and this will automatically be expanded
to this longer syntax by JavaScript.
This simply saves us some code which we don't have to type
and the same for setLastName.
So now these functions setFirstName
and setLastName are exposed
under these identifiers to the template.
So we can bind them, here
on the first input our point at setFirstName,
on the second one, I'll point at setLastName.
And calling these functions works just as you learned it
you can call them manually,
you can forward the event object manually then,
or you just point at them,
and let view execute those functions for you
passing on the default event object for you
when these events occur.
So regarding event listening and how you call functions
nothing changed.
But now we got these two inputs in place,
and we're updating firstName
and lastName with every keystroke.
Now, I don't really need uName anymore,
instead now I want to have a computed userName,
which is based on the first and the lastName
and which therefore should update whenever first
and lastName changes.
Now, as you might guess,
we're not going to do it is by adding the computed option.
This is as we would have done it in the past,
but this is not how we'll do it anymore.
Instead again, we'll write more code
here in the setup method.
But which code?
Well, there is another function
we can import from the view framework.
And that is the computed function.
And it already gives us a clear hint at what it will do.
You call computed in your setup function,
and then computed once a function
as an argument.
It's the function that holds your computed logic.
So basically what you had
in a computed property before as well,
computed properties with the options API were methods
where you returns to computed value.
And we're doing the same here in this function
which we pass to the computed call here,
we return our computed value.
So for example, firstName plus a blank plus lastName.
And not this firstName,
because we're not referring to a property,
I'm just referring to this firstName, ref here
and to this lastName, ref.
Well and actually since I'm referring to ReFS,
we should use dot value,
because you learned a ref is an object
with a value property and the actual value which is managed,
is stored in that value property.
Which is also why we're setting the value property here
in set first and set lastName.
You're only allowed to omit the value property,
if you use this ref in the template.
If you use it anywhere in JavaScript code,
and you wanna read or write to the value,
then you have to access dot value.
But with that we return this value as a computed property.
And this computed function simply makes sure that
this function we pass to it is re-executed
whenever one of the dependencies.
So in this case, whenever firstName or lastName changes.
And the view will automatically dive into this function
and keep track of all the dependencies specified there.
It will see that you're using firstName and lastName here
and therefore, it will automatically keep track of those
ReFS and updates the computed property
whenever one of the two ReFS changes.
Now of course computing a value is nice,
but only useful if we save it somewhere.
So here I have my,
uName,
I commented out the old uName.
So now I have my new uName, which is a computed property.
And a computed property under hood is also just a ref.
So on uname, you can access a value,
but, and that's important
but it is a ref which is read-only.
Normal ReFS like firstName and lastName and Age
are read and write.
We can set new values as we're doing it in various places.
Computed properties, computed ReFS are read-only.
Setting value like I'm doing it here
is not something you should do
is not something that's allowed.
Reading is okay though.
And with that,
we return our userName
still pointing at uName, which now is this new computed ref.
And with that userName should be output here.
And it should be updated whenever we type into those inputs.
So if we save this, you initially see no name up there,
but if I start typing, you see that name
getting longer and longer.
And that is because we're using a computed property
a computed ref which we exposed to the template,
which we update by updating our first
and lastName ReFS.