So that's how we can use computed.
Let me come back to those inputs.
I mentioned that event listening works just as before.
You can call those methods as you need to.
You can forward the default event argument.
It's forwarded automatically if you just point
at the method, and you can forward any other arguments
your methods might need.
But you can also use our core vue features
with the composition API.
For example, V-model to add two-way binding
in case you want it this year.
So instead of manually listening to the input event,
and calling our functions here.
Which of course were extended is fine,
but instead of just doing that, you can also use V-model.
And here's the cool thing, V-model also accepts refs
and reactive values.
So here I can just bind first name
and here I just bind that last name,
and vue will automatically detect that these are refs.
And it will update the value properties
whenever you type into those fields.
So you don't bind dot value, instead, as mentioned before,
in the template, when working with a ref,
you'll always just use the ref like this without drilling
into the value property.
Vue will do this for you behind the scenes.
So with that we're binding first name
and last name here, but if we save that, we'll see
that it won't work.
If I reload, I'm getting a warning already.
And if I type here, we see no update on the screen.
And the warning is that property last name
was accessed during render but it's not defined.
Wait what?
It is defined here.
Well, it's defined in setup, and we're using it in template,
but one thing is missing.
We're not exposing it to the template.
Whatever you wanna use in a template needs to be part
of that object, you return at the end of setup.
And here, we're not returning first and last name.
We are returning our old update functions,
but we're actually not using those anymore,
so we can't even delete them.
Instead, we should now expose first name
and point and our first name or ref.
Or use the shorthand, if we use the same key name
as we have for the variable name,
and expose last name.
So we need to expose those two ref's
under any names of our choice,
for example, under the same names,
so that we can access them here.
And now with that, if we save this and reload,
the warning is gone.
And now you'll see two-way binding works just as before
with refs here.