So, now let's have a look at the last option
we want to replace, and that's the watch option.
Watch can be useful for running some code,
like setting up behind the scenes HTTP requests
when some data changes.
Of course, I don't want to send that HTTP request
in the simple app here,
but I still want to show you a how watch works.
Normally, you add your watch option here,
which watch is object,
and in there, you could then watch age,
by adding a method of the same name,
so watch this age property by adding such a method,
you would get the new value whenever watch triggers,
and then you could console log val here, for example.
That's what you could do with watch.
Well, obviously that's not what we're doing now,
instead we import a new thing from view
and that thing is another function, the watch function.
The watch function is all the part of the Composition API
and the watch function allows us to register
a watcher inside of this setup method.
And yes, it's quite normal that you have a lot of things
in this setup method, as you can tell already.
So in here, let's say here, for example,
after we defined our refs, we can call watch.
Now, watch wants two arguments here,
the first argument, is a dependency of watch,
telling watch when it should execute the watcher function,
and for example, here we could pass the uAge ref.
So this ref is now a dependency of watch.
The second argument is the actual function
that should be called then.
Now, we need to specify this dependency
because with the Options API,
the dependency was just the name of the watch method.
Now, it's just watch as a function,
so to still let watch know
when the watcher function should run,
we need to specify the pendency first.
So, that's uAge,
and then whenever uAge changes, this function is executed.
In this function,
we now actually get two arguments automatically by watch,
and that's the new value and the old value.
So, we get to the value of uAge before it changed,
and then after the change.
And here we can console log old age plus old value,
and then also console log
new age plus new value, like this.
And that's all.
If we now save this and reload,
nothing is printed here, as you can tell.
But if I now click change age, which changes the age,
we see old age, 31,
new age, 33,
because our watch are executed since we changed age,
which is our dependency here.
Actually, you can also specify more than one dependency,
so that you even gain more flexibility than with watch,
the Options API, by passing an array of dependencies here.
Then here, you could specify uAge,
and let's say uName as a dependency,
and therefore, let's move watch below uName,
so that we do have access to it.
So now, either when age or does computed ref changes,
when either of these two changes, this function executes,
and then we actually also get
different kinds of values here, as arguments.
We get our new values here and our old values.
We now get a raise for both arguments
because we have more than one dependency.
So our old age now is old values,
and then the first element,
since the age is our first dependency
and our new age is new values, and then the first element.
Because if you have more than one dependency,
you get more than one value for these arguments,
and the order of values here,
follows the order of your dependencies.
Hence, of course, if you want to,
we can also copy those console log statements
and output the old name, which has old values,
and then the second element,
and new name, which is new values,
and then the second element.
Now with that saved, if we reload,
I can change the age
and you'll see old age, new age
and nothing for old name and new name,
because there we didn't enter anything.
But if I now start typing here, maybe just one character,
we see the watcher fires again,
because now the age didn't change, but the name did.
So, you even gain more flexibility with this watch function,
because now, unlike in the Options API,
where you always had just one dependency per watcher,
you can now have multiple dependencies
that trigger this watcher function.
And that's how you replace watch
with this watch function when using the Composition API.