Now, that is the core of the composition API.
We covered the core features in the last lectures,
ref and reactive, computed, watch,
and calling functions from inside the template.
What's really important to me here is that you realize
that the template code does not change.
We still use interpolation, we could still use v-bind.
We still listen to events in exactly
the same way we did before.
We can still use v-model.
That's all the same.
Other options we might have, like components or props,
also would not change.
It's just the logic here and setup which is new,
and which replaces, as you learned,
data, methods, computed, and watch.
Now, of course, still there are many other minor things
you gotta know when working with the composition API,
some issues and problems you will eventually run into,
which you gotta know how to solve when switching
from the options API to the composition API,
which is why we will also apply to composition API
to a bigger project, to see all those
special cases in action.
There are a couple of special cases,
which I wanna cover before we dive into a project though.
So in the next lectures,
I'll dive into some individual aspects you should
be aware of when working with the composition API.