Let's start with refs.
And now I don't mean refs in the setup method,
which are our reactive values.
But I mean, refs referring to elements in our template.
Let's say for the LastName, for whatever reason,
we don't want to use the model.
Instead here, I want to use set a ref
LastNameInput.
And I want to use the approach you saw a couple of times
throughout the course, where I read the value
from an input by using this $ ref's variable
inside of some method in our config object.
So let's say we want to do the same here.
So we have a button here,
Set Name, where upon a click,
I want to call some setName function,
and that function should then set the LastName.
Actually therefore, I will name it setLastName
and name the function setLastName.
Now, of course, first of all, we created that function.
So we add a new function in the setup method setLastName.
This function receives no arguments.
But in here, I now want to set LastName.Value,
referring to the value prop of my LastName ref here
equal to the value stored in this input.
And for this, historically, with the options API,
we would have used this $refs,
and then our ref name here, which is LastNameInput.value
This won't work here though, because
inside of the setup method, you don't have access to this
as you're used to.
You won't find $refs thing there.
Instead, the approach is the other way around you could say.
Now you've defined your refs, including your template refs
like this one, in the setup method.
There is no differentiation between your own refs
that manage your own data, and refs you want to bind
to some DOM element.
So here you simply create a new ref LastNameInput
by calling ref.
The initial value here is now because initially
this is not bound to any element in the template.
But now we can simply expose LastNameInput to the template
by returning it here.
Maybe instead of LastName, which we now don't need
in the template anymore.
We now expose LastNameInput, and also already
the setLastName function here.
So expose this function as well.
So now this new ref and this function is exposed.
And now LastNameInput is bound to this input here
because we're using the same name here.
And you still assign a ref like this,
just a string with the ref name that you created
in your setup function.
So LastName and put here, once it's exposed to the template
like this is then available under that name
for this special a ref prop, which you can set
on any DOM element of your choice.
And Vue will make the connection behind the scenes.
And with that, we'll be able to go to our setLastName
function here, and simply get the value from that input
by accessing LastNameInput.value.value.
Now this might look strange, this .value.value thing,
keep in mind you always get access to the value of a ref
with .value.
And the value of this ref will be a pointer
at this input element object.
And this object in turn will also have a value property,
holding the user input.
So the second .value is getting access to
that value property of the input element object,
the first .value gets access to the value of our ref,
which then is that input element object.
With that we get access to the user input,
and we're setting our LastName equal to it.
And therefore, with all of that if we save this and reload,
I can enter max here, my watcher fires and I see max here.
But if I type here in the LastName,
this does not update automatically,
because we removed two way binding.
Instead, I can now click setLastName, and it works.
And it also of course, triggers the watcher.
So that's how we can work with template refs.