Now up to this point,
I always just worked with my main Vue app here.
Typically, of course, you have multiple components.
Let's say we have a separate component
for the user data here,
so we could create a components folder,
and in there have a UserData.vue file.
And here in the template,
I want to have my age two tag with the username.
And I want to have my age free tag with my age.
Now we can add a script here
and we can expect some props here
because that data should come from outside,
username and age.
So we could add a username and age prop here,
and now simply go back to App.vue
and import this user data component
from ./components/UserData.vue,
and register it with the components option.
And as I mentioned before, you still have this option,
this does not go into the setup method,
you keep your option here.
So we register UserData here, this new component,
and we can then use it here,
user-data, opening and closing,
and bind those props, userName and age.
And I'll bind userName to my userName computed ref,
which is exposed here in the return to object
to the template, and bind age to this age ref,
which we're also exposing.
And that, therefore, all just works, as you can tell.
However, maybe we wanna do more in this component.
Maybe here we wanna use the setup method as well,
because maybe we don't get the userName like this,
but instead we get the first name and last name separated,
and we want to compute it here in the setup method.
Well, first of all, let's maybe not use the setup method,
but a good old computed option.
So let's use the Options API here.
Then we could have a userName computed property,
since that's what I'm using here in the template,
and simply return this dot firstName + blank,
+ this dot lastName, right?
This is how we could do this
in a regular component, using the Options API,
if we get two props and we wanna merge it
into one computed prop.
Now, we just need to bind first and last name.
So in App.vue, I now bind first-name and last-name,
and the values here should be my firstName ref
and my lastName ref.
And we now need to ensure that both are exposed
to the template.
The firsName ref already is,
but the lastName ref is not anymore.
So let's re add lastName to the object,
which we are returning in setup,
so that this is available in the template.
And now firstName and lastName are forwarded to user data.
And if I saved that, this just works,
and this might or might not be a surprise,
but there's a very important message here.
You can absolutely mix the Options and the Composition API.
App.vue uses the Composition API.
UserData.vue uses the Options API,
and there is nothing wrong with it, absolutely nothing.
Just because you used the Composition API in one component,
does not mean you have to use it
in all components, it's optional.
You can use it wherever it makes sense to you.
So, it is absolutely fine to use the Options API
and therefore the computed option here, in UserData.
And you'll see that those ref values
are extracted correctly by Vue,
and forwarded as values for first and last name props.
Nonetheless, even though we don't have to,
let's say we wanna migrate to the Composition API
inside of UserData as well.
So, instead of using computed here,
we import computed from the Vue framework like this,
and we then add our setup method.
Here, we got our uName, let's say,
of course, this name is up to you.
And we derive it by calling computed
and passing a function to computed,
where we now return, well return what?
We wanna get access to our props here,
firstName and lastName.
In the computed option, we did it with the, this keyword,
but I can tell you, and I told you before,
that this will not work like that.
So if we try to use the, this, keyword
and get access to our props here, this won't work.
We can still give it a try.
Let's return username here as an object,
and point at the computed uName property,
so that in the template, userName is available,
and let's save this.
And you'll notice that I can reload and get an error,
cannot read property firstName of undefined.
So, trying to access firstName on this fails,
because this is undefined at this point,
because setup basically gets called too early by Vue.
At this point of time,
the Vue instance object, doesn't exist yet.
So we don't have access to props like that.
Still, of course, we do get access to props
because setup actually is a method
that accepts two arguments.
The first parameter we get here, is the props parameter.
It's an object full of the props
you're getting in this component.
And therefore, you can simply access props.firstName,
and props.lastName, like this.
Now you can name this argument however you want,
by the way, it's your method.
So any name of your choice is fine,
but I'll go with, props,
and I'll stick to props throughout this course here.
And with that, if we saved it and reload,
now it's working again, as you can tell.
So, to setup method receives this props argument
automatically passed in by Vue.
If your component gets no props,
it's simply an empty object.
You'll always get this props thing,
but it can be empty if you don't have any props.
Here we do have three props,
and therefore they're all part of this props object.
And whenever props should change from outside,
this change is all propagated here to the setup method
and computed, for example, will pick up
that props changed, and will recalculated uName.
As you can tell, if I type here, it updates up here,
which is in that different component.
So props, by default, are reactive,
not the individual values in there,
but the props object as a whole.
So whenever the props object as a whole changes,
which will happen whenever one of the prop changes,
Vue will notice this, and will rerun any code
that depends on props.