Now, setup does not just get
this props parameter.
It also gets a second parameter.
A second argument is always fed in by vue
and that's the context object.
We can console.log(context) here
to see what's inside of that.
If I saved that and reload,
it looks like an empty object,
but actually if we inspect it,
we see three important properties in there.
Attrs, emit and slots.
attrs are any fall through attributes you might have.
So if you set something like let's say,
a class here on user data
and class is not a prop you define here,
then it's automatically a fall through prop.
It's an optional prop you could say.
Here in this case, actually, if I reload,
I will get a warning because there's fall through behavior
doesn't really work if you have multiple route nodes.
But if I wrap this in one route node here, like that,
and then reload, the warning is gone
and now under attrs, if we inspect the Target,
we see our class here with the test value.
So that's attrs it's properties,
which you didn't define as properties,
which just fall through.
slots would give you access to any slot data
you might have in your component.
This of course is a component without slots
but if you had a slot in there,
you could access the slots data programmatically,
through that slot property on context.
And emit is a function,
which you can call to emit a custom event
because of course, that's also something
you often need to do.
And with the options API,
we always use this dollar sign $emit.
Now, since this keyword,
as you learned isn't available here.
This dollar sign emit is not available in the setup method.
Still of course you might have code that needs to emit.
In that case, you have context emit
and that works just like this emit.
So if you had a safe data custom event, for example,
with some data you wanna emit,
the equivalent to this options API syntax would be
this syntax here with context emit.
We don't need it here,
but it is worth being aware of that.