So that's how we can go from the options API
to the composition API.
Data is replaced with refs and reactive,
methods are replaced with functions,
which you expose to the template
by returning them in that object,
which you return in setup.
Computed is replaced with the computed function,
and watchers are replaced with the watcher functions.
Provide inject is replaced
with the provide and inject functions.
Now there's one more thing I wanna dive into
before we apply that all to a bigger project.
And that are lifecycle hooks.
There we have, for example, beforeCreate
and created in the options API,
and we could simply add those methods to our config object.
How does this look like with the composition API?
With the composition API,
we don't add those lifecycle hooks
to our component config object anymore,
instead we have functions which we can import from vue,
which you can call inside of the setup method.
But for beforeCreate and created
there actually is no equivalent,
because these hooks are not needed here,
because the setup method basically runs at the same time
beforeCreate and created ran in the past.
So setup replaces these hooks.
Whatever you would have done in created or beforeCreate
should be done in the setup method itself.
Now for beforeMount and mounted, it's different.
There we have the onBeforeMount and onMounted functions
which can be imported from vue.
For beforeUpdate and updated it's similar
and the same for beforeUnmount and unmounted.
Here we have onBeforeUnmount and onUnmounted.
So you see a pattern here.
Let's not also have a look at that in code.
Back here, let's say in the user data component,
as I mentioned, we're now not going to add created
and mounted and so on here to our options object.
Instead, we're going to add them here in setup
by importing the required hooks.
Now as I mentioned,
there is no onBeforeCreate and so on,
but there is a onBeforeMount,
there is a onMounted, onBeforeUpdate, onUpdated,
and onBeforeUnmount as well as onUnmounted.
And I quickly restructure this to make it easier to read.
These are the lifecycle hook functions,
which we can import from vue.
Now how do we use them in setup?
In setup, you simply call them
like for example onBeforeMount, like this,
and you pass a function to them
and this function will now be executed
whenever this lifecycle hook is due.
So here I can console log beforeMount
or onBeforeMount, whatever you want.
And we can now repeat this.
We also have onMounted,
so here I will print onMounted.
We also have onBeforeUpdate,
so we print onBeforeUpdate.
We have onUpdated,
so here we can print onUpdated.
And we have onBeforeUnmount
and print onBeforeUnmount
as well as here onUnmounted
oops I mean here onUnmounted
and print onUnmounted.
If we now saved it all and reload,
we see onBeforeMount and onMounted here,
if I clear the console and click change age,
we also see onBeforeUpdate,
then our watcher runs and then onUpdated thereafter,
once the update was applied to the template
and to the real DOM.
Well, and for unMounting,
we would need to get rid of user data,
which we can do with an if statement,
for example, with v-if.
If we now had some condition here that could get false,
this component would be removed from the DOM
and when that happens,
the onUnmount hooks would be called.
But I think the pattern should be clear here.
We see those logs here
and we see that this is how you can register code
that should be executed
at different phases of the lifecycle of a component.
You simply call those special functions
which you import from vue,
and you pass your function that holds
your to be executed code to those functions.
And that's how you work with lifecycle hooks
in the composition API.