So now, with all the knowledge
about the Composition API
we gained over the last lectures in this module,
we can come back to this project I showed you
in the second lecture of this module,
where I mentioned why you could consider
using the Composition API instead of the Options API.
Now, you'll find this project attached.
If you install everything and start the development server,
you'll see this application here.
Here you can sort the users, you can filter for users.
It's a very simple filter here, but it works.
You can select a user to view the projects,
and you can also filter those projects here, if you want to.
So, that is the project we have here,
and that's entirely built with the Options API.
I strongly recommend that you maybe pause the video here
and go through the project real quick,
so that you see how it is built,
how it is made up of different components,
that you see how the different pieces work together.
In the end, it's not a super complex project,
it's basically all about having a list of users
where every user then has a list of projects,
but we've got a couple of components that work together here
for displaying the users, for displaying the projects,
and, of course, also for,
for example, adding search, and so on.
So, take that break to analyze the project.
And thereafter, we'll start migrating this
to the Composition API.
Of course, you can also try this on your own.
This might be a great practice,
but if you get stuck or if you're not sure,
definitely also feel free to do this together with me.
Starting in the next lecture,
we'll dive into this, and we'll migrate this entire project
from the Options API to the Composition API.