Were you successful?
In case you try this on your own
and you succeeded, great job.
In case you face some problems,
well, that is no problem at all.
We just got started with the Composition API.
So it is absolutely normal
that you're maybe not 100% sure
about all the concepts yet.
Now we'll migrate this QD Composition API together.
And I will start in App Vue.
App Vue is a very simple component,
it has a very simple template,
where I in the end just use to overall components
and pass data to those components.
And then we got two pieces of data here,
the currently selectedUser,
when we select a user here to view the project
and the activeUsers,
which simply are our users which we want to display.
And the activeUsers are populated with some dummy User_Data,
which is coming from the dummy data JavaScript file,
in there, I'm simply exporting a long array,
and I just outsourced this into a separate file
so that I don't have to as long array
in my App Vue file.
Of course, that could be data
which be fetched from a server,
in reality, here, it's just this dummy User_Data.
So in order to migrate this component
to the Composition API,
in the end, we will replace the data
and the methods option with the new setup option,
because that's what you learned in this module.
The setup option,
this setup method is the key to using the Composition API,
because in there you set up your component,
the data you want to be able to use in your template,
and also all the functions that should be callable
and so on.
And here we got two pieces of data,
our activeUsers, and our selectedUser.
So now we can make our first decision
on how we want to manage that data.
We could manage that data in an object,
and then we can create that object
either as a ref or with the reactive function
as you learned,
or we managed two separate pieces of data,
selectedUser, and this User_Data array.
It's up to you, what you want to do,
I will actually go forward to separated data.
So I will import from Vue
and I will import is ref function,
because I wanna create two separate refs here.
Again, this is just want to approach,
and if you want to manage one object with reactive maybe,
that is fine as well.
But I will go forward is ref here
or for these two refs,
and then we have to selectedUser here,
where I create a new ref where the initial value is null,
and then we have the activeUsers also ref,
where I pass in my User_Data.
Now actually, by the way,
User_Data, this doesn't need to be a ref,
because in this entire component
I got no logic for changing activeUsers.
And if you never change data,
this probably doesn't need to be a ref
because Vue doesn't need to know about any changes then
if there are no changes.
So actually, activeUsers could also just be managed
as regular data like this,
because it's data that never changes.
So I will not even turn this into a ref here
to make it clear that we don't need a ref here.
Well, and then we want to expose this to our template.
So we returned as object in the setup method,
which is a key concept.
You always return in object in setup
to tell Vue which features you could say,
which constants and variables and functions
from inside to set up method should be available
in the template.
And here, I wanna expose the selectedUser
using this JavaScript shorthand,
where instead of writing this,
I write this and I expose my activeUsers.
ActiveUsers can't change
or Vue will not notice any changes since it isn't a ref.
But of course this does not mean
that we can't expose it to the template.
We absolutely can.
And was that we can get rid of the data method here
and I will remove it here.
You could, of course, all the commented out
if you wanna see it in comparison.
Now with that, we migrated our data.
Now we all wanna migrate the method
because right now this method wouldn't work.
We try to work with this selectedUser
and this property doesn't exist anymore
because I just deleted data.
As a side note, theoretically,
you can use data methods and set up side by side,
if there is some data
and functionality you wanna manage
with the Composition API,
and other data and functionality
you wanna manage with the options API.
So even inside of the same component,
you could mix those concepts.
In reality, I would say you will typically migrate
an entire component to the Composition API
or stick to the options API and not mix it,
but theoretically, you could mix it.
Anyways, here I wanna migrate everything.
So therefore in setup, we can define a function,
maybe keep the name selectUser,
expect to get the user ID as argument here,
and then set selectedUser.value equal to,
well, basically this logic.
So I can copy this except for this keyword,
and find the user with that ID in my activeUsers
and set my selectedUser equal to that user.
And now we can also get rid of methods here
and expose selectUser, no selectUser like this
to the template as well.
So did our event binding here,
here sorry, still works.
And that should be all.
If we saved this and reload,
this application works just as it does before,
because as I also mentioned throughout this module,
you can absolutely combine components
that use the options API,
which in this case are all our components
and components that use the Composition API,
the App Vue component in this case.
This is absolutely possible
and that's exactly what we're doing here.
So with that, we migrated our first component,
let's now move on to the next one.