As a next component to migrate,
I'll tackle a big one UserList.vue.
This component contains a lot of logic.
This is actually the component I used
as an example of seeing logic
that is scattered out across options.
So now we finally can hopefully see
how we can keep the logic in one place
with the Composition API.
So here in the UserList.vue file,
again, I'll start by adding the setup method,
and I also wanna make it clear
that we leave components and props untouched.
These options still exist,
they are not replaced by the Composition API.
They still work as you learned it,
we still tell Vue which local components
we wanna use in this component,
and we still inform Vue about the props
this component receives, so that stays where it is.
But of course, I am going to replace my data here.
So instead of setup, I now got three pieces of data
which I wanna manage,
and all three pieces of data should be reactive,
they can change and Vue should be able
to notice these changes.
And again, it's up to you,
whether you wanna use an object or refs,
or maybe group these search things into an object
and use a ref for sorting, totally up to you.
I will go for refs here again,
because I like the simplicity refs offer us.
So here I'll simply import the ref function from Vue,
and then in setup, I got three refs I wanna create
and I'll keep the names we have down there.
So the enteredSearchTerm is a ref
where the initial value is an empty string.
The activeSearchTerm is a ref
that initially is an empty string,
or that holds an empty string,
and sorting is a ref which initially holds null as a value.
So now these are our three pieces of data,
and now I'll do one thing already,
which we can't do with the Options API,
I'll split the place where I defined data,
because I now wanna put all the other search related things,
functions and so on, directly below these refs here
and put all the sorting related logic below this ref.
So that we have search logic first and then sorting logic,
so that we don't have is splitting of logic
across different places so that now we can keep
the things that belong together, together.
Anyway, we can get rid of data and again,
you can remove it or comment it out.
And here I'll comment that out for now
so that we still see where we're coming from,
and so that we later can see the difference
between Composition API and Options API.
And we can continue with computed,
here we got the availableUsers
where in the end I'm checking my activeSearchTerm
to filter down the users based on the search term
and displayedUsers is another computed property,
which deals with sorting.
So here we got two different pieces of logic,
search and sorting.
Anyways, we get computed properties
and therefore we should import computed from Vue
because that is our Composition API equivalent
to the computed option.
And then let's start with the computed property for search.
So we can call computed it here,
and then pass in a function like this,
where I now want to compute well, my availableUsers,
and we can copy the logic
from the computed property down there, copy it in here,
but now of course, it's not this activeSearchTerm,
but activeSearchTerm.value because activeSearchTerm is a ref
and you learned we need to access to value property
to read the value.
It also will not be this.users,
but well, where are users coming from?
What is users here?
this.Users, Well that's our props,
in the Options API we can refer to props with this keyword,
this and then the prop name and users is a prop.
In the setup method you learned
that this keyword is undefined, so that won't work.
How can we get access to prop there?
Well, you might remember the setup method
gets two parameters, which you can accept
and which can work with it gets them always
automatically by Vue,
and here, the first parameter is the one that helps us.
This is an object full of the props this component receives.
So in this case, this will have a users key,
so here becomes that props.users instead of this.users.
We do this in all the places
where we access this.users here.
And here again, instead of this.activeSearchTerm,
it's activeSearchTerm.value,
and that's now the migrated computed property code.
Now I will name my computed property avaliableUsers,
because that is the name we also used here
in the Options API.
But with that, we migrated this computed property over.
Now let's work on the other computed property,
and for that, I can already copied the code
we have in there in displayedUsers, so copy that code.
But since it is related to sorting,
I will now put this here below my sorting ref,
again, so that I keep all the search logic
together in one place
and then the sorting logic together in one place.
That is one of the key advantages
the Composition API can offer us.
So here I have my displayedUsers where I use computed
and I have a function here, copy in the code.
And then here, I'm referring to this sorting,
well, that is now my sorting ref here.
So instead of this.sorting, it's sorting.value,
this.availableUsers won't work
because availableUsers is my computed property from up there
and computed properties as you also learned in this module
are all just refs, read only refs,
and they offer you also access .value there,
and of course it's not just there, but also here,
I'm calling slice by the way here,
to create a copy first of this array,
because otherwise I also sort the existing array,
which I don't wanna do, I wanna return a new sorted array.
Here, it's again sorting.value,
and then here in all these places,
it's sorting.value, like that..
With that, we migrated to our displayedUsers.
So we can comment out the entire computed property block
now, let me do this here and one to the methods.
Here we got a method related to search
and one related to sorting
and in updateSearch, I just updated my enteredSearchTerm.
I'm just going to copy this, this entire method
and go up to my search functionality,
maybe here below the computed property
and add a function and then copy in that name,
updateSearch, where I get a value.
And now of course it's not this.enteredSearchTerm,
but enteredSearchTerm.value
which is equal to the val chosen by the user.
And with that we can move on to the sort method here
and already comment out methods I guess,
and bring that sort method below our sorting logic here
into setup method, so that would be here,
there I now add a new function sort
where I set sorting.value = mode,
referring to my sorting ref,
and with that we migrated methods.
Now we gotta watcher, this watcher is basically here
to not update the search logic on every keystroke,
but add a slight delay and only if what the user entered
didn't change for a period of 300 milliseconds
only then I wanna take this as a new search trip,
that's the logic I have here in the end.
So therefore, copy this logic I have in the watcher
and then comment out is watcher.
And now, since I want to add a watcher related to search,
I first of all import watch from Vue
and then maybe here below to computed property,
we can call watch, and as a second argument
pass in a function, which holds that code
I just copied from the Options API watcher,
and of course set the dependency of the watcher,
which is the entered search term.
So point at entered search term here
to make it clear to Vue that this function should run
whenever the entered search term changes.
Here, we then get our newValue
and a newValue is then compared
to the value we currently have in enteredSearchTerm.value,
and I wanna set activeSearchTerm.value = newValue
if we don't have a difference here,
so if the user didn't change the input
for a period of 300 milliseconds.
Now with that, I've migrated all the logic,
now it is time to expose the things
that we need in the template to template.
So at the end of this setup function,
we now we'll add our returned object
and now return all the things
that should be available to the template.
And that's for example, the enteredSearchTerm,
we're using it here.
We will also need to the updateSearch function,
as we can see here.
We need to sorting ref as we can see we're using it here.
We need to sort function, which you can see here.
We need to displayedUsers, and that should be it.
And I even noticed a slight glitch here,
I'm emitting a custom event here
of course we should add emits here,
and that should have been added before
with the Options API as well.
Well, I just noticed it,
so to follow all best practices here,
let's add list-projects as an emitted event here,
but that's just a side note should have been added before.
Now let's expose what we need
and that was the enteredSeartchTerm, the displayedUsers,
the updateSearch function, the sorting ref,
and the sort function, and I think that'll be it.
So sorting and sort and I'm getting an error,
availableUser is assigned a value,
looks like I have a typo,
this should be availableUsers here,
the name of my computer property.
With that, it compiles,
and if I reload, this is looking good.
Let me open the dev tool to see
if we've got any errors here
and sorting seems to work, searching all the works,
and selecting a user also seems to do the trick here.
So it looks like the App works as before
and with that, we migrated the user list
that you find from the Options API,
which you can still see down there to the Composition API.
And of course that's still a lot of code,
I mean, the amount of logic didn't really change,
but one advantage, a possible advantage is that
now all the search functionality is in one block
and all the sorting functionality is in one block of code.
And that can make managing components like this easier
since you don't have to scroll as much,
if I need to change something related to search,
it's all in that area, not somewhere down the component.
Now, of course, that might or might not matter to you,
but it can be an advantage in bigger components.