So let's move on to the next component.
Let's say the UserItem.
This is a simple component.
It doesn't have a lot of logic in it,
just props, a custom event and then one method.
So we could, of course,
absolutely keep the options API here and you know what?
I will actually do, just that.
I wanna make it clear that the composition API
is not a must use and that it is fine
to mix and match components using
different APIs in the same project.
You also might have reasons for moving every component
to a certain approach in an entire project.
But on the other hand,
you could also argue that there's nothing wrong
with the options API in such a simple component.
So I will leave it here, but of course,
be aware that migrating it to the composition API
would also be fine.
But with that, I'm done with Users.
Let's move on to UI.
Here in BaseSearch we get another simple component
and for the same reason as before
I will keep the options API approach here.
But again, as I just said,
you could also migrate simply to have
all components using the same API in a given project.
The BaseContainer doesn't even have any scripting logic.
The ProjectItem.vue also doesn't really have anything
just gets a title prop, so there is nothing to migrate here.
And that leaves us with the ProjectList component.
Here, just as with the UserList component,
we get a bunch of logic,
so that will be the last component
I now migrate from options to composition API.
So, to do that as before,
let's add to set up method here
and let's start with the data.
You might notice SearchTerm thing.
It's basically what we did in the UserList.vue file.
And therefore, we will just repeat what we did there.
I will import from Vue and I will import ref here
to manage two refs and then create the
enteredSearchTerm ref,
which is an empty string and the activeSearchTerm,
which is a ref with an empty string initially.
And then we can comment out data or delete it of course.
Now for computed.
There, I got a hasProjects computed property,
which basically just checks whether this user
has any project at all,
and we've got the availableProjects computed property.
Now I will start with the
availableProjects computed property.
So let me use computed here,
import computed and call computed here,
stored the result in the availableProjects constant
to keep that name and then just copy the logic from here
into the function that we passed to computed,
where I'm checking the activeSearchTerm value.
And then I wanna work with props again,
so we should again, accept props here as our argument,
as a parameter in the setup method,
so that we can access props,user.projects.
And then here again, use activeSearchTerm.value
and here again, props.user.projects.
And with that, I migrated the computed property
to this new computed property.
So, let's now continue with hasProjects maybe
with the second computed property.
I will already copy the logic and then simply create
a new hasProjects computed property by calling computed,
and in the function we pass here,
I return props.user.projects,
and availableProjects.value.length now.
.value because availableProject is a computed property,
therefore now a ref,
and therefore we get the value by accessing .value.
And now both computer properties are migrated
and we can comment this out as well.
updateSearch is a function we have to add
so that should be pretty straightforward,
function, updateSearch,
where I simply update enteredSearchTerm.value
and set it equal to val.
And then last but not least,
I have my watcher here where I again will copy this logic.
I got a second watcher thereafter as well,
but I'll start with this first one.
So copy that logic, import watch from Vue
and then add the watcher maybe here
below the computed properties.
Add this watcher,
add this function with that watcher logic
and add enteredSearchTerm as a dependency,
because in the end,
it's the value of the enteredSearchTerm
we're interested in, and here I wanna compare the newValue
to my enteredSearchTerm value.
So it's the same logic as the UserList component
and update the activeSearchTerm value whenever that changed.
And just in case you're wondering,
activeSearchTerm isn't a dependency here
because changes is an activeSearchTerm
shouldn't trigger this watcher.
And then I got a second watcher here.
This one where I basically reset the enteredSearchTerm
whenever we got a new user.
So here, I'm watching the user prop.
And I'm doing this so that if I
just searched here, let's say, and I switch users,
I reset that and show all the projects
of the newly selected user.
So that's why I have this watcher,
and therefore, I'll copy that watcher logic
and add a new watcher function here.
And the watcher function holds that logic, of course,
where I set enteredSearchTerm.value.
But now the dependency is of course not enteredSearchTerm,
but as before, my user prop.
Now here, you could do props.user,
but this would not work as you will see.
But let's try this first and then I'll explain
why this won't work.
And now let's comment out the watcher,
and save everything, and now of course,
expose with return to the template
what we need in the template.
Because right now we're getting an error
that some things are missing or are not being used.
Now in the template we absolutely need our user,
this user prop, and that will be available automatically.
We don't need to expose it because props,
which you would assign here,
are automatically available in the template.
That logic doesn't change.
So you don't need to expose props here,
but we need to expose hasProjects,
the updateSearchFunction, the enteredSearchTerm,
the availableProjects.
Yeah, that should be the things we need to expose.
So the enteredSearchTerm, availableProjects,
hasProjects, and updateSearch.
And with that I'm getting val is not defined
and an unnecessary semi-colon, yeah, here in this watcher.
I renamed the argument to newValue,
something you don't have to do, but since I did it,
I should also rename it here,
reformat everything to get rid of that extra semi-colon,
which I have somewhere.
And now there's loads,
but now I'm getting an error or a warning here,
invalid watch source, null.
And that is coming from the watcher where I watch my user.
I mentioned that this wouldn't work.
The problem with drilling into props here to access the user
is that we're basically drilling into a reactive object
to then watch a non-reactive value.
Initially user is null
because initially no user is selected.
And now we're watching null, which makes no sense to Vue.
Instead, we need to watch something reactive.
A ref, or a reactive object.
Props is a reactive object,
but just as we had it before in the module,
the values inside of props are not reactive, are not refs.
And therefore, we should watch props as a whole here.
And if we do this and reload, now that works.
Now of course, here that's fine
because we only have one prop,
but if you had multiple props, and they could change,
the problem you would have is that your watcher
runs whenever any prop changes, not just a user prop.
So if you would want to handle this,
which again is not necessary here,
because we only have one prop,
but if you would want to be sure that only
changes in user triggered this watcher,
you could use a feature provided by Vue.
We can use the two refs function,
which we also saw earlier in this module,
in this optional, deep dive, reactivity, deep dive lecture,
We can call two refs on props.
And now we got our props with refs object, you could say,
and from there we can extract our user like this,
or with a bit of a more modern, shorter syntax,
using object de-structuring like this,
this will pull out the user key from that props object.
And now because of two refs,
that will be a ref and will then store this
in a constant of the same name.
And now we could add user as a dependency here,
which now thanks to two refs, will be a ref.
That is the alternative if you don't want to watch
all props, but just one prop.
It's a bit advanced,
but I hope it's clear why we're doing this.
With that, If I reload, this works.
I can switch to different users.
Searching here works.
Resetting, if I switched the user all the works,
and with that overall,
it looks like we're able to,
well, make this app work.
And it looks like we migrated this app successfully
from the options API queue to composition API.
And that hopefully does not just show you
why the composition API might be better,
especially for large components like userList,
but it also, hopefully now helps you understand
how the composition API works
and how you can use it in your next projects if you want to.
I just want to come back to one thing real quick,
and that is this second argument
for using the composition API.
I mentioned that reusing logic across components
can be tricky or cumbersome and could be easier
when using the composition API.
Well, this is something we're not going to have a look at
in this module, but instead in the next module,
which will be about reusing code and logic in general,
not just with the composition API,
but also still with the options API,
because the composition API is just an alternative,
not a must use.