The basics of decomposition API should be clear now,
but throughout this course,
we haven't just learned about data and computed properties.
We've for example,
also learned about a routing
and attached you find a number starting project,
where they got a very simple application
that uses routing set up for you.
Now if you load this application,
this is what you got.
You essentially got two main routes,
all products and add product,
here you can well add a new product,
and then you see it here.
And we face a couple of problems
or uncertainties here when using the composition API.
For example, when I add a new product
and I click add product,
it would be great if I would automatically be redirected
to all products.
In addition, when I click view details here,
I wanna see the details for that product.
And why is that complicated with decomposition API,
at least at the moment,
because we don't know how to get that data
on this route, for example,
because we don't know how to navigate programmatically.
Without decomposition API
we knew that there was this dollar sign router
and this dollar sign route.
So for example,
the product details page it's loaded
for slash products,
and then this dynamic segment.
Now we learned in the routing module of this course
that we can get the concrete value for this dynamic segment
inside of the product details here
with this dollar sign route object.
The problem with decomposition API
is that there is no this keyword in the setup method.
So how do we get our route parameters here then?
Well, there are two ways of fixing this.
For one you can, of course use an approach,
which has showed you into routing module.
You can configure this route,
such that the dynamic segment is passed as a prop
into the to be loaded component,
simply by adding this props option
on the route config and setting it to true.
Now the value for PID product ID will be provided
as a prop in the product details component.
And you know,
that we get props as a first argument here
in the setup method.
So now with that,
we could then use inject to inject the products
which I'm managing and providing here
in app view into product details.
So here we can get our products by calling inject products,
injecting the provided products
and on our props, we'll get this PID prop,
which holds the value off the dynamic segment in the URL.
So here in product details,
we can then get our selected product
by reaching out to products.
So to inject the products and finding the product
where product.id is equal to props.PID.
PID, because that's the name I chose here
in my route config,
and then we can get the title, price and description
from that selected product.
So we don't even need our refs here
because I don't want to set up or change the data in here.
I just want to extract it from the selected product.
So we get title by selecting select product.title,
and the same for the price.
And of course,
then also for the description
selected product.description.
And now the only thing we got to do is we have to ensure
that the different product IDs are provided in the URL
when we click view details
for that in all products where it is router link is set up,
this should, of course not be ID as a text
instead two, should be dynamically bound to a string,
for example, which starts with slash products,
but which then includes the ID off the product
we're rendering here
and we get that from product.id here,
just as I'm assigning the key here on the list item.
And with that,
I can click on view details
and I see nothing reason for that is that,
I got an error product find is not a function.
We of course must not forget that products,
which we inject here is a ref here in app view
and therefore of course,
when we wanna access the concrete value in their DRA,
we have to do this with the value property on products.
And of course,
we should also let you know
about the props we're getting here.
So add pid as a prop here.
And with that, we can view the details and this works.
Now, what if we, for whatever reason,
had a router link here in the details,
which always leads to product two.
So where the link goes to products/P2,
which is the idea of product two,
if I'm on the page of product one
and I click this, this doesn't update.
And we noticed problem from earlier in the course
now with the options API,
when we used props to get our product data,
we'd watched our props data,
our dynamic parameter value for changes,
and we need to do something similar here.
We could use a computed property, for example,
to make selected product, a computed property,
a computed value.
Like this, now of course,
we then should also make sure that those other values,
title, price, and description update
when we got a new selected product
and there are various ways of doing that one way,
definitely not the shortest one,
but one way would be to now turn those
into computed properties as well.
Like that.
And if we do this,
we of course have to use .value here
since selected product is now a ref.
It's a computed property after all
with that if we save this,
go to the first product
and click product two now this updates,
this is how we could do this with decomposition API,
but that was all just one way
of getting our dynamic route parameter by utilizing props.