What if we wanted to use
the dollar sign route object?
Maybe, also because we're not just interested
in our route parameters,
but in the query parameters or in the path.
Now, as mentioned before,
that this key word does not exist here.
So we can't access this dollar sign route,
and we can't access this dollars sign router,
but we can import something
from vue-router that will help us.
We can import a couple of built in hooks,
also called composables.
Now what are hooks or composables?
In the end these are different terms
for a special kind of function,
hooks, composables, custom composition functions.
These are special functions written in JavaScript,
which are built for the composition API.
So for being used inside of the setup method,
these functions internally typically use some composition
API features like Refs or Computed.
In a separate module later about reusing functionality
you will learn how to build your own hooks,
your own custom composition functions
here the vue-router team did this for us.
And it's giving us a couple of functions,
a couple of composition functions,
also called hooks or composables,
which you can call inside of the setup method
to then get access to certain features
that work together nicely with the composition API
and useRoute, for example,
allows us to get access to this route object,
here like this.
If we do this, I can console log route here.
And if I do that, save this, and reload
and opened that console we see that is a reactive object
and there for a proxy with all that route data in there.
And since it's reactive,
we can of course watch it or use it in computer props
to update any data that depends on it,
whenever route changes.
So with that instead of props PID,
we could also use route parents PID here
that would be possible.
And then of course we don't need props.
So if we use that go to the carpet, it works just as before,
but now using this route object,
which we get with help of the useRoute hook
or custom composition function
also sometimes called composable,
whatever you wanna call it,
which is provided by the vue-router package.
And another composable another hook
which is also provided by vue-router
can help us with the programmatic navigation
and add product here in submit form in this function
I wanna navigate to the all products page
As soon as a product has been added
in the options API world,
we would use this router push
and then go to slash products, for example.
In the composition API world,
the, this keyword doesn't exist and hence this doesn't work,
but again, the vue-router team has got us covered
from vue-router,
we can import useRouter,
so not to useRoute like before,
but now use router.
And we can call this anywhere in our setup method like this,
to get access to this router object.
And now we can simply call router push
using that router object we create
by calling that custom composition function
provided by the vue-router team.
So if we now save that and go to add product,
and I enter some data,
and click add product,
we're navigated to the all products page.
And that is all I wanted to show here.
This is how you can use the vue-router in components
that use the composition API.
Generally, the router works just as before
you define routes in the same way,
and you can use all the features you learn about.
But when it comes to dynamic parameters
possibly passed to a component as props
or when it comes to using the route or router object,
this is how you can use these features
by using the custom composition functions
provided by the vue-router package or by using props
as I showed it to you a couple of minutes ago.