Now we know how we can use routing
with the composition API.
What about Vuex?
How can we use that with the composition API?
For this, attached you find another
very simple dummy project.
We've got a counter there and a button,
which currently does nothing,
but this is built with the composition API.
I mean, these are very simple components,
but I plan on using the composition API there.
The App.vue file is pretty straightforward and simple,
just a couple of local components here.
And then in the counter, I output the counter,
but I plan on getting the counter with the composition API.
At the moment I just have a dummy counter here,
which does never change.
And in the control center,
I also plan on defining this function with the composition
API, but at the moment, it's does nothing.
Now, obviously we don't need Vuex
for this simple of an application.
We don't need Vuex for this demo,
but I want to show you how you can utilize Vuex with the
composition API in case you're building more complex
projects where you need Vuex.
So how does this work?
In main JS, I already set up a store with createStore,
as you learned in the Vuex module.
I have a state, mutations, an action and a getter.
And how can we now utilize that store,
which I'm already using in my app, in these components?
Well, just as the router,
the Vue router offered us a custom composition function,
which we could call inside of our setup method
to use routing features.
Just as the router did this, the Vuex package has
something similar in store.
So in the control center,
where I in the end want to dispatch the increment action.
I can import something from Vuex.
And that something, is the useStore hook,
or the useStore composable.
The useStore custom composition function,
which is meant to be executed inside of the setup method.
Here we can then call useStore,
and what we get as a result is access to the...
well to the Vuex store,
which we have attached to this application.
So the Vuex store, we are using with Use here on our app.
We get access to that store by calling useStore
inside of setup.
Well, and once we got access it'll of course be simple.
We can just use store, dispatch
and then dispatch the action.
So dispatch any action, like in this case,
the increment action, which we registered on this store.
And you can then use any Vuex feature you learn about.
Modules, namespacing... all of that is available.
And you just use useStore to get access to the store,
instead of using this dollar sign store,
which you would use if you would be
working with the options API.
Well, and therefore it's the same here in the counter,
where I want to get access to some data stored in the store.
I can simply import useStore from Vuex.
Then, get access to the store by calling useStore.
And thereafter when we want to get a counter that
depends on a getter in the store,
we just need to create a computed variable,
a computed value just as we do it in the options API world.
So therefore we import computed from Vue,
and then counter should be a computed value,
by calling computed,
where we provide a function that will be executed whenever
one of its dependencies changed.
And here in this function,
we returned store.getters.counter,
because counter is the getter name I defined here.
And whenever the counter changes, Vue will detect this
in the end and recalculate this computed value,
which we then expose to the template.
And since you learned that computed values are refs,
whatever the counter does change,
Vue will notice this and it will update the template
in the place where we use the counter.
With that we can save that,
and now if I reload, you see this works.
And that's how easy it is to use Vuex,
with the composition API.