Now that's it for
this very thorough introduction
to the Composition API.
We're going to see more of it
throughout the rest of the course
but with this module you should have
a first thorough idea of what the Composition API is about.
Well, and what is it about, and why do we have it?
First of all, as I emphasized many times,
throughout the module,
it's an alternative to the Options API.
You don't have to use it if you don't like it
or if it just doesn't make sense for your project
but you can use it,
and then you will use the setup method, which you saw,
to expose logic and data to the template
and the idea behind the Composition API
is that it's function based.
You have all those functions you import from Vue,
like ref, react, compute, and so on.
All used in that setup method,
and that this allows you to keep code
that is related logically to gather in one place
instead of splitting it across multiple options.
Data and reactivity of course,
is an important concept in Vue in general
and of course, they are found also in the Composition API
and here we can manage data as refs.
So as individual values or in object which is in ref,
or we use the reactive function
to create reactive objects.
I talked about the differences
and how to work with these values
in great depth throughout this module.
Reactivity is a key concept
and one of the most important takeaways
really is that you can create reactive refs or objects
but that their nested properties
are not necessarily reactive.
As I also emphasized throughout this module.
Now data and reactivity is a key concept
but of course, not everything.
We also have methods, computed and watchers,
when using the Options API,
and in the Composition API,
methods become regular functions
which you define in the setup method
and which you then may expose to the template
by returning it in that object which you return
in the setup method,
and then you also have computed properties and watchers
which are defined with these imported functions
which you import from the Vue framework.
Now if we have a closer look at this setup function
or setup method which we define in
our component conflict object,
this setup function, or this setup method,
is called by Vue, when the component is created,
and in there you define all the data and logic
for this component,
and most importantly for the template.
So what you return in setup
is available in the template as you learned.
In setup itself all the receives two arguments
which are passed and automatically by Vue
when it calls setup for you,
and that is the reactive props object
with all the props you're getting for this component
and this context object with the fall through props,
those attributes, with slot data,
and with this emit function
which you can use for emitting a custom event.